Amazing job you made it for the entire course and that means you learn a lot about node and the many
ways you can use it to build exciting web applications or any kind of application that needs to execute
some code really.
I hope you enjoyed the course and the obvious question is how should you now continue.
Well in general the most important thing I always recommend is that you keep on practicing.
Build example projects.
Clone popular apps build your own simplified Facebook clone.
Strip out some features you don't want to focus on and instead build some parts off that application
you picked.
Build the messaging part build the news feed part.
Anything like that.
Practicing is important and the most important thing there is that you will face issues.
You'll hit some problems.
There will be things what you want to build where you don't know how to continue where you don't know
how it works.
And then the part where you need to dig in where you need to research search on Stack Overflow find
block posts on Google that help you and dig through that problem on your own.
This will make you a better developer and it will help you learn how things work internally and how
you can approach certain problems and solve them.
This is the most important part really.
Now also dive into our concepts related to notorious dive into API eyes like rest API or graphics.
Learn more about these technologies build exampled project Stehr to dive into certain less technologies
and to serve less services.
I got a course on that but you can also just google for node J.S. serval S and you'll find some great
resource there because that is also a very promising interesting way of creating node applications as
you will learn.
You focus way more on your logic and way less on the overhead of spinning up a surveillance on.
So really interesting and maybe you to dive into Front-End development learn how to build a re-act up
like the one I gave you in this course from scratch that could be a great next step too because it will
make you a full stack developer who can do both.
Back in development and frontages development and these are just some of the possibilities you have
obviously as you practice you'll dive into more things that are interesting to you and to your exact
requirements and things that are interesting to you.
And I'm confident that this course gave you pretty solid fundamentals that allow you to build up on
and to dive way deeper.