So back in code let's quickly think about our project.
In the end what we're building here is an online shop.
So what we need is a starting page.
We need a page where we can do all the products that are listed.
We also want to be able to create new products to added products as administrator also to delete products.
We want to be able to add products to a shopping cart to go to a check out page and pay for the products
and then also as a customer we want to be able to see our orders.
So that's a lot of stuff and we'll build all that logic for the course but we can already get started.
And for that I will get started in the views and I'll try to add the views for the different things
we'll need.
Get at product and shop each day asks us for now.
Let's add more views here.
And I will also split them in some folders to group them together basically.
I will add admen subfolder and I'll move to add product view into the Edmond's subfolder for example.
I'll also add another subfolder and that will be my shop.
So does this the customer facing part.
You could say and then I'll have my shop Ejay last fall though I will renamed as to product list Ejaz
because that is what I want to have on this page in the end.
It should be a page with a list of all my products.
Now this of course is not a complete list of all of views but we already need to add some changes.
As I restructured the folder structure here forward a product list for example for my includes this
POV is not correct anymore.
Product list is now in a shop subfolder.
So first of all the two go up one level until I can dive into the includes folder.
So here in that pop we should have dot dot slash which means up one level and to say I'm here for my
navigation.
So all that should be done.
And also for.
And E.J. last year and of course the same for ad product there dare you want to go up one level you're
also up one level and down there up one level with this adjusted it.
We also need to make sure that we render to correct use because our controller products controller we
return the shop view.
But this is seen relative from inside the views folder.
However first of all we renamed this to product list and second it's now in a subfolder named shop.
So actually we have to go into shop and then slash product list desists a new path to our view and the
same here for ad product admen ad product here.
This is now in the adman's subfolder.
So we should go into the admin folder and then render ad product with these changes in place if I reload
my page here.
This should all still work.
And indeed I can still switch.
So the existing views are rendered correctly.
So that seems to work.
Now we can add more to use here and forget in the shop for example I'll have an index page.
So the starting page basically.
Right now this is my product list.
Well I will add a new area the products area which should rendered product list and the starting page
should be a different page.
And in the end it will be very similar but it should display less products.
Let's say now in the shop I also want to have a product detail that E.J. asked view where if I click
on a product I can see that and I want to have a card.
E.J. s view which I can basically see if I click on the card in the menu and we'll have to add this
menu item of course.
And there's one remaining for now and that is my check out each s view which will be the check outflow
which we can start from inside the cart.
Now in the Edmond area we got at product.
I also will add added product thought E.J. so that we can do that too.
And I will also add my list or product list don't Ejaz view.
Now we got a product list view already in the shop area.
The admin of course also needs to be able to see that.
And just to avoid name clashes or confusion you could name it like this wouldn't be a problem.
But to not confuse you when I referred to these views I'll name it products e.g. SNB Edman area and
product list in the shop area.
But you could absolutely use the same name because they are in different folders.
So now we got that set up and we'll add more if we need more.
But that looks decent.
Now let's go to the navigation and there I also need to work on the way level navigation items because
right now if I structured is a bit different to make it easier to read like this we get to navigation
items one for the starting page and one for adding a product in the admin area.
Now of course you could argue that you in general don't want one navigation with all the normal customer
options and all the admin options but that is something we can tackle later.
For now in the next lecture I want to continue working on this and add all the links to all my views.
For the moment so that we can then refine those from the course.