So let's start with registering the route's then.
And for this I will go into the routes folder there we have admin and shop and this still sounds like
a decent differentiation.
And let's start with the shop related routes.
Right now we got the starting page.
Now we will also need a Gach route for Slash products because if we have a look into our navigation
Ejaz file this is this new link which we added so slash products will also need slash cart because that's
another new link we have.
It will also be a Getaround and I will of course also add controller functions.
But I'll first define all the routes so all the neat slash cart and later I'll also need a route for
the checkout process.
So slash checkout is already something we can also add and obviously you are free to edit any of these
pauvres to your liking.
Just make sure today not just the links you might have in your application now.
Besides visiting slash products we will also need a single product and that will then actually contain
some new logic to which I will come back.
So let's stick to these general routes for now.
Of course we all need more than just to shop around.
We also got some Edman routes in and navigation for example.
We got the new admin products here and then we'll also need a route for editing.
We'll at this later and we're deleting all also something I'll add later.
So for now let's simply go to Edman J.S. and there I will add.
And you get route because I want to load a new page and there will just be slash products now.
Never forget this is Justice Roberts also already in a POV that starts with Slash admen.
Because this is what we filter for in J S and of course we'll also need a controller function for that.
OK.
So this is looking good.
Now how about the controllers.
Now we can follow different approaches there.
Obviously most of the things we have are still related to products but we also got some new routes like
card or check out.
And later we'll also add orders for example.
So we got that.
Now these are implicitly Of course related to products right.
We do buy products in the end.
But we could also argue that semantically or from a logic perspective they rather belong to the general
shop idea.
So now we might be back to actually using a shop controller and a new admin controller so that we can
split our logic by these two sections.
Alternatively you could of course think about using a product's controller and a shop controller and
have everything related to products only in the products controller and things like card and check out
in the shop controller.
But I will go for this setup.
Now that of course means that my two admin related drought's get at product and post at product should
be removed from the shop.
Yes file and go into the admin J.S. file.
This makes more sense.
I will also need my model here though.
So let's take data import and also add it here in the Edmond J.S. file.
This has implications for my routes because the admin routes.
I'm still importing to shop controller.
Well this should now become the admin controller and therefore I should also rename it to admin control
or appear and then replace it down there and a similar thing needs to be done in the shop js file in
the route's folder.
Dare we import shop controller which is good but I should name it shop controller then and then of course
also replace dat.
So it looks a bit cleaner to me.
And with that we can now also hook up our routes it is of course the first of all need to add them though.
So let's start with shopkeepers and their exports a new page and that should be my get index function
here are there.
I want to render the index page so I will get my middleware function here and in there of course I also
want to fetch some products and render a view.
For now I will therefore simply copy the logic from get products.
So for now the two pages are the same but I will render shop index here.
So using that index page view here.
And even if we have the same product on there we can of course work on the view and show a different
starting text there for the starting page.
Anything like dead.
OK now we got get index and get products and if we go to the route's file.
This means that for Slash anything I actually want to load it get index function.
Here in my controller because that is the starting page and it's for Slash products that I want to load
get products instead.
We all need to load the cart and check out pages and therefore let's go back to the shop controller
and there we got to get the index and get products.
I will export something you and that will be get cart and there again request response next is what
I have here.
And it will render a new view here and that view will be shop slash cart pointing at the cart Ejay as
file in the shop folder and it will pass some data to it.
For example I need to set the POF to slash cart byte away for product list here.
I also need to set it to slash products because that is the path we're checking for in the navigation.
We can also change the title here maybe to all products and on the starting page.
I leave it at shop.
I pass the products both view.
I don't need that code anymore.
That is a list we have we have from the handlebars times.
We don't need dead so we can remove that.
Now for the card view.
I will therefore also add a page title and there I will simply say your cart and that is it for now
later will also add or load the cart items.
But let's not focus on that for the moment.
Last but not least let's load it check out page with get checked out.
And there we have a request response and next year idon also render a view.
The view here is shop check out.
And then we need to pass some data where I set the POF to slash checkout and where I also set the page
title to checkout so that all our views get the data they should need.
Now that's looking good.
Let's go back to the shop yes file in the Ross folder then and there we can use these new routes for
the cart route.
We can use shop control or get cart and for checkout we can use shop control or get checkout the two
new controller functions we created.
Now we're almost done with the controllers and the routes at least the basic set up.
Let's now go to Edmund J S and there we also have 1 route products.
So let's go to the Edmond J S and the US folder and there I will add a new route.
Exports get products is my normal middleware function and here I basically want to do the same as I
do and get products in a shop here.
I simply want to fetch all products and then render my view so I will copy that code go to admen J.S.
and put that into this route.
Fettled products but of course then render a different view.
I want to render adman's slash products.
So this view here should be rendered.
I will also named admen products.
And the payoff will be slash admen slash products to market that correctly in the navigation with all
that set up.
If we go back and reload we see a white page which is a good sign because it's not an error.
And we do see a white page because actually for a slash nothing which just a of time on here we load
or we execute get indexed in the shop controller.
And this actually yields us shop index which happens to be an empty Ejay view.
So therefore we see an empty page.
Makes sense.
Let's take the code from product list each class and copy it into index Aegeus.
And if we leave it as it is and we reload we now see sharp we see the products the same is the case
for the products page because they share the same code for now.
Card is empty again.
And therefore we should add some content there to at least we should include the head and the navigation
so that we see something.
So let's go to card Aegeus and add that include of the hat.
We don't need product C S here for now.
We got the body start and then we get the navigation and then lets simply alter add and Ejaz so that
we have a valid HTL document.
With that added If I reload this Routier we all see cart with nothing on at product should still work
and admen products won't work let's copy the code from card ha ass.
And let's head over to products in the admin folder in the views folder pasted in there so that we at
least see that they offer an outlook on admin products.
It looks like it tries to render the 4 0 4 page but has an error there.
Now that means two things.
For a one hour route seems to be wrong in Edmund Jason orality folder slash products should be right.
Yeah but I'm.
I didn't hook up my admin controller dare so we should add admin control to get products here in Edmond
J s and to route's folder and on the other hand also on four or four page had an issue because dare
we see that the payoff is not the find.
So what I'm missing here is that for my 4 0 4 a controller error control to be precise.
I also need to add a payoff here because I try to extract that pop in my navigation and therefore I
also should set up half year and I can set that to slash for 0 4.
Doesn't really matter.
It just needs to be there.
So now reloading works because that's admen products.
But now even an unknown route will work again.
So this is looking good.
Also note that the active item is displayed correctly in the navigation and therefore we made a huge
step forward.
We added a bunch of us the fitting routes and control actions even though they don't do that much yet.
Now it's time to work a bit on the view and add a bit of logic already.