Time for more logic and with which logic do we want to start we could add more logic to product for
example so that we finally can not just add a title but actually also an image a prize and a description
texture.
So to do that first of all I'll work on my model here in this model.
I want to make sure that we don't just work with the title here but that I actually initialize a new
product with my title and I will now rename it here as an argument.
You probably got the point that these two names don't have to be equal but it's easier to understand
the constructor if we give it a title that makes sense or a name that makes sense.
So I got my timelier now a product will also have an image you are.
Later in the course we'll also add image upload.
For now let's take a finished.
You are of some image on the web.
It also needs a description and a price.
And that year I will simply store all that data in properties.
Image you are l will be stored.
The description will be stored and the price will be stored.
Not description price like this.
With all that future products we add to our file.
We'll have all that data in them and data we fetch or products we fetch will have to.
Now we just need to work on our ad product view and make sure we've got more inputs to fetch and additional
data.
And for this let's simply copied that form control and add an additional 1 were fetching the title.
Now as we just worked on the model we'll also need an image you are el and all simply fetch this as
some text input for it out again will add an image upload later in the course.
So here I will get my image.
You are all name that field image you are l and optionally also assign an ID.
Your FOR BEST accessibility.
Now I'll copy that again and here I will not add input but instead here I want to fetch the description.
Or let's actually fetch the price first so it stays in input actually.
And here I want to have a price.
Notice can be of type number and I will give this year an idea of price and also a name of price.
And now I will add one more form control and that should be my description.
So here this is for my description for the element with the description ID.
It gets the label description and now this is not an input.
Instead it is a text area and data text area has a name or description and an ID or description and
it also has let's say 5 Rozier if we add all that and we go to add product does the form we see doesn't
look too bad but the description field doesn't look good.
Well that is a styling thing and we can quickly fix that in the public folder by going to forums.
Us.
I want to give it the same styling as a normal input has.
So here where I have form control input that's add form control text area with a white space in between
and that's all the ads that rule or that selector for this rule here.
And also down there for this rule I will add text area and then the focus pseudos elector.
And with that if we now reload this looks much better.
So now we got all these fields here which we need to add a product.
And these are automatically added to the request which is sent to the backend because we are using regular
h m l inputs in a form and we assigned names.
So now we can extract all that data up by the names we assign to our input fields here.
And with that let's actually go back to our controller to the admin controller where we have post ad
product and then we create a new product.
I do extract a title here.
Now let's do this in a more structured way to make it easier to read.
I do extract my title here and store it in a constant tidal constant because I never overwrite the value
in this function.
I will then also add my image you are l which I extract from request.
Body image you are l.
Now make sure to type this in exactly the same way using the same casing as you assigned to name your
and the same is true for the price and that description.
So here also at a price field and extract the prize.
And of course also extract my description.
And now with that data extracted here we can pass the title.
We can pass the image your L we can pass the description which to order you to find in the constructor
and we can pass the price.
And now we create a product with all that data.
Now if that next that let's also extract that data and show it when we show all products.