We're now storing the product with all the data we need now we should also display all that real data
and don't show any dummy data anymore.
So for that let's go to our product list each last fall which is one of the views where we do display
all products and there we already output a real product title but that's it.
The image source for example is something we should not also replace.
And we can simply add our each day as expression in there an output image you are l and this will be
a string that should be valid.
You are sort of Shippy displayable.
Now for the alternative text we can also use deep tiles again.
So I simply copied each S-expression up there for a price.
Let's say it's always dollars.
So we'll keep that dollar sign your as hard coded text and then output product price and forward a description
here.
I will of course also replace the dummy text with my description as it is saved in the product.
Now all old products will not fulfill this new structure.
So in the data folder in products Jason I will actually remove them all from that array here so that
it's an empty array again.
With that back end product list is looking good.
Now in index EJA as we have the same logic.
So we can simply copy that and back in index Ejaz simply replace it.
Now if I reload my app on shop and product we got no products but if I add a new one this is a test
product or simply book let's search an image I picked you are here and inserted here.
Then let's add a price 1999.
And this is an awesome book.
Sounds like a good title.
Now you can press add products and right now this does not support decimal numbers to fix this.
We can change something in the product view there on that number input.
We simply have to add a step attribute and set to step to see that Cyril one.
This means you can have well two decimal places essentially and increment in this step size.
I'll save this but not reload.
For now I'll simply go with the number without decimal places to not lose my data and hit add product.
And indeed on the starting page it's now showing this product with all the data I entered.
So now we improved that and we made a major step forward.
Therefore on both pages obviously we see it.
Let's now of course also work on making sure that as an admin We all see the products here.
And we dared not just see them but we can also edit or delete them.
That will be the next step.