So let's work on the Edmond's side then we get a products each case file and in the end I want to render
my products there.
So what we can do is we can copy the product list Ejaz file content and end products Aegeus and the
admin area we can copy that in.
If an hour reload this page we see the same as we see on shop and products but obviously I want to show
different but instead let's say so that we can edit or delete them there.
And of course we could even change the whole way we display the products.
But for now let's focus on the logic and less on how we display that.
So here I have my add to cart button.
Now time to change this maybe to edit button and let's add a second button where I say delete with that
if we reload these two buttons are now they're not now they don't do anything if I click them or just
ask the cart button doesn't do anything.
By the way.
So as a next step I want to make sure I can load this to edited and how to do that.
First of all to make sure that clicking this button does send a request and actually I want to send
a simple GET request and get onto another page.
We could change this to a link with a reference to another page like this.
If we do that doesn't look too bad.
Styling changed a bit because well some things would have to be adjusted.
And then we'll do that later.
Now we got that link which show of course now lead us to slash admen slash added product like this if
we do that we get to the Page Not Found page because we haven't registered our route yet.
And the reason for this is that we don't just need to go to slash add product but obviously we want
to go to a very different route here.
We want to make sure that we go to a route where we know which product to edit.
So I actually will need to pass something dynamic as part of that.
You are L would be great if we could pass something like added product for the ID 1 and then we can
retrieve that ID in the route that we're loading so that we know which product we need to fetch from
the database or from our file for now.
Now this is some logic we'll add in the next module though because some people might have skipped this
module so let's ignore this for now and let's focus on deleting.
But to be honest we'll face the same problem there because we want to delete a specific product and
not all products obviously.
So therefore here we can also add a link but technically a delete Prozess should not send a getter request
to some route instead.
Here I will simply wrap this in a forum which leads to admin delete product and sends post requests
there to indicate that we really want to change something and not just load something or display something
and then I wrap my body in there and give it to type submit so that it does submit to this.
So now we get that connected and therefore on Abyan products you see that changed you to the form I
added will work on the styling or I will work on the styling between modules both styles or both routes
will not work because we haven't implemented them but will do that later.
The same problem can be found for our Add to Cart here by the way there.
I also want to do something which needs extra information.
I need to have the idea of the product I want to add and I want to add it to the route where loading
or to the POF were loading.
So here I also want to have a forum which goes to something like add to cart.
We don't have that route yet and then add a method post and then here I will have a button inside of
that form and obviously I don't just want to go to Add to Cart but I would want something like add to
cart one so that I know which product with which ID to add to a cart.
But again this is something I will do in the next module.
Just as for the admin routes.
So for now we're pretty much done.
We added more views we restructured our controller a little bit.
We practiced what we did thus far.
But now of course the exciting thing will be when we finally start working more with dynamic data in
our route pops and when we def we can start adding items to the cart and editing and deleting items
will do that over the next marginals of course.