In the last module you learn how to use sequel in a no chess application.
And we did this at the example for my sequel database which we want to use to store data.
Now we didn't complete the project with that sequel approach simply because this module will now implement
features like for example working with the shopping cart with the help of sequela eyes.
This will still use the sequel database still used to same.
My sequel database actually behind the scenes or in the background as a database but the code we write
will be different.
Instead of sequel statements as we have them here and as we wrote them in the last module we'll use
a third party package that allows us to work with javascript objects and convenient methods to create
new elements in the database to edit them to delete them or to find them and also to connect them.
Because you remember a sequel database typically also works with relations.
And we got non-golf to use in our current project.
So this is what we'll dive into in this module.
You'll learn what exactly sequela eyes.
This third party package is and how you can use it and will then implement our products and our card
and so on in this module with equalize.