Now before we start using it what is sequel eyes actually see equalisers a third party package to be
precise.
It's an object relational mapping library.
And this is a pretty long name which simply means it does all the heavy lifting all these sequel code
behind the scenes for us and maps it into javascript objects with convenience methods which we can call
to execute that behind the scenes sequela code sauted we never have to write sequel code on our own.
It works like this.
We got our object let's say a user with a name age email and password but of course this can be anything
could be a product whatever you need and does this mapped to a database table by sequel eyes so it automatically
creates that table for us even it automatically sets up relations and tables even for us it does all
that.
And when we create a new user for example we simply call a map that on that user javascript object and
sequel executes the sequel Kuri or the sequel command to this required.
So instead of writing this on our own we simply create a javascript object and work with that.
And here you one example using sequel to create an user which would behind the scenes execute the sequel
code we don't have to write sequels.
Offers us the models to work with our database.
As I showed you on the last slide and it allows us to define such models.
So basically define which data makes up a model and therefore which data will be saved in the database.
We can then instantiate these models so these classes so to say we can execute the constructor functions
or use utility Moffats to create lets say a new user object based on that model.
So we have a connection here and we can then run coerces on that.
That could be that we save a new user but it could also be that we find all users as an example.
And here again this always relates back to our model of which we define with sequels and we can also
associate our models.
For example we could associate our user model to a product model.
So this is what sequence does.
But of course we dont just want to learn that in theory we want to see that in practice.
So lets add lies to our project and thats slowly integrated to Manche our products in our cart and so
on fruit sequel's.