So back in the project we first of all have to install sequels and just as we installed all the other
packages we'll do that by running NPM install dash dash save because this also is a production dependency.
It's a court the pendency of our project and then the name is sequel's like dis.
Now important sequel's needs that my sequel to package which we already installed.
So this My sequel to package we installed the last module needs to be installed.
If you skipped the last Marchal or anything like that.
Make sure to and install my sequel to now with that we got sequel's installed and now we can do a couple
of cool things with it the first step always is that we create a model with sequels as well and also
that we connect to the database of course.
Now therefore the first step is that when I connect to my sequel database with the workbench which we
also used in the last module already and in there I will go into my node complete database and delete
the products table by right clicking on it drop table and then simply click drop.
Now I do this because I now want to use sequel eyes to managed by tables.
With that let's go back to our project and now let's go into the database.
Jay has fallen to utl folder there.
I now want to write some code to connect sequels to the database.
Now sequel's uses my sequel to behind the scenes.
Therefore sequel lies behind the scenes.
We'll do something like this but we won't write this.
Instead we will import sequel lies and I'll store it in a sequel like constant.
You can name this constant however you want but I'll name it with a capital S. Because I actually import
a constructor function or class here so I'll import sequels like this and then I'll treat.
And you see equalize instance by calling new sequel's like dis.
Now sequela is here.
The constructor function needs some options.
You can see we have to configure it with the database name with a user name to connect to it a password.
So here I will connect it to my database.
So to my schema name which is.
Note Dasch complete
node complete with my root user name which is root and with my password which is Noad complete in my
case.
Use the root password you assigned.
Now we can also pass a fourth argument and options object and then there you can see all on his menu
or get this menu with control space.
You can see we can set up a bunch of stuff for example the dialect we can set this to.
My sequel to make it clear that we connect to my sequel database because different sequel engines or
databases use slightly different sequel syntax and you can dive into the official sequel docs learn
all about it.
A link can be found in the last lecture of this module.
The one thing I want to set for now is the host.
By default it would use localhost so we don't need to set it.
But I will explicitly set this to localhost.
With that we're creating a new sequel as object and it will automatically connect to the database then.
Or to be precise it will set up a connection pool just as we did manually in the last course module
so I can now export my sequel as object here which is essentially that database connection pool however
managed by sequel eyes giving us a lot of useful features.
With that we got the connection set up.
Let's now focus on working on the models.