With the connection set up let's go into our models folder and their 2D product genius file.
And there we can actually delete everything.
We don't need all of that right now we'll write it from scratch here.
First of only two important things.
The first thing is sequel's itself.
So again I will require labs require sequel eyes here and that will give me back a closet or constructor
function.
Hence I named this here with a capital S.
The next thing I'll import is my database connection pool managed by sequel lies.
I'll also name this sequel as part with all lowercase ass.
So basically import export in my database just fall here.
I will import this by requiring and then go up one level into utile and then there to the database.
Jaspal.
Now with these two things.
Or did we can now define a model that will be managed by equalise.
So here in this file below my imports all treat a new constant and alignment product because the product
J file.
I want to define my product model.
Now this model is not defined as a class as we did it before.
But instead I use sequel eyes with the lowercase as.
So my database connection pool which has more than a connection pool it's actually a fully configured
siecle lies and Limond which does also have the connection pool but also all the features of the sequels
package.
And there we can find a new model by calling define the first name Danise the model name and by the
way here in the suggestion you also see an example and so on.
As you do in the official docs of course.
Now the model name typically is a lowercase name and I'll name it product like this.
You are free to name however you want but to follow along smoothly.
I recommend taking this name second argument defines the structure of our model and therefore also of
you automatically create a database table.
This will be a javascript object and in there we simply define the attributes or fields.
Our product should have for example of one to have an ID.
Now an ID is then in turn defined with an object where I couldn't figure it as attribute.
There For example we set to type and the type is now one of the types defined by the seek line package.
So now I use sequel lies with a capital S..
So from this import here and there you find a bunch of types like number or string.
So not var char and so on but here you have the more Javascript names I could would say and I want to
use an industry here because my ID will be a number starting at 1 and then incrementing to 8 that increment.
I also configured this attribute to be auto incrementing by setting or increment to true.
And in case you're wondering how I do know all of that.
Well again you find dead in the official docs on Doc starts sexualized J s dot com.
You can dive into sequel I'll learn more about how it works and how you can configure it and under model
definition.
You learn all about how to define a model how you can find your different tax for the model and you
also see a list of all the support to date as types like the integer we just used.
So this is where we can learn more about this and I can tell you that I want this to be auto incrementing
so I will set auto increment to NULL to true.
I also don't want to allow this valley to be empty so I will allow no to false because I don't want
to allow null values in there.
Last but not least.
Also the primary key to true to basically defined is a primary key of the table which is an important
concept in sequel data bases for retrieving the data and then also for later defining relations with
that to find a product of course also has our fields for example title.
Now we can again define a javascript object could figure it in detail or if you just want to set a type.
You can also use sequel eyes and then to type.
So it is a shortcut in case you only want to set the type though you could argue that we also at least
want to set that should never be null.
But here as a demo I will just assign the type for the price I'll go back to the javascript object and
set to type 2 sequel lines and then double and I will again set a low NULL to false to not allow null
values here then I will set my image.
You are all here again to a javascript object where I set the type to sexualize string and I will set
allow two falls to not allow and null values here and last but not least I also want to have a description
which also will have a type that is of type sequel's string and I will that allow null to false.
Now this is my product model.
Last but not least we need to export it.
So below my model definition here are also use module exports and export my product here.
So this constant in which I define as Doherty defined model.
This gets exported here.
And with that we made a huge step forward.
And we can now start using this product.
Now let's see how we use it over the next lectures.