We define the product model.
And I mentioned that we can now work with the small to create new products and so on.
But for this we of course also need a product table in our database and there right now we got no tables
because I deleted the products table early on this module.
I also mentioned that sequel I can create these tables for you and it indeed can now to create tables
for you.
You just have to tell sequel's to do that.
And I'll do that in the app js file in there.
I want to ensure that all my models are basically transferred into tables or get table that belongs
to them when ever we start our application.
And if the table already exists it will of course not override that by default though we can't tell
that to do so.
Now in my app last fall which is to file execute when I do start my program.
I want to import from the database fall as I did it before I'll just rename it to sequel lies because
I do import my sequel as object with a lower case s because I'm importing from my own utility database
set up file and then toward the end of this file.
Let's say here I want to call sequela eyes.
And then there's a special method to sync method to sync method has a look at all the models you defined
and keep in mind you define your models in your model files by calling sequel's to find on that same
sequel's object.
So it is aware of all your models and it then basically creates tables for them.
That is what sync does.
It sinks your models to the database by creating the appropriate tables.
And if you have them relation's so hearable calls sync and then I can listen to you the result of this
let's see what we get back as a response here or what we get back as a value here and we can also of
course catch potential error or staed occurred.
And if an error occurred here well then we can essentially awls locked it and I only want to let's say
start my server if we somehow made it into then let's see what this gives us.
If I now run NPM start to your it starts up and we see there is some log output.
If you scroll up quite a bit because we got back a complex object you see that this is a default lock
frozen by sequel's it executed this sequel Kuri for us without us writing this Kohary.
It created a table.
If it did not exist yet which unnamed product of products and that is that automatically inferred name
because we named our model product it automatically pluralize a stat and then it assigned a couple of
fields there which is configured according to our model definition.
And then does the return value we get back.
Basically our sequel lies object you can tell.
And if I now quit this server with Kontrol see clear to console and rerun NPM start you'll see it runs
this again.
But it does not overwrite the existing table because we have that if not exists check in there automatically.
So we can randomly run those again without issues.
And our server starts up even if this table already exists.
We still make it into them.
Now we'll comment out that result lock because I don't want to have this long object every time in the
console every time we start this.
So now I just get my sequel Kuri here and if we now have a look at the work bench and we Right-Click
on our database and click on refresh all we see under tables we get a product table and if we inspect
data with this I can see all the fields we defined and that is added by sequel's to a new field created
at and updated at.
So it automatically manage just some time steps for us.
We could.
Us.
But I actually liked this feature.
So we get these automatically managed fields too.
This is how we sunk our tables to the database and what sequel license for us.
And with that we're now ready to use that.