So time to use sequel eyes outside of the table creation for this let's go into our controller files
and there let's start with creating a new product because that will be helpful for later oles retrieving
them in Edmund Geass we right now import our product model from the mullahs fall.
And that's fine because we do still export it there at the bottom.
So we should still import it in Edmund J.
S. But here in post ad product we will now work with that product a bit differently what it will do
here is I will get rid of that old code we used for creating a product and instead I will now create
a new product here.
By calling one of the methods provided by sequels and by just typing the dot my idea is that just a
lot of methods I can call and these methods are all coming from sequels which shows its great power
and there we got create for example create creates a new element based on that model and immediately
saves it to the database.
There also is built which also creates a new optic based on the model but only in Javascript.
And then we need to save it manually.
So create basically doesn't one go with build.
We get the object in javascript first before we don't have to save it manually.
I would go for create to immediately store it and now create here simply takes some arguments that we
need to pass per our model definition so I can pass in a javascript object.
And now here I even get the auto completion by my ID to assign field values.
Now I don't need to assign an ID.
There will be managed automatically.
But for example I need to assign a title by storing the title here.
So on the right side of the colon I'm referring to my constant left side refers to one of the attributes
I find in the model.
I also have a price which I assign to price.
I also have an image you are which I assigned to image your L image your L and I also get a description
which I assign the description value fetched and as a set this will immediately save it to the database.
Now just as my sequel did in the last course marshal sequel Elize works with promises.
So here we can change then and we can change catch.
We can catch any error we might get to see what's going wrong and we can also have a look at the result
we get.
In case it does not go wrong.
Note that if we save this let's go to our application and it won't work by default because Fetchmail
is not working because we have no function place to fetch products.
So for now we have to immediately go to slash admin slash at product to load this page.
The other pages won't work here.
Also a story my first book I fetch an image Eurail.
Make sure it's not a base 64 or L but a real you are elde pointing at some j back or and you fall all
assign a price your and I will store a description desists of first poke.
I add fruit sequel lies.
If I click at product here and we go back to you know chess does seems to have succeeded here because
we get no errors.
Here we see the sequel statement it executed.
Insert into.
I got an error before that though.
That was when I tried to reach.
Well the page listing all the products where we failed to call fetch all because that is not provided
by sequel.
But there ofter once wasn't a right page.
Inserting this was executed.
You see it also executed the syntax where it escapes the values automatically as we did in the last
module end and the return value does is looking good.
It looks like it did create this book and we can prove that by going to our products table and refreshed.
We should see our book being added there so does indeed succeed at.
So this is how we can add a value fruit sequel.
And this is a huge step forward of course and I'll comment out my result log here and simply log to
create that product to not pollute my console as much.
So now we created a product.
Let's in a next step have a look at how we can use lies to retrieve data.