With the product create it time to also retrieve our product when we for example visit our next route.
So in a shop controller here and get in next it would be nice if we could get our products.
This current approach with Thach all will not work because product is now a sequel AIs model as we're
importing it from our model file and the sequel as models simply have no fecche old method.
But sequel's models have plenty of methods for getting data and instead of fecche all day for example
I find all to get all the records for this model.
Now find all as you can imagine also gives us back a promise where we can use to use salt.
Now find All right away.
Also can be configured with some options we can pass our options here and we could find a WHERE condition
to also restrict that kind of data we retrieve.
And you can read more about the possible options you have there and how to write this in the official
box but we'll also see a way of limiting the data we retrieve when we later fetch a single product.
For now let's get all without any restrictions.
And then here in the then block we should have our products.
So here let's assume we get a products list aere to our function to get executed that gets executed
here.
Here I will log any potential errors we might have and now of then block.
I essentially want to render my page of course once we got the products and simply passed the product
into the process key off my render function here.
Let's remove the fetch all call down there was that time to save this.
Let's go back to just localhost.
And indeed this is looking good.
You'll see it retrieves the data.
The data still has the same field names as before.
They are for rendering this automatically works.
Now we need the same logic on the product's page and therefore I will just copy that and go to get products
added to your end of course replace the render function here.
Make sure to pass products to Pre-OT's though and of course as I mentioned earlier and this course you
could refactored at 40 index and the products page to reuse this code instead of copying it.
I just liked the more explicit approach here which makes it really clear what's happening.
So now we gotta get products working too.
Hopefully yeah this is looking good.
Both work and we see even a difference because here I have a plank but with the dollar sign and the
text and here I don't have it.
So this is working and this is a huge step forward.
Now as a next step let me show you how to retrieve a single product.
If we click on details here.