Time to retrieve a single book when we click on details.
So essentially I'm talking about the get product action here in my controller.
We get the product that year.
And indeed this is the old find by the method I defined.
But if we were to delete that we see that sequel is also has a fine by the method.
So actually if a leaf does code exactly as it is right here at least it will work one differences dead
with sequel lies.
We don't get an array of products here.
Instead I get a single product so I can just use it like dis.
So with these tiny changes turning into a single product and using it as such and leaving this as it
is actually I should already be able to view the details and I am just the image just may be a bit oversized
here.
That is something we can quickly fix in C S S.
I quickly added the image class to the day of wrapping my product in the product detail view here and
now in the main Zia's s fall re old af my centered class.
I will add a new image class and restrict the max height to let's say 20 REM and then also say that
any image text in the nested in an element with the image class should respect that height and that
should also be just height not max height.
That final reloaders page here.
This is looking better and we should have no problems with the image any more.
Just a tiny change to main takeaway of course is we can retrieve a product like this.
However I also want to show you an alternative way.
So using disinfects here is perfectly fine but let me also show you how we can use the normal find method.
We also got find all to be precise.
We only have one product with that idea of course but I want to show you that where syntax.
So any object we can pass to find all.
All set to where a key.
And there you got a rich query language.
Or were it a rich amount of options you can use to configure this.
More a can of course be found in the official tutorial.
If you go to querying dare There you'll find all the details about how to configure your queries.
For example you can also control which attributes are retrieved.
You don't have to get all attributes all the time.
If you only need to title you can find us too and you'll see how to use where how to use in a basic
form where you want to simply check that one attribute has one exact value but also how you can use
operators to have alternative conditions or to check if something is greater than or greater than equal
or lower than a value and so on.
So you got a lot of options out there and definitely check out the stocks.
Here we could say I'm looking for all products where the ID is equal to prod ID and then I will use
them or catch any errors.
Now the one important thing here of course is by default.
This gives us an array because even though we know that only one product will have his idea find all
per definition always gives you multiple items even if it's an array with only one element.
So if we use this syntax and we render this we'll have products and we're interested in the first product.
In this case also the only product as we know.
So now I can comment out the other approach and if we save that and we go back to our application and
we reload that detail page it looks like it works but actually just keeps on loading.
So something went wrong and it did.
We got an error here.
Product is not defined yet.
Here for the title I should all use products sideroad of course.
So now that if we save dead and let it restart therefore now we can reload this page and it works as
before but now is using find where and find all with that where query and I simply wanted to show you
this alternative approach.
Of course it's perfectly fine and even preferrable in this case to use find by ID.
So I will actually switch back to that Alber approach.
It's good to know how you can query though.