Now let's work on the admin products page because they're all and want to display my products so that
we can interact with them.
So an admin.
J.S. again.
Get product still use fetcher all now.
It's of course a good practice for you to make this work with sequels.
So definitely posti video at this point and tried to change his code here such that it doesn't retrieve
the products and render them on the Admin Page.
Where are you successful.
Well the code to you is of course the same code we used in the shop.
Yes instead of factual we'll use Find all.
And we don't use the callback function approach here because we're not using a callback function with
sequels.
Instead we have then and catch since we're using promises.
So let's Cancellara our error in this case or pass our function we used as a like before to then and
now here we have our render function where we render the products they are for if I now reload does
admin page I see my product here and I cannot added or delete it.
These however are two things that don't work and it doesn't work because they don't load the product
successfully and delete wouldn't work either.
So the next lectures will work on these two things.