Updating was successful.
Now let's also make sure we can delete products.
So in adman's Yes I'm talking about the postal product method here.
Now we get the product that you would just get it now delete by it does not exist in a sequel sized
world instead on the product we can call destroy and destroy allows us to destroy any product we find
through our options here.
And these options allow us to for example add a WHERE condition to narrow down which product to delete
can also use a different approach.
Instead of calling destroy like disks and adding a condition which product to find which is of course
fine.
We can also use FINE BY idea again to find a product by that idea.
And then again have our well known then and error catch methods and then we know we got a product in
on that product.
We can also call destroy.
And now this will destroy the found product we can return this because this will also yield a promise
and they offer add and Navier then block which will execute once the distractions exceed it and there
we can if we want console log destroyed product and we can also redirect thereafter.
We should redirect here to make sure we only redirect once the deletions and see that if we now go back
to our application and I add a new Dammy product without any picture just like this and we get to admin
products.
I got stuck on loading this automatically I'll look into this a second.
But if we go to Aben prox manual we see it here for click delete this works.
Now one thing I noticed is that if I added a product here we get Stec and we don't redirect.
So for adding a product host add product here we don't do anything in then block there we should of
course all the redirect slash admin slash product.
So basically the same we redirect when deleting.
So now every go back
and we add a new product again this is working and now we can also delete the products here.
So this is now all working and how we can manage products.
We can do them here.
Now one thing we haven't touched at all our relations though because we don't just have products we
all have a card and eventually we'll also have users.