So it's now time to introduce more models and it will introduce a brand new mall before I start working
on the card again.
That new model will be my user model.
For now we have no real authentication process will only work with one dummy user who doesn't really
have to log in.
All indication will follow later in the course but I still want to show you how you could have a user
who did create a product and who therefore is connected to that product and at the same time a user
should own a card and that card will hold multiple products.
And this is how we can then overall connect everything.
So as a user just fall in the models folder and in there first of all let's define the user model.
And this is also something you can try on your own.
Try to define a sequel ice model with a user that has an ID.
The idea should have the same function as it has for the product model.
And let's say for now a user also has a name and an email.
Definitely try this on your own possed a video at this point will thereafter to find the user model
together.
Where are you successful.
Let's define the user model.
But first of all requiring the sequel sequels constructor or KLOS and then also with lowercase s let's
import our own sequel eyes object which holds the connections on from the utl folder and their database
file.
We can then define a user and store the user in a user constant by calling sequel's define a name the
model user like this.
And then as an object you define the structure of the user.
I want to have an idea for my user and to type your will be sequel eyes
integer.
It should be or incrementing I don't allow null values and this will be my primary key.
Besides that Id also have a name and here I'll use a very short definition where they say that the name
will be a string and the email here will also be a string.
So this is my user.
Now we need to export this model with Module exports user like dat.
And now with that being exported we can start using it.
And one thing I want to start using it for is that I want to create an association.
Now lets have a look at how we do that and what an association actually is in the next lecture.