What do I mean by association you could also say relation let's say in our project and that is basically
our project.
We have products users cards and at some point also orders.
Now if we want to connect all these things on and define how they work together then a product would
probably belong to many carts because our users will have carts.
Therefore we have multiple users multiple cards and they have for product can belong to many carts because
of course different users can add the same product to their carts.
Each user only has one card though.
So this is how we could relate that product.
Also can be part of multiple orders and the user can have multiple orders because you get order more
than one thing a user can also own multiple products.
In a sense all of this user created this product so not own it in the sense of I bought it.
But in the sense of Hey I offered this product I created it in the shop.
This is a rough outline of how we can communicate or relate different models.
And this is what we can also reflect in sequel eyes there I'll go to my app js file here.
That's close to views.
I'll go to my Applegate's file and before I sync all my data to the database I want to define my models.
So for this I will add more imports and I will import my product model by requiring this from the models
file and they're the product file at Amal's folder and the product file Andal import my user model from
the user following the models folder with the two models imported we can relate them and I will relate
them here in the same place where I's sync.
See a sequel.
But before I sync it here I can basically say that a product belongs to a user.
Now you can learn way more about these relations in a sequel like documentation.
There is a whole article about associations which kind of associations exist and how you define them
equalize and which effect this has I will kill you some important implications in this model of course.
So back to our code we are now setting up that for Sequel lies a product belongs to a user and this
is now talking about a user created this product.
We're not talking about purchases at this point.
We can all consider this by passing a second argument which is optional here.
It can define how this relationship be managed and very important we can find so-called constraints
set them to true.
And for example say that on the lead.
So if a user is selected what should happen to any connected products and here we can say cascade which
simply means well the deletion would then also be executed for the product.
So if we delete the user any price related to user would also be gone.
This is totally optional and you definitely need to learn a bit more about sequel to fully understand
your options here.
This is beyond the scope of this course but this can all be done with sequels.
And now we got this relation's set up.
You can also find the inverse and say that one user has many products because one user can of course
add more than one product to the shop.
Now this is optional.
You don't need that.
You can basically replace belongs to which I have many call.
But here I also like to define both directions to really make it clear how this relation works.
Now with this being set up sequel I sync will not just create tables for our models but also define
their relations in our database as we define them here.
The one problem we have right now is that we already create the products table and it therefore will
not override it with the new information and we can ensure that it will by setting force to true.
Of course a setting you wouldn't really use in production because you don't always want to overwrite
your tables all the time.
But here during development I want to reflect my new changes so we'll set this to true and therefore
after restarting we indeed see a couple of statements were executed.
First of all it dropped any existing tables and then created a new table users with all the set up.
And then it also creates a new products table and besides adding all the fields there.
It also defined that there is a new field the user id field which is an integer and which is a foreign
key that references the ID field in the Users table and that on the lead it should cascade.
And an update cascade is the default.
So this is Mehta's set up in the database which seek license also added to connect our tables there
too.
And if we go to work bench and we right click on our database and set call refresh all we see there
are two tables now.
And indeed if we inspect products we see that our product is gone because it recreated the table.
But now besides created add an update of that that were added by sequel's.
There is a user ID field which was all added by sequel lies and this will automatically be populate
by sequela too.
Once we create products that are related to a user.
So lets make sure that we have a user because right now data table is empty and that we then can connect
users and products in our app.