So we need a user.
And as I mentioned for now we have no authentication process.
So for the moment I will create a user manually first of all.
I will remove this force through call because I don't always want to overwrite my tables.
Otherwise all our products will always be gone.
So I go back to sync.
Now that the relations are set up and once all the tables were created.
So in this then call here I actually Nel's it want to create my user and they are over here.
I will use my user model and first of all check if I find a user with the ID one.
And this is of course just some dummy code to see if I do have one user because I only need one for
now as we have no indication.
And if I do have it or not create a new one if I don't have it I will.
So here I have user defined by id one and I will return this for all to take app listen out of this
then block and then add a new then block where I will get my retrieved user here.
I'll then check if I don't have a user so if this is null because if I don't have a user I want to create
a new one by calling user recreate there I'll pass in a javascript object where I set the name to Max
and to email to some dummy e-mail you can enter any values you want here.
Just make sure you populate all the fields you defined in your user model does all the returns promise
all returned is true.
But also we might never execute just because we already got a user.
So for this case our return user.
But now we're inconsistent because now this anonymous function ever returns a promise or just an object
we should always return to same so that we can change then year successfully.
And therefore I will actually called Promise resolve here which is essentially a promise that will immediately
result to user.
Technically you can omit this though because if you return a value in a then block it is automatically
wrapped into a new promise.
Just wanted to highlight that you should make sure that the values are equal.
But here it's managed for us.
And therefore here I now definitely noted I got a user we can cancel lock to user here.
And I also started listening to my server here so here's my user creation result that I get back and
if I go back to my workbench database and it refresh the users table we see the user here to.
And if I do restart my server with a start that still works and it doesn't create a new user here because
we already have one so this code is working as it should.
I'll comment out this it with this change made we now always have a user equatable as a next step all
will register a new middleware because I want to store to the user in my request so that I can use it
from anywhere in my app conveniently.
So maybe you're all adding new middleware ultimately at a function with request response and next as
you learned it before in this course.
And then here I want to reach out to my database and retrieve my user with user find by id one.
Now you might be wondering if Diskin ever return a user.
If we only create it down there.
Keep in mind app use your only registers some middleware.
So for an incoming request we will then execute this function NPM start runs this code for the first
time an NPM start is what runs sequel icier not incoming requests incoming requests are only funneled
for our middleware so NPM start runs.
This does code which sets up our database but never this anonymous function.
It just registers it as middleware for incoming requests.
So this code will only run for incoming requests which on the Iran can only reached us if we did successfully
start our server here with app listen.
And that in turn is only true if we are done with our initialization code here.
So we are guaranteed to find a user here so we can find a user by your.
And what do we want to do with my user then block then.
Well I want to store it in a request.
So here I will set request user equal to user and we can do that.
We can simply add a new field to our request object.
We should just make sure we don't overwrite an existing one like bloddy but user is undefined by default.
Now I'm storing the user I retrieved from the database in there.
Also keep in mind the user were retrieving from the database here is not just a javascript object with
the values stored in a database it's a sequel ise object with de-value stored in the database.
With all these utility methods sequel's added like destroy.
So we're storing this sequel eyes Optik here and a request and not just a javascript object with the
field values is that we got the extended version here.
And therefore whenever we called request user in the future in our app we can also execute methods like
destroy.
So with that all I need to do is I need to call next year of course so that we can continue with the
next step if we get our user and stored it.
Now with that we've got the user set up and retrieved let's make sure that we can also use it to create
new products that are associated to that user.