From now on all new products that are created should be associated to the currently locked end user.
For now this will only be this one dummy user that means that if I'm in the admin chase controller here
when we create a new product in post ad product will not create the product like this anymore.
We need to pass an extra information regarding our user that is associated one way of doing this is
did we set this new user ID field we got keep in mind user ID was added as a database field because
we now have a relation set up and we said this to request user ID.
Keep in mind that request user is just sequel's user object which holds both the database data for that
user as well as the helper methods.
So this should create new products with that user being associated to it.
Let's test this let's go back to ad product and simply enter some dummy values here for now.
Seems to work we get no error here.
And if we look into our products table by clicking on this I can hear we indeed have the user ID stored
here.
Now we also have one tiny problem or thing we can improve at least we manually fetched the user id and
this is not a lot of work here but there is a more elegant way of setting this so that we don't manually
have to set to use right.
We can use an oracle feature of sequel's we can use our user object as it's stored in the request and
always keep in mind this is a sequel as object with all the magic features and there will actually have
a create product method.
Now where is that coming from.
Well it is something you can get from the official docs if you read Frwy associations there you'll learn
that if you set up associations sequel add special Moffats depending on the association yet.
And for a belongs to has many Association as we did sequel lies ads methods that allow us for example
to create a new Associated object.
So since a user has many products or a product belongs to a user.
As we learned or as we set it up an aperture Yes since we have that relation to find sequels automatically
as a create product method to the user create product because our model is named product and create
and automatically add it at the beginning of the method name.
That is some magic done by sequel.
So create product is available and there we simply pass in the object with the product data that can't
be inferred by sequel.
So basically anything but user ID and timestamps and then we can chain are then and catch block here
just as we did it before.
The rest doesn't change but this not automatically creates a connected model.
So if I now save this and add a new product this still works and if we have a look at our database and
we refresh the products table here we see we also get to user ID here even though we did not set it
explicitly.
Now this is done by sequel lies with this magic way of connecting it and that is a really cool way of
using associations in sequel eyes and making sure that our models know about each other.