We learn about associations and that we get these cool magic methods you're about which you can learn
more in the official docs of course.
Now which implication status have for our Ivor Edmund Jr's actions.
Well get that product there's no implication we fetch a single product year and we can do this of before
we don't really care about the user here.
You could argue that you only want to find products for the currently locked and user though then what
you actually want to do is you want to use request user get products
and there to find where ID equals Pre-OT ID to also have that folder and then you can change your normal
then call and so on with that if you click on edit we see an empty form because it generally did work
and we see the sequel statement here where it simply looks for a product with the user id D1 and that
is not the condition we wrote were responsible for this part where it then also never stolen the product
ID but user ID 1 was added by sequel eyes because we used get products on the user.
But keep in mind here we get back in array even if it only holds one element.
So if we got products and therefore we know that one product the one we are interested in will always
be the first element.
So we have to store that separately in the new content.
And now if we reload this this works.
So this is a more elegant way though we could also still only use the ID if we want to use the old approach
if we move on for a post editing a product there.
I'm fine with finding a product like this because if we are at this point I assume we already have a
product for this user only.
So if I updated like this it's fine.
Now get product should change instead of finding all products I want to find price for this user.
So a call get products like dat which will give me all products for this user.
And then I can render them here.
So for now I'll go to admen products I see the products for days user here because this select statement
gets executed where we narrow down the user to the user with the ID 1 and post delete product.
Here again we could only find a product for it as user with this ID.
I'm fine with this setup though.
So some tiny changes showing you more of that power.
Sequel lives gives you four associated models.
Let's next have a look at how we can reintroduce the cart to our application.