We don't just have products and users.
We all have the cart and we haven't worked on the card for quite some time now from a relation or association
perspective.
A card should belong to a user and a card that in turn simply holds products many products with a quantity
associated to them.
So actually will need more than one model.
I can already tell you that.
But let's work on the card model first.
I delete everything here and start writing it from scratch.
First of all imports sequel lies by requiring the sequel lies package.
And of course then I will also import sequel eyes from my database file.
So from utl database like this and then it's time to create the card model with sequela is to fine as
we did it before.
Name ID card and a card for me here simply has an ID and that id will be of type.
Sequel lies string autoincrement should be true allow null should be false and the primary key will
be true.
And then I will export this.
Now you might be wondering where are the products well we have to keep in mind that a card should belong
to a single user but may hold multiple products.
The carts table however should hold the different cards for different users so will not just need to
cartes table and model will also need a new card.
Item j.
Yes file in there.
I will also again I'll copy a code from cards to define a new model.
I'll call it carte item though an export card item here and I'll name it card item here.
When I did find a model the name it does will all have an ID but then also a quantity and that quantity
will be an integer because each card item is essentially a combination of a product and the ideal of
the card in which this product lies and the quantity.
Now the idea of the card to which does this relate to doesn't have to be added by us here because we
will again create an association and let sequel's managed this so it's time for some associations then
let's go to the app js file your and in there time to add more associations besides product and user
for example a user has one cart and for this to work we need to import the cart.
So let's scroll up to the imports and let's also import Cartier from the cart file.
We all need to cart item so import cart item from the cart.
Item.
Following the models folder.
So these two new ports have to be added and wisdom at it.
If we go down again let's go back to find their relations a user has one cart and a cart on the other
hand belongs to a user.
So this is basically in a world of this relation and it's optional.
You don't need to add it.
One Direction is enough.
This set up you're either of the two approaches will add key to Descartes and you field to cart which
is the user id to which the card belongs.
Next I will add my card here and say that this card belongs to many products and on the other hand a
product belongs to many carts some many to many relationship because one card can hold multiple products
and a single product can be part of multiple different cards.
This only works with an intermediates table that connects them which basically stores a combination
of product IDs and card IDs.
And for that I actually had my card item model.
I had a second argument to belongs to many.
And there we at the fruit keep telling sequels where these connections should be stored and that is
my card item model so I'll add that to both belongs to many calls here.
So now we got this set up here and therefore now we should have all the setup we need if we now again
temporarily set forest to true to ensure that we do recreate all tables as required and we go back to
the work bench and refresh all we actually only see two tables because we have an error here.
We scroll up a bit we see incorrect column specifier for column ID.
So something went wrong here when C-Class tried to create our tables because it looks like we got some
error in one of our models.
And the thing is the idea here in card item that should be an editor not a string same in card should
be an integer not a string.
Now this is looking much better.
And now if you go back and refresh all now we see carts and cart items here.
And we can see that in carts we only got Id created and they did that and the user id to which the cart
belongs in users we don't care about that we only have to user information and in card items we have
a combination of the cart ID too which does card item belongs and the Product ID.
So now we get everything we need to manage our card items for the cards we need.