To work with our new cart Let's go to the control us folder here and there to shop chairs fall which
is where we have our cart related actions get products get product get index debtors all working get
card however will not work.
In their I want to use a card associated with my existing user to get all the products in it and render
them to the screen.
For this let's get rid of that code but I'll comment it out so that I easily can use my render function
again.
Let's use request user that's still a user stored in our request by the way one important adjustment.
Let's disable that force sinking again so that we don't always override any data we stored.
So let's go back to happen chase at a as excuse me and let's use the user we retrieve for every new
request and which we stored in the request and there.
Let's execute cart and let's look into this and see if this gives us anything meaningful.
Finale's safeness and I go to cart it doesn't load the page.
And if I go back we see on the find here.
So we can't access to cards like this.
But what we can do here is we can use our request user and get the card which is associated to it looks
at them and catch
here will get to the card and let's lock the card here.
We save that and reload this page and still will not load.
But now I get Knol here and not on the find.
Now the reason why we don't find anything here for either of the two approaches is that we got no cards
yet.
If we look into our database cards it's totally empty just as we create a user right at startup.
Alternate a card for dead user so here I create a user.
Now in the next or get dead user I will also create a cart by adding user create cart like this.
And I don't need to pass any data in that because a card in the beginning will will not hold any special
data it just needs to be there.
I'll then return this and only listen in the next step.
Where I get my card.
So to say and with this now set up you see insert into cards call is done here we now have a look into
our hearts.
We see now we get a card associated You are a user with the ID 1 and now if I tried to reload that card's
page again here we now get some output and this output is stemming from our Get card call here.
So disconsolate Guerrera you looked at card.
So now it is working now for completeness sake.
Let's also console log request user card.
Again that's does all the work.
If a reload year does still it's the old log.
But if I scroll above it we still see on the find.
So this does not work we can't access card as property here but we can call get cards to work with the
card.
So now we've got the cart a way that will we loaded the card from the database.
We know more about that card here with the card away label.
We can use it to fetch the products that are inside of it by returning cards get products.
Remember a card is associated to products in a rapturous fall through belongs to Manny and sequel lies
will do the magic of looking into card item and so on.
So into this.
In between table so we can get products was added by sequel lies as a magic method.
And therefore here in this then block will have products available.
And here again just like any error I get.
But then block here we should have the products that are in this cart and that of course means that
we can now render these products.
So here I will render
my products here.
Store them in products and pass them to to you.
Now this will not work as expected though.
If I now reload this page we see no products in CART.
Now we got no products in a cart but we'll see that later once we do have them it'll all not work but
I'll come back yet.
For now let's just have a look at our Querrey statement.
We can see the disaster statement executed by sequel ice.
And if you didn't see it before here we can definitely see the advantage we have by using a package
like this.
We don't have to write that sequel Saipan on our own.
We use sequel eyes and let it do that behind the scenes.
So before we come back to what we will have to do regarding getting the card products lets make sure
we can add process to the card.
So for now I'll get rid of all that logic here and I will focus on adding products to the card in the
next step.