So let's ensure we can see items on the card page.
And the problem is that right now this does not work because you're on card.
E.J..
Yes we're still accessing product data for every product we loaded but the products we have here are
now just the products from our database.
So we don't need to access any nested product data.
Instead here we'll just have pre-title we'll have a look at the quantity in a second and the down there.
So it's directly access to fields of our products on well the product we're looping through not a quantity
is not part of that but off the related card item you could say and conveniently sequel lies also gives
us a card item key for device which stores information about this in-between table and the entry that
is related to this product there.
So if this if we save this and we now reload this page it still doesn't work because that should be
Card item with a capital I.
This is how I named my model.
So now you can see this works.
And now we're displaying our current item here.
And that of course is not quantity but quantity.
So the key name we defined in our in between table and now we see the quantity 2.
So now we can see the card items again.
Now we can go back to making sure that we also handle the case that we add an existing item to the card.
So let's make sure we handle this case that we add a product to the card which is already part of the
card and Datchet of course simply increment the quantity that therefore here if we make it into this
lock I essentially want to get my old quantity First of all which I can get from my product by accessing
card item as we just did it in the view in the last lecture.
This is this extra field that gets added by sequel's to give us access to this in-between table.
And they are to the quantity and sequel as does not just give us access to the in-between table but
to this exact product in the in-between table.
So therefore we get the quantity for this product as it's stored in the cart.
So now we have our old quantity and new quantity.
The variable we initialize with 1 here is now simply old quantity plus one.
With that we just have to add it to the card.
So here I will return fetched cart to get access to the cart and then add product as I do it down there
to add product and then simply my product here and my Frue call where I set my quantity to whip's new
quantity just as I do it down there.
If we now want it to a wide nested then blocks here what we could do is we could add a new then block
here.
Where we get some data to which I'll come back where we do handle Day is fetch card thing which is the
same for both cases.
Essentially we add a product with new quantity.
So we can certainly remove that.
But now the differences that data here actually should hold both the product that needs to be added
and our quantity.
Right because the quantity is calculated differently.
It overstays at one or here we set it to old quantity plus one to make sure that we correctly get that
data we can of course pull new quantity out of this anonymous function and make it a top level variable
in this overall function here.
And they knew new quantity is available in all then blocks and we never leave it at 1 here.
Or if we got a product we also need to return that product here because that will then be our product
we receive in the then block.
It's automatically wrapped by a promise as I mentioned earlier.
And now we have a set up that should work again and that ultimately should ensure that we redirect.
So now let's see this let's click at the card again and decline the teen deed as to now.
And if I add a second product to your this one with the price 66 and I add this to my cart does this
now add 1 and that is not pretty neat.
We can now start adding all these products.
Now let's make sure we can also delete them from the cart.