Our program is taking shape we can't delete products from the cart yet though so we should definitely
all to do that.
To do that we still need product ID.
We want to delete.
But now again I will first of all get my card for a user by accessing a request user get carte and then
adding then and catch calls as we did at multiple times already.
And then block here.
I know that I've got access to my cart and in that cart I now want to find the products for this user
and to be precise the products.
Not all products but the product with that product ID.
So here I will return cart get products and then simply here where ID is equal to fraud ID in the next
block we at identify or have my products and I have to extract that exact product I'm looking for as
the first element in the product array.
And now I want to destroy that product but not in the products table of course but only in that in-between
cart item table that connects my cart with that product to do that.
I can simply call product card item using that magic field sequel I gives me to access the element in
the in between table and then destroy.
And that will remove it from that in-between table.
Nobbled return this so that I can add a number then block here with the result of the zipper operation
if I would care.
And then there I'll simply redirect back to the cart where I should then not see that product anymore.
Let's give it a try.
If we reload the cards and isolate that one with quantity free it's gone.
Got no arrows here.
And if we reload the card items we only have one element in there with quantity 2 and the other one
is gone indeed.
So this is how simple we can delete connected items in this in-between table.
Here at the example of the card.