So our cart is looking pretty fine.
And actually we have the old functionality again now without storing anything in files but now working
with a database as we should.
Now one thing is missing and that are deep orders now.
I'll not add a real check outflow here.
But I want to have a check out but then my card which will basically for now immediately move all the
elements in this card out of discard.
So clear the card and instead create a new order and order that is related to a couple of products and
a user.
Now if you're feeling fancy you can certainly try to use on your own.
Otherwise we'll of course do it together here and we'll get there step by step.
Adding a simple check out functionality.
Let's start with the model and it is all treat a new order japes file and copy my card.
Item just fall.
Move it.
Enter import equalize.
Rename it to your to order.
Also here and now should order look like.
While our order is in DND just in-between table between a user to which to orderable longs and then
multiple products that are part of the order and these products again do have a quantity attached to
them.
So just as we had cart items for the cart I'll have order items for my order so I can copy card items
again move that into order item and rename cart item your to order item starting with a lower case.
Here in the string name definition and then it will have the same structure as an order as in CART item.
Your an order item and the order itself will not have anything but the ID because the order essentially
is like the.
Here for me.
You could of course say Order has more information like an address and you could add this year.
You just have to make sure you add this for every order you create but that is essentially it.
Now regarding the relations there is one important difference to the card though.
If we go to the app js file where we do set up appled relations all import my order year from the order
from the order file and import my order item from the order item file.
But now if we connect D models here at the bottom we can say that order belongs to a user and doesn't
belong to many users because a single order is always belong to one user who placed the order and the
user may of course have many orders like this.
So this is not a many to many relationship.
It's a one to many relationship one user can have many orders now on order however can belong to many
products and it does so with an in-between table which we specify with Frue which is our order item
table like this and we can also find even worse here if we want and that would be basically that a product
belongs to many orders but we can also leave it out here.
Now we get this set up.
Now let me make sure we can sync again.
So let's turn on forcing this.
If we now refresh our database we should have new orders and order items in orders.
We see a connection to a user and an order items.
We see a connection to the order and to our product ID then so this is now the set up we need to use
and all this able forcing this sauted that we don't overwrite tables old time no.
So as a next step let's make sure we have a check out button and that this button does actually then
trigger something to create such a order.