Knouted we can add orders.
One thing is missing and that is that we cleared the cart.
I want to do this right after we edit the orders.
So down there I need to work with the cart and Daffer First of all all store it in a new variable fetched
cart.
Initially it's empty.
And here once I got the cart I'll store the cart in the fetched cart variable so that I can also use
it down there.
Now that cart should essentially drop all its cart items now I can use my fetch car to your to call
and effets set products for this cart and set the products to knol.
Now let's return this and then add a new then block with the result of this operation where I simply
want to redirect.
Let's give it a try let's save this and reload the card page here click order.
Now we're on the warder's page.
Go back to the cart and we got no products in the cart because if we go into the workbench we see that
the card items indeed are empty because we dropped all the items in a card by setting them to null.
This is how easy we can clean up the card here.
So with that we got all that logic done.
The last step I want to do here is that I actually show my orders and we can't get rid of the check
out page here for now because we have no such step at the moment.
So now let's make sure we all retrieve to orders correctly and can display them on our orders page for
this year.
All First of all get my user.
And now I'm interested in the orders of this user which I can get with get orders.
A magic method added by sequel's.
Thanks to our associations here we again get a promise that's Lague any potential errors we get.
And then the then lock I know that I have my orders.
This is where I want to render my orders page of therefore and I will pass a new variable into that
page.
The order is variable which simply stores all the retrieved orders so that I got my orders for it as
user.
Now let's go to the respective view and the views folder.
Here's the orders is it just fall which always shows nothing there.
Now obviously that's not what I always want to show it's that I only want to show nothing there or no
orders placed yet.
Whatever you like.
If we got no orders.
So first of all at a normal Ejaz statement where a check if orders length is smaller or equal than Sered
then we probably have no orders.
So in this case I want to display nothing there.
Now else and that is of course an important part.
Let's also close that statement of course with the closing curly brace.
Else I want to output borders and for now I'll do this in a very Oggy way with an ordered list of list
items which I repeat for every order.
So again Ejaz time to loop through all orders with for each for example now for each.
As you know takes a non-dysfunctional which gives us access to every order.
Then we repeat this code here for every order and then here we close to Kerley raise and the Purab record
of our For each method we can add a semi-colon if you want.
And now this is executed for every order we got.
Now every order we got has a couple of products that belong to the order.
So for every order I haveour I will output age 1 tech with ID ordered thought Id output like this and
below that number nested an ordered list with more list items where a loop through the products belong
to that order.
So here I'll have order and then its order item.
That is our connected model so to say for each cost that will be a list of all their related items.
And here I get my item.
Let's close this here and lets all the clothes De for each syntax then down there.
And now this list item is repeated for every item and in this order and there I simply want to output
the title so output item title.
Keep in mind this is a product so it will have a title and then maybe in normal parentheses I'll output
item quantity and this will not work.
I can already tell you that I save that I get another error actually.
And that assembly is simply coming from the fact that I a lead that one route to check out out.
We need to the leaders here too.
So I believe that the action would be to delete route too.
But still if I reload the orders page now this will just crash here because I have a Ejay as syntax
error though.
Let's quickly fix that.
OK here for item quantity you need to close that.
But even after this change this will not work now because order is not defined because that should be
orders for each but now because we can't loop through order item here this does not work.
And to understand this let's have a look at our shop as controller file and let's outport order is here
and let's see what exactly we get protists Let's now reload the page.
It will still break of course but now we can have a look at the output there.
Want to scroll up there is what we lock with this line Kohn's lock orders and there we can see that
we do have an array of orders but an order does not have an order item key.
This is not provided by sequel eyes.
If we all want to fetch their related products to an order we have to pass an object here where we set
include to an array with the field products or the element products as a string.
Now why products because an aperture as we associate order to many product products of course.
And if we look at our model the product model has been named product sequel eyes pluralize estus and
then we can use a concept called eager loading where we basically instruct sequel eyes.
Hey if you are fetching all the orders please old affectional related products already and give me back
one array of orders.
That also includes the products per order.
Now this only works of course because we do have a relation between orders and products as set up at
App G-S here and now we can load both together.
This will still not make our template will really be deadly.
But now we got orders with more data in them.
Each order will now have a product array and with that in mind we can go back to our view here to the
orders view and tweak that we can love Fruita orders and every order will have an ID that's fine.
Now our order will still not have a order item but it will have a products list and now we can look
for all the products and each item which is now simply a product and therefore we can name it as such.
To make this clear each product of course has a title which we can output and it does not have a quantity
but the product will now have an order item key which then stores the quantity for that product.
In that order and now if we reload this page we do see our orders with the nested products in there.
Not the most beautiful presentation you have for sure but this is how it actually works.
We also see there is one Dhami order that was created accidentally in between with no products and we
can always verify that by looking into the database we get for order items related to orderless with
the ID 9 and 11 in the orders we got 9 10 and 11 so indeed there is the order with the ID 10 which has
no items.
We can simply clear it.
Right clicking on it here.
Delete row.
Apply apply and close and now if you reload the orders page it's gone and we only see these two orders.
So this is now working and now we get the full flow.
We got a user who is related to created products we can edit the products we can delete the products
we can add products to the cart.
We can then also create the order based on the data in our cart.
We can view product details and so on.
So this is all working fine as it should.
And with that we get the set up we need for now.
This gave you an introduction to see equalize and definitely dive into the official box to play around
with that and learn more about it and how it works.