That's it for the sequel part of this course you learn about sequel dad it's a database philosophy or
schema engine type that uses strict data schemas and relations in the databases that use sequel and
that you can easily connect to such databases with no chips with packages like my sequel to there we
had to write all the sequel queries manually though.
And you also have to configure the database manually add tables manually set up relations and that is
a lot of work and definitely something you need to learn.
In addition to no chance it's its own language essentially.
Or you use packages like sequels sequels allows you to not write sequel queries but instead interact
with your database through models you define and not just models but also relations so-called associations
in the sequels world.
That gives you a lot of magic methods that allow you to easily connect data add data delete data.
Basically what you saw in this module.
Now you could easily create an entire course just about sequel and sequels.
And that is not what this courses its the complete Noad course up to complete sequel.
Course I strongly encourage you to dive into this sequel docs if you plan on continuing with that to
learn all the ins and outs of this package and simply play around with it build your own demo applications
and try out the different features different types of relations and so on.
All move on here and learn about a different way of storing data with a no sequel approach in long OTB.
This is what will dive into in the next modules.