You've now got an introduction to know Chase and how it works and how you can use it to write BASIC
no chess programs.
But what you also already saw is dead with no.
J.S. alone you have to write a lot of code to deal with basic things like extracting the body of incoming
request.
Now typically you don't want to do that.
You want to focus on your business logic.
The code that makes up your specific application.
You don't want to work or you don't want to care about standard tasks like handling incoming requests
or routing.
So executing different code for different pauvres difference or else you don't want to do that.
And therefore we'll now have a look at Express.
J.S. this is a framework you can install as a third party package into your note project and as such
it basically helps you outsource some of that nitty gritty work some of the details you don't want to
care about.
It gives you a rule set in which you work and a lot of utility functions that help you write cleaner
code and focus on your core business.
So what's inside this module then we'll have a brief look at what Express chess is.
I gave you a short introduction already now but let's take a closer look.
I'll then have a look at one important concept that pretty much defines express chess or that expressed
chess is built around middleware.
And what this is of course will that have a look at how we can work with requests and responses with
the help of express in a way easier way than we did thus far and we'll all have a look at routing and
see how we can execute different code for different incoming requests and payoffs or you or else without
having to write a bunch of if statements.
And last but not least of all to show you how we can return HVM pages so files we prepared to our client
instead of writing HVM all code in no chance as we did us far which was really that great.
So let's dive into all of that in this module.