So what is express and why do we use it.
Well I briefly mentioned it.
Writing all that server side logic is pretty complex.
Just remember what we had to do to parse an incoming request for extracting the body we manually had
to listen to the data and to the end event and then create a buffer which we then convert to a string.
And this was just one type of data we could get if we get other kinds of data like for example we get
a file or differently structured data then we would have to write new logic now expressed express shapes
helps us with that.
It actually doesn't have a built in way of fam handling or parsing that data but it makes it easy to
install another package that can easily be hooked into our project that will then do the parsing for
us and you will see what I mean in a second.
We in general don't want to care about all these nitty gritty details.
We want to focus on our code that defines our application.
So the thing that really sets our application apart from other applications our unique selling point
you could say and we do use a framework for this for all the heavy lifting a framework is basically
a set of helper functions but also of tools and rules with which we work.
So basically we have a clearly defined way or at least some outline on how we should structure our application
or our code and how we should work with that framework to write clean code.
And of course I will teach you all of that for Express as in this module.
So Express shapes helps us with that.
And this is why we will dive into it here.
Now of course ExpressJet is not the only package or framework you can use for no chase that will help
you write better no chase code and focus on your business logic.
Now for one you could of course stick to Emelin no chance.
We only use data thus far and of course that works and depending on the complexity of your application
or the level of challenges you are seeking you can absolutely stick to vanilla.
No yes you can theoretically write everything on your own just with that.
There also are other frameworks you could use.
For example there is a Dawna's genius.
Now if you ever use Lero for a Ph.
This is basically illegible inspired framework for no.
Yes but not from the same creators that are Ole's is kowa or a sales genius and there are many more.
You can basically Google for Express chase alternatives and you will find plenty of block posts diving
into the different alternatives and what their strengths and weaknesses are.
But Express chess is by far the most popular and most often used one.
Which is why I WILL ALL to teach it here.
The great thing about Express's that it's highly flexible and actually doesn't add too much functionality
is out of the box but it gives you a certain way of building your application or else working with the
incoming requests that make it highly extensible and therefore there are dozens or hundreds and thousands
of third party packages built for Express specifically that you can then easily add to your node express
application without having to configure a lot and dessous.
Probably the real strength of EXPRESS And of course it also does add some nice features out of the box.
So why don't we just install it and take a closer look ourselves.