Express yes is all about middleware and you see a diagram here.
Indian middleware means that incoming request is automatically funneled through a bunch of functions
by express chess.
So instead of just having one request handler you will actually have a possibility of hooking in multiple
functions which the request will go through until you send the response.
This allows you to split your code into multiple blocks or pieces instead of having one huge function
that does everything.
And there's a steep pluggable nature of express chase where you can easily add a third party packages
which simply happen to give you such middleware functions that you can plug into Express chase and add
certain functionalities.
But more on that later.
So this is the core concept of express choice.
The middleware and we can use that by going here ofter we created the app object.
But before we pass that to create server and then we can use the app and call a method which is defined
by the Express framework.
Use use allows us to add a new middleware function now to use method is pretty flexible.
It accepts an array of so-called request handlers here and it has some other use cases too.
Now one easy way of using it is that you simply pass a function to it and this function here this function
you pass to app use will be executed for every incoming request and dysfunction will receive free arguments
the request and the response object.
As you already know it basically with some extra tricks learned though and a third argument which is
the next argument.
Now you can rename any of these arguments but what do they do.
Request a response as just mentioned are basically what you know with some extra features.
Next is actually a function a function that will be passed to this function by express.
Yes and this can be confusing because you are passing a function as an argument to the use method and
does function you're passing is receiving yet another function here on the next argument.
And this next argument basically this function you're receiving here has to be executed to allow the
request to travel on to the next middleware.
Now let me show you what I mean.
We can simply console log in the middleware here like this.
Now since I have no Mondas automated restarts the server.
And let's now go to the browser and reload localhost free.
Now actually this will keep on spinning you see.
So we don't get a response which makes sense because we've got a logic where we would send one in the
consul here at the bottom you see in the middle where though.
So this did execute it this is what I meant.
This allows us to hook into this funnel through which the request is sent.
If I duplicate this and add a number you statement here in and number middleware and I saved this and
let it restart therefore and I now reload this page here on localhost 3000 then I see in the middle
where here again and I see it twice because I pressed reload twice in like last year.
But I don't see in a number of middleware.
Now the reason for that is that we have to call next year to allow the request to travel on to the next
middle we're in line.
So it basically goes from top to bottom.
Frood at file you could say through all the middleware functions but only if we call next we don't call
next to just dies.
So if we don't call next we should actually send back a response because otherwise the request can't
continue its journey.
So it will never reach a place where we might send the response.
But if we also don't send one here well then we never send one.
So now with this next call at it we actually make it into this middleware and we should receive this
console log.
And here we could then even send a response that will do this as a next step because sending responses
also changed a bit.
So restart at the server reload that page and now you see in the middle where and in and number middleware
thanks to next.
So this allows the request to continue to the next middleware in Middleware in line which is middleware.
Below this one.
So this is a crucial concept is this idea of middleware.
And you can use any function that has this format so that receives request response next.
And you should call next if you want to allow the request to go to the next function.
You should send the response if you got our plans so let's send the response in this middle where in
the next lecture.