We added middle and I mentioned that this is a crucial concept of the Express framework and that we
should call next if we don't send a response because otherwise the request will just die and will not
continue to the next middleware.
Now in this model we're not calling next.
And there also wouldn't be a next middleware in line.
This is our entire script right.
There is nothing to come express.
Yes and that's important.
Doesn't send a default response or anything like that.
So instead we should send a response here so we can use the response object and now sending responses
actually gets easier thanks to express.
Yes.
Instead of setting a header which we still can do and writing which we all still can do so we can still
send responses as before.
But instead of doing this there is a new utility function we can use Send send allows us to send Well
a response.
And actually this allows us to attach a body which is of type any.
Now let me show you what this could be.
We could send good old age Tim Ellicot here.
Just one tech Hello from Express like this.
If we do that and we now reload this page here we see Hallo from Express.
By the way one thing you'll notice is that if you open your network tap here and you inspects dat request
you got.
You will see that under headers the content type is automatic He is set to text h him L here.
So does this stand for you.
This is another feature provided by express your descent method by default here.
So we send some text here simply sets and H team l Content-Type.
You can still set one manually with set header of course so you can always override this expressed Yes
default but you can also rely on the default where the default response header is text aged him out.
And now with that you see that we all get no dying request anymore because even though we're not calling
next year and we shouldn't we're doing the alternative we're sending a response with send.
And this is of course easier than using all these right chunks and it will be particularly easier once
we start sending back real files or the content of files.
Something we haven't done at all thus far.
Now this is something we'll also do in this module but for now make sure you understand this basic middleware
concept that you add functions that are hooked into Does funnel through which the request goes and you
either have next to reach the next middleware or you send the response to well not do anything else.
And of course if we would send a response here instead of calling Next we would never reach that middleware.
So you really just travel from middleware to middleware from top to bottom by calling next.