So we now had some basic work with Express.
Yes.
Now let's also dig into the internals off expressed chess at least a little bit here SD express J.S.
code repository and get help.
It's open source so you can dive into the code and no worries will not do a deep dive analysis.
But it's interesting to see how some things work.
So in there you know on that get up click on lip and then you'll find a response J.S. file or click
on it in that fall you will find a lot of code.
Now let's simply search for send and then the opening bracket and you will see how to send a function.
So basically a function we are calling here how this is defined internally and this helps us understand
it.
And this by the way is always a great technique if you want to see what something does behind the scenes.
And if you need to do something yourself for example to set some header or if data is done for you and
we had dead default header of text each time.
All right.
So let's see what sense does internally.
But does a bunch of checks to see if we're using outdate that wears off that function which we didn't
and this course so let's ignore that and then down there it basically analyzes what kind of data you
are sending.
And you see that if it's a stringed data so some text as we are doing it here that in this case it sets
the content type to.
Tim L but only if we haven't said it yet.
So it checks if the Content-Type header is not present yet in which case it sets it otherwise it would
leave our default if we have a overvalues like a number of Boullion or Ozon.
It would actually set a two binary or Jason data.
So this is just some of the internal things it does.
And you don't need to go through the entire code here.
It's a bit much and you're using express so that you don't have to do everything on your own but diving
into this can help sometimes.
Now one other interesting thing to see is that we can actually also shorten disk code here where we
set up the server.
We can pass app qued it creates a real method.
But instead we can all just use app and call listen.
And this will do both these things for us something we can see in the official code.
If you go into the application genius file in there what we can see is that if we search for Alyson
here the listing function just does the two things we did before it called HTP create server and passus
itself.
So the app object which we previously all the past two that passes it to create server and then doesn't
the end just make sure that lists and gets called on that server object.
So it internally does the same.
Do here and does of course save some code.
And now we can also remove that HTB import up there.
So now our code looks like this and we'll still work fine.
It restarts here.
And if I reload this page does this looking good to me.
So now we're using Express J S and you hopefully get a basic understanding of what it's doing and why
does helps you write cleaner code because now you have a clearly fine structure.
Use this middleware funnel and is safe code.
The question of course is how can we now handle different routes as we previously did where we had slash
message and slash nothing and so on.
And of course it would be nice if we now could also read incoming requests in an easier way.
Well we'll do both and see both over the next lectures.