So let's see what else express Chase can do for us.
And let's also start building a more exciting application than solves for days.
We want to handle different routes to friend you or else to do that all.
First of all remove our dummy middleware which is not doing anything.
And this second one should only trigger for requests that go to just slash nothing.
Now how can we filter for such requests.
Well I mentioned that the use function here has multiple words.
You can see that here for overloads.
So we basically have four different or five different ways of using that function.
You can see a great explanation in the official docs and on Express JSE dot com.
They are the API reference for the version we're using here the latest version.
And there you find app that you use where you find the explanation of how to use it.
Now don't be confused that this is only one definition instead of the five I've promised the five.
Basically just as made up of different combinations.
So in the end this is how you can use app.
You got an optional first argument which is some Poth and dead already is what we're looking for.
This allows us to filter out certain requests.
However this works a bit different than our IF statements to it before.
But I'll come back to that.
Then we have to call back.
So basically the function that should be executed and we can have more than one off that callback we
can have as many as we want.
We can all have multiple paths filters here.
Now you can obviously read more in the docs here.
But let's just use it and learn during the course so we can add a payoff at the beginning.
For example just slash.
This however is the default by the way.
And now we would handle this for just with a team slash right.
If I reload we still see Hallo from Express.
Now what happens if I for example enter slash at product.
We still see Hallo from Express and we still see I'm in a number middleware so dismal where it gets
executed for both slash and add product because this does not mean that the full path.
So the part after the domain has to be a slash but that it has to start with that.
Now of course every route starts with just a slash.
And then we have different other criteria.
So what we can do is we can simply duplicate this and add it before it does middleware and add slash
add product.
Now why before this middleware and not after it.
Because remember the request goes through the file.
From top to bottom and if we don't call next it's not going to the next middleware.
Well I am not calling next year.
So in the end if we have slash at product does middleware will be reached first.
Because top to bottom ad product will match just middleware.
And since I don't call next disk middleware we'll never get a chance of handling that request even though
the filter here would have well-matched data requests too.
So here if I just add there at product page like this and I save this you will see that on slash at
product we see the at product page and on any Rip-Off including random stuff or just slash nothing you
see Hello from Express.
And this is how we can use staed middleware approach to control what is getting shown and the ordered
year as well as the fact whether we are calling next or not matters a lot by the way.
If you were sending a response this is a good indication that you never want to call next to because
you don't want to execute any of our response related code just as before with when ilah know chase
you don't want to send more than one response does won't work and will result in an error.
So this is a code we can use here.
Does this the code that allows us to route our requests into different middleware.
And if we have a middleware that should be applied to all requests we would simply add it on top of
all the average middleware.
And then add it like this if we don't add a filter or a filter that matches all requests it should match
then dismissal where it will always run first.
And if we call the next function well then of course the request will also be able to continue.
So if we have this middleware here which allows Tichel request to continue we have Kohn's a log does
always runs well with this code.
What we will get asked that if I saved this if a reload here.
And I also go to add product here.
We have this always run twice because well there's always runs.
That's just how it works.
So this is how the middleware works and how you can work with it to funnel your request into the right
place.