That we had a very close look at the whole middleware thing.
Let's now understand how we can actually work with incoming requests and how we can extract data and
for it.
I again want to be able to handle a POST request.
So let's say on add product here.
I went to actually return a HTML page with a form for that I'll again return a form and just as a side
note does of course is a bit of a incomplete h tim document.
We should also wrap this in H.
Tim L and Baden's and so on tax I'm keeping the shorter here to make it easier to read but later we
will also write proper aged him code.
No worries.
So I have my form here and in there I'll have my input of type title of type text your with a name of
title let's say and I'll add a button again and dead button will be off.
Type submit because it should submit this form and send a post request therefore and I'll simply give
it a caption off at product.
So let's simulate that this is a form that allows us to add a product to our own online shop or something
like Det.
Now this is our four year and the four needs in action.
So the poverty you are l to which the requests should be sent and let's named is product and the method
should be Post.
Let's say can also be written like this.
So this will send ational code back which holds a form.
And now we need route.
We're a middleware that handles requests to product.
So we can at app use slash product.
Now the important parts here is we can place that prior or after dismay to where they won't clash because
they have nothing in common regarding the Poth they have product in common but slash and dash product
is different to a slash product.
It just has to come before this one because otherwise this would execute prior to that.
So this position here looks all right and then we again have our function which receives these free
arguments as a side note you can of course omit an argument you are not planning to use at least the
third one you can't commit to the first one if you want the response because the order does matter.
But if you never use deferred one you can't admit it.
But I always edit here to make it clear that it exists.
So now with that we have this function which will execute for product and then there.
I want to redirect and for now I want to lock to incoming data to the consul.
What we can do here is for redirecting.
I can use response redirect which certainly is easier than manually setting the status code and setting
the location header so redirect has a number of convenience function added by express.
And here I can redirect to let's say just slash.
So it will automatically redirect me to the slash route.
But of course this is not the only thing I'm also interested in getting the body of my incoming requests.
So extracting what the user has sent me and for does express say yes now has a convenience feature for
us if I console Lauck request bought here this is a new field added by express and let's see what's
in there.
So if I now save this we should be able to go back to slash add product and hopefully see the input
field and let's add a book here and hit add product.
We're redirected to slash.
Does this working and on the console we see on the find Let's get rid of the Afrikan so locks so that
this is less clouted with locks.
We can also remove that.
So we see undefined.
And the reason is that we're almost there.
Request gives us his body convenience property here but by default request doesn't try to parse the
incoming request body to do that.
We need to register a parser and we do that by adding a number of middleware.
And you typically do that before your route handling middleware because the parsing of the body should
be done no matter where your request ends up.
And there I want to parse the incoming requests body now for that we can install a third party package
and we do that by running NPM installed dash dash.
Safe because this will all be packaged it is used in our code here.
That doesn't matter for production.
So just safe not safe death and the famous bawdy parser.
Now this would actually be included and expressed by default because the community wanted that again.
It was in the past then it was removed then it was re-added.
I will use that third party package which is the recommended way of using it because if they ever decide
to pull it out of express again this code I'm teaching you will still work.
So now we installed a new package the body parser and we can import them here.
I'll store it in a body parts that are constant the name as always is up to you and the package is named
body dash parser.
And now we can use that to Europe by calling body parser.
So using that object and then Daut you are encoded.
This is a function you have to execute and you can pass options to configure it but you don't have to
here and now what this does is it registers a middleware.
So dysfunction DNA just yields us such a middleware function.
So this passes such a function here in the end even though we can see it and this package will in the
end in the middle or a function call next in the end so at the request all to reach is our middleware
but before it does that it will do that whole request body parsing we had to do manually in the previous
core sections.
Now this will not parse all kinds of possible bodies files Jason and so on but this will parse bodies
like the one we're getting here send through a form if we have our bodies like files and we'll do that
all in this course.
We'll use that front parser's and this makes express Che's so extensible if we need something we can
just block it in.
You'll see how easy that is.
It's one line of code.
Well two if you count the important.
Now with that we should actually get output for this console lock statement.
So now let's restart the server.
By the way if you install a new package you need to restart.
You can't rely on your auto restart from the old one.
And we should configure one thing as I'm getting warned here.
You should pass de-conflict options here and set.
Extend that to false.
This is if it should be able to parse non-default features you could say.
So let's add this to comply with what we should use here.
And with that we get the body parser enabled.
Now let's try this again and let's go back to add product and let's add our book again add product or
redirect redirected.
And now we see this is what we get a javascript object with a key value pair which also makes extracting
that value easier.
Then we had to do before with a split function where we manually had to create that array and so on.
Now we get an object where we simply get the key we find in our import here.
So does name and then the value to user entered and does this definitely simpler than our custom approach
we used before.
And now we can work with all the data our users told us stored them in the database something we'll
do later showed them and the response whatever we need to do.
Now one thing of course is missing this right now would also execute for incoming data request.
Well we only want to listen to a post request.
So what can we do regarding that.