Were able to parse incoming request bodies with the help of the body parts or package which is pretty
neat.
But right now as I mentioned this middleware always executes not just for post requests but all to get
requests what can we do regarding that.
Well instead of the app use we can also use apt get dessous basically app use it has the same syntax
as app use.
We can use a POV or don't use a POV but it only will fire for incoming get requests.
So does this a novel form of filtering besides filtering for the Poth apt get allows us to filter or
forget requests.
And on the same page we all got app post to filter for incoming post requests and just by changing this
word does middleware will now only trigger for incoming post requests with this path and not forget
requests.
So if I save this and I go to slash product you see I get hello from Express.
So I don't end up here in the way I entered slash product but it was a get request.
But if I send a post request frood that form I have an app product if I do this year book to you'll
see we get this output.
So we clearly made it into this middleware due to our filtering.
So this is a novel way of using that middleware function instead of use which will work with all the
methods.
We can also use GET or POST to filter for these.
And additionally you all have to lead patch and put which are over HTP were apps which we'll use later
in the course because we can't really use them from a normal aged him document.