We're nearing the end of this module because we already learned a lot about the core concepts of express
chaps and disdain for a crucial module because all the rest of the Course will basically build up on
this and this knowledge of how Express shapes works.
Now even though our Dhami app here is really simple thus far we're already putting all our code into
this single capture last fall which is damn for getting bigger.
Now obviously for Apple this size it's not a problem at all.
It's still pretty small but typically we want to split our routing code over multiple files.
We want to basically export our logic in different files and imported into this fall.
We could do this we could create files where we export these functions but expressed Yes actually gives
us a pretty nice way of outsourcing routing into faults.
And for this I'll change our folder structure a bit.
I'll add a new folder which will name routes.
Now you don't have to name us.
You could name it differently too.
But it's a convention you often see that you put your routing related code so your code it should execute
four different pops and HTP methods that you put that into files which is stored in the route's folder
and there since we're building or we're slowly building towards an online shop here.
All in a route which I'll name admen dot J.S. because this should be the route that handles the creation
of products which the admin of the shop can do.
I'll also add another file and that will be shop J.S..
So basically what the users see let's say now will not build the full choppier will slowly develop it
over to the next Electress and modules because it uses a lot of cool features like database and so on.
But we candidly start putting our code into these files here the add product route and this product
post request should certainly go into our admin last fall because these are routes that are reached
by the admin and general Routier should go into our shop Chia's fault so that users that are whizzing
our front page see this route.
Now one convenient feature offered by express chase to achieve this is to go into these files and import
express again you can and you typically do import this into multiple falls and then we can use a feature
of it called the router.
Now you can also create this with a lower case r at the beginning the name is totally up to you.
And I do create that router by calling express dot router and this is a function execute.
This router is like a mini Xpress app tied to the ber express app or pluggable into the Express app
I'll say which we can export here.
So here I can use module exports and set it equal to the router.
Now of course this doesn't do much.
We have to use that router to now register things and actually all named this year with all lowercase
are to be in line with our names.
This however has to have a capital case.
So now the router here can be used to again define the use function for all requests a get function
forget post for post and so on.
So basically we can go back to recapture last fall cut these two admen routes from there put them in
here in the Edman Yes file and simply replace app with router here.
Now the router gets exported so the router now has two routes registered because we export that here.
And this is the Optik on which we registered these routes the agro code can stay as it is because the
router functions here basically work in exactly the same way as the app use function does or the app
get and so on function does.
I'll rename this to get though because I only want to handle get requests to add product and return
to this form.
And with that with this exported here we can now import debt into the last fall.
Now for this I'll add an import at the top separated from Express to make sure or to make clear that
this is my own file and I'll name it admen route's the name is totally up to you.
But I do require a relative payoff to the route's folder and that in there the admin fall and you can
omit diot JSA as I already explained this will be added automatically so now does this.
Importing this router object to your end does rowdier object in turn has these routes registered and
the nice thing is about this router that it is actually a valid middleware function.
So we can take admen routes and just call app use and put our admen routes in there just like this.
Not calling it like a function.
So without parentheses but simply just the object itself the router object we're exporting in this file
we can use this year and now it will automatically consider our routes in the Edman last fall when funding
the request for this middleware here.
Now just before the order matters so if we put this offer does middleware we will never reached it.
So this hasn't changed.
Now we can do the same for our front facing round here.
Let's go to the shop geus fall and there again feel free to post a video and try this on your own.
Try to implement this with the express router as we just did in the Edmon shares fall where you is successful.
Let's import express first of all by requiring express then let's create a dead router object by calling
express dot router as a function.
Let's export the router here.
And let's then use app use or paste in what I copied back replace app with router and maybe use with
get you don't have to do that the use method would exist too but now we only have to get requests here.
Now we can go back to Edmund J S X you need to add J S and import all routes there to the order of the
imports doesn't matter.
So my shop routes I required them from the routes folder and they are from their shop js file.
And now here again the order matters we should register this second.
Now if I save this and I reload add routes at product this works.
Now Actually here's one important thing to understand.
Even if I would switch the position here and have shop routes first and I reload it would work and we
would not end up in disarray.
But this only happens because I have Gettier get post and so on will actually do an exact match here.
If I would use use here as I did before to handle any incoming HTP method then if I reload here we see
a halo from Express again.
So this exact matching is not achieved by using the router but because we use Gettier and that would
have been the same if we stick to the app way of doing this in the app japes file we had previously.
So get.
Also make sure that it's not just a get method but this access path and therefore.
Now if I enter some random stuff I actually get an error because now I got no single middleware that
would handle this.
But I do have my routes set up here now and split up and then registered here.
And as I mentioned it's not the worst practice to still care about the order.
Even though at the moment it'll work fine no matter what the order is.
But if you ever change something back to use it would matter and therefore why don't we just care about
it right from the start.