Now one thing we did in the last lectures is we used the Express router and right now we have a set
up where we also have some unhandled routes if we enter some random string here we get this error.
Now typically we would want to see a 4 0 for error page and we can do that back in the fall.
We can take advantage of the middle of weares or the way express uses to middleware and funnels the
request for them.
Remember that the request goes from top to bottom.
So if it finds some middleware that handles it it will go in there and then for example year for Slash
with that get method on the router we would actually.
And here we also get no next call here.
So no other middleware would be executed but if we got no fitting middleware and we don't have one here
then we actually make it all the way to the bottom and eventually we don't handle that request.
So to send a 4 0 for error page we simply have to add catch all made aware at the bottom where we don't
need a path filter but we could add slash but that's difficult anyways.
And then simply hand the request recoat response next.
Since I use use here this will also handle all HTP methods not just get requests and there.
I can then also send some code like Page Not Found.
So little dummy h HTML document and maybe we all want to set the 404 status code and you can do that
by changing a number method prior to send and that is the status method.
And of course you cannot just use that here.
You could have used it here or in the admin Chesed fault too.
So always before sending you can call status to or set header.
You can actually chain all these method calls send just has to be the last one.
So you're calling status to set my status code and number a convenience method added by express Yes
and I'll send it to 404 which is the common code for a page was not found with this edit.
If I save this and then now reload my dummy POF your I get page not found whereas for at product I still
get that form.
So this is still working.
The rest however changed.