So knouted we had a very close look at the whole express middleware thing and how routeing works and
express and how we can use that to our advantage how we can filter routes and so on.
Let's actually start working on what we serve to the user.
Thus far it has always been some dummy HDMI content but you're probably not in the course to just learn
how to build dummy HVM mal content.
So let's return some real HVM files to the user that awls don't look like crap.
For this all create a new folder in my project and I'll name it views.
Now that name is up to you.
You can also name that folder whatever you want but in that course we will slowly go towards the MVC
model view controller structure and I will explain what this is a little bit later.
One part of it is that we manage our views.
So what we serve to the user in one place of our application in the views folder you now the view is
will just be a bunch of HVM files though.
So we'll create a new file and that will be my shop Daut aged HTML file.
It's file I want to serve for users visiting just slash and I also want to have my ad product fall here.
So at ad product or aged him all later by the way in case you already know the concept of templating
engines will use these two so that we can dynamically add content into th tim outfalls.
But for now let's just start with these files.
So let's start here and add product h tim L and now here's one important note.
If you're not interested in writing that HDMI code you can skip this lecture now and find the finished
HVM code attached to this and that the next lecture.
So if you want to skip.
You can do that and just follow along in the next lecture where I will provide that finished H.T. of
all the code.
Otherwise let's now create it together.
So in this ad product h HTML file.
I'll now create a new h tim L5 skeleton and visuals to do code helps you with that.
As you saw if you just type H Tim L It should open does pop up if it doesn't you can Forsett by typing
or by hitting control and space and then navigate to h tim L5 with the arrow keys and hit enter and
it gives you this nice skeleton which basically defines a basic Well HVM elth skeleton.
Now here all change the title to add product and then the body there.
I now want to have my forum.
I don't just want to have to form in there though I also want to have some navigation bar that allows
me to switch to my shop.
Tim Page today slash route and the other way around.
So here I will.
First of all add a header and in that header I'll add a math bar and then that nav bar I'll add on or
a list with list items which are links where I go to slash.
So this is just my shop.
And then another list item at product which will be slash at product.
This is the page we're on here but I always want to show both options.
Obviously you can write VHDL code that fits your needs.
So this is the header.
It will be pretty unstored for now.
We'll add styling too.
And now let's add a main section too.
So this is also a normal HVM element which holds or which should hold the content of our page here and
there.
I want to have my form with the action that is also adds product.
Remember here we're done targeting does post route and in there or there I will add my post method and
I will now also add my input here the input type text with a name of title and I will add my button
of type submit to your Which I'll label add product.
Now we will add more to this for and later because a product is obviously not just made up of a title
but for now this will do.
We got our form in here.
Let's now copy that entire HDMI Tim Allen code and paste it into the shop.
A team will fall.
And then of course in the main section I don't want to have a form.
Instead each one tech my products and below that later in the course we will render all the products.
So here we will have a list of all the products.
Right now we don't have that but we'll get there.
Once we learn how to manage data on the server and so on.
Now the rest of the page can stay the same for both pages.
And again as I mentioned styling is missing.
Let's now move onto the next lecture where the goal will be to serve as age HTML pages before we then
work on the styling.