So well come back in case you skipped.
You'll find these two age Tim files attached to this lecture.
So make sure to download them and enter them insert them into your views folder.
And now the goal is to serve them.
We didn't work on the James Files and The Last Lecture.
We just edit th html files and make sure to explore them to understand what they do in the end.
We got the same content as before we just added an extra header and then at product we still have the
forum in shop HTL we got some dummy code since we have no products to serve yet and now we want to serve
DS H.T. mail files in my routes.
Now how does that work.
Let's start in the shop japes fall instead of sending some text or does H.T. email text here in this
case let's instead send a file with send file and send file.
Well allows us to just get sent back a file to the user.
And as you see here in description it automatically sets to content timed response header field and
we'll see if that works for us or not.
So send file is a way to execute.
And now we just need to point at that Fabi when I sent.
Now here the question is how does the payoff look like the file is in the views folder.
But how should this pov now look like.
Well we could try using slash and assume that we see all of that from the view of the capture last fall
which is an dnt the fall which starts our entire server.
The fact that shop Chasse's subdirectory doesn't really matter because we export its functionality and
imported into the aperture as which is in the root folder.
So we could try using slash for the root Poth an absolute payoff scene from the root folder and then
viewers and then shop h tim l like this.
Let's give this a try.
Let's save this go back to the page and reload localhost 3000 slash nothing.
And I don't see that.
Well the reason for it is this that this path is incorrect.
Let's try dot slash here.
If we now reload POV must be absolute is the error we get.
So whatever we tried this doesn't seem to work.
The reason for it is this that an absolute payoff would be correct.
But slash like this actually refers to or root folder on our operating system.
Not to this project folder.
So in order to construct the path to dis directory and this file here ultimately we can use a feature
provided by no chase.
And now for core module we can import Rip-Off core module by requiring Poth like this.
And then here we send a file where we create a path with the help of this module by calling the join
method.
Join yields us a payoff at the end it returns a payoff but it constructs this path by concatenating
the different segments.
Now the first second we should pass year is Dan actually a global variable made away lable by node.
J.S. and that is the underscore underscore and that's important.
These are two underscores.
Dirty name does is a global variable which simply holds the absolute payoff on our operating system.
Q This project folder and now we can add a comma and simply add viewas here because the first segment
is basically the payoff to his whole project folder.
The next segment is that we want to go into the use folder and then the first segment will be on file.
So here shop that H-2 him out and don't add slashes here because and that's important.
We use lbf join not because of the absolute path we could built it with their name and then concatenating
this manually too.
But we're using paff join because this will automatically build the path in a way that works on both
Linux systems and Windows systems because as you might know on Linux systems you have pauvres like this
and I'm not talking about possum to you or else but on your farm system now but on Windows you use backslashes
for your paths and therefore if you manually constructor's slashes it would not run on Windows.
And the other way around POF joint basically detects the operating system you're running on and that
automatically builds a correct path.
Now with that we could expect that it works.
But actually their name here will point in this route's fuller right.
Derham gives us the path to a file in which we use it and we're using it in the shop G-S fall in the
route's folder.
So this will point to the route's folder but the use is actually located in a sibling folder to routes.
So what can we do regarding that now to solutionis that we add one or a segment in there and that is
dot dot slash and this simply means go up one level.
So this will now build upon where it first goes into the folder of these files are into routes.
Then it goes up one level then into views.
So if it's up 1 level it's in the root folder then into views and then it serves this.
And with that if we now load localhost free thousands slash again we see that age Tim file being served
and now is a great time for you to post a video and ensure that you'll serve at product.
When does route's gets loaded.
Where are you successful let's do it together.
For this let's first of all import Poth module again the core module.
So conc POV require lbf to pull data in.
We don't need to install that because it is a core no chess module.
And then here we don't use send but send file and we will then use POV join the name variable to get
the payoff to disk files folder.
And then we can go up one level and then into views.
Whip's should be a string views and then we want to serve at Dasch product.
H tim Alpha fall with this if we save that and we head over to add Dasch product stetch be Edmund slash
at product.
We see this page too.
Now the styling is missing because we don't have any.
But this works and we can all to check on add product that the correct content type was assigned by
express.
So does all the works.
And now we see how we can serve simple H team l files for the different routes we have.
Now here's one bonus task for you which I want you to solve and which will solve together in the next
lecture at a New Age TMail file which is your page not found page which is denser.
If we ever reach this middleware function.