Were successful let's add it together or add a new h to him l fall in the news and I'll name it for
Ford or h tim l.
But the name is totally up to you.
Well it has to be a html file of course and then create a new age HTML5 skeleton with the help of visuals
to you code here and then you're all named is.
Page Not Found.
That sounds like a fitting title.
And now you can get of course really creative your.
I will in the end just add H-1 tag where whereas say Page Not Found.
Obviously you can add more content here if you want.
Now I want to returned his h tim l file.
When ever we make it into dis middleware and therefore again I should send a file here.
But obviously I want to construct the path with the help of the POF module to make it work on all operating
systems.
So required a POF year and then go down there send and don't send but send a file and that file will
use a POV with which we construct here with their name.
And now here's a gotcha.
We already are in the project folder here because we're in actually yes.
So we don't need to go up a level here because we already are in the root folder.
Instead here we can go right away into the folder and then served four or four aged him file like this.
We also still want to set his status code because we still have a 4 0 for error.
If you now save this and you enter any random route that doesn't exist you should see that page not
found being served.
And you see that 404 error are being sent back to.
So does this now working to you.
And does this now a way better well way of serving the soul but styling would also be nice wouldn't
it.
So let's work on this over the next Electra's.