Before we work on the styling let me add one note on how we navigated to the root folder in shop G-S
and adventurous.
For one you could just use dot dot here instead of dot dot slash and this would be preferable.
Even though both should work on Windows and Mac because now we make no assumption about D separator
we're using when constructing a path.
So with this if I go back and I now go to just admen at product here it still works.
But now we get a cleaner way of doing this.
But there is even nicer way we could implement this.
We could also get the parent directory with the help of a little helper function.
For this I'll create a new folder here helper's or utile.
I'll go with you till you can name it however you want.
And there I'll add my Poth dot J.S. fall.
And it doesn't matter that this clashes with the global module because we'll import it differently.
Anyways now there I'll add an export with Module exports and I want to export a little function that
helps me construct a path to the parent directory or not a real function instead.
Variable I should say first of all here all import the POF with require lbf as we did it before and
then it will use a different function or not join.
But Durr name their name as you can see in their quick help on the right here returns the directory
name of a path.
So this sounds pretty useful if we use that we just have to find out which directory or which Folley
want to get the directory name.
Well there we can use the global process very well.
That is also a variable that is available in all files.
You don't need to import it.
And there you will have a main monohull property.
This will refer to the main well module that started your application.
So basically to the module we created here an app J.S. and now we can call file name to find out in
which file this module was spun up.
So put in other words this gives us the path to the file that is responsible for the fact that our application
is running and this file name is what we put into Der. name to get a payoff to that directory.
With this we can import from this file here.
I'll add my own import separated from the other ones simply to make it easier to identify and named
this route.
D'oh.
The name is totally up to you but it will require this from going up one level into utile and then Poth
and does root directory isn't the end.
What I want to inject here is a root directory is what I'll start with.
And when creating this path.
And now let's try reloading this page here and it still works and it should still work because now we're
in the end having a pretty neat way of constructing a path to our root directory.
I'll do the same and shop yes.
Import router from the uto folder at the path file in there and replace Durr name dot dot with router
again.
You could have totally sticked to the old approach but this one is a even cleaner one and one that should
be pretty straightforward to use and that should work on all operating systems and it always gives you
well the path to the root file.
With that let's move on to the styling.