Our age team all pages look pretty boring and obviously dessous know of course.
I got one if you want to learn more about seems as though but that's just a little side note.
But this is no it is of course but still it's important to understand how you can serve C S S in your
node apps too.
Because typically you have C S S and also a javascript code in your apps.
Now let's start simple.
I'm on the slash page here so on shop h tim L and let's add some styling here with good old style Tex
in the head section and does this Nottoway will keep it.
Does it just so that we can work on it and auto update this because importing an external style file
wouldn't work at the moment to spoil the fun already.
Now ask before you can skip this lecture.
If you don't want to write dishtowels together with me and you'll find it attached to the next doctor.
Otherwise let's do this together.
So let's start stalling this and let's start with the header.
Now I want to target the elements directly instead.
This will be my main navigation or my main header.
Let's give it a classmate however.
Header.
This will be the main header neth And if you're wondering about the strange CS's class name I'm using
a styling system named BVM.
More on that can be learned in that C as s course I mentioned or of course you can google SEUS SBM.
It's a certain way of naming your classes to avoid double class names.
Basically here I'll have my main header whoops head header item list and here I'll have my main header
items like this and you can of course named as However you want.
So these are a bunch of CS's classes that should help us with styling.
Now let's start with the header.
The header should have a width of 100 percent to take the full width of the page and let's say it should
have a height of 56 pixels.
Or if you want to work in R.E.M. which has certain Vonta just we could also go with Freethought 5 RPM.
Now let's all give it nice background color and here you're really free I'll not stick to red but now
I can hover over this and use this nice color picker and pick any color you want.
Now I'll try to pick a nice yellow golden ish orange colors something like this.
Maybe if you click on RGV it will also convert to a hex code.
So let's use debt and of course the class is not Hetter but main header and now if is saved us and go
back and reload.
We got that looks better now.
There is some some padding in the bodies.
Let's actually define that we want to have no padding and no margin.
I think it's a margin that we don't want to have that looks at this looks almost better.
We still got some margin here at the top.
Does this coming from our list in here though that some margin call it missing doing its job here.
Now let's also get rid of that by now.
Also styling our main header.
Tim list.
Let's copy that.
Add a class here.
Set the list style to nonne and remove any margin and padding.
We might have year that looks better now.
Obviously the items are not looking nice.
For this I will actually change the display here to flex to use flex box for de-list and then style
our items here a bit on these items.
For now I'll remove all margin and padding them I'd have reload.
Now thanks to flex books they're sitting next to each other.
Now let's also style our links in there.
So main hador item.
Any nested anchor tag should have no text decoration and the color of white may be looks a bit better
now.
Where Diggles centering would also be nice.
And for that I'll go back to the main Hetter execution back to the main had are Navier let's add a class
for dads too.
And here all first of all he has a height of 100 percent because this is a child element of the main
header and therefore it should take all its height and this will all be display.
Flex now and we can center items vertically with a line items centered.
With this device save that and reload this page.
Now it is centered.
Now let's add some padding to our main header.
For this let's go here add a padding top and bottom.
I don't need padding but left and right maybe 1.5 RLM something like this.
On mobile phone also still ok I'd say.
Let's all change the global fund Bytheway.
So in the body.
All set.
Fun family to send Sarath for now.
Looks a bit nicer than the surf font I think.
And now I want to have some spacing between my navigation items for sale.
Let's actually go to the main header item and let's add a margin to the left and right of one REM like
that.
And for now this will do.
Now little Huberty fact for the links maybe.
So let's all go your main had or item habere and Main had or I'd active and that's all the define a
rule which would apply FDA anchor has an active clause attached to it.
And there I want to set the color.
Q Well we have this nice little yellow touchier so we could go into the bluish direction here.
Maybe like this purplish color.
Let's let's see how that looks like.
Not too shabby.
So let's go with that.
And now since we have that act of class rule here on shop H L where disliked is active we can actually
add the act of class here and you will learn how to set that dynamically later and of course too of
course.
So now does is active now for the main section.
It's all a style this.
Here I will define a general rule for main that I want to have a padding of let's say one in all directions
and now this is to stop when I go with.
Now let's also of course work on the admin adds product styling here and we can simply copy the entire
style object from the shop.
H tim l fall in the ad product h HTML file and this will already get us pretty far.
Now one thing we should change in ad product we should of course add all these classes so we can basically
copy that header.
And later we will also learn how to reuse it across files.
By the way let's copy that header.
By the way that auto formatting I'm doing occasionally can be set up in the preferences by going to
the keyboard shortcuts and searching for format document desists a shortcut I am using here but that's
just a side note.
So here we now all have to change the act of class.
It's not on the shop link here but of course it should go onto the add product link and with that if
I now reload this page looks way better.
Now let's work on the form here too.
And for this I want I go to my form give it a class of product form maybe the name is up to you.
Add a little div with which to give a class of form control and indebt div.
All insert does import here and also add a label for the title get the title as a label on it give that
input DVD titles so that it matches the label for accessibility reasons simply.
And now let's stall this to four days.
All use my form control.
So does KLOS I added to to just rounding Dith and here I want to make sure that a label as well as input
which is nested in a form control use as a display of type block so that it takes the full away level
with.
And also want to style the input then.
So the input here should have a border of one pixel Sallet.
And then I will reuse stat yellow color we used for the header the font should be inherit that so that
it uses a default font family and so on.
And I'll give it a little border radius of like two pixels maybe let's see how that looks like or border
radius if I now reload this doesn't look too bad.
Let's now also work on the button for this.
I will set up a generic button style here for now.
Inherits debt default font.
Give it a border of one pixel Sallet and it is light gray.
A background of white maybe.
Maybe give it a blackboard or he or simply and a border radius of free pixels.
Now let's see how that looks like.
It's OK but let's reuse the yellow color here actually.
And let's also get the text that yellow color.
Additionally I want to make sure that we assign the pointer a Kirsner to get this hand cursor when hovering
over it.
And last but not least I want to have some spacing but we my form control div and the button.
So on the form control itself I'll add some margin to top and bottom off.
Let's say one REM and Cyril left and right.
So it looks like that.
And I think for the button maybe you to go with the purple colors instead.
Should be easier to read.
And let's all assign a hover and active state for that button.
And when it is active I just want to set the background color to purple and the text color to white.
Then
now it looks like this.
And this doesn't look too shabby.
We can go with that I guess we can always work on this and we will continue to work on this for the
course.
But for now this is good.
Let's now centered the entire forum.
And for Dad I assigned the product form class to to form.
So here I want to give it as a width of let's say 30 REM a max width of 100 percent or Also 90 percent
in case we're on the mobile.
You give it a margin of auto does will automate center it horizontally.
And now just make sure that the input and so on take the available space.
Let's reduce this 20 actually I think Ferdie's a bit too much.
And on the form control for Laili an input.
I'll give it a width of 100 percent.
And now this looks much better.
Now I'm not happy with the white text here now to think about it.
So let's actually go to the header and change to white link text to Bleck Let's see how that looks like
yeah I think I prefer that.
So let's actually take that and also add it to shop h tim L. so that we have the black color there too.
And I think the purple could be a little bit darker.
So let's now also go to the hovering and active stall here.
And make this a darker purple and replaced the purple in all occurrences with that color style.
I'm using a multi-select feature.
The idea here to do that quickly.
And of course also search and replace to do that reload.
Yeah I think that is a bit better now.
You can always tweet this to your needs.
It's not a C is s course here.
I just want to have some basic styling that we can use.
So this is the style with which we'll go from now on and which will of course continue to tweak.
Now one thing we should also do now let's copy that style from the shop age him alcohol and put it into
the 4 or 4 edge to melt fall here.
Because there I also want to take the header and copy that into there because I don't just want to have
the page not found thing.
I also want to show the header so that now if I do enter some route which does not exist like this we
also got the head or dare.
And we can at least leave that route though we can't because I obviously got an error.
Indeed you are l.
That should be adman's flash at product.
Let's fix that everywhere here including our form of course.
Like Dat.
And now if I reload we can navigate around just fine here and try adding a book that seems to work.
And with that we get the styling in there we get the basic h tim l Mark up.
But of course regarding the styling the issue is staed it's all in our html files would be nice to have
some external falls for that wouldn't it.