In the last lectures I edit some styles and please just take these free html files which you find attached
to this lecture and replace your existing views with them because it don't just didn't just add some
styling.
I also added some see as classes.
Now the page will look something like this.
You can tweak the styles if this is not your style obviously discourse is about the logic the Nocera
logic.
And we will continue working on this project DHC.
And to Stahl.
One issue we have though is right now all the styles are defined in the html files and I went to use
external CMS as follows.
Now the problem is right now we can't easily import them.
But let's see how we at least theoretically would want to do that.
Now typically you would have some C S S falls somewhere and would point at them.
When your app gets served now you can create a new subfolder and you can name it whatever you want but
the convention is to call it public because you want to indicate that this is a folder that holds content
which are always exposed to the public crowd or which is always exposed to the public.
So where you don't need any permissions to access it and that's important.
All your files here are not accessible by your users.
If you ever tried to enter localhost and then something like views shop HVM and that will not work because
this is simply accepted by express and it tries to find a route that matches this.
It tries to find it here in Aperture.
Yes basically.
And also of course in shopper all it's is on it doesn't find that route and therefore it doesn't give
you access you can't access to files system here.
And that is of course good and what you want.
But now I actually want to make an exception.
I want to get some requests.
Can I just access to follow a system because ultimately let's say in shop h t m l I want to have something
like a link in here where I simply point at something like C-s as main dots CSSA anything like that.
And my imagination would be that in public I have a C S S folder with the main don't see us as file
in there and that is the file I want to serve with this link.
Now right now this wouldn't work.
But let's take that code already.
That's style code coded out of shop h tim L and move it in there because that pretty much is the main
stalling we use in all our pages.
The header and body.
Let's remove the style text here.
And obviously if I now save and reload my main page all the styling is gone now because it can find
remains as far as you can see here in the developer tools because we can't access the file system.
Now you could say yet Apapa is incorrect right.
It's public.
C S S but even if I change it to does POV you will see that if I reload this fall it will never work.
And now it does look in the public folder for this we need a feature.
Express chase offers us we need to be able to surf files statically and steadily simply means not handled
by the Express router or above middleware but instead directly forwarded to the file system.
And for this we were just for a new middleware with app use.
And this this one express class ships with.
Therefore we use the express object itself.
So does optical re-importing there and this does have a static method and this is a built in Middleware
as you can read on the right.
It serves static files so we can execute this function.
And now we just have to pass in a payoff to the folder which we want to serve statically.
So basically a folder what you want to grant read access to.
It's only read access but that's still more than what we normally have.
And here again we can construct this POV with lbf join and then simply our Durr name.
So our root folder and then public because I want to grant access to the public folder in our current
folder here.
So in the Durr name so in the root folder with this user should be able to access to public Poth And
now if I save this and a reload shop h l. still doesn't work.
The reason for that is that the payoff with public at the beginning here is wrong.
Instead here we should omit this and directly act as if we are in the public folder already.
Because this is basically what Express will do here.
It will take any request that tries to find some file and that's important.
It looks at the extension.
So anything that tries to find a dot CSX or dot javascript files if we have such a request it automatically
forwards it to the public folder and therefore then the remaining pop has to be everything but that
public.
So therefore we stripped the public out of this puff and just act as if we already are in the public
folder because this is where file requests will be forwarded to.
So now I have a reload here.
This looks much better.
Right now we find dead main CSSA file because now this pov can be resolved because we request a file
here and if I omitted CSSA it therefore will fail.
But if I add it again does this handled by the stedding middleware and forewards the request to the
public folder.
By the way you could register multiple static folders and it will funneled a request through all of
them until it has a first hit for The File.
It's looking for.
But here I'll just go with the public folder.
Now with that we can of course take that link and also added an ad product in our head section.
Now there we just have to watch out in the style text I got more than what I is set up in Maine s so
will also add product dossiers as fall and moved the extra styling code which begins here with product
form will move all that into product C as s and the other part in the style takes here can now simply
be removed and therefore I now also have to add import here to see us as product Dotsie as S..
And in the 4 or 4 page of course all that want to import.
My main see is as code and there I got no extra code so we can remove the stalled hex and simply import
the link here.
Now with that if we save that and we reload this page it works.
Add Productus looking good.
Let's add a book here.
Looking good.
And let's was it a route that does not exist.
All is looking good.
Regarding the styling at least so does this now how we can store thoughts statically.
And you're not just limited to C S S and javascript files.
You can also serve images and so on.
So this is the last important piece for now.
How you can serve content statically in the next modules will then dive deeper into actually doing something
with that user data.
We can submit there and we'll dive into and very interesting concept.
The concept of templates because Dad will allow us to turn our static HVM code.
So basically the code which is hard coded which doesn't have any dynamic element into more dynamic elements
where we can inject data we have in our javascript code in the HVM all templates.
We return to the user.
Pretty interesting we'll dive into all of that in the next modules.