We had a very detailed look at how you can use sequel based databases like my sequel to story or application
data and most importantly for us as note developers how you can interact with your mysql database from
inside.
Note Jaz.
Now sequel based databases are popular are great and are used a lot but there is a number of very popular
alternative which is used heavily and that is no sequel or no sequel based databases especially Mongo
D-B.
And then this module will have a look at more.
Would it be what it is and how you can start up Monga to be database.
And most importantly of course how you can use it from inside your node code.
So specifically I'll give you a short introduction to what moment it is and why we would use it.
What the difference to sequel is.
I also had a brief discussion about this earlier in the sequel module.
And then most importantly we'll see how we used the so-called moment to be driver.
Basically a package we install to interact with Mangu to be from inside our no js applications.
So let's do Maunganui B and Z why it's awesome and why we could use it and how we use it.