So what is Mongo DVH.
No let me first of all tell you that I do actually have a complete course for developers on Long Beach.
So you might want to check that out if you want to learn way more about money to be than I'll be able
to cover in discourse.
But now with that let me start with a brief introduction to Mangu to be at least what is it Mangieri
be is both the name of the company which developed Mangu to be but also a den of their most famous product
a database solution a database engine you could say a tool you can use to run very efficient no sequel
databases.
The name stems from the word humongous because Mangini was built for one major purpose that you could
store and work.
And that really is important to work part that you could store and work with lots and lots of data.
So Monga to be is build for large scale applications Monga to be as bult to quickly clear the data store
data interact with data.
So it's really fast and it's really awesome data Bay's philosophy behind those sequel databases and
they'll for all the behind.
Mom would you be.
Now how does it work.
Well just like in the sequel world we spin up the beast server and then we can have multiple databases.
For example a shop database now in such a database in the sequel world we would have multiple tables
in the no sequel hmong of the world.
We have multiple collections like to users and orders collected for example.
Now inside of each collection we don't have so-called records but we have a couple of documents now
documents also look different.
Dad records did and it's not just about different names being used.
The core philosophy behind that database really is a totally different one.
For example Mangieri B is schema less inside of one collection your documents which is your data your
entries so to say don't have to have the same structure in sequel that was totally different.
We had a users table there and in that users table we had an ID and name and email password.
Now here that different.
Here we can have any kind of data in one and the same collection.
Often you will still end up with a at least similar structure but you're not forced to have exactly
the same structure.
And this gives you more flexibility also for your application to grow and to change its data requirements
over time.
Without that being difficult to depict in your database world.
So this is one thing a document in long to be looks like this.
And this looks a lot like javascript object notation.
And to be precise it kind of is to be uses Jason to store data in collections.
So every document you store looks something like this.
It follows the javascript object notation format to be very precise moment to be used a something which
is called Pisan for binary Jason but that only means that Monga to be kind of transforms this behind
the scenes before storing it in the files.
But you don't have to worry about that.
You will basically use it as Jason now such adjacent document is basically the same as a javascript
object you could say and there as you see we can have nested or as Moli to be called STEM and badis
documents for example the address here would hold and embed to document.
And you can also have a race inside of that document and the data array can.
Like in this case hold on for documents of the objects or it could also just hold strings numbers.
Anything of that kind.
So again for data you have great flexibility and the existence of these nested documents also means
dead relations are managed a bit differently in the no sequel Maunganui be world.
So let me come back to that in the next lecture.