Now that you had a brief introduction to what Mongo DB is and what no sequel databases are let's install
more.
Would it be.
Let's set it up and let's use it for our project here now to install longer to be.
You can either do that locally on long would he be dot com you can click on get Mongo D-B download the
installer or the tools when you click on community server here and follow the insulations struction
and this will all work and it will give you a locally running along with the server.
Now I would go for a cloud solution here because it's a more realistic environment.
You would use for a deployment anyways and it's really easy to set up and it's free.
And that will be Atlas Atlas.
So I got here by clicking on get more would be and then choosing Atlus.
Now again this is free.
You don't need a credit card or anything like that.
You just need to sign up and you can spin up your own in the cloud.
Best practice managed long would be server which is a great environment for practicing because this
will follow all the best practices so sign up here.
Now once you did sign up you should end up on a page that looks something like this.
Maybe you need to create in your project first give it any name you want and then you should be on that
page where you can build a new cluster.
You might also end up in dead which are derived from the start.
Now here you are among the cloud clusters so basically among the TBS server and they offer a longer
to be database or multiple data amazes as many as you want running into a server.
You can generally leave all the default settings.
Make sure to do you choose a region where a free tier is available behind the scenes moment it uses
one of these cloud providers but you don't need to be signed up with them or anything like that.
So you can choose anything you want here then you choose to cluster tier there you should use the free
one zero where it says free.
And then this will not cost you anything under additional settings you can will lethal defaults.
You can change to any ways in the frontier but that's fine.
You can change a class name if you want to then you can click Create cluster and this will now create
a new cluster.
We'll take a couple of minutes which you then can connect to later and what you Denn can use as your
Bakken.
Now one important note you might see that I have some cost here in this account and this is not coming
from the set up.
I'm showing you here.
I was simply using this for some of the set up in the past which did cost something.
This does not cost you anything.
Now Watts's getting set up you can already click on secure to year and there you will probably not have
as many users as I do.
No make sure you add at least one new user and I already did this which.
And that's important which has read and write access to any database.
You can turn it into an atlas admin but more realistic this year because this will later be the role
which are no japes application assumes which should be able to read and write our databases but not
to administrate them because we'll not do database administration Frue no chance Dad would be something
our database admin does.
And then for not our app.
So make sure you create such a user.
You can also sign your own password or order generate a secure one.
Make sure you do save that because you'll need it later.
And then also make sure you have a look at IP wirelessed.
There you see all the IP addresses that are allowed to connect to your mom would to be server.
Now I already got a bunch here that will probably be last for you.
Now one thing you should do here is you should add a new IP address as your current IP address.
Since the note runs locally on your machine your node app will have this IP address later when you deployed
a node.
This should of course use the IP address of your server where you deploy it to.
But here you can use your local one so that you can connect and your node app can connect to the server.
That's of course a good security feature because this makes sure that no on offer ised access can tap
into your database so your database is now locked down both from our IP perspective but also from a
user perspective.
And now we can wait for it to set up to finish and I'll be back once it did finish.
Now to set up this complete and now we can connect to our mom would it be server from inside our node
app ad for this we can click on Connect here and choose a connection method which in our case will be
an application.
Now here we can check I'm using describer and we get this you r l which will need it.
But first of all we need to install them on to be driver in our case for no chase.
You can click on an example down there but I will simply show it to you in our project.