So at the moment be server up and running.
Let's add the moment to be driver which simply is a package we can use to connect to long would be for
Sequel or MiSeq will we use my sequel to and also the sequel is now in my case here or with mom would
it be we'd run and install dash dash save and then it's just Mongo DB And this installs the official
Monody driver which we can use to connect to mom.
Would you be now with that installed.
We can start using it and we can start using it in the first file that gets executed when we bring up
our server which would be the app last fall of course.
There we basically already do some database set up with sequel eyes and we can get rid of all of that.
We did create a different user here but we did this in the mystical world.
So we'll start from scratch.
Basically we can't get rid of all the associations and so on we set up here.
So let's get rid of that.
Therefore we don't need these imports anymore.
Let's get rid of all of them including sequel lies from the utl database folder.
And with that all removed.
Also here where I've used my user model to find a user by ID I'll at least comment this out for now.
So did we really have a lean app just fall.
And now I'll go to my utl folder and their database folder and I still want to connect to a database
here but that will no longer be sequel lies of course.
So let me clear all of that here too.
And let's now set up some code that will connect us to Mongo D-B and I'll forget all first of all implored
Maunganui be here.
So all said Monga to be equal to requiring Mongo D-B does gives us access to the Maunganui package in
there we can extract Mongo client constructor by simply accessing long would you be.
The thing we're importing.
And then Mongo client with a capital M and C.
The constant here can be named whatever you want of course.
So now with that we can use of client to connect to our among the DBI database.
When we do connect by running long with the client Mongo client connect like this.
So does all we need to do to create a connection to mung would be.
Now connect here simply takes you are l to connect and that U R L is exactly dead.
You are alue having to connect motile here on the Mong would be Atlas closter page so you can copy that
and paste it into here.
Now one important thing you need to make sure you are using the right user and in my case that should
be Maximillian the user you created and your mom would be cluster under security users and the fitting
password for this user so I'll quickly insert my password here too.
With that we got all set up that we need to establish such a connection.
Now the connect method here actually returns a promise which ever Fail-Safe or frozen error if the connection
fails.
And in such a case here I of course wanted to output my error here so that we can diagnose it or we
have a successful connection.
So here I can say console log could that end with that file which when we executed would connect to
Mongo D-B.
Now of course you want to execute this together with app genius.
So here we are we bring up our server.
Or actually we're not doing this right now but where we will soon do this again here.
I also want to connect to my database so to do that.
How can we achieve this.
Well what we can do here is we can wrap our connection code here into a method and I'll simply create
a method by using cons your No-Name at Mongo connect this will be an arrow function and inside of that
Erol function here.
I will then execute my Mongul client connect code like this.
I also expect to get a callback here and I will call that call back and pass the salt into it here instead
of my then block.
Once we did connect to your customer Risaldar can already tell you this will be the client.
So basically a client object which gives us access to the database and then here all I need to do is
I need to export Mongo connect dysfunction here.
Now with that export it we can go back to Abdias and import that here.
So you're also name that Mongo connect but that name is totally up to you and all import from the uto
folder and their database file there.
I will import my Mangu connect concent which will be a function because I'm exporting a function here.
So an amp j is at the bottom.
I will execute Mongo connect.
And remember here we have to pass a callback so function that will get executed once we connect it.
And here I will get access to the client object.
So any here I will run app lists and bring up my notes server because I want to do that once I know
that I connected to the database and I will also console log.
My clients are sort of you can have a look into that with all of that.
Let's run them to start and bring up our server.
And the problem I now have is simply dead.
When I bring up my server we do actually register all our Routier and in the Rollin's files we dive
into our controllers and in our controllers we are using that sequel's object which simply does not
exist anymore because we're importing the models here and in our models we require a sequel eyes.
And well that simply does all not work as before anymore.
So in order to make this work for now to simply see how we connect I will comment out my routes here
and they are also coming out down there.
So now we got no working routes for the moment but this means that we can now at least connect and indeed
with the automatic restart.
This does not look like an error.
Instead we see connected here and then we see this Mongo client object which we got we have some details
about the connection and this isn't the end the object which we'll be able to interact with to work
with.
Q Well creates data in our database for example.
So now we are connected but of course our setup is broken now because it still relies on sequel sequels
which we're not using anymore.
We're not even using sequel anymore.
So let's now implement Hmong would be in our app step by step.
And once we do this you will learn how to insert data find data and so on.