Be connected to Mongo D.B and this is nice but it also means that we can't do anything else right now.
The rest of the app is not working anymore.
And of course it should work.
So let's get there step by step and let's start by resetting the admin routes.
So let's ask this middleware again and for this I also need to import admen routes again.
And if we now have a look into our admen controller here we do of course use the product model and the
product model.
We have a look into that does rely on sequel lies of course because we define the product model with
the help of equalize.
Now that is all something which we won't do anymore.
Instead we now want to use Mongo DVH.
So to get there I will remove these two imports up there and instead And here I want to create a new
class again because I'll create my own model again.
And this is something we did before already in the pure My siecle module saw create a product class
here like this.
And of course I will also export this submodule exports will still be my class here.
Now in that class I'll have a constructor and in that constructor here I want to store the title price
image Eurail and description of the product when it gets created.
So here I will simply get the title the price description and image you are l and that in the constructor
I'll say this title equals title this prize equals prize this description equals description well and
so on.
You know the game.
So your image your L equals image your l.
Now we can create a new product in javascript and you will object which follows this forum.
And now to save it in the database I will also add a Save method here.
So a function which can be executed on this class and then here I now want to connect to Mongar D.B
and save my product.
Now to do that to be able to connect.
I'll need to import Mongo D-B or Mongar connect.
So import Mongo connect from my utility folder and then from the database file.
So I will simply import that method.
The function I created here where you pass a callback to where we do connect to more would he be inside.
And then we basically execute the call bag and return the connect to the client so that we can interact
with it.
However if we do this we would have to connect to Muang would be for every operation we do.
And we would not even disconnect or after.
So this is not really a good way of connecting to Hmong would he be since we will want to connect and
interact with it from different places now wrap.
So it would be better if we could manage one connection in our database and then simply return access
to the client which we set up once from there or to a different place in our app that need access and
to do that all Kune my set up here a bit let's unit together in the next lecture.