So I still want to have a function which I can call to connect and therefore this function still is
looking good to me in general.
One thing I want to do is I'll add a fro error here today all of the error again when we fail here.
But besides that I'm happy with having bought Mongo connect here but I'll change something I'll not
return to client in my callback here.
Instead I'll add a variable underscore D-B the underscore is only here to signal that this will only
be used internally in this file.
But you don't have to name it like this.
You could also have normally just the DBI.
And initially this will be undefined.
Now here in the van block I will store a value in there.
I will store access to the database here and if I leave it like this what we will do is we will connect
to the test database by default because that is what we specify here in our connection string so will
connect to shop here and then this will give us access to the shop database to which we automatically
connect and you could also enter the database name here.
To override this and connect to a different database then you were connected to initially but I'll not
enter anything and just connect to that database as a side note.
Unlike in sequel we never need to create that database or add the tables to collections in there ahead
of time it will be created on the fly when we first access it which is again fitting that flexibility
the long way to be gives us in sequel we had to prepare everything in advance at least when not using
sequel eyes which also had to do that but it did it for us here.
We don't need to do anything we're just telling Mom would he be hey connect me to the shop database.
And if that database doesn't exist yet more would he be able to create it as soon as we start writing
data to it.
So that's just a little side note here.
I do store a connection to my database in the DB variable and with that store it now in my callback.
I don't need to return it but I will add another function to your own name that gets D-B and here I
will simply check if DBI is set so if it's not undefined and in this case I'll return DB So it will
return access to my database.
Otherwise all essentially not do anything here.
So I'll return on the find.
We could all have fro and error.
No database.
Found something like this.
Now here I also want to export that's all not just export Mongo connect but instead I'll just use a
different syntax you learn about exports.
Connect equals Mongo connect and I'll also have exports get D-B which equals get D.B like this.
So now I'm exporting two methods one for connecting and then storing the connection to the database
and therefore this will keep on running and I have one method where I return access to that connect
the database if it exists and mon would be behind the scenes.
We'll even managed this very elegantly with something called connection pooling where would he be will
make sure it provides sufficient connections for multiple simultaneous interactions with the database.
So this is really a good pattern we should follow.
Now with that changed we still can't connect.
One thing I need to adjust though is in the aperture as file where I do connect.
I'll not get declined anymore because we don't return it in the callback anymore.
So now we just know we are connected.
But there is nothing else we can do.
But one thing I won't be able to do is in product JS where I create my product model there.
I don't just can't connect the connection now but I can import get D-B and that of course is very useful
because that means I had to import this by access and get to be here because this means that I now can
call this function to get access to my database and therefore I can use it to well interact with the
database.
Now let's use that database connection starting in the next lecture.