So now we're importing something which allows to get access to the database connection.
We set up initially when starting our server which now is a concept that we can reuse.
So in a safe method of the product model I can now get access to my database by calling get D-B remember
get deadbeat does simply return that database instance we connect to.
So now we have a connection which allows us to interact with the database and then here in Long would
be you can call collection to tell to be into which collection you want to or something or with which
collection you want to work.
Because remember what would it be you have databases collections and documents.
We have a database connection.
So the next level is a collection.
So here we can connect to any collection and just as with the database if it doesn't exist yet it will
be created the first time in their data.
So you're all connect to a product's collection.
Now on that collection we can execute a couple of Monga DBI commands or operations.
Now a full list can be found in the official box.
And of course you'll learn all about them and all the details in my full long would be Course which
I mentioned in your official docs you can click on Mangu to be server.
And here for example click on Monga to be crowd operations to learn how to Izard find that is what Korea's
updates and deletes documents and you'll see all the examples here and all the commands and how to configure
them and so on.
So this is a great place for you to dive deeper.
Besides the record I mentioned.
But of course Here's a short introduction too if you want to insert data.
You can do this with insert one or if it's multiple documents at once.
Many injured many then takes an array of javascript object you want to insert insert one which I'll
do here because I want to hazard one product only takes the object you want to insert.
Now what do you mean with object.
Well you would simply pass an object where you have lakes for example the name a book prize.
Wells 99 and so on.
So this is something which would be valid code that would insert such a document into the database.
By the way does this not Jason does this javascript object but it will be converted by Muang would you
be.
However here in our case essentially it's the product which you want to insert right.
So we could just say this and see how that works.
If we try to insert this into our database now it is all we need to do right now.
Insert one then returns us a promise.
So we have then then catch and we can log any error we found or we can have a look at the result we
get back so we can look Kohn's a lot the result with that out of the way let me remove the sexualize
model and export our CLOs with the Save method.
And now with debt we fixed the model fall.
Let's now go to the aberant chase fall and here obviously we got a couple of methods or a couple of
functions which still use parts of the model that won't work anymore like this one here request user
create product for adding a new product.
This will not work anymore.
For now we'll have to create a product without storing something about the user.
We'll reintroduce this later again.
So for now we can override this year though.
And I also want to comment out my methods because these will not work anymore.
So let's Calment them out.
Will comment them back in later once it works and they offer in the admin Rollin's here routes.
Edmond Yes there I also want to disable all routes that will not work anymore.
So essentially that's all.
But this post route.
So you're for getting all products.
This will not work any more and all these routes down there will not work anymore.
But these two routes should still work.
For ad product.
So now with that I need to fix one more thing in the last Fall here I need to import Daut Mongo connect
here from my database utility file.
And with that now we're not only connected but we should all be able to insert a new product already
so let's try this out wizard localhost free 0 0 0 0 and slash at product and this won't load because
an app chance when I commented out the code here and app you is well I should at least call next hour
why is every incoming request will die here.
So with that changed now if you reload we are back to our admin at product page.
Now let's simply check this and see if it works by adding a product.
Now I get an error here regarding 3:08 product and that of course makes sense because in the Edmon chase
file I didn't change any code.
So let's work on that code.
Next.
Let's make sure that we can add a product.