So let's make product work again.
And for this will not use the user anymore.
But instead here before we use it then we'll Rieu is that.
So no need to delete it before we do that.
We'll use our product model solitaria a new product constant by initialising product again and here
I will simply pass title price description and image you or else so we'll pass all that data into the
constructor of the product.
Then on this product I can call save and then here to call then I'll go into my model again and I will
return this year.
So we'll return my collection and then this entire command chain because Dad will allow me to will treat
his overall as a promise and change then their offer.
And then there were also redirect.
So now with that if I save debt and I go back to the form and resubmit that I'm actually redirected
to a page which is not found because I commented out all the shop pages.
But if we go back to our service side console we see something interesting.
We see that this here has to be the output of this console log line and the product model where I print
the result of the insert operation and there we see a lot of data about that operation.
And for us important if we scroll down to the bottom we see one document was inserted.
It received an ID and such an ID is managed automatically by Hmong would it be because every document
needs to have such a underscore ID.
This is a must have and long would you be created on the fly automatically if the object you entered
does not have it.
So we'll use that to generate that ID.
And then you see the data which we entered all that was stored.
So we can't look into database yet because we're not fetching anything.
We see that are injured one operation was successful and did successfully add a product into the collection
which is of course amazing.