Now in the last lecture we did insert a product into our monkey database which is awesome.
Now I also want to see it and before we actually fetched it in our node application let me show you
another tool called Compaq's.
If you click on get long would you be on Mongo to be dot com.
You can choose that and you can download and install it for free as well.
It's a way for Windows Mac OS and Linux.
And once you get that installed you can start your Kompas application on your machine.
And this essentially is a tool that gives you a graphical user interface to connect to your database
and to interact with it.
So let's wait for it starting up here and once it did start up you can connect to it now to connect
to it.
Let's go back to our mulga to be cluster and click connect here and then click connect with mom would
it be Atlas choose your operating system and then copied that you are down there.
Now one cool thing is if you now quickly close campaigns again and you restarted offer you copied that
you are l.
It should tell you that it detected a connection string.
And if you click yes it will insert the most important pieces here for you.
Now you still need to choose how you want to connect to make sure your username is correct and also
entered the password for this user.
You need to do this manually all the defaults can be left as they are and you should be able to now
connect to your database.
And here is this interesting enough you are to be precise are now connected to the database server.
And here you see a couple of databases two default ones which you don't need to touch and which you
shouldn't touch.
But then also your own one shop and the shop database here actually has a product collection as you
can see if you look into that product's collection in there.
We can see the documents that are stored in there.
And here is one document we inserted.
So it is one product we added in the last lecture.
Now you can also insert documents and edit them inside of campus and check out the official comp docs
to learn all about the features you can use here.
I just want to use this as a nice visual support so that we can see our data before we fetch it in our
no doubt.
That being said obviously the data is not that useful to us here.
So let's go back to no chats and write some code so that we can use the product data on our shop pages
again which we commented out at the moment.