So let's work on our shop pages now and let's make sure we can use our data there for this.
Let me go to my product model again and here the sides be able to save data.
Of course all they want to be able to get my products so I'll add a static method again and I'll name
that fetch all.
Now here I want to interact with MY MOM WOULD IT BE database to fetch all products for this I will again
return and then use D-B collection to tell me where to be to which collection to connect to and are
a collection.
I want to connect to is products of course.
And then their moment to be has a method for finding data which is called Find.
Now find could be configured to also use a filter.
For example we could find all products that have a type of a book and there are more elaborate filters
than just the quality filters available too.
Again something I cover in great detail in MY MOM WOULD BE course if you want to learn more about that
here.
Of course want to find all products for now.
So want to find all products which you can do by just calling find like this note important thing about
find is find does not immediately return a promise though.
Instead it returns a so-called cursor.
A cursor is an object provided by Hmong would it be.
Which allows us to go through our elements our documents step by step because theoretically and a collection
find could of course return millions of documents and you don't want to transfer them over to wire all
at once.
So instead find gives you a handle which you can use to tell the only to be OK.
Give me the next document OK give me the next document and so on.
That being said there is a two array method you can execute to tell me long would it be to get all documents
and turn them into a javascript array.
But you should only use that if you know that we're talking about let's say a couple of dozens maybe
one hundred documents.
Otherwise it's better to implement page nation which is something we will implement at a later point
of time in this course.
So for now let's use two aere and then does returns a promise.
And here we can again catch any errors we might be getting.
But most importantly here we should have our products we can log our products here and then also let's
return our products in here and let's see if that works the way we want.
So now we have a fecche all method that hopefully works.
One important thing is I of course need to get access to my database by calling get D-B in fecche all
just as they do it and save.
And now let's head over to our shop controller and there we have the get products function.
Now this is the function I want to work on now.
And instead of find all let's now use fetchmail because that is how I named the method there I should
get my products and hopefully get them in a format that works.
Let's see.
Let me also go to my shop route's now and here get index and get products.
Be Fine.
Let me comment out all other routes for the moment because we can't work with them right now because
we have no code that would support them by the way in the shop controller you also want to make sure
that get index works but also using fetchmail in there.
So just as we did it and get products we want to do the same and get index.
OK.
So now I got some code in place.
Let me go back to J.S. finally and comment in that Schopper import and not just comment it in of course
but also uncomment this middleware down there and now we hopefully have a set up where we can actually
reload our route route.
Let's say these are just local host 3000.
And here we go.
Here is our product just like that.
And of course it works automatically because it didn't change any property names.
If you suddenly store to Thailand a field named name you would have to adjust your view and so on.
Well there is something where I want to adjust my view and deaths related to how we work with the IDs
but we'll see it in the next lecture.