So we're able to fetch all the products.
Let's now implement the code to fetch a single product and for that I'm back in the shop.
J.S. controller file and here it is to get product functional I want to work on here we get the product
ideas part of T U R L and then we want to use our product model to somehow find the fitting product
and therefore we of course need to work on the model again and feel free to implement this on your own
if you got some long would you be knowledge.
It's a great challenge.
Amber wise of course we'll just do this together.
So how would I fetch a single product.
Well besides having my static fetch all method I'll add another static method fine by ID and you can
name this however you want of course here I expect to get product ID as an argument and then just as
before all call gets D-B to get access to that database connection we have.
And I then want to return to a result of an operation where I use my collection and there I will now
pass products again because it's still the same collection I want to interact with.
And I will find a product here but I'll find only one product.
And to do that all narrow down the result set with find and then I'll pass a javascript object to it
which allows me to configure a filter here I want to look for a product where underscore ID is equal
to prod ID because that's the idea of the product I'm looking for.
So with this I'm returning theoretically all products which have this idea but I know it'll only be
one so I can use find like this and I'll only get back one product or do I will actually find will still
give me a cursor because more would it be doesn't know that I will only get one.
And here we can use.
Next the next function to get the next.
And in this case here also the last document that was returned by find here.
So here I can then add then and catch.
And as always log any error I might have.
And then then where I will have my one product there I will log into the console for one and then I
will return my product.
So now this should hopefully yield my product here.
Now with that we go back to the shop controller with find my ID.
I either have an error or I get my product and I try to render the product detail page.
Now let's go to the routes and there to the shop js file and we need to comment in that route here for
getting the product details we now save everything.
Let's click on details here
and one thing you can see is that this doesn't seem to work right.
We always get redirected to slash products page.
So if I go back to the starting page and we can tell the difference by the distance between the dollar
sign and the character on the starting page the click details I just get forwarded to products.
Now why stat now does actually happens because no product ID is passed when it click details and therefore
we end up in this route.
Now why is no product passed.
We have a look at our view and there at all are it next Ejaz fall in the shop folder in there.
We got our details button and I do actually get the product idea here.
But what is the error here well I Axxess product thought Id.
But with Mongo be it's underscore ID.
So I should use Pracht underscore ID and the same of course on the product list page there.
I should also use product underscore ID.
So all the places of the app where we use product ID we should now use product underscore ID with that
if we reload that page here to starting page or products page doesn't matter.
For now click details.
Now something else happens.
Now we get stuck here because we have an error but that is better than before because now at least we
do have an ID which we try to find.
So what's the issue here now.
Why do I get cannot read Property tyle of NULL.
Well for one it's worth noting that NULL is printed here as well and that NULL should be stemming from
my product model from fine by ID when I can unlock the product.
So it looks like we didn't find any product for that ID.
What could be the reason for dad now.
The reason for that is that the ID long would it be is actually stored a bit differently and we can
see doesn't compress the idea is actually sucha object id thing.
Now I did mention that moment he'd be storing data in Beast on format and this binary format of Jason
is not just used because it's a bit faster to work with.
It is but also because multi B can store some special types of data in there an object id is such a
type.
It's a type added by Mongo D-B its not a default javascript type actually doesn't exist in javascript
at all and its simply an ID object which Monga to be uses because this generates and manages IDs which
look random but actually aren't.
So IDs for example are created in a way that if you create an ID now and then a D-1 second later the
idea one second later will alphabetically be a higher value than the previous one.
But that's just one thing.
So object ID is an object provided by Mangu to be.
And if we look for a quality we can compare underscore ID which in that database will only hold object
id values with a string because a string is not equal to the object id and to string and here does not
count Maunganui B will not comparatives.
It compares the entire object to the entire object ID.
So to fix this we simply go into our product model and in there import long really be by requiring man
would he be from the package.
And now I can use would be to get access to the object id type.
So here when I compare I can use Muang would be dot object ID and I can create a new Does this a constructor
and you object that to which I pass a string which will be wrapped by that.
So now if I saved it and I try reloading that page for that ID.
Now you see this works because now I create such an object that you object and therefore here when I'm
telling mom would it be fine be all documents where are the ID stored in the database is equal to that
one would be will now succeed because we now pass on object id object to the comparison instead of just
a string.
And now this works too.
It's very important to keep in mind that Mangieri be stored as IDs an underscore ID and that it uses
special object type for that.