Time to edit products and Ford s all first of all work on my admen genius fall in the controller's folder.
There we have two routes that are or two functions that are related to editing products to get the added
product page which is responsible for fetching the product that should be edited and for rendering it
and the post edit product page which is responsible for saving these changes to the database.
I'll comment both back in.
And let's start with get at it.
Product there the majority of the code can stay as it is.
But when we then fetch the fitting product we of course do this differently.
We use product find by id and we find the product with Prod. Id like this.
And then we still get back products however.
Well actually we don't get back products anymore.
We get back one product year so no need to store it in a concert like this and extract it from an array.
We get back one product automatically because we wrote that method in such a way and we therefore can
rendered this product.
So this should work.
Now let's quickly have a look at the view that belongs to this controller action.
So it is a product Ejaz file and in there you know what I'm looking for.
We want to make sure we're always using product underscore ID when using the product ID just to make
sure that we extract the right thing from the document we get back from the server.
So now with that we get everything in place to hopefully make this added Button work partly click on
it.
Well almost Let's leave it on this page.
The control should work but in the routs and the Edman shares fall I of course have a comment disk Getaround
back in.
So let's make sure does a stun.
And now that if we now reload that page we indeed see the form with the default values filled back in.
So now this is liberating.
But of course it's not that useful to only see the data.
And we were able to fetch data before the interesting part now would be to update it now to update it.
Let's go back to the product model.
How could we update our product which is stored in the database well.
Let's go to the constructor and let's add a fifth argument here the ID and then I'll say this underscore
ID is equal to the idea I'm getting here.
You could name does underscore ID or two if you want it to.
So now we accept a kind of optional fifth argument.
We're not passing it on the places of tiap.
But here I do at least create the option of passing this to an ID will therefore be undefined and be
auto generated by Mangieri B.
Or we did set it and then when we called SAVE I don't want to insert one.
I want to create a new product instead.
So for this what I'll do is I'll simply check if this underscore ID if that is set and if it is set
we'll update the product.
Otherwise we'll insert it.
So move my Konst function up there.
I always need access to the database in both cases.
And now create a new variable Let d be up for a D-B operation and then the else case where we insert
a document D-B up is equal to my connection to the database and then connecting to collection and then
inserting one and then down there I can use D-B up to follow along and actually return that.
So now I have one case where D-B OP is simply my insert command and then I return my result or D-B OP
is access to my database and to the products collection still.
But then here I use Update 1 and as the name suggests update one will update exactly one element.
There are all this update many where you can update multiple elements at once.
But here I know I only want to update one so I can use up that one.
And now Apptd one takes at least two arguments.
The first one is that we add a filter that defines which element or which document we want to update.
So here again I'll pass a javascript object and we can filter for equality also.
Or run more complex queries which you again can't learn about.
And my mom would be course if you want to add here.
I only want to find a document where the underscore ID is equal to.
And now again I'll create a new Mongomery B object id to which I pass this underscore ID so the ID which
is part of that object here.
So I'm looking for a document where the ID matches the ID I have here in my product I'm currently working
with and for that document we now has a second argument to update one.
We now specify how to update that document.
This again is a javascript object where we described the update and this is now not the new object.
So we don't say this year as you could imagine that we tell long would we be fine with the existing
document and replace it with this update.
One does not replace.
Instead we have to describe the operation and we do this by using a special property name which is understood
by man would it be kind of a reserved name you could say Dollar Sign set.
This again takes an object as a value.
And here we describe the changes we want to make to do exist in a document which we found with this
filter.
And here you could actually say this and you would instruct would be to simply set these key value fields
which you have in your object here to to document it found in the database.
And therefore since these are only key value pairs which exist in the document in the database it will
update the values of the document in the database with your new values.
You could also write dozen or more were BOA's way and explicit say title should be equal to this title
and so on.
But since we want to replace all fields we can't just say this here and now with that we have a database
operation that will update an existing database object.
By the way DD will not be overwritten or anything like that only the fields are.
So with that let's go back to our admin chat controller and and post edit product that is the part I
want to work on in the next lecture to make sure that we actually are able to save our product.