Now one important note about Update video what I did there is I actually passed an object id in admen
chase controller to my product constructor.
Now actually I could also just pass product that has a string and therefore remove my object registration
up there and the Hmong would he be import all of that is happening in the controller.
Now if I do that and I try editing this and changed apprized to 16.
You see now it fails.
Now if we go to the product model and we have a look at the safe method to dare I am actually looking
forward to right write object but I'll have a problem with updating it because there I'll try to set
my object ID to a different object to a string because here I'm just referring to this which will hold
the unmodified object.
So what I should do is I should automatically convert the object id the ID here which is a string to
an object that the object in the constructor.
So now they can remove it down there because I underscore ID will now always be an object id field no
matter if I'm using it in a filter or if I'm using it for updating.
So now if that if I added this again and I changed the price to 18 now it works again.
Because now I'm not trying an invalid update by trying to change the ID to some invalid value.
So this is just an important note I wanted to add.
You don't have to count words the ID in the controller file.
You can leave that untouched but you can do a general conversion in the product choice model of file
which is the better approach of doing that.