So knouted we're able to at faction's update products.
Let's work on the leading them now for deleting you could implement different approaches.
You could add a method to the product class so that you can create a new product object and call delete
on it just as you called Save on it.
But I will go with a static method and I'll add a static method which I'll name delete by id and where
I expect a product ID as an argument.
Now in here of course again we need access to the database.
So let's call get D-B to get access to that one central database connection theory and at the start
and then all the debris again it's time to reach out to the products collection and all that collection.
We want to delete an element.
Now as always you'll find more in the official docs and the crud operations.
If you click on the documents you see that just as we had injured one injured many and so on.
We all have to leave many and delete one now.
I don't want to delete many products but exactly one solid lead to one product here and you need to
specify a filter now.
So again pass an object where you describe how to find that product.
And again will be are boring IOD equal to check here.
Now here product ideas an argument.
So we need to convert it to an object id manually again by passing it to the optical constructor.
And now we will go ahead and delete the first element.
It finds that has this criteria fulfilled.
So I will return here.
And of course just as before we can add then and catch your if you want we can catch any error and console
larget and we can also work with the result of this operation.
We could cons a log at all just console log deleted and that will be it.
So now we have to delete by id Methot.
Now we just need to add it.
So the admin.
Yes control or file here to post delete product outlet's comment it back in.
Or not route.
The action I mean of course we extract the product.
And then here we had a different flow.
I first of all found two products here.
Now we don't do that anymore.
We just call product delete by ID instead we pass Toprol ID as a string and then we just have our then
block here which won't receive an argument.
And yet that is it we redirect thereafter.
So let's go back to our application.
Let's quickly add a new dummy product with totally invalid and uninteresting data and dat fails.
That's an interesting behavior.
Let's fix that in a second.
Let's first of all check if deleting were X I get redirected to a page that is not found yet makes sense
because obviously working in a controller is not enough.
I need to go to my admen routes and comment in that post delete product route.
So after changing dis Let's now click delete and now I get no products here.
Let's confirm in column pass by quickly refreshing that page and our product is gone.
So deleting works.
Let's now see what's going wrong when I tried to add that product.