The leading works but when I try to at product and I'll just enter some dummy data here that fails and
it seems to fail because I would imagine that in safe here we somehow make it into this if block so
that underscore ideas to a problem and that makes sense because I actually do initialize underscore
ID here at the beginning by creating a new Mongo D-B object.
So even if we pass no ID and this therefore is undefined this will create an object and store in an
underscore ID.
So underscore id down there will always be defined.
And if its just such an empty are automatically generated object id object should be the issue here.
So how can I overcome this.
Well for example for turn every expression we can check if ID exists basically.
So if this returns true and if statement and if its the case then I want to create my object id object.
Otherwise all store now and now will be treated as false down there.
So if this tiny change in place with this turn their expression added in a product model we should be
able to add a product real quick with some dummy values.
And now its created.
So now does this working.
And it was just the fact that we were always creating an object that you object which we shouldn't.