Get time to use our user object.
And the question of course is where do I want to use my user object.
Well a one to use the user object when creating a new product.
Right.
When saving a product I want to store a reference to a user here or and that's the entire user data
as you'll learn.
However for products and users you could actually find arguments for both approaches here.
You certainly don't want to enclose all the user data in an embattled document because that would mean
that if the user data changes you need to change that data in all products.
But if you do include something which is unlikely to change very often like to user name for example
well then you could certainly go ahead and and bad debt together with the idea so that you always have
that ID to fetch more data about the user if you need to.
You've got to find by the method and user model after all or that you have at least some snapshot data
like the username available immediately if that should change you need to update it everywhere.
The alternative to this is that you just store the ID.
So just a reference and therefore if you need connect data you always have to fetch it manually from
two collections.
But on the other hand you might not do that too often and therefore here.
Indeed when I fetched a product I don't really need the user data we're not displaying user name anywhere
in our app.
So I actually just want to store the user id so that we know who is connected.
Even though we're not fetching that a lot.
Now what does this mean for our application here though.
Well it means that when creating a new product we can pass the user id where we can accept the user
id here.
So this user ID is equal to user ID we store does as a property of our product now and with that we
have all we need in the product model.
Now we need to make sure that we do pass that user data when creating a product.
So the Edmond J us controller when adding new products here I want to pass now for the Product ID because
we dont have that when creating a new product but for the user id want to pass the ID off to user which
as you know we now store in our request we do this the press fall right.
We have that middleware which we set up in an earlier module where we find that user where I didnt store
that user in our request.
Now it is a bit of a constructed example because I'm storing it just to extract the ID which I hardcoded
here so we could just hard coded into our code anyways.
But the idea here of course is to show you how you can extract the user in one central place and then
reuse it in any other route.
And that's the idea here.
Later once we get an indication we'll manage that user a bit differently.
So for now we just have the user Optik in the request and they offer and the admin chase controller
here I can access request user and then underscore ID which will be just a string here because when
retrieving data the object id is converted to a string for us.
So we have just the string here.
Now with that we should actually store the user ID when creating a new product.
First of all delete that old product and then lets quickly add a new product here.
And I get an error that it cant read Property ID off on the find and should be coming from inside our
Aventuras fall here when I try to access my user underscore ID.
So something seems to be going wrong here.
I'm storing to request user here though.
Let's go to the user model find by Eddie let's add then and catch your and catch any error we might
be getting when fetching that user.
And here are also console lock to user Optik I'm getting right before I return it again.
And with that let me try to relate the admin product at product page and I now get an error.
We did retrieve the user here but then I sent duplicate headers by the look of it.
Yeah because I'm calling next to off to your in apt.
Yes.
Since I added the code again I don't need to call next at the bottom of it.
So let's save debt do not call next to you often.
Let's now reload this page here and now I just fetched a user with the ID which is a string here so
bad is actually valid.
Now let me try adding this again.
And now this works.
So it was dead error with double next.
So now if we have a look at our products here we see that product sold have a user ID which is just
a reference pointing at the user who did create that product which is one way of establishing relations.
The way you already know from my sequel of course this is not a bad document but here the argument simply
is when we're fetching products we don't really need any user information.
Hence we do it just like debt does of course will change once we start storing orders.
There you could say it does make sense to store information about the user.
For example the e-mail at least and for a product you want to store the title and the price maybe.
So there it makes sense to Satterlee aggregates does together.
Speaking of that why don't we work on card items and orders.
Next.