So we run it on products and users.
It's now time to work on the card and the card items again and that will now change.
Now we're using Muang would you be.
So let me start with the card model now what is what's the overall goal we have here.
Well obviously for every user we have we want to store a card right and that user will have a cart and
that card will then hold the products.
So actually with them would you be.
This is a great place for embattled documents because we have a strict one to one relation between a
user and a card and therefore there is no need to manage just with a reference.
I could actually get rid of my card items and my card model so that I just have product and user.
And for now also the orders.
And now on the user model there I also want to store my card items.
Now the question is how.
The answer is we get our shop jast controller and then there we got code to store something in a cart
here for a user we got the card and then we got the products to see what's in there update it and then
save it back.
Now we can't do that without the help of the user model.
Let's say on a user object instead of just having safe I also add a new method add to cart something
like this.
Now here Add to Cart would be a product I want to add to the card of course.
Essentially what we're doing here and shop are already here.
We already fetch or we got everything we need to fetch a product which we could then add to the cart.
So I expect to get a product to your chicken at and then add to cart I can have all the logic I need
to find out if that product is already inside of the cards and therefore if I just want to increase
the quantity or if it is not and therefore I want to added for the first time now to understand how
this works you must not forget dead add to card will be called on a user object and will create that
optic with data we fetched from the database with the help of find by ID here we will return a user.
So therefore we just need to be able to accept more data in a constructor.
For example the cart so we can also store the card in our javascript object here which will be based
on the data stored in the database.
So now we can assume that we'll have a cart property on our user and now we just need to find out if
that card contains a certain product already.
Now the cart will essentially be an object lets say that looks something like this an object with some
items so an object which has the items array in their.
So what we could do with we assume that this is the case could create a new constant card product and
then use this current items and find let's say the index of a product in that card with the same idea
as the product we're trying to add again.
So all has a function to find index which simply is a function javascript will execute for every element
in the items array.
And then here I want to return true if found derived product in my items array and this will be the
case if C.P which is the product in the items array.
If the underscore ID there matches the underscore ID of the product I'm trying to insert if that is
the case.
So if this returns a valid index for something else than minus one which would be the default Oberweis
then I know this product already exists in a cart and then I just need to find out what its quantity
is.
Now we'll do this a second step.
First of all we can assume that there will be no products in the cards because we're just starting from
scratch.
So let's add the code to add a product without checking whether that product exists yet.
So we can call this out for now and it's a constant Maybe named updated cart.
Which is an object where we might have items property which is an array where I will now include my
product.
However not just a product as I'm getting here.
I also want to add a quantity field so I'll actually say product quantity and does this how you can
add a field on the fly and Javascript equals one now and never approach maybe a bit more elegant than
that is that in items you create the object with curly braces because we'll add an object here and then
you use the javascript spread operator free dots to pull out all properties off this object so if the
product object and then with a comma you can add or overwrite a property.
So here I'll add the quantity property instead of 2:01.
Whatever approach you choose this will create an object which holds an item property which is an array
off.
In our case only one object one product with an additional quantity information and now I want to update
the user to store that card in there.
So I will get access to my database with gets D.B and I'll reach out to my users collection and I'll
update one user in there and I'll update the user with this user ID here.
So what I need to do is I need to accept debt ID as an argument.
So this underscore ID will be equal to ID lets say and then here I can say I want to find the user where
underscore ID is equal to new and they all use object ID which I extracted up here because I need dead
for the comparison.
Where does equal to this underscore ID.
And once I found that all describe how to update Knol use dollar signs set where I pass an object which
holds all the information about which field to update in which way.
And here I essentially want to keep everything as it is I dont want to change to user name or anything
like that.
I'll just set cart equal to update that cart that is it.
So card which I expect to have in a user in the database will now receive updated card.
So this object as a new value which will overwrites the old one and this is important.
It will not merges with the old one it will not merged the elements in the items array it will simply
override the old card with the new cart.
It can return this year to update one call and what it should do is well it should update our user to
add a product to the card.
For now it will always overwrite any existing products and a card will fix it later.
But for now this should work.
Now lets wire it up in the next lecture.