So we're making progress on the Add to Cart functionality at least a very basic first version of it.
Let's now go to app just to wire it up when finding a user I'm storing it in the request like this and
does actually should be.
All right.
However it's important to understand that the user as I'm storing it here will just be an object with
the properties.
So the data we have in the database all the methods of our user model will not be in there because the
user I'm getting here is data I'm getting out of the database and the methods aren't stored there.
They couldn't be stored there.
So to have a real user object with which we can interact I should actually create a new user here.
And then simply pass user name which is my user name how it's a stored user email user or a cart and
user underscore ID.
So I should create such a user object and store that in the request because now this enables me to really
work with.
Well all the user data or with the whole user model and this now allows me to also call all these methods
like at Ducard on it.
So if this change to app J.S. we can go to the shop just fall in the Control List folder and then there.
I want to work on the post cart method for now which allows me to add an element to Descartes.
I do get my product that year which is nice.
And then we have all the logic here for fetching what's inside the card and for updating us.
I will actually comment this out because for now we don't need that.
So instead what I want to do is here I want to fetch a product I want to add here.
So I will use my product constructor my product model and it will use find my ID to find a product by
product IDM extract and here I'll just add the then block here and here I should have the product that
I want to add to the cart.
Therefore in here I will now use request user which now is our full user model and call Add to Cart
and past that product they fetched as an argument because in the user model add to cart does expect
a product and then returned the result of update 1 which will be a promise.
So back in the shop chest controller if I returned that promise instead of then here I can simply change
a number of them.
Block where I get the result of in this case my update operation.
So just can so lock that resolved.
Now with that let me go to the shop J.S. routes and let me add that cart post-road I get.
Let's now go back to products and let's give does add to cart but not try and get an error here.
The problem here should be that if we have a look at our debut at our product list last fall that for
add to cart we have to add add to cart E.J. ass snippets that include where I pass my product to but
an add to cart AJ s I still access product thought id is set of underscore ID.
So I need to change this in order to pass on the ID correctly and Ive reloaded that product's page and
I click Add to Cart.
Now we get stuck here but actually we were successful in a way we did actually modify something as our
resolve tells us here and if we quickly go to comp as and have a look at our users you see there is
an embedded document a card document with items with an object which holds product data.
Now that user ID here is a bit redundant because were already are in that user we could strip that out
and only store what you want but all that doesn't matter too much.
The important thing for us here simply is that we now store a whole product which we do also store in
a separate collection as part of an embedded document in our user.
So we clearly have duplicate data here.
We have the same product here as an embedded document and we have it in products.
So does this maybe something which we should change because if we change to product right now if we
change a title or price this will not be reflected in the cart and the cart.
We should have correct data because if the price changes we can show the wrong price in our car.
Right.
So actually will need to tweak this a little bit more in our user model where I store product in Add
to Cart well.
I actually dont want to store all product data in this object.
And then the quantity.
I just want to store the product ID by creating a new object id here and passing product ID as an underscore
ID as an argument and the quantity.
So not only to reference and to quantity and not the rest of the data.
For now safeness and I click Add two cards again.
It gets stuck again.
Doesnt matter too much right now.
If I now update my users
I get an error here that should be Product ID product underscore IDF regatta duty.
So now again if I update this and I click Add to Cart again and I reload my users document here are
my collection.
Now you see I'm only storing the reference and the quantity and this is exactly the information I want.
If I now want to display information about the product I have to fetch that manually because I only
have the ID that on the read is all I need for fetching information.
So that is what it is.
But on the other hand if I now do change my product I don't have to change it in the products collection
and my users because that would be a lot of work for data that might change quite a lot.