Some now able to store some data in the cards at least in a very basic way.
But obviously we don't just want to overwrite the existing card all the time.
We want to be able to store multiple products in there and increase the quantity in case we already
do have a product in there.
So we need to find two in our code a little bit and we already started.
So I'll comment this back in where I do check whenever a certain item already does exist.
Now I just need to tweak Dakota a little bit here.
I need to look for Product ID because that is where I store my product IDs in the items in the cart.
So I'm looking for product that because I'm storing the ID and product id down there.
And now with if that is something else than minus one we know that this product already exists in the
cart so I can add a new quantity field again and set this to one by default.
But if cart product is greater than zero or greater equal than zero.
So if it's anything else but negative basically then this means this product already exists.
So then new quantity is cart product that is actually the index let's maybe name ID card product index.
So this is then actually equal to this card items for that given index we just identified and there
will have a quantity plus one.
So does the new quantity of that item already exists or if it already is part of our ecarte.
If not we'll go with the default of one and therefore here I will always update to new quantity.
However I also don't want to update but always overwriting items with a new array with exactly one object
instead of one to add a new object to did array.
If the product does not exist in there or if it does exist in there I want to update that one product
so how do we do that.
Well one of the simplest ways and you could use other approaches where you leverage some functions Mongolia's
but one of the clearest approaches you can use is that you get the updated card items that you create
such a constant and then you access your card items and you create a new array where you copy in all
the existing elements with the spread operator with the free dots.
So this gives me a new array with all the items that are in the cart and they are now stored here.
And they can now edit dicere without touching the old array due to the way javascript works with reference
and primitive types.
So now I can edit my card items and now I just need to differentiate do we already have that item in
the card or not.
So actually move it up here before my check.
And then here if I make it into this if statement I know that we have this product already in that case
I can access updated card items for the card product index I found.
So now I have access to dead item I'm interested in.
I know that it already existed so I can set its quantity equal to the new quantity like this now else
if the item did not exist before.
I'll take my updated card items and simply add a new one with push.
I'll add a new card item and I'll add a new card item which looks exactly as described down there so
I'll just wrap that code it added here.
So now ever update the quantity of an existing card item or I add a new one and then down there for
updated card I can always set my items equal to the update of the card items because that will always
be in a rate with all the old elements because I copy it first and then with the update edit.
So either with the quantity increased for the existing element or with a new element added to the card.
So then I can safely have my updated card down there and save that to the database with all the updated
items in there.
So if I save that now a first of all add a second product real quick so did we.
So that we have some alternatives here.
And then we'll go to products all at this first one with twelve dollars to the cart.
Now if we update this in campus we look into the cart there.
We see this was added again even though it already existed.
So our logic is not too convincing if I pressed this one more time.
We now see it in their free times I'd imagine.
Yeah.
Free times the same object so clearly our logic fails.
Let's see what's wrong and then found the issue.
It was this comparison up here.
The problem we have here is the product I'm getting here.
Right.
The product getting as an argument is a product I just retrieved from the database.
Now the underscore Id have in there actually is treated as a string in javascript but is not exactly
of type string.
Since I'm using free equal signs in my check here however I am telling javascript that this should only
return true if Deis to do not only match by value but also by type.
And technically this is no string.
Even though we can use it as such.
So one solution is to use two equal signs or to use two string on both.
So here and here to make sure we only work with strings here in both cases.
And with this adjustment made I can edit my objects here by double clicking into some field and then
we can mark the latter two objects you're in the array for deletion by clicking on the cross on the
left click Update thereafter.
Now this is updated we only have one item in there with quantity 1 but now they go back and I click
Add to Cart and I do update doesn't compress.
I should still only have one object but now not quantity 2 if I do add my Abra element here though by
clicking on acha Cartier and I do update now I should have two elements in the cart one with quanta
to one with quantity one click at two cards.
Again an app that does again should still be two objects.
Now both of quanta to and so on.
So now this is working.
Now I am updating the cart.
This is now add to card functionality a basic one implemented on our own.
Now of course we want to be able to also display the card items.