Now well we're able to at product sort of card.
Now with this code let's make sure we can also display them when fetching them when going to the cartes
page here to this page because right now we don't support this page because we still have that route
commented out and we've got no logic to fetch all card items anyways so time to go into the control
us folder into the shop chess file where we do have the gas card route.
Now this request user gets card thing will not work anymore.
So let's make it work.
Let's go back to the user model and in there we have added two cart.
Let's now also call or add a get cart method.
You could name it however you want of course.
The idea here is that we do indeed returned the card items.
So did the controller we have the card items there and we can start outputting them in the end what
we need as you can tell us just the products right.
So we want to have a list of the products with the respective quantities.
Now get card exists on the user who already has this card property.
This system would be way of thinking about relations.
We don't need to reach out to a card collection because there is no such collection instead.
Here we can simply return this card and that's it.
This gives us access to the user card.
Obviously we could have directly access to card property on the user if we wanted to you could add more
logic to transform it or anything like that.
But in the shop chase controller I can now already call get cart and have the cart.
For now on that card.
I can't call get products though but I don't need to because the products are all already included in
the cart or at least their references.
Right.
Because what I'm storing in the user model with at cart is the ID of every product.
This is what we store now and that is exactly something we can change and get cart instead of just turning
this cart.
It would be interesting to return a fully populated cart so cart with all the product details which
we also require and to do this.
We of course have to reach out to the database again.
So let's get access to our database client And let's return to assault of a database operation where
I do reach out to the products collection now because I have all the user data I have all the card data
now I need to fill it with some live from the products database.
And there I want to find all products that are in my cart.
Now how can I do that.
Well for this we can use a special Greason text mong would be supports in find I can tell I can say
I want to find all products where underscore IDs equal to.
And now I don't pass an idea here because I'm not looking for a single ID.
Instead I pass an object because this allows me to use some special Mangieri be Currey operators of
which there are many covered in detail and my mom would be coarse or in the official box of course but
we are looking for the dollar sign in operator and this operator takes an array of IDs and therefore
every ID which is India array will be accepted and will get back a cursor which holds references to
all products with one of the Ids mentioned in desir.
So all we need to do is construct such an array.
So product IDs can be constructed by using this card items.
And remember this is an array of objects that look like this.
So objects that have a product that dnt the quantity.
Now we're only interested in the product idea here.
So I'll simply map this.
Does a default javascript function all map this to transform every item in there and I simply want to
return the product ID.
So what I'm doing is mapping an array of items where every item is a javascript object into an array
of just strings of just the product IDs and this isn't stored in this new product IDs constant does
it.
Then my array which I want to use here to tell long would it be give me all elements where the ID is
one of the Ids mentioned in this array here.
So this gives me a cursor with all the matching products.
Not again use to array to quickly get that converted to a javascript array and then I'll add a then
method.
So in this method I'll have all my product data for the products that were in my cart.
Now of course we want to add the quantity back to every product because that is something that is important
to us.
Now how can we get that information back into there.
Well in this.
Then block all again return a mapped origin of my data so mapped worship of my products array where
every product will be converted.
A little bit of return a new object for every product which is fine because every product is an object
and I'll distribute all the existing properties.
So I want to keep all the data I retrieved but then I'll add a new quantity property and that quantity
property of course needs to be populated with data.
I know where I have on that product.
Now we of course have the products stored in the card of this user.
So what I can do is I can use dys cart and make sure you use aero functions here to ensure this instead
of this function still refers to the overall class with normal functions.
It would not so use this card in here X as my items and simply find the item with that ID at hand here.
So here I'll have my card item again and Abal return true if that item has a product ID to string that
is equal to the product underscore ID to string off the product with just fetch from the database.
So this can look confusing but in the end I have an array of products here fresh from the database.
Then I want to transform this which I'm doing with map map takes a function that executes on every element
and products which describes how to transform this element here.
I'm basically returning the new value which is an object where I still have all the old product properties
but I add a new quantity property and to get to the right quantity for a given product I reach out to
my card.
Items which exist on that user.
And I again use a built in javascript method find to look at all elements in card items with this function
here and then identify the one product where the product ID I'm storing in my card items matches the
ID of the product I have fetched from the database.
And since with map I'm going through all these products this will all very for every run.
Now the last thing is this whole thing here.
The whole Find method.
In the end just gives me the product object.
I want to get the quantitive though.
So now from the card items I have I extract a quantity for the given product.
And now with death code get cart shot return products which are enriched with all the data that is stored
in a product's collection because users in the card will only store the reference.
And this is what we need to do in long would be if we don't have a connection between two collections
with a reference we need to merge them manually as we are doing it here.
And with that merging being done manually here we can now use that data.
So get a card should now return a card with all the information we need.
So on the user we can call get card and then we know we get back some products here so we can delete
that here.
As well as does and then render our view with the products we fetched.
Now on that the you sell the shop card.
The issue here we just need to make sure we output our products correctly because we cycle through them
but now due to the way how we merge.
Every product will itself already have the quantity here and whenever we use that ID we should have
underscore ID as you learned.
Let's see if that works by going to our routes folder and there to shop last fall and let's add that
get Carter route again.
So I'll reload his cart page here and this is looking pretty good.
Now let me add a new product.
Third with some image and some description now does exists not in the cart though unless I add it to
the cart.
Once I do that and I go to the cart we see it there too.
Now the one thing that is still working is that if I do add a card item we're stuck.
Let's fix this in the next lecture.