So everything works but when clicking add to cart it won't be nice if we don't get stuck here.
So something seems to be wrong.
If we look at post-cart.
Well the thing is we never send a response here.
We do add our product to a card but that's it.
Now in the old code we redirect redirected to slash cart and that is what we should do here too.
So instead of returning those were salt which doesn't matter.
No one's interested here.
I just want to call wrests redirect here.
We're not here but here.
And then I guess we can return to us to see the result of that operation here if you wanted to.
But the important part is that we redirect at some point with that.
If Lake add to cart here and redirect it to the current page.
Awesome.
Now let's make sure we can the lead card items.
As always feel free to try this on your own in the next lecture and thereafter we'll do this together.