We're nearing the end let's make sure we can also delete card items.
Now for this first of all get rid of that code I previously had for updating the cart.
We outsourced design to our cart model for now.
And now let's work on the post-cart delete product action here in the shop controller.
I of course want to be able to delete items from the cart and to delete items from the cart.
The user model is again a great place to work on.
I'll add a new method.
Delete item from cart.
The name is up to you and I only need the product ID here to remove the entire product from the card
with that Id passed.
We can create a new constant updated card items and first of all copy all existing card items.
Again with this spread operator however we can even take an easier route and just use discard items
and then the built in filter method.
This is again a method provided by Vanilla javascript filter allows us to define a criterium on how
we want to filter the elements in that array.
So in this case the elements of the items array and then it will return a new array with all the filtered
items so all the items that make it through the filter the filter is a function here which runs on every
item and then we'd return true.
If you want to keep the item in the new array.
Or false.
If you want to get rid of it.
Now I want to keep all items except for the item which we're deleting.
So I will look into each item and discard items are objects off the structure we define up here.
They are objects with a product in a quantity so I'm looking for the product ID now.
Down there looking for the product ID and if that is equal to the Product ID and getting here then I
know this is TLM.
I want to remove all check for the opposite because remember I return true here if I want to keep the
item.
So I want to return False if I want to get rid of it.
So this should return false.
If I want to get rid of it and I want to get rid of it for this condition ask before with two string
we can guarantee we're working with the right type of data here.
And now we have the updated card items which we just need to save back to our cart and therefore to
the database because it is already Ardit cart items with the one item we wanted to get rid of removed.
So I can simply copy my code from up there where I update the database like this and when I say updated
Cartier will simply mean I want to assign this to an object with an item's property because that is
what our card has right.
We have items that are an item is equal to our updated card items and that as it does now we'll update
the card to have all card items except for the one we deleted.
So back in the shop G-S controller here I don't need to call get cart instead on the user.
I can call my new method delete item from card which you just edit.
We can call that year and pass the product ID as an argument and that we can get rid of all that code
and simply redirect.
Once we're done so let's see if that works.
If we now saved as lets go to the routes and add this post route for deleting card items reload this
page here and let's delete the second item and this is looking good.
It's gone here.
No arrows here.
So this is looking good.
And if my update doesn't compeers we see that for this user We indeed.
Well obviously only have the other items so this worked and that is how we can delete card items with
these.