So now did we added some relational information to our orders.
We can go back to getting all the orders in our user Jay fall in the models folder there I half get
orders and now I want to reach out to my orders and simply find them all or at least find all four dead
user.
Now how do I find all orders for that user.
Well remember each order has a user object and in the User object we have the idea of that user.
So we need to compare dead ID to the current user ID.
Now to do this we add a filter and now would it be.
You can also check nested properties by defining the path to them.
The only important thing to know here is that you need to use quotation marks around the path and then
you can say check user.
And then the idea for the user.
You do that by specifying user dot underscore ID and this will look for underscore ID in the user property
which holds and then bad a document.
And then here I can compare it is to a new object id for this ID and this should give me all orders
for that user and this will now be more than one.
So again we can use to two aere shortcut and return that data to return an array of orders for that
user and our user here for example has two orders because we got two orders for that user ID.
So now we want to output that order information.
So let's go to the shop controller get orders now.
I named my function get orders here too.
So calling that here should work.
We don't need data anymore that include thing was relayed to sequel's.
I then get back my orders and I passed them to the orders view.
So let's now just inspect that orders view here and there.
I loop through all my orders and for every order I have an underscore ID that's important.
And then in the orders I don't have products we could name it as such but I named the items here.
So I'll loop through all the items now.
There will be product information in there though.
For example the title and the quantity which is now a top level field and product.
So we access it like this.
And with that out of the way let's save that and let's go to the route's folder and there to shop as
fall and comment in that one orders route you removed earlier.
And let's now click on orders up there get to be is not the find.
That should be a typo in get orders and the user remodel.
Yeah this should be get D-B with a lower case b.
So let's read that page and does looks much better.
Now we got our orders with their ID and with the items we ordered.
So this is now working.
Now we got that basic shop functionality working again which we had work earlier with sequel.
Now we're doing it with Mongo D-B now Aguas deep just as we used sequel eyes for a sequel.
To make certain things easier we can do the same with Mongo D-B And also we can find an alternative
that makes our life a bit easier.