In this module we had to look at no sequel and especially long would it be of course now no sequel database's
Mulready B is just an alternative to sequel database's It follows a different philosophy.
You have no strict schema schemas what you do have and sequel and you have fewer relations.
You don't split your data across dozens of tables.
Instead you work with things like and batting data or using some reference or even mixing the two concepts
as you saw in this module too.
So in general you've got way more flexibility.
And since you can store the data in the format you are fetching it in.
You often can write a bit simpler coteries because data already has the format you needed in.
When working with mung would he be.
You should use the official Mangu to be driver and then you got a lot of useful commands like injured
one find update one delete one and so on which make all these crud operations corrupt stands for create
read update and delete.
Very simple.
Now check out the official docs or my full mobility course to learn all about the a way lable operations
how you can configure them which operators like dollar sign in which you sign this Marchal.
So all these things which you can use you can learn about that because indeed Mangu to be offers enough
content for an entire course.
And this is of course not the idea behind this course it should stay A.J. of course now it's also worth
pointing out that all the operations are promised based and they are for creating more complex chains
as we did it.
Where you have this first command and then the second command is pretty easy and is pretty easy to read.
So overall no sequel in Hmong would be very popular especially in combination with no chases because
you work with javascript objects anyways and because it's very fast and therefore it's definitely worth
checking out.
And I will also stick to more.
Would it be for the rest of this course though.
I also want to mention that you can of course use MS sequel.
Ultimately it always depends on your preferences and the requirements of your application and there
is a large gray area where neither of the two is wrong to use.