Thus far in this course we always had a look at a particular kind of request and response.
The request was always a request sent from our browser.
When we submitted a form or entered a u r l or clicked a link and the response always was either a redirect
or a new home page.
Now that can take you very far but sometimes you get some work some requests that will only happen behind
the scenes.
That means you don't want to get back and you h team l page you only want to exchange some data with
the server for example and it will show you what I mean and how this works in this module.
So we'll have a look at what Asynchronous JavaScript requests are why we would use them and how we will
use them.