So what are asynchronous requests.
Well we have our client and our server so the browser and our node application and that's the setup
we had for this entire course.
This is the set up you have with any web or even mobile project that you built these days.
You have your back and you have your Front-End.
Now typically you send the request from your client to the server and you get back a response.
And as I mentioned thus far in discourse the response always was Ha ha Tim L page or a redirect to a
route that then returned age Tamalpais.
Now there is nothing wrong with that but there are tasks where you don't want to reload the page just
to for example delete item and actually in modern web applications the portion that happens behind the
scenes grows.
Since we can do a lot with javascript in the browser where we never need to fetch a new age HTML page
but where we constantly change the existing page asked is is faster than loading a new one.
But that's something I'll cover in the rest for API modules.
Now the idea behind asynchronous requests is that you do send the request but dead request typically
contains just some data in a special format named Jason and dead data is sent to the server to a certain
you r l or a route.
Except that bited server.
So that logic doesn't change the circuit do whatever he wants to do with debt.
And then we return the response and that response is all returned.
Behind the scenes.
So it's not a New-Age html page that needs to be rendered.
It's instead Again just some data in that Jason format typically.
And that is how clients can communicate through Javascript.
So through client side javascript and a service side logic without reloading or rebuilding the page
without exchanging a new HTL page and that allows you to do some work behind the scenes without interrupting
the user flow without reloading the page.
Now let's have a look at how that would work in this Marchal.