Our course project on the admin products page where we can delete products I want to implement this
delete function differently.
Right now when I would click delete I would simply well delete that send Dad requests to the server
and get back and you weren't off that page.
Essentially where does product stand missing.
And we can see that of course on our service side if we have a look at our admen controller and we have
a look at that post the lead product action this action here.
Then we see that we while we also extract some incoming data off course and then we work with that data
to delete the image belonging to that product and then the product itself.
And by the end we redirect back to admen products which is a route which will return to home page.
Now don't get me wrong there is nothing wrong with this set up and you can absolutely use it but maybe
it would be a great user experience if you would never have to leave that page if you wouldn't reload
that page.
But if we click delete We sent that information that we want to get rid of that item to the server behind
the scenes the server can then still do its thing and once we're done this terrible respond just with
some adjacent data.
So some success message or anything like that.
And once we get that message in our browser we can delete this Dom element so we can delete this article
here.
We could do all that with client side javascript.
So with javascript writing in the browser and some help by our service site.
And that is a so-called Asynchronous JavaScript request or this will use so-called Asynchronous JavaScript
requests.
Now the logic won't change too much but the way we expose our route changes a little bit and we'll have
to add some logic on our client side.
So let's do that now and forward at all.
First of all go to my public Jay s folder and I'll create a new folder the admen dodgiest file.
Then you can name it however you want.
Important.
Does this javascript code that will now not run on the server but that will run in the client.
So in the browser I will import this javascript file into my product's page here.
So there let's say below the bottom here below our footer I will import a script with script source
and you have to close the script tag like this.
And then I will import J.S. admen J.
So we'll import that java file from the ingenius folder which is in a public folder which is served
statically.
Now this script will execute on this products js file and if we loaded at the end of this fall we make
sure that we had hired Dom has been rendered and parsed by the time we execute our Javascript code.
So now we can go back to Edmund J S and add some logic in there.
Now which logic do I want to add.
Well I want to react to a click on this delete button here and therefore First of all this button should
not be of type submit anymore.
It should be of type button instead.
Actually I will remove this entire form because this form was required for sending a request from the
browser sending a request which does X W W W R L form a coded data.
Now I'll not do it like this anymore.
I will get rid of that instead.
And instead I will now Gaverick that data here manually.
So I will listen to a click that button and then I will Gabr to product ID and to see SRF token manually
foody help of my client side javascript.
Now with the former removed I'll go back to Admetus and here I now want to get access to all these delete
buttons.
Listen to a click on them and then do something when they get clicked.
Now for that all to find a function admen genius
delete product.
Here I'm using NexGen code but this is code it will run in the browser.
All modern browsers support the syntax but of course if browser side javascript is new for you you should
take a dedicated course that discourse will not focus on that but here will have a function where for
it I will simply execute collect.
Now this delete product function is a function I can use from inside my.
E.J. essentail for H.T. mail file on that button.
I can add on click and simply say delete product so dysfunction your delete product like this execute
that function when you click on that button if you're now saved it and we reload this page here and
I open the browser developer tools if I click on delete you should see click here.
Now it's not the leading to product anymore because we delete that form right.
So now I'm reacting to a click.
And now the next thing will be that we have to find out which ideas see SRF token we have for that back
in the Edmond's last fall when we click I want to get access to the field next to the button.
I want to get access to to see as our token and as I mentioned to the product ID.
Now how do I get access to the surrounding elements.
Well in products yes we can pass this to delete product.
This is a special keyword.
And in the context here it will refer to the element on which we clicked.
So the button doesn't say I get this in as many as I can access to the button since I now received this
as an argument and it can prove to you that this is the pattern by simply logging it.
If we reload the page and click Delete we see the button being locked here and here it would be that
button.
So now we have access to the button.
And with that we can easily get access to the running inputs.
I can simply access to a parent node of my button which will simply be wild element or around my bottom.
So in this case this defeater and I can find my inputs in there the input with the name product ID and
the input with the name see SRF underscore C S or I can do so by using the query selector on the parent
node and here all used the attribute selector to find name equal product ID.
Now let me lock this to the console to see if it works.
If I now reload my page and I go to the console log.
Now I get that input ID being locked that hidden input ID.
Now from that input I can't of course also extract the value which is then just the product ID itself
and not the entire Dom element.
So with data value added.
Now I just get the ID and for the product I get well.
Do you ever ID.
So now I have a way of getting that.
Let's start at fraud.
ID in a constant and then let me all the store to see SRF token.
And here I will simply repeat that code access the element with a name of underscores C S or F and extract
the value.
And now with these two pieces of information we can now send our asynchronous requests to the server
for data of course we need a fitting route and so on.
So let's work on that next.