We have some basic code in place to extract values about the product which we want to delete.
Now to continue we need a route on the back end to which we can send our javascript request for now
let's go to the route's folder and dare to admen J.
Obviously we already have a delete route here a delete product route and we can build up on that route.
There is nothing wrong with that.
But now since we'll sent the request directly through javascript we can actually use a different HTP
word.
Thus far we always use GET and POST because the browser natively is port Steese 4-D requests sent by
the browser by forms submission and by clicking links.
It only knows GET and POST when we send requests through Javascript.
So from browser side javascript we have access to Ivor HTP works too and you'll learn more about the
different HTP words in the rest API section.
One of them is delete and this is a HTP word.
So HTP method which makes a lot of sense for deleting.
Now it's only a semantic thing.
We could use post you can in general use any HTP word to do anything because you to find with your server
side logic.
What will happen.
But it makes sense to try to be clear about your intention and there is a delete.
We can now use it.
So why wouldn't we use it.
So now does a delete route to delete product.
Now I can all change does a bit and may be named as product dash and then the product ID as a dynamic
parameter.
Because delete requests can have dynamic you are parameters.
So now we can extract that information from our u r l and I'll leave the controller action as it is
but I will now name it delete product like this because they are not sending a post request anymore
so I guess this name makes more sense is all.
Is a middle word.
I will keep in place though.
So now that let's go to the admin controller and here I'll rename that function that handler here to
delete product because I renamed it in the route's Faltu and now the product ID first of all is not
extracted from the request body anymore because delete requests as it turns out also are not allowed
to have a request body.
But instead we now have dat you r l parameter.
Product ID.
So I can extract my D from there.
So I simply change body for parents Odets it.
So that gives me my product ID and then does logic here will still work.
I only need to change to response I'll return.
I will not redirect anymore because I'll not load a new page.
Remember that the request triggering this action will be sent behind the scenes for the existing page.
So I want to keep that existing page and therefore my response will be a response or I'll send JS send
data.
JS send data as a special format and with Express Yes I can use a chastened helper method to conveniently
return Jason data and Jason is simply a data format that looks like a javascript object.
So with curly braces and then key value pairs.
The only important thing about Jason is the key is have to be wrapped between table called Hashemites.
This is Jason data.
And this is what we can return here.
And now we can also set a status here of 200 maybe because for adjacent data this would be the default.
But there since we don't redirections on where we get a status code set automatically it would make
sense to be very clear about the status code we have and therefore here are also not to use my default
error handler where I would load the 500 page instead.
I'll also return a response with status 500.
Now that is what I mean about setting that status on your own and there are also veterans I'm Jason
data.
The question is of course which data you simply pass a javascript object year which will then be transformed
to Jasen automatically for you.
So here you can pass on an old javascript object.
You don't need double quotation marks around your keys there.
And here we could have a message read just say success.
Of course not that interesting but we could do that here.
I could have a message where I say deleting product failed.
So now I have that in place and now we have two important changes.
This is how we extract the parents or the product ID.
And now we return Jason responses because we don't want to render a new page.
We just want to return some data.
Obviously we now have to continue in Edman shapes and make sure that we send the request and then work
with their response data.
Not this file though.
I mean the one in the public just folder here we worked on the service side and we added a new route
or we changed the route to use to delete the word and to look like this.
And now we need to send the request there from inside our client side admen chase falls so in the public
folder here we can use the fetch method which is a method supported by the browser for sending HTB requests
and it's not just for fetching data.
Asked and they might suggest it's all for sending data here.
You can't pass a u r l.
So we want to send a request to slash product.
And then of course needs to be replaced with the Product ID.
And this will send that to the same server.
If you don't specify a different host with HTP and then something.
So if you have nothing like data we'll send it to the current host here.
I will add my ID of course and then the second argument is an object where you can configure this fetch
request.
Now here you can set a bunch of things you could add a request body but not for a delete request as
I just explained in the last lecture.
But for a post request which you can also send with that you would set it.
And first of all let's define that this is a delete request.
So method to delete here doesn't have to be uppercase but is a good convention.
Now with Methot set what else can we set Well we can set headers and in the headers we could encode
our C as our token because we still need to attach this to our request.
And right now we are not doing that.
We cannot send that in the request body because delete requests don't have a body.
But the good thing is this see surf package which we are using on a server does not just log in to request
bodies.
It also looks into the query parameters and therefore we could add it there.
And it also looks into the headers.
So there we can add a SEUS or token header.
It will look for this key.
You'll find all the keys for which it will look in the official door so you can add as a token and then
see or F as a value to attached to your outgoing request as well.
Now this will send the request and it will return a promise that allows to listen to the response.
And here I will console log any error I might be getting and here I'll be consul logging any resoled
I might be getting.
Let's see what we have there.
Now one important note by the way I'm not sending any adjacent data with my request here because it
does not delete request without a post body.
If it were and that is something we will see in the rest API section then I would have to parse Jason
data in my backend because there right now.
And that's just an important note.
And actually yes there right now we only have two parser's one for you are all encoded data which we
don't have when we sent Jason data and one for multipart data which we also don't have there we would
have to add a new body parser that is able to handle Jason's data and extract that from incoming requests.
I don't add it here because we don't need it here but we will added later when we need it.
So with data all in place with our client side code adjust it.
Say all of that and let's simply click that delete button after reloading the page and see what we get
clicked delete.
And first of all get a 4 0 for error dead.
This route is not found product with some ID.
And this makes sense because my route product product that isn't the admin routes folder of course we
only get there if our request path starts with Slash admin.
That is all we can figure in the file.
So in my client Edmund J.S. last fall in the public folder I should of course point at slash and burn
slash product slash product ID so that's a little mistake on my side.
Let's now reload after changing this.
And now this is looking good.
I get a response with a status code of 200 with request body which is a readable stream.
I'll show you how to get to that request bawdiness second.
And if I reload the page the product is indeed gone.
Now that's a step forward.
But of course I don't just want to reload the page.
It should be gone immediately.
That would be the main idea of doing this behind the scenes.
So how can we make this work.