So we get a result and that's great.
Now first of all that salt had some cryptic body which was a readable Stream.
Now what we can do here in the then block is we can return a result Jason which is a function that will
throw a new promise or return on your promise so I can add a number.
Then block and here I will have the data.
So the response body I don't necessarily need that but I want to show you how you could get that data
that's getting returned by the server.
More importantly I know that either here or here doesn't matter.
I have a response so the item was deleted on the server.
And now I want to delete it here in the dorm as well.
Now how can we do that.
Well we got access to the button on which we clicked right and the button is in the end inside of the
whole Dom element.
You want to delete.
So it is this article which I want to delete.
So therefore what I have to do is I have to find this article based on this button and that's relatively
straightforward to do.
My product element and you can name this constant however you want is basically my button.
And then there is a closest method provided by javascript and you pass a selector to close just which
gives you the closest element with that selector and the closest ancestor element to be precise.
And there I will simply use article because I only have one article in my ancestor history year for
this button.
So if I select my closest article that should be the element I want to delete.
So inside here.
Let's say I can call product element remove that is a function that will not be supported in Internet
Explorer.
There you would have to access the parent node and then remove a child
and that child would be the product elements of that is code that works in every browser.
Remove would work in all modern browsers.
Now is that in place.
We can reload this page here and now.
Click on delete it will eventually be gone.
And here we see our success message.
Now just to validate that it really only deletes one element and not all elements.
Let me log in with my user who also has two products I candlelit.
These two products.
And now let's go to Aben product delete the boat let's say and now only the dock left.
So this is great.
And indeed if I go to products this data really has gone icon loaded here.
So this is how you can use asynchronous requests.
Now of course there is more you can do on the client side but this is not a client side javascript course.
The important thing here is that you can send data to your backend with the help with these asynchronous
requests and how you can include data and how you can handle that on the backend.