Now that the core basics about no chase and express chairs are set.
It's time that we work more on what the user sees because ultimately we obviously want to build an application
which delivers some value to our users right now.
Thus far we're always returning static HVM pages and typically does is not what you do in real applications
because you don't just have static H.T. mail code.
Most of the time instead it is pretty common that you have some data managed on your server.
Later we will also do that in the database that you have some data on your server which you want to
dynamically output in the aged female code you sent back to your users.
An example would be a page with a list of products.
Where do these products of course are coming from your database.
So from your server or for example we already have a very simple form where people can submit a new
product title.
Well right now we're not really doing anything with that in a real application.
You would obviously want to store that and then kind of return it in some other page where you have
that list of products I already mentioned.
So as module we will have a first look at how we can start managing data on a node Express back end
for now without a database.
No worries there will be a very extensive module about that data basis in this course so you will learn
how to interact with the database too.
But for now let's just manage data like this and let's focus on something else here on rendering dynamic
for now dummy content in the U.S..
So these all pages which we're returning should now become more dynamic and actually contain some content
that is dynamically entered into them on the server so that if we had additional data on the server
we would send back a different HTL page with different content.
And this will use something called a templating engine and you will learn how such templating engines
there is more than one alternative.
And I will present some alternatives in this module.
You'll learn how they work and how you can use them.
So this is what's in this module.
And with that let's dive right into it and let's have a look at how we could manage that data before
we then have a look at how we could output it.