I already mentioned at the beginning of this module that for putting dynamic content into our aged female
pages we would use something called templating engines templating engines were like this.
We got to HVM Eish template.
And with that I mean that you typically write some code some file that contains a lot of H Tim L your
HTL structure and mark up your style and Javascript imports all of that is typically loaded.
But you have some blanks in there some placeholders and then you have your note expressed content in
your app like our dummy array our products array we're currently using.
And you've got a templating engine which understands a certain syntax for which it scans your HVM Elish
template and where it then replaces placeholders or certain snippets depending on the engine you're
using with real time the content but def content this time I'll content it uses Stehr is generated on
the fly on the server by the templating engine.
Taking that dynamic content into account.
So for example you could output an ordered list with list items for the data you have in your node express
app with the help of the templating engine and in the end the result will be dynamically on the fly
generated HDMI file which is then sent back to your users so the users never see the template.
They never see the placeholders.
All that happens on the server.
They just get the normal HMO page but it's not hard coded by you as it currently is in our project.
But instead it's generated on the fly.
Now we got a couple of different the whaleboat templating engines and actually you get even more options
then I'll show you here.
At the end of this module you'll find some useful links to dive deeper into them and learn about more
alternatives free options.
I would present you are to free most popular ones.
We've got SJS Pike formerly named Jayde and handlebars.
Now these are free templating engines that use a different syntax and different set of features different
philosophies that you can use to well create these templates inject your dynamic content and get h html
files out of them.
Here's a brief a very brief look at how their syntax looks like.
But I will also present all three of them in this module.
Each of us looks something like this.
You write normal HTL markup but then you also add like is smaller than percentage sign.
And then sometimes an equal sign sometimes not depending on what you're doing you will see that in this
module and then the dynamic continue when output.
So if we had some name variable being injected into our template and you will learn how that injection
works if we got that then the value of our name variable would be output there and we would send back
and watched him fall with a paragraph tags and the value that was stored in name between them POC uses
a different syntax.
It doesn't use real l it replaces does with a minimize to Word or minimal persion.
And then it also allows you to output dynamic content with this syntax.
The hashtag curly brace syntax for example handlebars in turn uses HTL again.
But then you have to double curly brace placeholders for Dynamic Content.
So similar to Ejaz actually handlebars has a bit less features a whaleboat you could say or it it follows
a different philosophy but it's closer to each as Poch ISDE.
Well the outlier here which also uses a different HVM else syntax.
So a short summary would be each asked normal team out and then actually you got these placeholders
which allow you to just use plain javascript in them actually.
So you can also write if statements for loops Poch use as a minimal HTL word.
And a custom template language which is extensible but generally offers only a set of things of operations
you can do but if statements and lists would be included.
Iterations would be included handlebars uses normal HTL but also a custom template language with a limited
set of features.
Again including common things like statements or lists.
So these are free popular templating engines.
Now let's briefly dive into them how we install them and how we use them before we then pick the favorite
for this course and stick to that favorite.
And again at the end of this module you'll find more resources on all these engines.