Where rendering our shop template but we're not rendering any dynamic content.
That however is the whole idea of this module.
We get our admen data with the products.
So let's actually take these products out of admen data products and now we want to pass that into our
template injected into our template so that we can use it in this template file and somehow output it
there to do that.
We can simply pass a second argument to the render method the render method allows us to pass in data
that should be added into our view.
Here we can simply pass products however not like this.
But as a javascript object where we map it to a key name which we can use in the template to refer to
the data we're passing in and we can pass in Pre-OT's simply to avoid naming confusion.
You could use products but then all bind my products.
So does constant Brodsky in this object.
This is passed into this template.
And now in that template we will just be able to access process.
This is now available by the way we can all pass more than one field.
We could pass in.
Let's say a doc title which is shop and now we can use that too.
And let's maybe start with the doc title.
So does additional field where passing in this object in Schupbach let's say the title here should actually
be data doc title for this we can use to custom templating Sendak's pack gives us.
And if you just went out put some text does a hash tag followed by two curly braces and between these
curly braces you can put any value you are passing into your view.
So any field you have in this object like Doc title we can use that and simply refer to Doc title here.
If we now safe that we go back to our page right now it's still in my shop right.
If I now reload it's shop and Adis shop because it's a title I'm storing in Doc tightly and Doc Thaila
is what we're outputting here.
So this flow is important to understand.
Now of course we can also use debt to output our products for this next to the header.
So on the same indentation level this is important because it defines the nesting of th html we get
at the main element just as we have it here.
And now I don't want to have does age one paragraph.
Instead now I want to output my product with this code so I'll copy it over even though it is H-2 him
all the code but will a justice and transfer it to packet code.
So the defeater becomes just dots grid.
You don't need death because you don't have anything.
It's assumed to be a death.
The article with dishcloths becomes article dot product.
Item however important if you've got multiple clauses you need to merge them and simply concatenate
them separated by dots and never forget the inundation.
The article should be inside of this div with this class so let's indented one level here.
We got an indented header because it's nested in the article and this header also has this class here
so let's added like this and then in the header we got to h tech.
So lets all.
And then this And here again this has a c as as class.
Now it all has some text and you simply separate the text with whitespace from the element and you never
need closing tax here.
That is handled for you by pug.
So this is really a syntax that is very different to normal HTL and is really up to you if you liked
it or not.
I personally don't work too much with it but if you like it.
This can of course allow you to write very lean Rached female files.
We don't need the closing had to attack because again this is added automatically so we can move on
to the card image which should be next to the card header.
So let's indent remove that smaller than sign at this Placidyl without the class keyword.
And let's add the image inside of there.
We get an image and again as before with the links here.
If you have attributes you wrap them in normal rackets like this.
Select the source and also the alt key.
You can always by the way also use Emett here.
This is the plugin which helps you with auto treating this.
If you type the tag or the class name with a daughter at the beginning and hit enter it will autocomplete
that for you and give you the respect the pocket representation.
And there we saw that we actually need a comma after source right before Allt.
So now this will create the image nested in this card image.
Don't need to closing Divac know the card content is also a sibling to the card image.
So let's indent this remove that and at this start here.
And let's do the same 40 to tag indented.
Turn it into a pocket conform.
Set up here.
We have some text next to it like this.
For now that's static.
Later this will become dynamic.
And let's also do the same here for a paragraph adds declasse here and have some static text and remove
the closing tag.
And we're almost done only a couple of elements to go.
We get a diff.
Now this should be all next two cards contents let's indented a div as I mentioned doesn't have a tag
you need to add.
You can just have dot something.
So Dot and the class name if you have no class of course you would write that diff.
Otherwise there is nothing the button is inside of card actions.
And this does have a clause in.
And then it does have some text inside of it which we add next to the button element.
And all these closing tacks can be removed.
Now does outputs a grid of product carts.
However only with static content.
Now to make this less static we need to iterate through all the products and remember that we do pass
the product into the view here on the Pre-OT's key so to iterate and repeat this article for all the
products we can simply add a special syntax provided by POC and you do create such a loop by adding
each keyword then a value in which you want to store the value for the current iteration.
So a single product that our case.
And then in and then the array for which you want to loop.
So this would be Pre-OT's in our case again with Pre-OT's referring to this key in this object we're
passing to our view.
So now we're looping through the process.
Let's all indent this into the loop so that we repeat this entire block for each product.
In this process irrate and now we can use the product variable which we're creating on the fly here
to output the data.
Like the title here we could output hash tag.
And then again just product Daut title because remember a single product we add to this array here is
an object with a title key.
We do create this here in Edmond J.S. we push an object with the title key.
This is one single product as we'll have it when we loop through it.
So this is what we add here or what we output here with all these changes in place.
If we now save this and we reload this page we don't see anything because we have no products yet.
But if we add a first book here we do actually see that here and we see that TMH does not work anymore.
Let me quickly add a number free to use image you can of course simply google for any image that you
can use as a dummy image here for now once you got one take that source whichever it is and simply replace
it here.
This is only for practice purposes here.
So now if we repeat this this looks much better by the way if you only change something in the template
as I just did.
You don't need to restart the server and no one will not do so because the templates are not part of
your service code.
They are basically just templates which are picked up on the fly anyways.
So if you change them for the next request that's coming they will automate he'd take that and you were
already.
So with this we get a basic introduction to pi.
It's strange very minimal syntax and how you can output single values like some text or loop through
some items.
Now of course we could have the case to be bigshots no products at all.
So one thing you also want to do is you want to ensure that you have a conditional check and render
ever content a or content.
And we can do that too with Pug.
We can add an if statement and check if product length.
So if this array of products is greater than zero if it is greater than zero then we'll output this.
So let's indent it all into the if statement because then we do have some pro-tax to output overwise.
I will go into the same level as read here.
Asti of statement and the else block because ABA wise I will output age 1 tag where I say no products
which does now have a restart the server to clear my product's array.
And then restart reload this page.
I actually get an error because of course it's froths here.
Remember we're passing Pre-OT's as I Keitt not products so froths is what I should check here now if
reload.
I see no products but if I add one first book like this.
Now we see that instead.
So now we got the free most important parts outputting simple text and so on outputting a list and outputting
additional content business.
In a nutshell this is how you use templating engines in Express's in general.
Now feel free as a practice to play around with that and also work on that ad product.
Tim Page and replace all these items are all the content here with Poch templates keep the HTL code
around.
Don't delete these files so that we can easily switch to Obert templating engines later.
But make sure you add pucked templates forty two pages and then you render them all in a few free to
inject some dynamic code like the page title in the next lecture will do that to Gebre.