So let's convert all these HTL falls to Poch templates now.
And for this I'll start with ADD product and entry to add product dot POC file in the views folder.
Now again I will create a team of five skeleton with the help of Emett here by typing h tim L. selecting
Det.
H HTML 5 template here and hitting tab.
So this already gives us a nice start.
Now I'll set the title to add product and now a one word is for him to park and of course he had to
now to Hatteras something we already got in the shop so we can just copy that here.
Move it over to add product in the body like this.
Just make sure that you move the act of class from the first anchor tag to the second one.
Because now this is the active route and of course I also want to add my main section with the foreign
Now I'll again reverse engineer it by copying the main HVM code going in there and next to the header.
I want to add it.
Main is now just main the form then is nested in there so let's indent it to form has this class.
Let's change this and the form also has attributes.
So let's add them here as a comma separated list in brackets.
Now we can indent div here because that is of course nested in the form.
The div has this class and you learned that a div can also be omitted so you can just have dot and the
class to render a div and that in there we have to label the label here has an attribute.
So let's add this and it has some text which is separated with the whitespace as you learned.
Now we also have put your input of type text so let's add this brackets.
Set here to render some attributes separated with calm us and d id can actually be rendered separately
with the hash tag in front of it.
Again using it as selector.
Something you already solve for the class.
Does all this to see us as selector for does class pack uses DS selectors.
So now you have hash tag title.
Now let's remove the closing tag of the div and let's also add the button it's indented because it's
part of the forms.
Let's make sure it's in the form.
Let's give that the button class.
Don't forget this and let's add the attribute list to make this a submit button like that and then a
whitespace to separate add product text.
Let's remove the closing tax and that should be it.
Now let's all the render some dynamic content here.
For example at product to your title all again.
I'll put this dynamically page title for example.
Now we have to make sure that we pass this key into this template and we do render this template in
Edmond J.S. So here where I do will send this file.
I don't Cintas fall.
Instead I now render I render my admen file here.
The admin actually got the Edmond the add product part file does automate the then and I pass in an
object which holds the key value pairs.
I want to be able to access in the template and there I got my page title key.
So that's key.
I'm trying to access here.
I got that and I will assign the title of at product just like debt with that free reload.
This has gone because the server restart it due to our society changes.
Now if you click add product does this VHDL code by the looks of it.
I forgot to add d imports.
Yeah I need to of course also import my Stahl's sheets so let's copy the links from a shop plug and
add them here in the header.
That's all the check yet.
Product HTL file.
I also need to import the forums.
Seems as far as you can see.
So let's duplicate this here.
Does align at all at this import now knows every restart is required because we just changed the template
and therefore gnomon doesn't restart.
And now the reload does looks much better.
And let's give this a try.
It also still works.
So that's it.
Now let's work on you for 0 for a page for this.
I'll add 4 0 4 Poch file here and I will again create a normal age of 5 skeleton.
I will say Page not found here and I will already copy what you need.
The main C S S fall.
I will copy that import your from the product part file does link let's copy it over to the 4 0 4 part
files so that we got that and then in the 404 HTML file I get the header and I got Page Not Found.
Well we got the header already and add products.
Let's copy that Hatter here.
Move dat into 4 or 4 pack into the body by indenting there and next to the header inside the body.
At age 1 tag whereas a page not found.
And with that we should have it.
Now let's just make sure that this gets rendered and for that we have to go to the aperture last fall
because that is where we have our catch all middleware and there instead of sending a file.
I will now also render div 4 0 for file and ASP before it will automatically look in the views folder.
Due to our setup and it will look for datt POC files so that if I now enter any random pove which doesn't
exist we indeed get page not found.
So this is now working and is now using pack as a templating engine.
No there are a couple of other nice things that can do that I want to show you.