You probably do notice that we do repeat a base structure in all our files here and that of course is
a bit annoying that we manually have to do that.
For example this base set up and all of the import of main C S S as well as the header is part of every
single page and therefore it's a bit cumbersome if we manually have to repeat this set up where to import
all the time.
So what can we do regarding that.
We can create a so-called layout for it is all true then you subfolder in views which are name layouts.
In case you might have multiple ones and I'll add a main layout.
Poch file.
Now I'll take my ADD where my shop Poch fall or maybe 4 or 4 which is the most minimal one and copy
that file content into main layout.
Now of course we get some elements here which are dynamic now which depend on the page and want to use.
And the question is how can we reuse this skeleton anyways.
Well we can extend this layout from inside our Obert POC views and we can actually to find some placeholders
some hooks in this layout where you can then enter their content.
For example here in the links we get a base layout which looks like this.
But in over the use that should extend this layout.
They Majdi was disallowed and add more leagues in this place.
We can find such a hook by adding the block keyword which POC understands and then defining any name
of our choice styles for example.
Now we will be able to add more styles from inside our files here.
And I will show you how to add this in a second.
I also want to remove that active link here.
By the way also for potful because I have no assumption about what's active and it will show you how
to then magically set this in a second too.
Now the content below the header also is dynamic.
And here I again will reserve a block.
So a hook which will name content and the name again is up to you.
So now we get this basically out with two hooks we can dynamically enter content into from inside our
profiles.
Now lets start with the 4 0 4 PAC page here there.
I will just copy that content that matters to me and remove the entire rest and we can now extend DeLay
out by adding d extends keyword which understands and now we just to point at the layout for that.
We have the layouts folder and we want to use the main layout file in there.
We have to add here too.
So now we're telling Pakhtun we want to extend this.
And now we just have to tell it what to render in that content and maybe also in that stylus hook we
defined for a stouts I don't need any special setting here but for the content block I want to enter
my own custom content and I do this by again typing block content but now I extend a layout this will
not define a hook but actually allow me to add content in that layout and then indented here.
I define what should be injected into the content block in the layout.
So in this place with that if I saved it and I enter some random lbf which doesn't exist I still get
page not found but now behind the scenes this actually uses my layout and we can of course do the same
on the pages like ad product there let's also for now keep the content so that we can copy and paste
content over into our new layout.
So we extend main layout pointing at the layout file.
And here I will add something to the content but also into my Stout's block and we do that by simply
typing block Stultz here and then indent did we add what we want to add and these are these two lines
because these are the two style imports which are not part of the default layout.
So let's add them here in the styles block and then we have to either block the content block this one
where I want to enter my own content.
So for that I will copy the entire part in the main section or the entire main section actually like
this carrot and move it over and replace this age one tackier and make sure the intonation is correct.
And now we can remove the entire rest here and we should now have a file that does extend our layout
and therefore still looks the way it looked before but now it uses is way more concise approach which
also ensures that if we ever change something to the layout we don't have to change it at all the files
but only in that main layout file and the our files since they extended will automatically get it.
So let's say if this let's go to add product and this looks good styling is good.
So all these styles are imported as you can see and it looks like before almost We got this act of KLOS
missing we don't see that D at product link as the act of one.
And that makes sense because in the main layout we make no assumption what is active.
So the question is how can we dynamically set this.