Let's make sure we do is set this act of class on the right leg depending on which page we are now for
debt I will go to my routes and there since I'm working on the add product to the Aben just fall where
I do have that at product route this one.
Now I will return a new field here.
The path field and I will set this to admin add product so you can set this to whatever you want it
doesn't have to match the path this route has just a pattern I like.
So now I pass this POV into my view so that the viewer can find out what is the POV for which this was
loaded.
Now in main layout will get this payoff.
And now I can do something interesting in the main layout here.
I know that I want to add the active class to does add product.
If the payoff and the payoff now simply is a variable i get passed into the page.
If the POV simply is this one and that is something we define a Therefore you could pick any path you
want.
So now I will add a check here.
Now a class can be added A C is as class as an attribute here too.
You don't have to use that dot notation.
So class is equal to.
And now we'll have some javascript code which we can enclose with brackets here and now here I simply
check if Poth and pop is simply just what I pass in here so Diski.
If Prof is equal to this value and that is why I meant you can use whatever POF you want you are defining
the condition here.
So if pompe is equal to this then I know that at Productus the page I'm on because only 40 ad product
route I do set this path.
So then if that is the case I want to render active as a class here.
Otherwise an empty string.
So otherwise I basically set no class with this set up.
Now if I reload this page you'll see ad product is yellow because now it is marked as active.
If they go to shop that's not the case but on shop we also don't use the layout yet.
So let's continue.
Now for the shop I also want to use the layout so I will go to add product pack copy my code here and
move it all over to shop plug.
Let's keep your original code for now.
Extend the main layout therefore now I do need the product Zia's as follows here.
But I don't need the foreigns So let's remove that from the Stout's block and for the content it will
need main.
But we don't render a form here.
Instead we rendered this if loop so that's Or does if block.
So let's copy that entire code and put it in here.
Make sure indentation is correct and you don't mess this up.
And now we can get rid of all the other code here.
Now again for styling off the header we would have a problem if I now reload because it's not marked
as active because I need to use that same approach I did for the add product route I pass in an additional
key Poff and there I-PASS slash like this or slash shop.
Again you don't have to use the real path that led to this round.
I'll use slash though to keep this matched.
And now in May layout I copy my code from down there where I dynamically add does class and add it here
for the shop too.
But the part I'm checking for is just slash here and now I do an act of fear.
If the POV variable which gets injected into the template matches slash which is only DKs for this route.
So I've saved this I got an error here.
Yeah.
This should not be an equal sign here.
This should be a colon in shop.
Yes.
Because we're creating a javascript object.
And now over reload here this is active.
This is active.
And if we try adding a book this also works.
So this is now working.
Now there is one thing I saw that I forgot and that is the title for the page.
It's always page not found.
And that should of course not be the case.
Now you could turn this title into a block which you then set from inside the templates or if you do
add a dynamic output here with hash tag curly braces and give us a name page title maybe.
And now you just need to make sure that every render function passes in a page title.
So 44 0 for Page 40 at product page and the shop page we have to pass in that page title key.
So starting an admin J.S. here we already got page titles so we're fine in shop Chaz here at stock titles.
Let's read just two page title to be in line with the Arbre file and with our layout and in the aperture
Yes fall where we have our 4 0 4 route.
I'm not passing anything.
So there let's all send some data into the view and that's all set.
Page Title here.
Page Not Found.
If we now go to our page and reload it we see it shop here as a title for ad product we see at product
and if we enter something random Here we see Page Not Found.
So now does this working.
And now we're using Poch.
Now you can do way more with pi and you can combine all these features and do crazy stuff.
I recommend diving into their official box.
If you plan on using that I instead want to show you the alternatives to.
Now we learned the basics of how templating engines work and how you can use them to output dynamic
content in your views.