Know we had a very close look at Pike as a templating engine but it's only one of three options.
Now it is was a quite extensive look because I also explained what templating engines are and what their
core logic is.
It'll be a bit faster 42 overlaying which just for the other two solutions.
Let's continue with handlebars which does not follow such a minimal Tim approach but uses normal Tim
L mixed with some templating logic.
So let's use handlebars and Fortius.
Let's go to aperture.
Yes.
And in there we now need to change our view engine.
Now we did install express handlebars but this actually is a package that is not auto installed by express.
So instead we manually have to tell express that there is such a Express handlebars engine available.
And for this we first of all import it and to find out whether you do need to do this for your favorite
engine or not you'll simply check their docs because there does this mentioned to express handlebars.
We at Express.
Yes the name is up to you by requiring express handlebars.
So now it is important.
And now we have to tell express that this exists that this is an engine.
It can use.
We do this by calling app and now there is engine Methot and this registers a new templating engine
in case we're using one which is not built in pi was built in kind of express handlebars is not.
So to register this we have to define a name for our engine and you can use any name you want though
of course you should try to not clash with the built in engines to which you all to find a link at the
end of this Montral by the way handlebars is a name we can use for example.
So let's give this engine this name and now we just have to tell.
EXPRESS This is just a name.
Now what is the actual tool I should use.
And that is express.
So that object we just import that dead just turns out to be a function we can call and we have to call
that basically initialises this engine you could say.
So this function returns the initialised view engine which we can assign to engine here.
So Express handlebars gives us this engine and now we have to switch the engine here to handlebars.
And obviously this name here has to match the name you set up here.
It does you're good to go.
Now you're ready to use handlebars in your coat.
Now how do you use it.
No you do create new files for this.
And let's start with the 4 4 H.T. male page ultra 4 0 for handle bars page.
Now we have to name it handlebars here.
Asked Is this a default by express handlebars and we find this as an engine name your.
You can also change the name.
For example do abs like this and now you're able to use thought abs as an extension so this is how that
works and how you register handlebars as the view engine.
Now with that just let's use it and let's take the four of four HDMI all fall and copy its content into
D 4 0 4 HP Saval because handlebars uses normal HD mail with some custom syntax.
Therefore there is no minimal H.M. version as was with Plag.
Now in this file let's remove that act of clause on that link and the navigation because that's still
wrong in that file.
I now want to change that here.
I want you output that title dynamically so that you can see how that works with handlebars.
Keep in mind that in APT Yes where we load that for 0 for page we are passing in does data and the way
you pass data into templates doesn't change with the engine.
This is always the same type of flow you pass in an object with key value pairs where the key is and
therefore indirectly all of the values are available in the template just the way you use it in a template
differs from engine to engine.
And in handlebars we output this value year by adding double curly braces opening and closing and between
these we add page title so that key name for which we want to output the value.
And with that if we save that and we go back and reload some page which does not exist we should still
get Page Not Found this time handled through handlebars and just as before with Paga if we inspect the
source.
We of course see no handlebars code the curly braces was simply replaced with the content that should
be rendered.
So this is how we use handlebars.
And now you we're feeling confident with the help of the official docs where you'll learn how to use
IF statements and loops.
Feel free to go ahead and all that you've placed the ad product pages with the handlebar equivalents
Otherwise we'll of course do that together in the next lecture.