So let's work on handlebars now.
For now without delay.
So let's go to the ad product HTL page and copy that over into a ad product.
HP says fall like this.
Now this is now our ad product page.
This is all looking good.
Now let's output the page title dynamically and we're not using a layout for now I will show you how
this would work in a second too.
So let's add to Page Title Act of KLOS should here be on add product.
No need to assign this conditionally because we're in the ad product H.B. as for any ways here does
this not in the layout.
And now let's all go down there.
This should all of course still work.
So this was pretty straightforward I guess.
So if we now save this and click on Add product to work and this is now rendered by handlebars because
that is our view engine.
Now let's go to the shop team l fall and let's copy all that code here and add Shop on.
HB as fall here at step code here.
Title becomes shop or better dynamic the output page title and now the interesting part of course is
here in the main section there we can comment in this code.
So let's remove the comment tax here.
And now I want to loop through all the articles and then of course also changed the image here does
is still the old not working image.
Let's take that new image link I added in the pocket template.
Let's move that into your q like that.
End with it added Let's now repeat this article for all the products we have and show no products found
text.
If we got no products for this we need to use a new handlebars next which you obviously don't know yet.
Maybe you explored it in the official docs are wise let's edit together here.
First of all there is and if helper you still add your double curly braces here.
But then you add a hash tag for a special block statements block statements simply are statements which
are not just outputting some text but which actually wraps some content that should be output conditionally
or in a loop.
Here we can that if keyword and check if Pre-OT's length is greater than zero.
So it's the same condition as in the pack template.
Justice syntax is a bit different.
Now we want to output this article we're actually not the article the entire grid.
So it's actually switched at the entire grid here.
Let's indent this indentation here.
Doesn't matter but makes it easier to read.
Here we want to wrap this.
And now we want to close that lock a dnt and we do that with a closing statement where we all have.
If you're by the way if you're all asked to sit next to the hash tag.
So this opens the if block with the condition then this content is only rendered if that condition is
met.
And then we close it.
Now of course we all want to have an outside block so let's add this here to hash tag Altes extend the
key and there we simply put the content we want output.
If the condition is not met no products found with that let's save that and let's go back to the shop
and we get an error.
The problem we have here is that handle bars doesn't actually support statements like this.
It just supports the output of key is that true or false.
Now this means that we have to move that logic from the template into our node express code and pass
the result of this check into the template.
So we would go to shop genius and there we actually add a new key value pair we pass into the template
has products maybe.
And this simply holds a value which is the result of our check here products.
So this product's array here length greater 0.
So now we just pass this key and there which is true or false.
The result of this check and this is a core difference to pack already besides that H team L thing here
in handlebars.
We can't run any logic in our handlebars template.
We just can output single propertys single variables and their value and we can only use these if blocks
too.
So here I can now check if Hafs product is true because dessous now the data I pass into this template
and this actually also has a positive side.
It might sound very complex but it forces us to put all our logic into the node expressed code where
our logic typically should live and keep our templates lean because if you put too much logic in your
templates it can be hard to understand your code because you always have to check both your expressed
code and your templates.
Otherwise you know the template is really just about displaying stuff.
The logic always happens in no would express.
So these are two kinds of philosophies.
It's up to you to choose your favorite But this is how Express handlebars or how or handlebars in general
handles this.
So now with this change we can reload this page and now we just have a problem with else here.
But that is just that it's not hashtag.
Just to else just the keyword.
My mistake.
Sniveler reload.
We have no products found.
And if I do add my first book here we do actually see that.
However this of course is not the values we have in our products array.
We have some hard coded data here because I still have to add a block where we loop through all products
and this is done with each block statement with hash tag each.
And then you pass in and array Pre-OT's in our case.
So now Pre-OT's is passed into this loop and now in there this element is repeated for each element.
And we also have to close as with slash each.
After we're done repeating our code.
So now this block of HTL the code is repeated for every product.
The question now just is how can we access this product and here handlebars.
Also gives There's only one way.
It gives us this key word which refers to the element India array forward occurred iteration.
So to each product so therefore we can output this title here.
For example because this will always refer to one product and one product still is a javascript object
as stored in the array here in the Edmon just fall an object with a title key.
So now if we save this and we reload this page.
Now we see first spoke here because this is the title we assigned.
So this is now how handlebars works and it's really important that you understand this different philosophy
of having less logic in the template more logic in the node expressed code.
So you have to prepare everything there so that in the template you don't have to write any javascript
expressions.
Therefore does this.
Now the project converted to handle bars.
Except for one thing and that is of course the layout.