Handlebars does support layouts but it works a bit differently than it did with Poch.
First of all we have to configure something in app G-S where we register our handlebars and then we
have to pass some options.
Now my ID helps me here if I controls space it shows me which options I can set.
And you can of course explored your official box to learn all about them now what it allows me to do
here is it allows you to set up where my layouts live so which folder I can find my layouts.
Let's set this year to a string which by default is the layout so you don't need to set this but you
can set it kind of to reconfirm this but this is redundant.
You only need to set it if you would store it somewhere else like in Les's or if you had a different
default useful or I'll send it today even though that is to default so that you'd see that setting.
Now you can also define a default layout that should be used for all files.
And here I'll just name it main and that means you will have to have a main or main layout.
In my case you will have to have a main layout but H.B. as fall in your layouts folder.
So let's add a main layout.
HB as fall in the layouts folder and let's set it up similarly to the POC layout and that was of course
influenced by you for a for a page let's copy overdye for a for HTL code into the main layout code.
And first of all Peytral found.
Of course we want out of this dynamically or we'll output the page title here with the handlebars handlers.
Now regarding the styling in Pike we did find a block where we could dynamically add the content that
should be rendered from inside the view that extended this layout.
Unfortunately HP doesn't have such a feature so we can't do that we can't define a block here.
Instead the only thing we can do there is we can define a placeholder with three curly braces.
Opening a closing so not normal double curly braces but free curly braces and then adding body here.
And you have to exactly use this placeholder.
This is understood by handlebars and you will then be able to target this in your view that extend the
layout automatically because you just said it as the default layout.
However if you have some part like this where you need to add some styling depending on the page you
are on you will have to solve this differently in a kind of a similar approach as we solved the act
of class here in public.
You will have to add if statement here.
Your main layout and this is of course a bit of a more cumbersome or complex way though you can do way
more with handlebars.
You could define custom helpers to help you with that.
But this is beyond the scope of this course where I just want to give you a brief introduction.
Let me show you the easiest way of solving this and this is that we add the if block here and we check
if product C-s s and if this is the case let's all close the if statement here.
Then I will add a link.
To buy a product C is as follows.
And I will repeat that same logic of course for Florance.
And again as I said this is the easy solution but it will do for now.
So forums here we have forums CSSA.
So this is working now.
Now what regarding the act of class we all want to add that dynamically right.
Well again simply at the class here.
And I add my handlebars handlers here and at the if statement to check if act of shop is true.
And this is a variable we'll have to pass into this view.
If that is true then I'll at the act of class.
And of course all the clothes may have statement so he can also write this in line.
That is an important take away.
And I'll do the same for the ad product route here where I check if active at Productus truth.
Of course we'll have to make sure that these variables are also passed into the view at least when they're
needed.
If you don't pass them they're always treated as false.
So you only need to pass them if you want to have them treated as truth.
With that our layout is prepared.
Now let's go back to the shop Chia's fault who starred with that and as I just mentioned we now have
to pass in active shop does it is variable or does property we're checking for here in the statement.
And we should set this to true for this route to ensure that for this route the act of Klaas's added.
So let's set this to true and therefore in the main layout this will be true and therefore actif will
be rendered active that product would be false because we don't pass it at all and therefore this would
not be rendered.
So that is that.
Now of course we also need to make sure that the product C as S gets rendered.
So we need to pass in this to.
So back and shop.
Let's all pass in product C-s essence add this to true.
So you can already tell you configure a lot from inside node express when using handlebars and that
is its philosophy.
So now with that set up we can go back to lay out have that finished and move over to shop abs.
Notice we'll use to lay out by the fold.
You could this abled is by going to the render function for a given page and setting a special layout
key and setting it to false.
This is a special key that is understood by handlebars and it would not use the default layout.
Otherwise it will.
So since it will do that by default in shop H.B. as we can get rid of this entire code here.
Occluding the.
And just half in this fall what should be injected into our triple curly brace body tag in the main
layout.
So here what ever should get entered in displays should be added to shop abs and nothing else.
So if that if we save this and we go to the shop you'll see we get an error and the error is a bit annoying
to be honest with Express Helleborus it's looking for the main layout thought handlebars file.
So it does not take dot HP sir.
And for whatever reason you explicitly have to tell handlebars to do that differently you have to go
to the options and set the extension name which only applies to the layout and not to all files just
as this applies to all files but the layout you have to set the stage here.
HP Yes this is really strange but it is how Express handlebars works.
So now we're setting the extension to H.B. apps for layouts too.
And now if we reload this page we see our normal shop page and with that we can of course also go to
add product here at product HP s remove everything but the part which should be rendered in the place
of our body triple curly brace body tax.
And if we reload something's missing right.
Do you know what went wrong.
Well we're missing some styles and the reason for data is that we need the forums and for this however
we need to ensure that foreigns CSSA is set to true.
We will also need product Zia's s by the way so it admin.
J.S. we should ensure that when we rendered this route we set forums C-s as to true and product CMS
as this one product CSSA to true and that we also to get that active link in the navigation that we
also set active at product to true because active at product is the key we're looking for here.
With that if we save all files and we reload here.
This is looking better.
And now it's all working again with handlebars.
So as you can see handlebars uses a different philosophy.
Definitely something you have to get used to.
Therefore your templates are leaner and there is no better or worse way of doing this.
It really is up to you which one you prefer.
Let's now have a look at a third option Ejaz which is my personal favorite.