So now we had a look at POC and at handlebars to possible templating engines you can use and if you
plan on using them definitely dive deeper into their docs not want to show you my favorite templating
engine will use for the rest of this course and that is Ejay s.
Now each pass is a templating engine which is just like Pac supported out of the box so we don't need
to register the engine as we did it with handlebars.
We can remove dead.
We can also get rid of that handlebars import.
And here we just set the engine to Ejay SNL.
Now E.J. asks has a very nice syntax in my opinion and has a nice mixture of DX 10 that functionalities
of Poch so not regarding the team.
But regarding the javascript code you can use your templates that you can do things like that.
A simple comparison here and shop Plack file this comparison here with the if statement which we couldn't
do in handlebars.
That is again possible with Ejay ass and do this the nice thing I like about it and still it uses normal
time.
Just like handlebars which I personally always like.
But of course you can follow along in this course with any solution.
I will stick to EJA as though an old source code will therefore be provided with that templating engine.
So let's use it then.
And let's start with the good old for 0 4 page again.
I'll add my 4 0 4 dot EJA ass file and go in there.
Let's start with the HD mail code again and let's copy that into that file here.
So all d for 0 4 h t Moloko.
Let's move it in there.
Get rid of that act of class which still incorrectly stare.
And now we got this set up now.
E.J. S. does not support lay outs but we will find a solution to at least have some kind of reusability
of certain building blocks.
But for now let's just create the whole document in that file.
So this is now our page and let's start with the Thaila again and let's output that dynamically now
in handlebars we use double curly braces in Poch we used hash tag and then single curly braces in each
ear as we use a smaller than sign and then a percentage sign.
And then if we just want to output a value in the place we're placing this placeholder we add an equal
sign right after the percentage sign and then we close this with just a percentage sign and a greater
than sign.
So this is the syntax.
And now here we can output the data which our template receives and justice before the method of how
we receive.
That hasn't changed.
So we can still output page title here just as before.
So just to bring this back in memory in Abdoulaye as we're passing in that page title here and therefore
we can reference page title in our template.
So this will still work.
And with that we can already test this.
If I now save it as an I reload here I get an error for at product because I've got no Ejay as template
for data yet.
But if I enter anything else which is not found.
We do indeed see our not found page rendered frue.
E.J. S..
So this is now working.
And with that let's move on to add product.
Let's add the at Dasch product.
E.J. s file here and in this file.
Again I'll just copy in my ad product HVM l code here.
I also want to output the title dynamically though.
So again our syntax year which we used just a second ago.
Let's output the page title here and then the rest can stay as it is for now.
Now the more interesting part is the shop file because there we all need the if statement and the loop.
So let's add our shop thought E.J. as file and in that shop thought each case file here.
Let's copy in the HVM code we got here for the shop and let's make sure we all take that new image here.
Let's copy that from one of the other files then move over to shop SJS and replace that here.
And with that now let's remove these comments again so that desists part of our page let's remove that
part up there.
And now in this file we can of course again simply output our title equals page title as we did it before.
But the more interesting part are obviously the if statement and or loop.
So we want to output this grid here only if we do have some products now and if statement is placed
a bit differently then with handlebars we still use are smaller than percentage sign syntax but not
an equal sign because we don't directly output a value here in this place.
Instead you want to end close.
We want to wrap a certain block of code and we do this by adding our opening and closing Ejay as tax.
You could say like this.
And now in there and that's the cool thing you can write vanilla Javascript code.
Now we know that we will get in our shop here.
We will get a process key which holds our products array and this will be an array and therefore here
what we can do is we can write a normal javascript if statement so normal javascript code and that is
really important.
And simply say Pre-OT's length greater 0.
And if that is the case I want to render dis So there ofter after descript I also closed this important
you simply close the curly brace which you also have to open here at the beginning.
So in the end what you do is you write an IF statement as you would write it in a javascript file just
that the part inside of that statement is not javascript code but this HTL code and I find this to be
very straightforward and easy to understand.
So it is our statement here with the opening curly brace and once we're done we close that curly race.
Now we can of course then also combine this and add a ELSE block here just as we would do it in normal
javascript again and eventually once we're done.
Also close that.
And now here we can output our age one tag where we say no products found.
Now that is nice.
Let's see the action by saving and by now going to the shop page and indeed we get no products found.
If I now do add a product on add product to your first book we do see it here so the statement is working.
Now again of course we want to loop through all the products and output our data and vedette again.
We use the same logic as with the if statement we create simply the normal javascript code you would
use for looping and there are multiple ways of doing it.
We could use broths for each to use this for each function.
Vanilla javascript supports or we use an all for loop.
We could say for let product of froths and then we simply open a curly brace wrap all the content that
should be repeated and once we're done we add over HHS Tech where we close that trollied brace again
using normal javascript and then we have our product in there and now we can again output it as before
with this E.J. as equal syntax as I like to call it here basically does inline output syntax.
And now of that if I reload this page here with the object object that is my mistake.
Obviously we want to access product title because product indeed is an object.
So now we see the title does is Eja.
And I prefer disinfects because I like having that flexibility of being able to write some javascript
code in the template whilst having a clean syntax that nicely mixes with HCM.
Because I personally like using HDMI L instead of the minimal werfen pack offers us.
But as I mentioned you can go with any approach you like.