Now we added some Ejay as magic or some as templates your one thing that is missing here is delay out
functionality pack or handlebars gave us and indeed Ejaz doesn't have layouts but we can use so-called
Parshall's or includes by the way a feature that Pike and handlebars also know.
The idea here is that you have some code blocks which you reuse in different parts of your templates
and you can therefore just share them across your templates.
So it's a bit like the opposite of a layout.
Instead of having one Mostert layout where you put your individual view parts into it you have a couple
of separate shared parts which you can merge into the views you're creating and for it at all create
a new subfolder in the views folder which I call includes and then name is up to you there.
I will treat a couple off shared files or shared code blocks and which code do we share across all our
views.
Well we certainly share this part here where we have like the beginning of the HTML document including
the title including the main C S S even and then we share the body of each document so we all can outsource
that even though it's not that much code right now.
But that might change if we have a common script that we import everywhere.
We also shared the navigation so that are free include files.
I want to create here head E.J. s for the start of the document.
And E.J. s and of course you can name these files Harbury want and navigation Ejaz.
And now we'll just go to D for 0 4 Ejaz fall.
Grab the beginning of the page.
Everything that is shared kept it out of here and move it into my head Ejaz.
Now I just need to import this and this can be imported into the 4 0 4 Ejaz fall by adding our Ejaz
syntax.
Now with a minus and you use stat if you want to output unescaped h team l code that by the way means
that by default if you have decent X with the equal sign and you would render some variable that holds
a string that holds HVM l code it would not rendered it h tim Alico.
But to render it as text to a why it cross-site scripting attacks with the minus you can of Y doesn't
really render D.H. HTML code.
We can do this combined with a keyword offered by each S.
The include keyword which allows us to include a certain element into this page and then you close that
with the normal Ejay as tack without the minus.
Now here in include you simply add a string which holds the POF two to follow you want to include and
you have to enter this POV as it's seen from the file you're in.
Sort of four or four just fall.
Is in the views folder.
So the follow one include isn't a subfolder So we just have includes and then had e.g..
Yes and this will now take the H Tim L code in here.
And as I mentioned then also render it here.
Let me save that and let's go to some route that doesn't exist.
And we still have a valid document here as we can prove if we open the page source.
So this all works.
Now we're using an include by the way if you use an equal sign here.
You see now it gets rendered as text and that is what I meant.
Does is escaping devalues.
So it's not rendering it.
So if you had some script tag or anything fishy in there it would not render it.
It would just displayed as text and therefore protect you.
But if you know what you're doing like we do here because we wrote the code we're including we can and
we should of course include it as age to him.
So this is now using a include and we can also use it for navigation.
So let's take all that navigation code here put it into the navigation Ejay as file and in there will
also have to manage the active link again.
I'll come back to that in a second.
For now let's just go back to four for each case and here again I will just include includes navigation
SJS and close that and last at least the end of the document is all the shared even though it's very
short.
Let's move that closing bawdy and H.T. mail tag into end each as and let's share this too.
So here at the very end I will have include includes and UJA ass like this.
Now with all that out of the way I can still load this page just fine and it works.
Now let's also implement this and this is of course a great practice for you too.
So feel free to pause the video.
Let's also implement this for the other two templates we have.
Where are you as successful.
Let's try it for at product Ejaz dare.
We also want to take our common code here out.
So the start of the document not the two links which are exclusive to dis page are those of which we
really only need there but instead of the other part we can now include our includes folder and there.
E.J. us to bring back that start off the document here and add product.
You obviously need to replace more like the header.
So there we also should use include and then go to the includes folder navigation.
Close that and close the tag.
And all do the same for the end of the document since we did that before include go to include us.
And then here includes And then there we have.
And each Yes.
So now we get this in there too.
But of course one problem we face if we reload this page is that our act of class is gone.
So we need to bring that back and market is navigation item as active.
If we are on the product page now for this let's go back to the Edmund Jaspal real quick where we do
render this route and there let's remember that we already added this path for pug and we can reuse
that functionality.
We can go to our navigation each last fall and then add a class here and there simply output something
rendered for Aegeus.
We can do this in line with the equal sign so we don't need to enclose a block of HVM code and simply
check if Poth is equal to.
And now the payoff here is slash admen slash at product.
So basically the payoff which we define here and if this is equal I'll use a turn their expression here
which is in line if statement in Javascript.
So here we have the condition and if data is mapped we now do whatever comes after the questionmark.
So then I want to render active here and since I'm inside the class text here I will basically just
add the act of Klosters is how you can read this.
Always keep in mind that this simply gets replaced with text when the template is rendered.
So this will just become class equals active.
And then I add the outer condition with a colon and else it's just that a read or nothing.
And now I can copy that here.
That class assignment and do the same for for for ad product where it is shipped belong there where
I did it originally I should check for just slash because dad is actually the Poth we set for the shop
here and shop.
Yes dispatch.
So now I got this in place I'm checking for two different posture and it rendered the act of class based
on that.
And Daylesford if we save all of that and we reload the page we got at product added here.
Now let's go to the shop.
Jay Jay last fall there.
Let's do the same.
Keep d link.
Which we need in that file which is the product C S S fall and replaced the our part with our general
include.
So in the includes folder there we have had each as file replace the navigation as we did it before.
So there we have include includes navigation SJS and of course all the replays.
The body of the document.
So here we have include includes and Ejaz like this.
And now with that if we save that to go to the shop page it looks like it did before and we should still
be able to use our application as we did before but now we're using includes which is kind of giving
us the same experience as with layouts.
We have to repeat all this include code all the time but that is OK and we still benefit from having
shared code.
So with that out of the way we got AJ s added and we'll continue to work with that for this course.
And I hope you got a solid understanding of why we use templating engines which options you have and
how they roughly differ with that.
You should of course be able to choose your favorite.