So it's time for a quick summary and clean up.
First of all let's clean up since we're using E.J. s now.
We don't need to layouts folder because we only use that for pack and handlebars.
So let's delete layouts here.
We also can delete all HP as HVM L and pack files here because we don't need either of those.
We just use T.J. as files.
Now let's delete all these faults.
Now does this much cleaner and not just one to make sure that you really understood the flow of how
data flows into the templates and what the templating engines do.
We do render a template with a special render method provided by express choice that render method will
always look for the register engine something we do here at the beginning in app yes we do register
our JSF view engineers.
In this case by setting this special duty engine configuration reserved configuration key which is understood
by express to us.
We also tell express chase where our views are to be found though dad actually would be the default
setting here by the way.
So you don't need to add this if you do use the views folder with that express.
Yes.
Will code render we'll take our templating engine which we still have to install separately as a NPM
package.
Keep that in mind.
We did install Aegeus as we did install pike and handlebars and then you always just refer to the name
of your view like we do here at product Aegis.
By the way if that were it in a subfolder like products it would simply refer to it like this.
But then you just referred to that view without adding the file extension and you can also define an
object which will hold the data that is passed as variables into that template.
So not the entire object is passed in there as you learned but instead you will have a page Thaila variable
a way label in the template.
You'll have a path variable away label in the template and so on.
And this is why we can use something like this year dessous now syntax.
Understood by the specific templating engine we're using Ejay s in this case.
It simply detects these tax year and then it simply looks for a variable named page title and tries
to output its value well and finds the page title.
Because we do set a page title property here and we got more features than just outputting values.
As you can see in the shop Ejaz file we can also use if statements or for loops and you'll learn the
different words of this for the different engines in this module.
So this is how to templating engines work what they do and why you use them.
And it's important to keep in mind that in the end if you inspect the source code you always just get
back inaudible.
Tim Allen code you don't find any Ejay as code in here or any javascript code.
Does this just HDMI all the code that is generated on the fly but also on the server does is not code
that would be generated in the browser.
It's generated on a server on the Mont. for a request forgetting and templating engines all to do some
advanced stuff like caching some built templates for you if the data input didn't change so that they
can return the template even faster and don't have to rebuild it for every request even if the data
didn't change but that some behind the scenes stuff.
For you it's important to understand the general flow.