A lot of exciting things were covered in the last modules rest API is a single weight and we'll continue
on that road.
We'll dive into a very exciting technology that you can use in node applications web sockets web sockets
are a nice way a protocol essentially which allows us to build real time web services.
Now what exactly does that mean and how does that work.
That is what we'll cover in this module.
You'll learn why you would want to use real time web services and what that actually is and we'll see
how we add real time communication to our node app or to any node app of course will use a certain library
for that socket IO and I will teach you everything you need to know about why to use it how it works
what you can do with that and how you use it in your project.