Let's start with the status quo how does our application we both thus far work.
And with that I'm not just referring to that arrest API but to the shop we built before that.
Q How do typical node or node express applications work.
We got our client we got our server the client would be our browser mobile phone or something like that.
The server is of course essentially what we built our node application.
Now thus far we always sent the request from the client.
We waited for his request on the server.
We set up some routes to handle different kinds of requests.
And once we're done doing something on the server for example reach out to a database we send back a
response to the client.
So first request then response.
Now that is how our application works thus far.
And this is how most web applications work.
And by the way we're now not going to replace it with something totally new which will then use all
the time.
This is a fine pattern because a lot of resources on the Internet should be available biogas pull approach.
So you pull information from the client you tell the server that you want something.
Does the typical approach and is a fine approach.
But sometimes you have a different requirement.
What if you want to send something from the server to the client so what if something happens and you
want to inform the client.
Let's say you're building a chat application user aid on PCa or on his mobile phone sends a message
to user or B.
Now obviously they're not sharing the same device.
They might be in two totally different places on the world.
Now User A sends a request to the server that contains the message and disserve restores the message
in the database and the server can return a response to user.
But User B the person with whom user chats does not send the request to the server asking for the message
or at least that is unlikely to happen.
You could certainly use some patterns where you send the request every second to see if there are new
messages.
But you'll then hammer your server with requests were most requests will not yield new messages.
So instead it would be nice to have some push way off and forming User B about the new message.
And that is exactly the scenario we're looking at here.
What if something changed on the server and we actively want to inform a client well then we can use
web sockets instead of HTP.
Now HTP is the protocol we used thus far.
Where we send the request and we get a response.
Web sockets built up on HTP.
They are established via HTP.
They use a so-called HTP handshake to upgrade the HTP protocol to the Web sockets protocol and the web
sockets protocol that simply talks about how data is exchanged.
Right.
So this protocol is something you don't have to manage.
Actually the browser and the server communicate through a protocol and protocol defines how the communication
can happen with HTP It's request response with WEP sockets.
It is push data are actually it's both.
We can also send data from the client to the server does is still included.
But most importantly and that's the feature I really want to highlight here.
We can push data from the server to declined and you can and you typically will use both together in
one in the same nodes.
So it's not like you have to decide do I build an app with web sockets or do a build one with HDTV.
You still have a lot of places where you want to use that request response pattern.
For example if you were sending a message or if you're creating a user.
These are operations where you do send some information from the browser to the server.
So there is a request response narrow makes perfect sense.
But if you have some active notification you want to get to your users then you all want to integrate
web sockets.
Now let me show you how to add web sockets to your project in the next ELECTRESS.