Now for adding web sockets you've got a broad variety of methods to use.
If you google for node web sockets or node Express Web sockets you'll find a lot of articles and packages
you can use.
One of the most popular packages however is socket I O Succot I know is a package that uses WEP sockets
and gives you a lot of convenience features around that protocol that make it very easy to set up a
web socket channel.
But when a client and a server and to use that channel you can learn all about it here and the official
docs.
Does this nose socket I O course so will not cover every single feature it offers.
But I will show you how to add it to a project and how to set up some basic communication.
So socket IO is what it will use and socket IO and that is the key thing I want you to understand does
use the web socket technology the web socket protocol and sets it up behind the scenes for you.
You don't have to use socket I O to use WEP sockets though you could use one of the Avar options I showed
you on Google before there are packages that give you a more raw approach with less convenience features
and that might be what you're looking for for specific operations.
We'll go with the convenient solution of socket I O here though and I strongly recommend diving into
some advanced resources if you want to learn all about web sockets or socket I O specifically.
So how can we add it to our project now.