Want to use Socan I'll.
And we have to add it on both the server and the client.
So both on the node appier and on the re-act up because client server will communicate through web sockets
so we have to establish that communication channel on both ends on the front end react and on the back
end note.
Now let's start on the back end here.
And for that I'll quit my development server here and I will install this socket IO package with NPM
installed dash dash save Succot dot IO let me enter here and this will install the package in your node
project.
Now how do we use it.
Well let's go to actually yes.
So the first file that runs when we start our server and there we should set up or Succot IO connections.
We want to expose just as we set up our routes there.
In the end we forward requests to our routes.
And you could have cords all the socket I O set up in a different file but I'll do it here.
But just as we set up our routes Florida normal HTP requests we can also set up our socket I O channels
and keep in mind socket IO uses a different protocol.
Web sockets and therefore web Succot requests will not interfere with the normal HTP requests which
are sent by default by the browser.
So how do we set up socket IO here.
Well once we connect to our database when we start up our server there I also want to establish or I
want to set up my socket IO connection.
I tried a new constant I know and I will require the socket I O packets here this package or the thing
we are exporting here actually exposes a function which requires our created server as an argument.
Now the list method here does actually return us a new node server so we can store that in a constant.
This is the notes server we spun up.
It's stored here.
We have to pass that to a function returned by require socket I O.
So we add parentheses here to execute that function that is returned by socket IO and we passed a server
to it.
This sets up socket I O.
And I mentioned that web sockets built up on HTP.
Now since this server here uses HTP we used that HTP server to establish our web socket connection that
uses that HTP protocol as a basis you could say.
Now this gives us an i o a socket IO object which does set up all the web sockets stuff behind the scenes
for us and which we now can use.
Now we can use it to define a couple of event listeners for example for example to wait for new connections.
So whatever in you client connects to us.
So then we execute a certain function where we get the client the so-called Succot disconnect as an
argument or the connection as an argument to be precise.
So this is the connection between our server and the client which connected and this function will be
executed for every new client that connects.
So not only one time but as often as required as many clients as connect.
So here I will for any client connected.
And right now if I run NPM start will never see client connected in the console.
You don't see it here because we established all that on the service side.
We now got a waiting socket connection or port.
You could say but we got no client which would connect and that of course is the next step we have to
do.