You want to go to our re-act app and Daryl quit the development server to and here I will also install
and you package with NPM installed dash dash save and that will be a socket on Io dash client.
So it's a different package name it's socket IO dash client because it is to code that will run on the
client.
Hit enter and this will install that package into our Riak project.
Not once does a stun go to defeat it japes fall in your re-act project and they are at the top.
First of all import with that Front-End and ports and text that differs from the back and send texts
and you can learn more about that in my re-act horse.
But their import open socket you can name it however you want but this will be a function that opens
and you Connection use socket implored open Sarkin from Succot IO dash client.
So from that packet you're just the start.
So this exposes a function on the client too.
And this is a function that allows you to connect.
Now let's go to that component that Mount function your where we load our first posts and so on.
And after we loaded these posts here after this line let's call this open socket function.
And now you need to define d.
You are on a server where you've established your socket IO server and that of course is our back and
server address.
So it's HTP localhost ADHD.
Nothing else is required.
And please note you do use HTP here because web sockets build up on that.
And now this function which is provided by Succot I will do all the heavy lifting behind the scenes.
And if we now safe that we restart our front end to the back is running as well.
Let's wait for that development server to restart.
So of our application here in the browser will actually reload.
And now this should have already executed this open socket code because the page did reload.
So if you now go to the back and you indeed see client connected here because now we got an established
connection between a client and our back and application through socket IO and all the other normal
HTP requests will still work as before.
Now let's use that connection for something useful.
And let's see what we could do with that socket IO connection.
That would make sense in our appier.