If we have a look at our application you're What could we do in real time.
Well what would be interesting is that if we create a new post with user aid that we can instantly see
it with user be to and for that we need to add some code in our client.
And then also on our backend Now let's actually start with the client.
Let's say we want to react to a new post being created and we then want to render it in the client instantly.
For this in my re-act that offer this component that MT function before lotos let's say I'll add a new
function at post with this.
So next I expect to get the data about the post as an argument.
So I'm using a normal Erol function here.
And then here I want to render that post to the screen.
Now for that since this is not a re-act course I prepared some code which you find attached to this
video.
Just copy it here in this code snippet we're using some re-act functionality set state to basically
update our existing data we used in this re-act application with this new post received here.
And I will take care about page nation to insert this post in the right place.
That is the end what I'm doing here.
Important thing is dead.
I'm using some re-act functionality here so that we don't have to reload the browser page.
I simply changed the existing dorm.
This is what re-act will do for me with this code snippet.
And as mentioned before if you want to learn more about re-act dive into some dedicated re-act resources
of course.
Now we got ADD post but we're never calling it.
My idea is that I want to call it whenever we do create a new post on some other client.
Now how do we do that well.
For that let's go back to the node code.
We have to go to the place that's runs or to the code that runs when a new post is created.
And that would be in the feed controller to create post function of course.
There we want to use socket.
I owed the existing connection we have set up to basically inform all connected clients about the new
host that is the idea.
Now for that however we need to share that connection which we currently set up and actually yes.
How do we get that connection out of actually into feature.
Well let's do that and continue with the set up and next lectures.