To be able to read was one and the same I O object dad manages the same connection that is exposed.
Let's create a new file name its socket touchiest a name is up to you though.
And in that file here I will create a new variable which I'll name I own.
And then all export with the notes as exports and takes an object in that object I want to have two
methods to functions the init method.
And does how you define a function in no chase syntax you have that key here like in a normal object
then a colon and then the value and the value here is a function which receives the HTP server as an
argument.
And then the function body using an arrow function here of course in the function body you require some
video.
So just as we do it and actually yes here we require socket IO and we passed a server to the function
that gets exposed by the exported object or by it it exported package.
So here I awls execute this function and I pass in that HTB server I expect to get here as an argument.
Now the result of that is our i o object which l store and that I O variable here and then I can return
IO like dis Indian function in Aperture.
Yes I can now require slash socket.
So my own socket Yes file.
And there I will call init dysfunction.
I just a find in there so this function I call that and there is still passed my server because in that
function I expect to get that server jarocho here does not change its stays the way it is.
Yes I now just add another function.
So an average key value pair in that exported object.
So let's add a comma and then I'll name does get I O.
The name is up to you just as it was for in this.
By the way here I don't expect any arguments but in the function body I'll check if I O does not exist.
So if this variable is undefined in which case I'll throw in a new era or socket I O not initialized
or something like that.
If I make it past as if Geck I know that I O has been initialized and then I will just return it.
Now is this.
We're managing a connection in this file and we can import this fall in all the places of our app where
we need to be able to interact with IO like our feet.
JS controller so let's continue with that next.