Knouted we have a way of sharing our I O connections across multiple files.
Let's go ahead and in feature as an air controller on the backend there I want to use that I O or that
socket js file.
So here maybe above my Alber imports I'll add and you import and I'll name that.
I know the name is up to you though and I will require dots going up one level and then slash socket.
So this file was just created.
I will require that object for it.
And there I can now call get o to get my existing IO object which I do initialized first.
It actually is right.
We initialized it here.
So this will be initialized by the time we use it here.
So now this is how I import the year in V-chips.
Now instead of create post I now want to use stat.
And of course in create posts I want to use it once I'm done creating the post essentially.
So right before I sent my response back and that you're responsible to go back to the user who created
the post will not change does we have to send back a response.
But now I want to inform all of our users and for that I can use aioe and there I can call get IOE to
get my established IO object or connect Should we set up an app.
Yes and now there are a couple of helpful methods.
The I O a socket I O package gives you one of them is emit.
They're all would be broadcast the differences that emit will now send a message to all connected users.
Broadcast sends it to all users except for the one for which this request was sent.
Knobbly actually go with all users with emit Then you define a name and that name is totally up to you
all name it posts
and all to find data when I send this all up to you.
Typically it's a javascript object and you're all sending an object with any data you want all to find
the actual key to inform declines.
What happened to the channel you could say is posts but the act now is create and that is just one way
of implementing this of course.
And then the posted was created will be stored in let's say a post key and that is the post which we
do savior.
So I'm sending this post object in this data package on this post's channel you could say now that we're
sending this to all connected the clients in the next step will have to adjust our client side code
to also reacts to such incoming events.
And for that I'll go back to my client side code and here in component that mount in the future just
fall I want to set up the code to listen to incoming data from socket IO because in my app the events
I broadcast or I commit on the server happened to be related to post which I'm managing to features
fall in the end.
So here is where I'm interested in.
Well changes to that.
So in component did mount ofter opening my socket I would actually store something which is returned
by open socket and that is my socket.
So the socket the connection which was opened.
I'll store that in a constant named socket.
The name is up to you.
And now on that socket we can use to on method to listen to certain events.
And now here we want to use that same event name we used on the backend.
So dare I used posts if you use something different you now have to change that and your front end too.
So I use posts on the front end that they are for listen to the post-event and there we will get some
data.
Now I know that due to the set up I chose here my object which I send back and will have the action
key that defines what happened to posts but that's just the pattern I established here.
That is not enforced by socket I O.
You can send any data you want here.
You don't have to have an action key.
I want that though because I'll actually send different events or different kinds of operations on posts
through the same channel eventually.
So here I'll have my data object and I can check data action and see if that is equal to create which
in my case it will be for that event I'm emitting on the backend.
And then I want to call this at post.
So this function we created before and all pass data post because again I'm creating this whole set
up.
And I know that on the backend that data package I'm sending from socket I O will have a post key with
the post that was created.
So that is the post which I will send to at post which will be rendered by that code.
Then and that is it for now let's save that and also save all your back end code and go back to the
application.
And now to see that in action I'll actually fake to have a second client so I will actually open a different
browser Firefox and this is essentially the same as if it would run on a different PC now.
So these are two browsers are now like two different machines and you can tell by the fact that I'm
Loddon not locked in when you're on Firefox get a little display back here but we can ignore that for
now.
So let's use let's say the test to user create a different user if you don't have one.
And now I'm logged in on Firefox on the left and on chrome on the right now on Chrome does a test user
and on the left it's a test to at test dot com user named Max.
Now let me create a new post your own name that a duck and choose that duck image here and click except
and you see it to show up on the left to you also see show up on the right.
Two times simply because there I also get informed about this created post from my socket because I'm
not filtering to not send it to the client who sent the request and since I also have some code for
rendering the post in my finish edit handler and the features fall if you scroll down a little bit here
the post will show up there as well to prevent this from happening.
I can remove as elative case and I was saved as all the pages will automatically reload.
And now let's try this again a cup.
Let's Schuester Cup.
Mitch except and you see it show up on the left side.
Q And that is the interesting thing.
I never reloaded the page on left and still we see didn't you post show up there.
That is simply due to socket IO where we have an established connection on both clients now and thereafter.
It also updates on the left or Anstiss item on the left due to the code we added on our front it.