By the way if you're wondering why there is no name be displayed.
I have a bike on my back and code you're in get posts we should add populate creator to not just fetched
treat or ID but the full object for the creator and uncreate post.
Well there we have the issue that the post I am sending for a socket I O is just a post object where
I did at my creator ID but not all the creator data.
Now how can we fix that or how can we add more data.
Well we can send the entire post underscore doc data so all the data about the post but set to create
equal to an object where we do have the underscore ID that will be our request.
User ID
but where I also then add my name field which will be user name and user name can be used because of
fetching to use here and that will be an object which also has a name.
So that's just a little tweak We want to add to your to send all the data with a created post that we
need on the front end.
We now save that and we reload we get the data up because of that change and get posts and if I now
add a new post and number DAQ choose Adak as some content except we all see the name there.
Now both users are named Max but still keep in mind the left user are locked in with is a different
user than on the right and still we get the updates here due to socket IO.