Now we worked on code that allows us to mid end event and we create a new post.
Now obviously we're not just creating posts rules or updating or deleting posts.
We want to be able to handle that.
Q Now let's do that together and let's continue with updating posts on the back end of the feed controller.
I'll scroll down to the update post Methot and in there we won a midnight event.
Once we're done updating.
So towards the end once we got our result we saved the post and we're sending a response here.
I'll again use IO get IO to get access to our established I O connect.
You could say and again emit on this post's channel and I'll limit my data just as before.
Now I will keep my pattern of having an action where I this time right update because this ISDE action
were performed and my post asked and my result here calls for assault.
Turns out to be the result of my saving operation.
Now just as before I want to be sure that I also have some user data in there so will actually scroll
up where we find that post and how well populated with my creator data.
This again will take that creator ID which we stored in the post object.
Reach out to the users database for the users collection fetched data for that specific user and added
here in our host.
Now I do admit this event where I sent my created post.
And let's now go back to our front application year and also establish some code here to update our
posts for this ofter does add post function.
I'll add a new function which I'll name update.
Post Re again get my post data and then I do something with that in the Arrow function and ask before
I prepared some code which we just copy in there which will add or which will update to post in our
list of posts.
Now also scroll down in your re-act code here in the same file to finish edits hndler because there
were all to have some logic to edit the post here.
I will get rid of debt.
I will actually get rid of this entire part here and also of my update post assignment index returns
statement in set state call because I now no longer updated here but I do admit the event to all connect
clients including to clients who did well sent that update and therefore I can also set up my listener
and stead.
With this new update post function I copied it up there.
So let me now go up and here where I have my established Lisner 40 post-event.
I'll add the else block to see if the action maybe is update.
If it's not create in which case I'll call this update post and past data post to that.
Now before this will work let me go back to the service side code and there since I do populate my creator
when find that post in the update post function near this check your will actually fail where I do check
F.D. ID which is now not the ID any more but the full Creager object is equal to the request user ID.
So here I actually want to access creator dot underscore ID to string right because we're populating
to create field with the full user data.
It's not just the ID anymore.
So you would fail editing this post.
If we don't make this change and now if we save both and we go back and reload both pages I deleted
one post in the meantime so I only got to any more.
And let me now edit this post here and a couple of thanks to my remarks maybe and click.
Except and you'll see it added or being changed on both clients.
So this is not also working.