So now we also manage updating why a socket I.
There's one tiny thing you might be wondering about.
If we create a new post like a duck again.
Where I at the imagines I'm content.
It does show up at the top but once I reload it's actually at the bottom of the list.
Well there's simply Ju-Ju How has sort on the back end.
When I get all posts here in a feature Ask controller get posts there we simply have to sort
by created at date in a descending way.
And now by doing that if I reload on the front end our latest posts come first there too.
So that's just some tiny cosmetics which better align with the rest of our application of course.
It doesn't affect the way we use socket Io of course.