We're now using Sokolow to successfully update and create posts.
Now let's of course awls a line deletion of posts.
And for that let's first of all go back to the back end quote to defeat the controller and find our
elite host methods here.
There it is now just as before.
I won a mountain event once we're done deleting.
So I will do that right before I sent my response here let's say I will use i o get I O to get that
connection and then I will admit to the Post's channel and I will keep my pattern of defining what happened
to my posts instead of the data package I'm emitting so I'll add my action which I'll name delete or
where I have a value of the lead I should say and then my post field here is just a post ID perps written
like that which in this delete post function.
I am extracting up there so I'm passing that ID through that event.
I'm now emitting Frue socket IO.
That is what happens on the backend.
Now let's move on for undealt to react.
Code of course and there just as before.
We want to do something when we delete the post and I'll keep it simple.
I'll simply reload the page here.
You could of course implement some cohered that simply finds that post a change and just delete said.
But I'll keep it relatively simple and just load the entire page.
If we scroll down a little bit to the delete post handler here we can tell for all the comment out this
code and instead just call this load posts to reload the page but reload the posts.
Essentially this will make sure that page anation also is considered correctly.
And now if it will up again to component add mound where I have my listeners for Succot I'll I'll check
if the date action might be delete which is the latest action we're emitting on the server and then
I just call this load posts to basically load all posts again.
Now this my Front-End code and now they go back to my application and I do delete a number.
Here it reloads and it also reloaded the posts on the page as you see.
So now we're also orchestrating deletion to have my trust multiple clients fruit socket IO.