So in we had a closer look at some video and I hope it became clear what you can do with it.
You can push information from the server to the client through that emit method provided by socket IO.
And I also mentioned that socket IO is not the only way of implementing WEP sockets because behind the
scenes it's that web sockets protocol that allows you to push data from the server to connect the client
socket I O just makes using that WEP socket protocol that technology particularly easy and therefore
it's a very popular package definitely dive into the official docs office socket IO to learn all about
the different features it offers and what you can do with it because it's a very powerful library it
gives you a lot of cool features.
So definitely check out the official docs to learn more about it.
And of course also have a look at our implementations you might be able to use.
I just want you to be aware that web sockets are something that build up on HTP you established them
as you'd see in our application as a HTP handshake.
So you need a running HTP server ever set up with just no JSM or a package like Express and you can
use that server to establish Succot a socket connection on top of that.
So both run simultaneously.
And as you see in our example app we actually got both going on we got normal requests.
So to say and we take advantage of socket IO as well.
So this is an exciting piece of technology that might be interesting for your next application too.
And I hope that this module provided a nice introduction to it.