Now before we dive into dynamic routes you need to adjust your project of it ever because you skipped
the last module altogether and therefore you should download the entire snapshot I attached to this
lecture which contains my latest state.
But you should also download that snapshot or the adjustments file which contains the files you will
need to add to your project in case you don't want to use my snapshot.
But if you skipped the last module always go of the snapshot now when you adjustments up file and you
can ignore that if you download the snapshot in the adjustment zip file you will find that javascript
followed the main js file which you should move into a J s folder in the public folder.
You will also find that main Zia's as file and the product Zia's as file in there and you should also
replace yours and this is as folder with the ones you find attached because I find you in some styles.
Additionally make sure that you also replace all the views you'll find in that attached zip file and
you simply replace your existing files or their content with the attached files or the content yet hatched
falls.
And with that added.
And in case you are facing any problems simply take the snapshot with all that added.
Let's now start writing our dynamic route code.