So time to extract this idea from the you are an.
And for that let's go to the route's folder there in shop J.S. we want to handle a new route and I will
add it below my all products Routier.
It will be a good draw because we want to display a new page for now.
And part of tipoffs products but that's not everything.
We also have this dynamic segment the ID d express router supports us with this.
We can tell the Express router that there will be some variable segment by adding a colon and then any
name of our choice like Product ID.
Later we'll be able to extract that information by dead name here.
So remember it.
The important part is to Colan here though this signals to express that it should not look for a route
like products product ID but instead that this partir can be anything and it will simply route or load
this route for does off then and we will then be able to extract that information through that name.
Does has one important implication if you will also have another route like router get products to delete.
Let's say.
So that is a normal route.
Does this not a dynamic segment the order would matter if you order it like this.
And keep in mind that your code is parsed from top to bottom and the request goes frood at from top
to bottom.
If you order it like this you would never reach that route because if you had a route like product still
it expressed as would already fire at this route or would already handle it in this Routier because
delete would basically be treated as the dynamic segment.
So if you had at an emic segment and a specific route you would have to put the more specific route
first.
So for products delete does handle the request enter offer.
It'll not continue its journey because you don't fire next.
But if you don't have something else which does not match products delete then you would go into debt
dynamic route.
So this does matter here however we don't have that case.
I just want to mention it.
So for now let's simply connect a controller where we then can handle this incoming request and where
I then can show you how you can get this information out of the you or else.
And for this let's go to controllers shop genius and they're simply add a new controller.
I will edit been below get products the position doesn't matter.
But logically here we get all products.
So now I also want to add the function where we get one product.
So here we'll have get product BP's response next like this.
And in there.
Let's now extract that dynamic Pop segment or the value it holds to be precise.
So this will be our product ideal store it in a constant named proft ID.
That name is up to you.
And we can get access to it by accessing our request and then expressed as already gives us parents
object on our request.
And on that parents object we can access our product ID and we can access product ID here because we
use product ID in our rollock shop as file as a name after the colon.
So the name you use year after de colon is the name by which you can extract the data on this Perrin's
object.
And let me show you that this works by logging this Prod. ID and I will then for now simply redirect
to the starting page later will of course render a different view.
But for now it will do.
And with that I can now go to shop yes and use my controller here.
So connect the shop control or get product function here.
And with this connection setup if I now go back and please note I'm still on that route with the dynamic
segment.
If I now reload this I'm getting redirected.
Which means we handle this.
We don't get the 4 or 4 page anymore.
And in a console your eyes see my dynamic segment locked out from does line and that of course means
we can not just log it.
We can also use it.