Knouted we're able to output our dynamic segment here.
We can of course used that information to instead load that product from our product file.
So for our product model which is responsible for interacting with the product and then we can return
a view which does actually show us these product details.
So for loading lets get into our product model now that we got to save them we get fetcher all.
Now I want to load a single product and Vardis I'll add a new static method and lame find by id the
name is totally up to you of course.
But there I expect to get an ID as an argument.
And then also a callback which will be executed once we're done finding the product here in this function
here.
I will get all my products because I basically need to read the entire file.
We got no database here where I could run a query for one product only.
We'll do that once we add a database of course.
So for now I get all my products just as in my fetch all function your.
But here I now have my products a way lable.
And before I returned them in the cold like I want to filter out that one product with my ID.
Now keep in mind products which are returning here is already a parsed array of products and our product
will have an ID right.
We assigned it id here and we stored it ID.
So we will have an array of objects where each object has an ID and therefore we can now use normal
javascript to filter out the product we interested in.
I can simply find my product and store it in this temporary variable there.
I can find it.
Why is searching products with the find method default javascript method.
This will execute a function we pass to find on every element in the array and will return the element
for which this function we pass returns true.
So this function we pass year will get.
The product is currently looking at because it executes it for all the products in the array.
It will pass us this product into the function and then I write an arrow function here and there is
a short arrow function syntax where you can omit the curly braces.
If you only got one line in there and you all returned a result of this one line so there is an implicit
return statement in front of that code and I'll now right.
So I will have one line of code here which is returned and there I will check if the idea of the product
I'm currently looking at is equal to the ID I receive as an argument here.
And if this is true then the product which I'm currently looking at will be returned and stored in this
constant here and therefore I can then execute a callback with that product.
This is a synchronous function doesn't execute any async code.
So simply having two lines after each other will do the trick here.
So now we have that fine by ID function in the model.
And now in a shop class controller we can use that.
So instead of logging the prod ID here we can log product referring to our model.
Remember we're importing the classier product find by a DB though we can't block this because that will
be an asynchronous function.
We have to pass in a callback.
So here instead I pass in my prod ID and then I will get the product eventually and in that function
here I will now simply locked it for the moment.
So did we see if that was retrieved correctly.
So back on the product's page.
Let's view the details again.
That works.
And in the console log on the server we indeed see the details for the product reloaded.
So this seems to work.
Now let's also verify that this still works if we add another product here.
I'll add this and indeed we see the product here so this is working and now have a click.
The details link here on the products page.
I also get the information for this product and the link of the image is so long here because it's not
a or L to an image stored on a server but actually the image encoded in base 64 which is like a text
encoding techniques you could say.
So this is the product and this is our fetch product function working.
So it is a next step.
Let's add a view that displays the details and obviously feel free to post a video or two.
Well this video ends here but to go ahead and do this on your own we'll do it together in the next lecture.