So let's add a view or we do have you but let's add some logic in that you infer this all take the code
from one of my other simple views like orders each class and pasted in there so that I got the hat and
also my navigation and so on.
Now in here I don't want to output nothing there of course.
Instead here I want to output my product information so my product detail for this I will quickly give
those main elements to a class of centered and find you my see is as code real quick.
The main idea is as follows.
Let's simply add a class can added anywhere.
All added relatively top centered where I said text align to center for now so that everything is centered
horizontally.
Now in there I'll put my agent one task and there I expect to get information about the product we loaded.
So here I want to get some product and output the title.
Now right now we're not rendering this view and we're not passing the data into it.
But eventually we will.
So here is my title.
Then maybe render a horizontal line and then display an image for this product because we got it right.
So I will add a div here and in this different image and there I will output product image.
U r l datus the field in which you are storing the image.
Check your model in case you're not sure.
And as old text output product title now below the image I want to output to tag where I output my product
price like this and believe that a paragraph with my product description just like this.
So that is my detailed page there and if we now saved as we have to make sure that we render this view
for our detail route.
So in our controller where we do get this single product data instead of redirecting here I'll remove
that and instead of logging this to the console all say rest render.
And I want to render my view into a shop folder and there is the product Dasch detail view.
So basically the filename here product detail and we have to pass some information.
We do that by passing a javascript object and in there we now need to pass in a product property because
we're accessing this here in the view.
So back in our shop J follows.
Let's pass product and set this equal to our product.
We're retrieving your product on the right side of the colon is the product for retrieving product on
the left side is simply the key but which will be able to access it in the view.
That Let's save that and go back to product to load the details here and we get an error or that we're
missing the page title showing us which Linus following the error and old tells us page is not the find.
And this makes sense because in the head of our of each page we're outputting to page title here.
So we also have to pass that into our view.
So in shop JCR let's make sure we don't just pass the product but also the page title.
And here we can actually use product title to dynamically set the page title to the title of the product.
With that simply reload this page I'm also missing the POF now because in the navigation we're using
data to determine which path is active.
And now there the question is which path do we want to highlight in a navigation file here.
We obviously have no ports no link to this exact product but I think it makes sense to highlight the
products link here because we're still in the product area just in the detail for a single product.
If we want to highlight this the POF we should pass is slash products because that's the payoff We're
checking here.
So in shop.
Yes.
File said pove to slash products here because this is the POV for which I want to mark the navigation
item as active.
Now if we reload.
Does looks better.
And now this doesn't look too shabby.
We got a nice detail page here.
Does the trick for NL.
Let's maybe finish it up by adding add to cart button below the product.
But with that I'd say this is what we need for the moment.
So let's go back to our product detail Ejaz file and below all that information.
I will now add a little forum which leads to cart with post request because I want to add that product
and I'll add a button with class button and type submit and the route for this is missing still where
I say Add to Cart.
And now if that if we reload we got that but you're too.
So this is now working.
And this is looking decent.
With that I'd say Why don't we work on that.
Add to card functionality as a nextstep.