You now learned how you can display product information by getting that information out of you or else.
Now we have a similar problem for adding a product to the cart.
We get that add to cart button but in the end when posting our data we also want to know which product
to add to the cart.
However here I will send a POST request right.
Andrew Card sends a POST request and this has one important implication.
We can pass data in the request body.
This was not possible for a Gach request but for a POST request you typically use the request body.
This is also what we use when adding a product for adding a product.
We have a forum and as I mentioned there when we added this the first time and of course this automatically
gives us a request which puts all the input data and so on into its body.
But this only works for posting data.
This is not available for getting data but for posting data we therefore don't need to add anything
to the U R L because we can put the information in the post body so damn for what we should do on product
detail in this forum as we should simply pass some important information as part of the post request.
So I will add input here and I will make it of type hidden so that it doesn't really get displayed on
the page but still is encoded in the request that is getting sent and I will give it as a name of product
ID the name is up to you though.
And now we all need to store a value here and that value will be the value that is added to the request
for that product ID.
And here I'll use it again to output product ID.
Because I still want to pass that ID to my back and so to say to my node express app but I don't want
to use u r l because I do use a post request so there's no need to use it.
You could do it though.
You can also add a dynamic segment for post requests.
That would work too.
But there is no need to do it here.
So let's pass that data with that hidden input and let's now work on the back end on our shop js file.
There we got get the cart but gift card is not the route we're working on right now.
We'll use that to display the card then.
But for now I need a post request.
So let's add a new route which accepts a post request.
Still to get it to slash card.
That doesn't change but now we need a new controller function and we'll add one here.
Maybe in your get card maybe in front of it or offer it.
That's up to you.
Exports post-cart.
And there I also will get my request response and next function as arguments and any here.
We will now have to retrieve the product ID from the incoming request and then also fetch that product
in our database.
So in our file and add it to our cart we got no card yet though.
So this is all something we'll have to work on.
For now let's simply extract the data as a first step.
The prod ID by accessing request and now it's part of the request body will access request body here
and then Product ID because product ID is the name I'm using.
In my view here on the hidden input therefore your I got does away label.
I can console Lochness for the moment
and thereafter I can simply redirect.
Maybe to just slash Cartier and does will then load to get route so it will render the card page so
with that let's go back to the route's file and let's connect to a newly created controller action with
the poster out there.
So post-cart should be connected here.
And now if you safe at and you go back to the details page.
And for now only there.
This button will work.
And you click Add to Cart I'm on the card page and then the console we see that random ID which was
generated that random number being locked.
So this is working.
Now obviously we're not storing that in a card right now.
And before we work on that let's actually go back to the product detail page and grab that entire form
here and make sure we also use that form in all the places where we also have added two cart buttons.
So let's add it on the product list each as file.
Now important.
There I also have product idea whaleboat.
So I Ole's X as a product feels that this is working here and it's added to index J.S. Aegeus and they're
all they have for product object available which is not important all the time of course because I'm
accessing product ID here and since this is exactly equal in all free use we can also add include add
to cart Aegeus and put dead entire code into that include here and then simply well include that include.
So instead of having that code here in each case we can use DHHS tagged with the minus to add include.
And then we go to well up one level and then NKU into includes and then add to cart and we use that
same code also in the product detail page you're And also in the product list page.
So dare I also want to replace this for him with my include.
Now let's see if that still works if and I'll go to products.
Now we get this error because if you have to include in a for loop or in a loop in general as we have
it here we're looping for all the products and then product is a local variable available in that loop
only then and include included in the loop.
Unfortunately it doesn't get that very well by default but you can pass it to that includes here and
you can do so by adding a second argument to the include function where you again pass an object and
simply add that variable again.
So here this product is what will be available in include and on the right side you include where you
add the value you have available in this fall product in the loop is now past two product in the include
does of course needs to be done for all our includes So also in the index each last fall and not 4 to
1 in the product detail though because there it's not inside a loop.
So it's a way to blic globally and therefore works.
And now the reload here does we're ex starting page works and the details page also still works and
we can go to the card on all these pages.
This is looking good.
Berle's output and yet this is working now as the next step will have to work on that cart.