We work that out on the cart model some things are still missing.
For example we never display our card and we also never really we're not able to delete an item from
the card but let's ignore that for the moment.
Let's instead focus on editing a product.
We've got the added product each as file and in the end what I want to do in there is I want to render
the same form I have for ad product.
The difference will be that I want to create populate that form with the values of the product I want
to edit.
Now if I'm using the same HDMI code in the end it would make sense to reuse the same template if you
ever plan on using a different one it doesn't but it makes sense.
So what I will do is I'll take my ADD product Ejaz code and move it into edit product because I find
this to be the more generic name and I'll delete the add product Ejaz file.
So now we just have added product each S with all the time code in there that we need.
Now first of all that means that I have to load dat file in admin.
J.S. when we load get at product I no longer need the add product lbf I need added product here only
the part on there can stay at product because that is what we use for highlighting a certain navigation
item but a way we can get rid of these additional additional information pieces.
So now this should still work if I click on Add product.
I still see that form.
So that's looking good.
However for editing a product I now also want to have a route I don't want to use that same view so
I'll copy that route.
You're an added maybe below post at product to keep these two together.
And here I will have get added product as an acronym and I also want to render edit product here.
The difference is that here I plan on passing in my product information.
But the problem is of course how they reached as control or action.
And my idea is dead since I already have my edit button here.
If I clicked that I don't want to call added product like dis.
I also want to get the idea of the product I want added.
So if I grab a real ID from my products Jason fall like this one.
Then I would have data and you are all.
And if I load this now I want to have to form pre-populated with the data for this product and if I
hit the save button I of course don't want to create this product but simply edit the existing one now
this means that I need two things.
The idea I need to pass that and the information that I want to add is the product instead of created.
Well if we go to our admen routes we can add a new route.
First of all there's added product Routier with the ID and you'll learn how that works actually you
can add a new route to your route.
We'll be at slash and then here the slash Aben is available for all routes and the Edman Jaspal.
Anyways as you know so it's just added product.
And then the idea and again this is a variable.
A dynamic lbf segment indicated with a colon and then we can load the admin controller and there d get
added product.
Actually we just add it.
So this is step number one.
And actually we now already can go to our admen chase controller.
And here we obviously know that we want to added a product.
So what we can do is we can pass an additional information field to our view editing and that's true
maybe so that we can check with the if condition to find out.
For example if upon clicking that save button we should try to add the product and send a request to
that route or try to edit it and send it to a different route.
But let's say we want you get an additional confirmation by ensuring that people have to pass us a so-called
kukri parameter in the euro query parameter can be added to any you l by adding a question mark and
then a key value pair separated by an equal sign like edit equals truth.
And you can have multiple query parameters by separating and with and percents.
So we could all have title equals new for example.
So this is possible.
And this is so-called optional data.
The Here is a route which gets reached is determined by the part up to the questionmark.
So you don't need to add any information about query parameters.
You might get to your route's file these pauvres are not affected but you can.