So to populate this forum with the product data we need to fetch the product first.
So for an added note here after not being redirected then I want to get my product information for this
I need the product model which I already have and I need the product ID fraud ID can be retrieved from
the incoming request because if you check the routes real quick we have that dynamic segment here.
So by this name we can extract the Product ID.
So Edmund J.S. here I can set or I can access request parents product ID and get that ID from the URL.
Therefore I can then use my product model and find this product by id and then here I have my callback
where I received the product that was retrieved and by the way of course you should also try to add
a check to see if you have a product and redirect to user in case you don't let's do it like this for
now.
So here I will now get my product and then rendered this page assuming that I always get a product and
pass my product on a product key and you can name Diski whatever you want of course.
And we can for example add a check if we don't have a product so if this is invalid if it's undefined
then we could return a redirect for now which is not the best user experience.
Most of the time you would want to show an error instead.
But let's now for now do we like this.
So we assume we always make it here and we get the product in the view no.
So let's move over to the edit product to you as you're first of all let's work on that button.
Right now it's at product.
But I want to change that button caption if we're in added mode.
Now remember we're setting this editing property year so this is a variable away that will in the template.
So here I reasonably want to check if editing and then add a curly brace.
If this is true then I actually want to display the added or maybe update product texture on the button
Oberweis and for dead all clues the first IF block here and Attah else block still in my Ejay as tax
of course.
So overwise year if we're in this Altes block here I want to show at product and thereafter I also have
to close my curly braces off that if statement if and I'll reload this page we see Update product correctly.
And by the way if they go to add product I'll now get an error because editing is not defined.
So to fix this I also have to make sure that in my controller for showing the ad product page eyes that
editing to falles of course and now you're reloading this page will work.
Going back to the editing page will show us the update button.
Now that is one step back to the template.
I don't just want to show the caption here.
I also want to change the action so here on the forum the router is setting the request to should all
change of course.
Right now it's always add product but it should only be add product if we are not in editing mode.
So here indeed.
I will also output something dynamic
I will check if we're editing.
So all have the same logic for de Botton.
And if this is the case I went to load slash edit product let's say our wise all closed that and have
my ELSE block open up so Oberweis does is my Ejaz else block I'll add add product into my u r l here
and I can inject these segments into DO YOU OR.
Because this will just be converted to normal text in the end.
Does this what each asked us or what all templating engines do.
So all the clothes that curly brace of the else block here and with that if I saved this we should make
sure that if you click that update button we go to add a product.
Well let's go back and let's see if we can pre populate this with product information.
Now keep in mind that in Edmond J as I am retrieving the product whip's not here but here and get at
it product and I pass product information into my view.
So therefore in the view we can of course use that.
And we can set it on all our inputs here on value.
I also want to check if I'm in editing mode and if I am I want to display my product information if
I'm not I don't want to do that.
So same logic as before
all check if I'm editing if I am then I will display product title here because this is the title input
Oberweis I will not do anything and therefore I don't even need Altes block.
I just DUDAS if I am in editing mode.
Otherwise nothing will happen.
So for now reloaders we indeed see product title and the issue here is that of course this is simply
output as text to output the real value behind it.
We need debt equals Ejay as tag here nested into our other Ejaz tasks like this.
So this was now added equals unclosing with a dollar sign greater than sign.
And this can be hard to read.
You simply have to divide it up in blocks you've got if then you've got the output and then you've got
the closing curly brace for and with that safety if you now reload you'll see the real title behind
that and let's do the same for all the other values.
So I'll just copy that value here real quick for the image you are l.
I always want to output image.
You are el for the price.
I want to output a product price for the description we get a text area.
So here I will not have value equals I'll just output the value between the opening and closing text
area tax.
And here I'll put the description in it if that all saved.
If we reload this is looking good.
And now we can start editing our products.
Now I want to hook up that edit button so that we can really load the product and this newly added view.
So let's do that.
And then also work on the functionality to store the updated information over the next Electra's.