Let's make sure we can reach that Adut product page from a route and Free-Net on our products page you're
on the Admin Page this added link your added product should also include the idea of the product.
And again we can use Ejaz to simply inject that into our POV by accessing Product ID.
That's all we need here.
If we now reload this page and click Edit we get redirected.
What could be the issue here well remember that we added our query parameter right and were checking
this query parameter in our controller and if we don't find the added query parameter added will be
undefined and therefore we get redirected.
Now this is of course just a bonus but it's important for you to understand how query parameters work
and therefore we have to set this to when creating our linked to this page.
So let's go back to products Ejaz and don't just add this idea but also simply append that query parameter
set added equal to true.
With that if I now save this and I go back to aberant products and click Edit.
Now we load this product for editing.
So this is looking good.
Let's make sure the clicking update product which does already reached a correct route dust and also
do something vidis First of all in Edmond J.S. we need to register this route.
So let's add a new post route which is at added product.
This will not receive any dynamic segment because it's a post request so data can be enclosed in the
request we're sending.
So let's now work on their controller here.
And add new action post edit product which of course receives the request object response object and
the next function as all our middleware functions which our controllers just art.
And then here what do we have to do.
Well we basically want to construct a new product and replace the existing one with this product.
This means that we have to do some work on the product model.
We'll do that in the next lecture.