Time to work on our product model again in there we get a safe method.
And right now we used it to create a new product.
Now why don't we all use that for updating an existing product if we already have it.
DUDAS what we'll have to do is in safe we just have to check if we already have an ID and therefore
when creating a new product we should accept an idea or two and then said this ID equal to ID but will
simply pass Nahlah here for a brand new product so that we can still create products that don't have
an ID yet then the ID will be assigned here.
But if I were editing one we do have the ID already so we can simply assign it here and then and save
we can simply check if this ID is already existing IF it now does will fail and will automatically make
it to the next line which we want.
But if we do have it Id save should not create a new idea and new product instead it should simply update
the existing one will still have to get all the products though.
So indeed this should be moved into our callback because we need all the products anyways and a new
idea creation can also move in there but offer this if statement.
Now in his statement I know want to update the existing product and for that I need to find it first
so find my existing product index again by searching for or going through all my products with the find
index method.
Products will be an array as we know and there I will get access to all my products stored in the temporary
Prod. argument here or in the argument of this anonymous function I should say and I can simply check
if the idea of the product I'm looking at in this array is equal to this Id put in other words if I'm
now looking at the product.
I plan on editing.
If that's the case then I found the index of the product I want to edit and now I simply have to replace
that in that product's array.
Sole trader.
Updated products aere where I used that spread operator again to pull out all the existing product elements
store them in a new array and then on that aere update products I'll replace my existing product index
with this because of this.
Inside of this class year is of course the updated product because you have to imagine that I create
a new product instance I will populated with information about my existing product and then I just call
safe and that we'll find out that I already have this product and therefore I just place it in the array
which is stored in the file with the newly created product I'm in.
So with debt being saved I just have to write that information to the file.
So as right fall is what I need to execute.
So this code will stay the same.
Just that I need to call it on updated products here and I will now also wrap the repartitioned the
else block so that not both snippets execute but only one of them.
So now we're storing the updated products and right file will always replace all the old content.
So we won't added or anything like that.
It will replace it.
And therefore we should now have a safe function that we can use both for adding new products or editing
existing products.
Now it is as one important implication.
We now need to go to the controller and when adding a new product here in post ad product we now also
need to set now as an idea as a first argument to your on our product constructor because we just added
this as an additional argument here in the constructor.
And if it is null then this check will fail and we will therefore make it into the new product created
mode which is what we want.
We now can also work on the post add edit product method there.
I need to do two things.
First of all I need to fetch information for the product then I need to create a new product instance
and populated with that information and then I need to call it safe.
That's first of all extract the product ID fraud ID by accessing the request and their essence is a
post request.
I expect to get that information that requests body.
However at the moment this will not happen.
So let's go to the view first to the edit product Ejaz file.
And there I need to add a new hidden input which stores the existing product ID.
However data is only an option if I'm editing a product not if I'm adding one.
So first of all I'll use it as to again check if I am editing and also close that's your we all need
to open a curly brace therefore.
And if I am editing and only in this case all render a new input here which is hidden so wished which
the user can see where the value is now my product ID.
So I'm using Ejaz to output the product ID there and this will now therefore be included in the form.
Now I just need to give it a name product ID maybe.
And now I can extract that Piedad name into incoming request in my controller so request body product
ID because of a used product ID as a name here in the view on the hidden input.
Now with that Id fetched I could fetch my product through the product model but actually does this he
added.
All right.
So I get the new values I want to store as part of my post request body because the user enters them
here in the form
here.
All this is sent to me so I will now simply store all that in values are in constants like my updated
title will be request bodies Heidel I'll have my updated price which is request body price.
I'll have my updated image.
You are out and you can name these Constans however you want NOW and or of course is what you access
your on the request body.
These keys have to match the names you have on your inputs in your well added product view.
Last but not least we got the updated description here which is request Wadih description and now with
all that data I can create an updated product.
This name is all up to you instantiate a new product therefore And here I do pass my existing ideas
to a first argument and this will ensure that in the product model.
In this check here we do find a valid ID and therefore we go into this updating mode instead of the
Add mode so old has to add ID at all past my updated title then I'll then also pass my updated image
you are l.
I'll pass my updated description and my updated price.
So this is what I pass.
And now thanks to our changes to the product model I can update updated product save and it should hopefully
just save that and override the existing one.
Now let's try this out.
And for that let's go to our advantage as routes.
First of all and registered as newly added post added product action on the Edit product post route
and now let's reload our page here and add a couple of exclamation marks and hit up that product.
And the problem is I never send a response so this failed.
But if we have a look at our product Jason File the first product didn't change but the second one indeed
has all the exclamation marks.
So this does work.
So the missing thing just is that we send the response in our controller.
So here after calling save I will actually call wrests redirect and go back to just slash admin.
Or let's have a quick look at the admin J.S routes.
I want to go to slash products so slash admin slash product.
I mean this is what I want to redirect to.
So let's save this
go back and reload.
Here we see the estimation marks too.
Let's change the price to 30 Daut 95 and also change the description.
It's really great.
Update the product we are redirected and we can already see the changes here and we can edit it again
of course.
For example remove the estimation marks.
So this is working.
We're now able to edit the product.