Let's edit the cart model now we got the static ad product i 90 a new static method which is delete
product or I get an idea of the product I want to delete
and I also want to get the price of that product can also name this product price because I'll need
to update the total carte price of course.
So with that what do I need to do.
Well first of all I need to get my cart so I need to read my file here and copy that line.
And of course you could also refactored this.
For now I'll simply duplicate it to code here to make it a bit easier to understand.
So there I read my file.
I try to read in the card and if I got an error here I can already return because that simply means
somehow I didn't find a card.
So there certainly is nothing to delete right so I can't just ignore this.
Otherwise we will continue.
If you get no error we'll continue.
And now is the part where I want to update the cart protists all have my updated card here and take
all the properties of the old card and put them into a new object with that thread.
Operator I now want to update both the products and to total price the card.
Total price should be reduced by the product price how ever this would be incorrect because if we have
the product in the card free times it should be reduced by the product price times free.
So that's postponed us for later.
That's first of all find out how often we do have the product in the cart and Redus I'll have my product
in next and I'll find the product in the updated cart in the products array with the find index method.
And there this goes through all the products and I'll check for the product where the ID matches the
idea of the product.
I tried to remove from the cart.
This now my index of the product.
However a year I could even find the product right away.
Just a product like dis because I will remove it differently from our products.
For now I just need the product to find out what the quantity is because remember we're storing the
quantity in that cute field.
So Konst product huge y equals product Kuchi why you don't need to serve that in a separate constant
just a bit easier to read.
And now is that quantity I can use that here to have the card total price be my card total the price
minus the product price I'm getting as an argument.
Times product.
Product quantity.
Sinaloan reduce the total price by product price.
Times how many times I had to product in the cart.
So that is one piece of information.
And now I can also update my cart products here products and set it equal to
snotted cart by way of the updated cart down there.
So updated cart total price up that a car total price and updated cart products is now updated card
products which for now is the old products array but dial coal filter again just as it did in the product
model there.
Dysfunction runs over all elements in there and keeps only ones where I return true.
So I want to return true for all products except for the one I'm removing.
So here I will return true only if the product ID is not equal to the idea I'm looking for.
So all Obert products are kept.
With that I can write the card back into my file by copying this right file and store my updated cart
there.
So this should now in theory work.
I can also go to the product model and there I now need to import my cart model so Konst card equals
require cart like this.
And now with that imported any year I can simply call cart delete product and pass the ID and I also
need to price now to get this I will extract my product before removing it so I'll have my product here.
By searching my products with the find method for the product where the ID matches the idea I tried
to delete.
So I got that product information here which allows me to pass in the product price to my daily product
Methot.
So now we are able hopefully to delete a product by its ID and also to then delete it from the card.
If it was in there.
And right now for example if we have a look at our card we do have that ID the milk can.
We do have debt in there so this should be gone if we delete it.
So now in the admin controller in Postol the product we can use product and then delete by id and pass
passing our prod ID here like this.
And then we can also redirect to slash adman's slash products.
Now by the way a little side note it would be best if we have a call back into lead by ID so that we
only redirect once we're done.
And the same is also true for updating.
By the way there a call back and save would be best for redirecting for now I'll not do this later.
We will add this little functionality but let's now see if that works.
If I delete the most you can hear I get an error card is not defined in my card.
J.S. model deleting the product work.
So if you check products Jason you don't find that anymore in the district but in the cart model Yeah.
I'm trying to get all cart fields but of course I'm looking at the file contents so I should use this.
This is a bit annoying because now I did leave the product while it's still have it in the cart but
it's no problem.
I will simply recreate it and then hack the ID into the practice chase Jason fall.
Let's go to admen products and a new product real quick test.
Get that image again.
Set the same price.
So did I correctly update my my cart price year and remove the correct price
and then some description test.
So now does exists again.
Now let's just make sure they copy the ID we have in a cart and replace the one that was newly generated
and products Jason so did we really well lead to correct from from the card to save all of that.
And now let's give this a try.
If I click delete if a reload does first of all have to be loading the new ID or two with a click delete
cannery property you find of undefined is not a problem and a card model and that problem here is that
of course is still a string Jason format.
So I need to parse it before using my file content.
So let's save this same problem as before.
I will quickly Riette does add some type text as the image doesn't really matter.
Set the price some time in texture will not see the image here because it is not a real link but that
does not matter.
Now before doing anything let's go to product Jason and again place the newly created ID with the ID
in a cart like this.
Reload this admen products page and click delete.
And now does looks much better.
Now it seems to work and then that card indeed Productus empty and the total price was reduced to zero.
So this is working.
And now let's finish this module up by also making sure that we do display hard items on the cart view
here.