We're already able to work on the cart.
Now when a display card items on cards s there I simply will add a main section before the end each
and include.
That's important.
Now first of all what do we need to do here.
We need to check if we do have products and if we do have them then we want to display them and I will
simply display them in a really boring list.
For now we can add styling later.
Just want to see if that works.
So let's go real quick to the shop controller where we load the cart and there.
First of all we need to be prepared to fetch all products because we want to return them to the cart.
However of course not all products we have just the products we have in the cart.
So it is we need to go to the cart model first of all we get the lead product and add product.
Now we need a way to get all the products in a cart so at a news static function get products here and
in this function I will exit my file and simply return the product IDs.
I need to get a callback date for which I can call once I got the products and then I can use disfunctional
here to read the file.
And in here I know I get my card this time doing it correctly with Jason Parr's follow content.
This is not a card.
And actually all named as get card and not get products because they will return the entire card here
and my callback does.
All I want to do now obviously this can fail if we have no cards yet so we'll check if we have an error.
And if that is the case I will call call back null here and I reply as in the else block here I will
return a card with valid values.
Now we can go to the shop G-S controller in get cart and here I call cart get cart I will have to pass
a function there to call that function I just added in the cart model where a will eventually received
a card and it will render my view inside of this function.
However I don't just need to cart I need a little bit more information about the products too.
So I will use my product model then to fetch all products here and I will add my call back here.
And make sure that this is nested in the cart function and we're having a lot of callbacks here but
it's still readable.
Later we'll also find a number way of working with a lot of depending async actions.
So I got my card and they got the products.
Now I just need to filter out the products which are actually in the cart so I will go through all of
their products.
So for product of products looping through all the products I have in there and I will check if this
given product is also stored in a cart and I can check this because the card we got the product ID.
If you have a look at card Jason here will store the product IDs.
So I'll check if cartes products if I do find this product here.
So if the product I'm looking at in the cart if the idea of that product equals my product ID here and
of course this is some code that can be improved if you store large quantities of data but we won't
store large quantities of data in our files anyways.
We'll use a database for that.
And therefore for now is perfectly fine.
And if I do find an ID in the cart then I know well the product is part of that and therefore I will
try a new constant your cart products which is an array.
And I will simply add that product to cart products then so card products push it I will add the product
I'm currently looking at in this iteration of the loop.
So this product I'm looking at if it's part of the card I'll add it to card products.
This means that after the loop is done I'll have an array of card products that contains all the products
which are indeed part of the card.
Now important just adding the product like this does not suffice.
Instead I'll add an object with product data field which holds the product and also quantity field because
the quantity is stored in a cart too but not in that product looping through because these are just
a product some storing in the product.
Jason fault obviously there is no quantity in there in the card.
However every product I store there does have a quantity attached to it.
So in shop.
J.S. here I will also store the quantity of the product I'm looking at nomics directing my cart product
here.
So actually all store it is Condes cart product data all store ID card product I'm finding in the card
products array in card product data and I'll check the existence of that then and if it exists I know
there is some data about this product in the cart ident stored the original complete product data from
the product model and from the card product data.
I'll take the quantity we got quantity and product data in there and we push that object to cart products
and cart products is now what I want to return.
So here I'll return a products field which holds card products.
This is sent to my view.
Now if we have no products in the cart then cart products will simply be an empty array and I can check
for that in my template.
So now let's go to the card each S file.
And first of all the if statement and check if products and remember products is simply this key here
I'm sending into my view.
So check products length is rage or Cyril and then close that.
And also already define Altes block here because I want to render something if we got no products in
a card too.
So here in the else block and you need to close that curly brace thereafter in the else block I'll rendah
h one tag whereas say no products in cart
like this.
But here of course I want to render the products in the first block of the if statement.
So here all render an order list for now where I simply loop for all the products again using Ejay as
products for each product.
And that is an anonymous function you're like that then close deep for each loop by closing the curly
brace off that anonymous function and then bracket off does for each method here.
Now in here I want you output the product information.
And now it's important to keep in mind that product here.
Maybe we should name it product data that does
does actually hold or does actually refer to a product with a product data field in a quantity field
and the product data field is the product I'm interested in.
But I also need to quantity.
So maybe even I don't name that product data but just Pete.
And then in here I can output the dot product data referring to that nested pro-black data which holds
the product information like the title.
So dot product data or title would allow me to put the title and then also maybe in brackets and there's
no Ejaz indexes n'roll hardcoded text here.
But then in there I use Aegeus again to access P-doc quantity and remember he simply is that object.
We passed that card products array on our back and code.
So now let's see if that works.
If I save this and I reload this card page we see no products and cart if I go to products here and
I click Add to Cart we indeed see that on our page.
If I add does one more time we see it twice.
So this is not working.
The last step is that I want to be able to delete it.