Let's make sure we can also delete items in the cart and vidis in CART.
Yes I will change my list item a bit in there.
I'll add a diff First of all.
Or maybe let's add a paragraph to be semantically more correct which will output to text for discard
items so things like the name and the quantity.
And then I will also add a little button there.
Wrapped in a form the form should go to card.
Delete item maybe the method will be a POST method and in the form I will of course have my button with
a class of button with a type of submit which says delete if we now reload the card here.
We see delete does the button we can certainly work on the styling but for now I just want to make sure
that it works.
Now it is the a delete button.
And if I click that it well should delete this item of course.
So card delete item is a route.
We now need to add and then let's go to route's here and shop.
J.S. because of course this is a costumer action.
Our customers will manage to cart and they're below the cart.
I'll add a router post Meffert cards.
Delete item.
Now we need a fitting action in the controller.
So in a shop controller here and there I got kept get cart and post card.
Now I will also have exports post card delete product maybe you could of course use any name you want
and then here will have to remove that product from the cards but only from the card not the product
itself.
Well to do that let's first of all extract the product ID from the request body product ID and therefore
we need to make sure that we pass it there too.
So in our form let's again add does a hidden input with a value of our P product data dot ID and then
a name of product IDs so that we can extract that by that name on our backend.
And with that added with this hidden input added here let's now go back into the controller and with
that Id Let's use a cart and then there we can delete a product right now that delete product function
takes the idea of the product and we do have debt.
But it all takes to price and therefore we should get that product information first.
Let's also call product find by here and get that product for does ID and add a call back with the retrieved
product simply so that we can get the price before we well issued the deletes request.
So in there in this callback I will call delete product and now I can pass in product price too.
And of course we could have also used a hidden input to pass the price to the back end.
But I think this is a cleaner approach.
If we only pass the ID Fruita request and then we do all the data retrieval on the back end in our node
expressed code.
So now we get to delete product.
And with that we can also send a redirect request back to cart and in theory this should be all we need.
Now of course the missing thing is that we connect our card lead.
I wrote to the newly created shop controller action the post cards delete product action and with that
added in the shop G-S file in the rabbits folder we can reload our cart page here.
Click delete and we see our products.
By the way you can ignore these errors on the right.
These are related to my local network here.
So now I got no products on the cards.
And if we have a look at our card Jason it's indeed empty product Jason still has the products though.
And if I quickly add another product with no real image like this.
So today if more than one and I add both to my card
and I delete just a bookkeeper only that is removed all is in cards.
Jason so this seems to work just fine.
Let's also delete this one now.
Seems to work good and with that we improved our app a lot and you hopefully get a bit of a feeling
for how you can pass data around and how you can work with your models now correctly you would say that
of course.
Our current approach or Namath's is a bit Suppe optimal because working with the file and so on.
It's not that great.
We can also improve some things in the controllers because for example as a set we should redirect if
we know that the deletions exceed it and not right after this line.
Because since we Axxess a file in there theoretically we should use a callback here too.
But these are all things I will do once we finally also added the database something we will do in the
next module now.
So time to move on to this exciting big block of the course.