Now I'm generally pretty happy with the state of this application.
But there is a minor issue in it.
If we have no products in a card or at least not the product which we're trying to delete let's say
to one on the right here.
We actually get an error.
And we do get an error because we try to access the quantity of a product which we just don't have.
And the reason for data is dead we simply use in our products just follow the all folder.
We used a cart model to delete the product from there.
Right.
The problem just is obviously not every product is in the cart.
So in the car here where we have to leave product we first of all need to check if a given product is
part of the cart.
So here when I parse the overall cart here when I find the product in the card I should check if we
really have that product because if we don't have it.
So if I add an exclamation mark in front of this.
So if this check here is true that means we don't have a product then I simply need to return here.
I don't want to continue.
I don't want to try to edited because it's not part of the cart so therefore now if I reload my app
and I quickly add a new product to your website with a price and a description like this and I'd then
click on admen products and delete this.
Now this works.