So that's it for this module.
Again we learned a lot and practice a lot you'll learn about dynamic routing and that you can pass dynamic
path segments by adding a colon to the Express route or path the named after the colon is then the name
by which you can extract the data on request parens as a side note.
You can have more than one dynamic segment per route.
It is absolutely possible.
You can also work with optional equerry parameters.
These are the parameters you append with a questionmark at the end of your u r l and you can have multiple
ones separate with an ampersand and you can extract these values with request query and then the name
of your Param.
Now you don't need to register or name these parameters in your route registry.
You totally don't add them there.
You can just start extracting them but since they're optional You should also have a check in place
to see if that parameter was passed.
In case you are depending on it we all continued working on models and we added a cart model which only
holds static Moffats because we don't we create a card that often instead we just want to work with
the data storage behind it all the sodded you can interact between models.
For example delete a card item if a product is deleted.
But as I also mentioned towards the end of this module it's not that good if we only work with files
for data storage because accessing them is a bit slow to be honest.
And in general there are better options.
Most importantly of course databases.
So let's move on to how we can work with databases in a node express app in the next module.