In the last module we had a closer look at no sequel or especially among or D.B and how you can use
such a no sequel database in our course would be the most popular no non-sequel database in a no JSA
application.
Hopefully you saw that it wasn't too difficult and still just as we have sequel.
We can abstract some complexity away from us and focus more on our data than the queries we write and
here just as we had sequel eyes for a sequel we got mongoose for Mongo DV and mongooses is indeed pretty
similar to sequels in terms of what it tries to do.
It tries to enable you to work with the data instead of with the queries.
So what's in this module will have a look at what mongooses is in detail and how we can add it to our
project and how we can start using it and then we'll.
Well we will use it.
We will use our no chess application.
I will give you a thorough introduction to Mangu is also show you where you can learn more about that
if you want to dive deeper.
And we will transform our project once again to move from A.
We write all queries on our own approach to q we just define how our data should look like and then
work with it approach.
So that let 7.