So what is mongoose Mungo's is a OTM an object document mapping a library.
And that's really similar to equalize which was N O R M object relational mapping library.
And the difference of course Justice that would be is not a relational database.
It's a document database.
It thinks in documents and hence we have a odium here.
So the idea is the same though we have some data some entity and our application.
Let's say a user and we want to save that to a collection we want to map our javascript object to a
document in a collection that could look something like this.
And of course you can write a query for that on our own.
That is exactly what we did in the last module but it would be a bit easier if we could just focus on
our objects and our data and see how it should look like and then work with it and there's not even
the final syntax you see here.
We can use mongoose a bit differently than you see it here but even that would be a bit more concise.
So just a sequel.
Mongoose tries to allow us to define models with which we then work and where all the queries are done
behind the scenes which of course does not mean that we can't influence and that we can't change some
things.
The core concepts are that we work with schema and models where we define how our data should look like.
And then we have so-called instances where we instantiate our models.
So where we create real javascript objects we can work with that are based on our blueprints.
And once we get that set up we can run queries and there we again use our objects we use our models
and we can then query the database.
But Fru mongooses with various helpers we get some syntactical sugar and so on.
So that's the idea behind Bangu is really similar to what C-Class did for a sequel.
And therefore with that let's say Ivan let's add it to our project and let's see how we can use it there.