Now first of all let me show you the official docs.
You can always wizard mongooses jast dot com.
And there you can dive into the full docks to learn everything about mongoose all its details all its
advanced features which will not cover in this course because this is not a good course.
I just want to give you an introduction to Mangu is here so everything can be seen in great detail here.
But that being said I will walk you through all the core fundamentals in this course and in this module
of course and we'll also keep on using mongoose for the rest of this course.
So we'll gradually use more features as we add more features to our application like authentication
and so on.
So this is how you can learn more about mongoose.
Now to add to our project I quit my NPM start process and then I can simply run NPM install dash dash
save Mangu is like dead.
That is the name of the package.
Now this will download and added to our project and then we are already ready to start using it.
And the first thing we want to do when we started using it is that we want to connect to our database
and for that we could use our database utility file here but actually mongooses all of that utility
management and the management of that connection behind the scenes for us what we can do is we can get
rid of the database Cheras file and we can go to the objects file and in there simply import mongoose.
So here let's import mongooses by requiring mongooses.
Mongoose like this.
And with Mangu is imported we can set up a connection so down there where I used my own Mongo connect
I can use mongooses like this and then there there is a connect method we can use now that connect method
takes these same you are all we used for connecting before.
So make sure you grab that your Al from your back and again and entered at here.
Make sure you're using the right user which you set up for that and of course enter your password.
And this will now connect to mongooses.
Then you get a promise here or you can call then at least and there you'll get to the result of this
connection but most importantly you noted at this point of time you are connected.
So here I also want to bring up my notes server or to be precise.
Start listening for incoming requests.
I can also add a catch block here and log any potential error.
I might be getting when trying to get connected.
So with this we already have everything in place we need to connect and Mangu is as I mentioned we'll
managed to add one connection behind the scenes for us.
So that and other places where we start using mongoose from the Magoo's package we use that same connection
we set up here really convenient of course and that already leads us to the next thing we have to do.
We have to move our code over to mongooses now and not to use them on the DVD drive or directly as we
are currently doing it.
So will again have to rewrite all our models but I hope you still see the advantage of this.
You first of all learn how to use to Mangu the driver and you could of course stick to that and continue
using that if you wanted to.
But now I will show you how you can move that over to Mangu is to focus more on how your data should
look like and less on all the logic for it interacting with the database.
Now to move over again I do something I did before I will comment out my dear friend route's here in
the shop chastened and the admin shares fall so that we can gradually comment them back in as we make
them work again.
Now with all route's commented out if I run NPM start I get an error of course that you tell database
was not found in Aperture.
Yes I'd certainly have to get rid of that import here where I do import something from that database.
And the same is of course true for my models where I do also import something from the database.
Now the problem is if I comment that out nothing will work here anymore.
And therefore I will simply comment out everything in my models for the moment.
Now with that it looks like we are connected because we don't get any error here.
This warning can be ignored and therefore we now are connected to our same long would be server.
But now by using the mongoose package with that set up let's start working on all our models and all
our code to make it to work with mongooses in the next lecture.