Get so time to fix our code and make it work again and for that first of all I also connected to my
mom to be server with campest again and I want to clear everything so that we can start from scratch
essentially and therefore I will go to my shop database and simply delete that entire database.
It will again be created on the fly or when required when we start inserting data.
Now I've got a problem I connected with the wrong user where I'm not allowed to delete a database because
I connected with a user who has only read or write access.
So I'll just delete the collections here of course.
The alternative would be to simply connect with a user where I am allowed to manage the overall database
but this will do for now.
With that I also implicitly got rid of the shop database and now we can start working from scratch again.
And let's start working with it by making sure that we can create products.
And for now products dead will simply use very simple data without taking the user into account for
now and where we can simply add them for the admin controller.
So I'll go to my product model.
The model of file and there will eventually remove all the commented out code.
I'll leave it here for reference for now.
And first of all in here we need to import mongoose.
So I will require mongoose here.
Mangu is like this.
Now with as important all great and you constant and I'll name it schema with a capital S..
The name is up to you but I will use something from the mongoose object or that I will use the schema
constructor here.
This constructor allows me to create new schema.
Here I will create a new schema a new product schema.
You can also name does how ever you want.
I create a new schema by instantiating a schema object by calling new schema using that constructor
here.
Now this is just how language works and attitude is constructor here.
I pass a javascript object and in that object you now define how your product should look like.
So you now to find a data schema of a product in our case here.
So this is how you set up such a blueprint in that object.
You define a schema with a simple key value pairs.
So for example our product will have a title.
Now you don't just have find which keys you have but all of which type these keys will have.
That's important to type.
I did find your would be string string as a default javascript object hence we can use that here and
this is what say.
OK so here I create a schema for an object which I will eventually be able to work with which must have
where which will have a title that is of type string.
Now important in among would be module.
I mention that Mongul DBI is schema less so why do we now start to create schemas Well the idea simply
is that whilst we have the flexibility of not being restricted to a specific schema we often will have
a certain structure in the data we work with and therefore a mongoose wants to give you the advantage
of focusing on just your day.
But for that it needs to know how your data looks like and therefore we define such a schema for the
structure our data will have but important we can still deviate from this by assigning a title like
this.
We could even work with a product and create a new one and save it to the database without setting a
title because we still have the flexibility of not enforcing this though what we can do is we can pass
an object instead of just type here as a value and then set a type property which could be set to string
and then set the required To true.
This is basically a more complex way of configuring the value for this key.
And here we would say well the type of this is a string as before but it's also required.
And now we indeed give up some of the flexibility we had before.
And we force all objects to have a title but in the end in our application every product needs to have
a title and deed because we will run into errors otherwise.
For example when outputting products in our views.
So having some kind of schema makes sense even though we have the flexibility to deviate from that and
it really just depends on your application wherever you need all that flexibility or whenever you want
to have some structure and you want to have some tool mongooses that takes some structure and then helps
you work with that data.
So that was a lot of talking about schemas but it is important that you understand why we now all of
a sudden start working with them.
It's just a deliberate decision to give up some flexibility but gain other advantages.
Now of course a product doesn't just have a title.
We also need to have a price and there we can set the type 2 number for example.
And then this would all be required.
And we also want to have a description image you are l.
So we'll add a description here.
This will be of type string.
And let's say this is also required.
Now of course you can always deviate from my set up here but I want to require it at all and will have
an image you are l and in that image you l will be of type string because it's just a u r l and this
will also be required.
So that would be my product schema.
This is basically a description of how a product should look like in my application.
Please note that I don't add underscore ID here because this will still be added automatically as an
object ID.
So we don't need to define that here.
The user ID is something we'll add later.
So now we got that product schema to find in the next step we will create a model based on the schema
and then create an object based on the model and work with that.