So we got a data definition defined.
We got a loop.
We got a schema for our product mongoose now also works with so-called models and the model is also
what we export here.
So I can always say module exports.
And now what I want to export is mongooses model.
No model is a function I call in a model basically is important for mongoose behind the scenes to connect
a schema a blueprint with a name basically.
So here you give that model a name and that name here would be product typically you name it here like
this with a capital starting character and then simply just well the name of the entity does reflect
in your project or in your application.
The second argument then is to schemas on Mike has that product schema we find and this model is what
I export because this model is what will work with in our code.
So with that model defined here we can now move over to the admin controller where we have post at product
what we do is save a new product and there indeed one to treat a new product.
And then I want to be able to save that now.
For that we can basically keep the code we have here.
We still import product from our models folder from the product file because I do export a model here
and we can basically use that just in the way I used to hear one adjustment is required though to the
product constructor.
We don't pass multiple arguments like this.
Instead we've had one argument only and that one argument is a javascript object where we map the different
values we find in our schema.
So here I would map the title to the title and you basically now have to go through all the fields you
defined in the schema.
Order does not matter though since it's a javascript object.
So you then map let's say Prize to as you map description to description and you map the image you are
able to image you are l and just in case you're wondering the part on the right side of the colon.
So tidal apprized description image or L refers to the data you receive in your controller action and
the part on the left side of the colon refers to the Keys you defined in your schema.
So to these things and now is this this creates a new product based on our model and they are for a
product managed by mongooses you could say and indeed such a product happens to have such a model happens
to have a safe method now provided by mongooses.
That's really important.
This is not defined by us and the product model.
We define those same method we did before but this is commented out.
So we're not defining a Save method this Save method here is coming from mongooses.
And then we can indeed call then on that.
Technically we don't get a promise but mongooses still gives us a method.
It also still gives us a catch method we can call and therefore this code should actually continue to
work.
Let's see if that is the case.
And let's head over to our application and click on Add product now I do get an error from actually
yes because they're I of course still use my user model.
Let me comment that out and let me comment it out here let me comment out that entire middleware for
now we have no user and other wise all requests will break for now.
Let's remove all that user related stuff and the asphalt does middle or end user model port and with
that removed Let's try reloading that at product page.
And obviously we need to import the route again.
So we should do that not only to get out but also the post route.
So make sure you read at both admin and product routes as opposed to wrong one does one is required.
So make sure you have to get the post product route EDID again because we manipulated DS to admin control
or actions and now with debt.
Finally if I click on Add product this works.
And now let's test this let's test test product with some fries some image.
Does does work.
Click Add product.
We get a page not found because we can't load any other pages that is OK in the code.
Ican see an error.
But I've got to create a product which looks good.
And in Kompas let's refresh.
By clicking that I can pop left and I connected to the wrong you are l.
I'll fix that.
Therefore I'm connected to the test database instead of the shop database.
But theoretically it worked.
Theoretically we get a product collection with the product at it now whereas the product collection
coming from you might be wondering by the way because we never defined that name well.
Mongoose takes your model name so product turns to all lowercase and takes the plural form off that
and that will then be used as a collection name.
So this is why our product here has a great impact because it was used for naming this collection.
And here we see the data we entered.
So it is working.
That's all great.
I will still drop this collection of your and quickly fix my connection settings in Aperture.
Yes at the bottom of the file here.
I do connect to the tested Abbas.
I don't want to do that.
All connect to the shop database instead.
Just as we did it before and with this tiny change.
If I now go back to my application and I try adding this again a book.
Now let's use that book you are used before
must read and click add product.
Now this still works in the same way it did before but now with a refresh here my data is safeness shop
database and they're in a product collection.
So this is looking really good.
We're now able to save data through mongoose.