Knouted we're able to save products.
Obviously we again want to be able to fetch up.
So let's head over to the shop yes.
Fall in the control us folder and let's start working on get products and get index action star so we
can indeed fetch all products.
Now we got no fetch all Methot in mongoose.
That was a method we defined on our own but we can still use something on the product model which we're
still importing from the product bottles folder and which is the mongoose model and yet and there we
got a couple of static methods.
You can find all in the official docs of course.
And one of them is the find method which you already know from them on would be driver.
Now find works a bit differently when used with mongoose.
It does not give us a cursor.
Instead it does give us the products we could add dot cursor and call this to get access to the cursor
and then use each async which would allow us to loop through them or next to get the next element.
But I will just use find and this will essentially give me all my products automatically.
So then in products I should get my products and I should be able to output them.
So if I now console log my products here sort of we can also see them.
We we have to go to the shop route as well and there we want to include to get a next route and to get
products out.
And since I also did include to get in route here I of course also need to work on get index in my shop
js file in the controller's folder there we all want to use find instead of fetch all but that should
be it.
If we now save everything and we go to the products page.
Indeed I do see my product here.
So this is looking good.
And if I go back well then I see here is the output of the data that was fetched.
And you see I get an array here because I find when used with Mangu is automatic.
It gives me that array year.
Now again if you know you will query large amounts of data you should turn this into a cursor.
Or of course manipulate find to limit the set of data that is retrieved something we will see in the
page anation module later in the course.
So here I now got my work in get products and get indexed route.
Let's next work on the detail route for a single product.