Now that we're able to get all products let's also make sure we can get a single product and for that
I'll work on my get product action in their shop controller and then we extract the product that which
is great.
I don't need Dischord here anymore.
By the way.
And the good thing is product is a mongoose model and Mangu is indeed has a fine by the method.
So little convenience method that defines for us.
So I again find by a d here it's not our own method it's defined by mongooses and best of all we can't
even pass a string to find by id and mongooses will automatically convert this to an object ID.
So it will handle data for us as well.
So again getting a lot of that convenience by just using mongooses.
And then we should be able to get back a product and use that.
So actually this should be everything we need to do.
Nothing.
Basically I guess.
One thing I have to do of course is I have to comment that route back and so does route for loading
a single product with that if you save everything and you click on details here we indeed see the detail
page for this product.
So this is now also working.
And that of course is really great because well this allows us to easily adjust our code to use mongoose.