Last but not least let's make sure we can also delete data so that you see that last part of the drug
operations with mongooses as well.
For that we got our Postol product action and I'm calling delete by ID here on my product model.
Now if I have a look at delete you'll see this is not something offered by mongooses.
However we do with find by id and remove and dead is exactly what we want here right.
So if we call that then we've got everything we need.
This is a built in method provided by Mungo's that should remove a document.
And now we can go to the admin route's again comment in that last Edmon route again.
Save that.
And with that being saved if I now click delete.
No products are found and we can of course also confirm this in comp as if I refresh there are no documents
in the product collection.
So this is how we can work with mongooses and do basic craft operations with it.
Now let's again add a user and see how we can relate different entities with mongooses So how we can
manage relations.
And let's then add that cart and orders thing again.