We worked on the admin side and on the basic product.
Let's now add a user again and let's see how we can add a user model how we can connect it to a product
and so on.
For that I'll go to my user just fall in the models folder.
And first of all I want to import mongoose here by requiring mongoose like that.
So let's now work on the user's schema.
Well first of all we need to find a schema so the user schema to user schema is defined by using something
from the mongoose package which you don't have to.
But I will store in a separate constant.
So Mangu is schema with that we can call and use schema down there.
And I pass a javascript object to that constructor and then that object we describe how a user should
look like.
Now here I will say that I want to have a name where the type of data will be a string and this will
be required.
As an X feel I want to have an email as well.
This will be of type string and this will also be required like debt.
Now we also used a cart before and I still want to embed the card into my user document that hasn't
changed just because we use mongoose.
So we'll add my cart here and now in that cart there will be an embedded document and we can define
it just like that.
I will add items here and items will be an array.
And this is how you define that you want to store an array and here you simply create an array and then
you add what is inside of this array.
You could say an array of strings if you have an array of strings or numbers or booleans or an array
of wild documents that of course is all possible.
Now I want to have an array of documents where I have a product ID which I'll configure with this document
here I'll come back to that and I'll have a quantity and the quantity all configured at right away will
have a type of number and is required.
Now what's the product ID here.
Though the product ID will have a type off and now I need to get something from the schema there.
We have a type's field and there we got all these special types like object ID.
So I'm telling mongoose that this will actually store an object id will because it will store a reference
to a product and that is all is required.
Now that is a bit of a more complex schema therefore because we have an embattled document and we have
an array of then even embedded documents.
But this is how a user should look like.
Now just as before all export this by calling mongooses model give this a name and the name will be
user.
Hence this will be stored in a user's collection because mongoose will automatically take the plural
lowercase words enough that as a collective name and I pass my user schema here.
OK so now we get everything we need to and for mongooses how a user should look like.
Now of course I want to work with a user and for that I'll go back to the app chess file and it will
actually create a user here.
Before we start listening that let me import the user model again in J s.
And with that import it I can create a new user by simply calling new user and just as before I pass
a javascript object where I can figure out where I sign a name where I assign an email and where I also
need to set my card and that card will have an array of well empty items.
So this is my user.
I can then call user safe and this will be done when I start my server.
So here after I restarted we should have a user all ready for you refreshed the overall database server.
We indeed see our users there we see one user with that nested data.
So now with that user created that idea I'm interested in.
So let me copy that ID and go back to the AP-Reals file and comment does middleware back in here.
I again will find a user by ID.
I just need to paste in that Id off that user we just created find by ID is a method provided by mongoose.
So this will work.
We get back to user here then and then I can simply store that user in my request and keep in mind this
is a full mongooses model so we can call all these mongooses modeled functions or methods on that user
object and they offer also on the user Optik which I do store here.
So does should work if I now save this for every incoming request it should actually give us that user.
Now one issue is that with every restart of the server we also create a new user.
As you can see here.
So let me delete that new user because I have my a user creation code down there and I dont check whether
I want to create one or not.
So what all they quickly do is I will first of all see if we do have a user with user find one and find
one with if I give it no arguments will always give me back the first user id finds and then here in
the then block I will have my user object and only if this is undefined so if it is not set only then
I will create a new user.
So therefore now if I refreshed as we shouldn't have a new user if I however delete that first user
here and I therefore temporarily get rid of that lets say and I save and add restarts now or refresh
my users collection I do have a new user and now I just need to grab that ID and paste it back in here.
And now we get a set up where I don't constantly create new users.
OK so this is how we add a user model and how we basically use it.
But now of course we want to use it in conjunction with the products model and with the products.
So lets do that in the next lecture.