With the user model set up let's make sure we can use it together with the product model.
Now obviously every product should be assigned to a user.
So first of all we need to change our product schema a little bit.
A product should also have a user ID field let's say just as we had it before in the last module.
Now a user ID field is of type and Now which type estus.
Well it won't be a reference to a user so this will actually be of type schema types object ID.
And now we Kensit something special here we can add a special ref configuration and ref takes a string
where we tell mongooses Hey which average mongoose model is actually related to the data in that field.
We know that we will store a user ID here but just because the type is object id This is not obvious.
This could be any object ID of any object.
So I will add user here and you use the name off your model to which you want to collect this.
So since our model here is named user I will name it user here.
So I referred to my user model here.
And with that I got a roll lation set up does also means that in my user model where I do store and
a product ID I can also add a reference here and refer to product because I know that for every user
in the cart items I will store products where I refer to some ID and that Id happens to refer to a product
stored or defined through the product model.
So now we got relation's set up with ref.
Of course you only need this when using references when using embedded documents as we do with the cart.
You don't need to do anything because while you use an embattled document this already has kind of an
implicit relation that is managed inside of one document.
So now with the reference a set up.
Let me also add a required to true here and now I adjusted my schemes now with this schema adjusted
be of course need to adjust our code like in the admin control or when we create a new product when
creating a new product we also want to make sure we store the user id and that is super simple.
We just add user ID here to the fields we pass in the object to the product constructor and now remember
that we did save the user in our request so it can just do request user underscore Id like this and
this should give me access to the user id and assign it here now conveniently in mongooses.
You can even just store the entire user object.
So this is really the entire user Optik not just the ID and Mungo's will just pick the ID from that
object.
So thats a narrow convenience you got there.
Let me save my code.
Let's go back and lets add a new product a nice book.
Lets use that image your L we used before.
Lets give it some prize.
You should not miss that and click add product now you zip.
That looks good it was added.
And now let's have a look at compas and see if the user ID was added to.
So if I refreshed there indeed we see the user id here and just the ID not the entire user just the
ID as we wanted.
So this is pretty awesome.
This is how we can manage relations through mongoose.
Now let me show you something cool.
When it comes to fetching these relations.