Get zoned out and were able to relate data and store products that are related to user let's work on
that shopping cart and the orders again so that we can do more to just look at the products Now previously
in our user model in the part which is now commented out I had utility methods like add to cart to add
products to the card to the user.
And actually it was really useful to have these because that allowed us to move logic from our controller
into the model which is typically where your data led to logic should live.
So therefore I will re-edit and Mongoose makes this really simple.
You can work on your schema so my user schema here.
And then there you'll have a method that's key.
The method key is an object which allows you to add your own methods by simply well adding them Add
to Cart.
And this should now be a function.
And the important part is it has to be a function written like this so that this keyword in there still
refers to the schema and not to something else.
And now in this function you can add your own logic and that is exactly what I want to do in this function.
I want to add the logic I had an Add to Cart before and tweak it a little bit.
So let's wrap all that code from Add to Cart.
Let's add at your and comment it back in.
Now the function here should also receive the product which I want to add.
That is something we required in the past as well.
So we still will get a product to that function does something we just need to assume because we are
the one writing the code in the end.
And now in there we should still be able to use this card items because our schema has a cart and then
the items array.
So this should still work.
And keep in mind this will be called on a real instance based on that schema.
So really on an object which will have a populated card with either an empty array of items or an array
of items with items in there.
So this code should still work for getting the product index.
I also still want to control my quantity as before and update my cart as before.
But first of all copying it then I will keep the log of checking whether we already do have the product
in the cart in which case I'll calculate a new quantity based on the old quantity.
And then I'll update my array or if I will update my array by pushing a new object onto it.
Now here the thing just is this will not work like that.
But I can just store the product ID like this and Mongoose should automatically wrap it in an object
ID.
The quantity can be stored like this however and this should fit my schema of an item with product at
the end quantities.
So make sure that the names you used up there in your schema are the names you use down there for creating
new data.
So with that I got my updated cart.
Now I don't need to get access to databases like this.
Instead here I will indeed return something but I will not manually update this.
Instead I will just call this safe which should work before I do that.
I just need to set this card equal to the updated card.
Now this should be a utility method that saves itself so where do you object safe's itself by using
the built in safe method where we update the cart.
Now let's see if that works as it should let's go to the shop Chia's fall and they're We have all our
post-cart Methot.
Now I find my product by D which still should work because mongoose gives us this function and then
I do indeed call request user add to card which should not all it because we just added this method
to the user object in our user model.
So this should work without any changes hopefully.
Let's go to the route's therefore and comment that postcard route back in there now save everything.
Let's go to products and let's try add to cart.
I do get some output here.
And let's now have a look at Compeyson looking to the users there I have my cart I got my items and
I got an idea in there now that was added by mongooses automatically it adds IDs for some documents
as well.
But most importantly I got my product ID and that product ID which ends with 3 C 6 should be the ID
of that product and it is now let's confirm if that really works by going back again and adding that
same product to the card again.
It still doesn't find the page it wants to load but that is.
All right let's update our users collection now.
Look at the cart.
We got one object with quantity 2.
So this is working.
And this shows us the power of mongooses we get a bunch of nice built in methods which we also leverage
here in our own method which we can add which we can call on our objects are based on our schema.