So in the last lecture you saw how you can extend mongooses with your own functionality and that is
really powerful.
Now obviously also check the official docs there under a schema.
You can learn way more about that.
This is the technique we just used.
We added the instance method you can add more about that and all the nice features you can add to your
own schema.
And models.
So definitely check that out for all the details that could be interesting to you.
Now here I want to work on the route that allows us to load the cart and this is a nice practice for
you again.
Feel free to post a video at this point and go ahead and try to implement this on your own before we
do it together.
Rhodey was successful.
Well let's go to the shop.
Just following the controller's folder and we're looking for the get cart method here.
Now there we have request to use or get cart and get cart is a method we find in the past which does
not exist by default.
Mongooses does not give us this method.
So we again have to revisit our user model and in there.
Let's have a look at Get card how we defined it in the past in the past we simply reached out to our
card items.
We got all the product IDs and then we had a look at the products collection to find all the products
in there where it does to an array and return to products.
So essentially get card gave us an array of all the products in the cart.
Now with mongooses this is a bit easier.
We already have our nested card items IRET.
And if we have a look at comp as we see the items are objects where we have the product ID.
And now we simply need to populate the product ID with all the data we are interested in.
So in shop class and get cart I will not call get cart on my user.
Instead we can call populate on the user to fetch data even though we already fetched a user.
We can also call populate on debt and tell mongooses to fetch data for now which part is it.
Well for a card dot items dot product id let me console log my products here to see if that works.
Now we all need to add that route again.
So in the shop js file and the results folder Let's at that get card route again.
And with that changed that big load to card page and I get an error.
And the reason for that is popular does exist but actually it does not return a promise.
So calling them on it would not work.
We have to change exec populate after debt and then we'll get a promise.
So then we should be able to call then.
So now if that lets lock products save that and reload that page now get no products and card.
But if I go back what we see actually what we have here is the full user object which makes sense because
we're not just fetching products.
We still work with the full user.
So that is a tiny change.
So let's actually use or lock to user card items here to see if dad was still populated with all the
item data and I'll temporarily create an empty product array.
So the rest of the code does not fail.
And now let's say that and reload the card page one more time.
For now go back you see indeed here what a log user card items now is an array of items where the product
ID is populated with the product data.
So now it works a bit different than before but it still gives us the data we need.
So here products now actually is user cart items and that is what I passed to my view but I will need
to look into my view now because the structure changed a bit compared to before the card.
A jazz file is what we need to edit.
And then there we loop for all products which is fine but remember that our product data will then be
nested in a product ID field and you could also renamed us to chust product in your schema therefore
which makes a bit more sense I guess but I would still have product ID here.
So the title is not available on the top level object which would be this object but on the nested product
ID object.
So here we have to say the dot product ID dot title The quantity is on the top level object.
So this is fine the product idea again can be found on the product ID nested where and bad a document
though.
So with that let's save that and let's now reload the card page and indeed we see our card item here
now.
So this is looking better now we're able to populate our a card with data.