Knouted we're able to load the cartes data.
Of course make sure we can also delete cart items for that we have the postcard to delete product action
in our shop controller.
Now in there I used to delete the item from cart method on the user object which we wrote on our own
in the last module and which of course is also not a default mongooses method.
So it's time to go back into the user model and have a look at the delete item from card method and
see how we can recreate that functionality there.
What I do is essentially I create an updated card items array by filtering out the items that should
survive.
So all the items except for the one I want to remove and then I update my model.
Well we can of course do that by copying.
Well basically just that code here and adding a number Methot just as we did it with Add to Cart.
So I will use my user schema and there are the methods again and then I'll add or remove from card method
which will be a function.
And in that function I will add that code which I copied from the bottom does code relies on being aware
of the product ID of the product we want to delete.
So Product ID is an argument I expect in this function here in this method.
And now we get the updated card items.
And now all we need to do is we need to set this card item's equal to the updated card items and then
we return this safe.
And now we got a method that we should be able to call to remove an item from the card just like Ted.
So let's move over to the shop.
Jay has fallen to control this folder and there in the postcard delete product route.
Well I just renamed it a bit.
I need to remove from card.
You could have kept the original name of course.
Now I have removed from cart I passed the product ID and a redirect here to the card page.
Once we're done that should work but it will only work if we enable the fitting route again.
So let's go to the routes folder the shop chaps file and let's comment in the card delete item read
it again.
And with that all changed we now go back and we click delete your.
That looks good.
We load up the card page and all the data is gone let's all verify doesn't compress by reloading our
users collection there in the cart items is an empty array.
So we're now able to add items to the cart and remove items from the cart.
Let's next work on the orders.