Time to work on the last two pieces the orders and again feel free to post a video and try implementing
this on your own.
It's always a great practice even if you can't get the full result or full equivalence to my solution
or if you get stuck at one point you can still then go back and watch just solution together with me.
But you will still have a lot of practice by trying parts of that on your own.
So here's your chance to post a video and we'll do it together after.
So let's dive into that together and let's work on our orders now creating orders and getting orders.
That is what you want to do.
And let's first of all look into our controller forget the shop controller.
There we have.
Post order.
Now what are we doing there.
Well here first of all we got an unused variable which we can get rid of there we call add order on
the user and that's essentially it.
So let's look into the user model and let's see what ad order did an order simply took our card.
So the products are cards to be precise and created an order object which contains the product data
but also some data about the user.
And then we insert this into our order collection.
Now since we work with the collection there will need a new model that's for sure.
And then as a result we just cleared the cart so we get multiple steps we need to do here.
First I'll add an ORDER japes fall in the models folder because I don't need an order model to store
data in orders collection.
First of all let's import is here by requiring mongoose like that.
Let's create the schema constant where we access mongooses schema like this.
And let's then the fine or order schema and how that should look like.
And of course here you can also go with the schema that works for you.
Or that you want to use.
Now I will try to recreate the schema we used before where the order had the items and the user data.
And that was Ed and the items were our products which in the past was all the product data and the quantity.
So here in my schema I will have my products let's say I name that items in the past year old payment
products products will be an array of documents and every document will let's say have the product data
which will be of type Object because this will be full of documents you could say that is required.
And besides the product data I'll have to quantity for that product.
Could also named us just product here by the way if you wanted to.
So here to quantity that will be a type number and this should also be required because if this is how
my products will look like.
Now all that will have a user and there I want to have a name.
Let's say we're the type is a string and as is required and what what else did we store about the user
in the past.
Well just the IDs so also have my user ID here which is a type schema types object id and which is also
required.
And does will also refer to the user model now type object by the way is a bit of a shortcut.
Of course we could find a full nested product with all the properties there.
Feel free to do that.
I'll just say well this is any object.
So this is my order schema.
Now export a model based on that schema with Mongoose model name that order and hence the collection
will be named orders.
And then I got my order schema there.
OK.
Now I got my order model and that is new we didn't used that before in the last module we could have
but now we will we implemented it differently there.
Now we use a model based package again for interacting with the data we have to be more strict about
that.
And that is a good thing generally and therefore we have an order model again now with the order model
at it.
The question is how do we interact between the order model and the user.
Now we had an order and the possed and add order essentially just wrapped user data products created
in order and stored it.
Now I still want to do that but I'll do it in a controller now in post order.
I will work a bit differently I will first of all import my order model at the top from models order
like this.
So does import was added.
And then down there in post order I will create a new order object by using that order model a constructor.
Now that order object needs to be initialized and needs to be initialized in the way we defined it here.
So it needs to get products and it needs to get some user data.
Now the user data is a bit simpler.
We got our request user.
So here we have the name which is request user name because remember request user is a full user object
fetched from the database.
So there will be a name property and we also want to store the ID of that user in the order.
We also have like d user ID.
So we shipped stored that as well.
So we'll add user ID here and that will simply be what we can't just use the entire request user object.
And as I mentioned mongooses will pick the IP from there.
OK.
And this is the easier part.
Now we also need to add the products for this user's cart.
However it's not that difficult because we already implemented something similar for getting the cart.
We use this approach for fetching all the products that are in the user's cart.
So in the end we can't just copy this year all the way up to the part where I extract the products and
reuse that in post order at the beginning here.
Just make sure to close that then function your.
And here we now got the products that are in the user's cart.
Now important is just products is not entirely correct.
You should remember that here we have an array of elements were we have the quantity and then the real
product data wasp's nest and in a product ID field.
But we can work with that of course.
We can now create our order in side off days then block Adhir we can now add products which should be
an array of products and that should be an array of products which is a bit transformed.
So not the structural products we get back here but after some transformations to be precise products
for us to have a product field with the product data and a quantity field that is almost what we have.
But we have the product data in a product ID field here not in a product field but that is easy to fix.
I will simply not just extract items like this.
I will also map the items so that I stored the changed items in my products array and a map item should
still have its quantity so we'll keep that the eyes simply refers to the item since this function goes
for all items in that array symbol half the quantity and then we'll have a product field and the product
field should have all the product data set will store everything that I had an AI product ID before
because that was the old structure we had in there.
Now we have this structure.
We have an array of products which just have a quantity and then the product detail data which is exactly
the structure we expect to get in that order model.
And now we can simply store these products in the order.
And with that we got everything we need.
Almost now we just need to call save on that order so order save now saves that order to the database
and then we can chain then on that.
Once we return orders save so that we can all to redirect and so on.
Let's see if that works by going to our shop routes again and commenting to create or to route back
in and back in our project.
Let me first of all add a second product so that we get something to play around with and see that this
does not get added to just a dummy product obviously.
So now in our card we got no products.
Let's add a nice book to our ecarte.
Maybe all the from the details page.
And let's not add our product and let's look.
Order now.
Now we don't find the page you want to redirect to.
That's fine and the card also was not cleared because we haven't added that logic yet.
But let's have a look into Compaq's And let's see if we refreshed the entire set up.
We got the orders collection and then there I got an order with some user data that looks pretty good
let's quickly confirm the user ID.
It ends with 8 8 8.
That looks good and let's have a look at the product there too.
And there I got a quantity of two and I got my product ID.
Well the product idea is that what I wanted though I wanted all the product data right.
Let's fix that in the next lecture.