So let's clear the card after storing an order.
And for that here once I'm done with saving the order I want to clear the card.
And one way to do that would be to go to the user model and add a new method there.
We can go to the user schema to the methods key and then add a clear cart method.
So simply a function of we can call to clear the entire cart.
And how would we do that.
Well we would simply set this cart equal to an object where we have an empty array of items and then
we just return this whoops return this safe and that should be it that updates to cards you have no
items in it anymore and we didn't save as and therefore we update this which is let's go back to the
shop controller.
And here once we know that the order was placed let's simply call request user clear card.
This method we just added and then I will return that and move my redirection into a new then block
after the previous one which will only execute once the card was cleared.
So now with that let's say that let's now also go to products and maybe add another product to our cart.
Let's order that card.
Now let's click on card again no products and cart does this looking great.
Let's quickly check our orders and compacts and this new order should now have two product set is looking
good.
One with quantity Q That walls are nice spoke and one with quantity one that was the second product.
And in the users the card is empty.
So now we got an elegant way of managing orders sent the cart through mongoose.
However of course also had the functionality to get the card in the next lecture.