Let's move towards the end of the module by making sure that we can all get the dollars and display
them on our orders page here.
So for that we want to work in the shop controller with get orders and there I had to get orders function
on my user model that we could call if we have a quick look at dysfunction get orders simply reached
out to the orders collection and all orders for this user.
While that shouldn't be too hard right because we can do of course is in our controller here.
We know what a user ID because we got it here in our request object.
So in the end what I can do is I can use my order model which we're importing at the top of the file
and I can find all orders where and let's have a look at the order Maller real quick where a user user
IDs or disinvested object to your design on s that key is equal to the user id of the locked end user.
So here we have user Daut user ID that just be equal to request user underscore ID that is to check.
I want to Meggan This will give me all orders that belong to that user.
Well and then we can just use these orders here in the van Methot.
So essentially I can just reuse my old then method where I already expect that the order is and it can
render the orders page if we now save that we just need to make sure the route exists.
So let's quickly common data in the here and now have a click on orders.
I get an error because the structure of our data changed a little bit.
So we need to work on the view to adjust it to our data.
In my orders page here how did change we loob fruity orders and each order has an ID that will still
work.
But then we have no order items anymore.
We've got order products now we can confirm this with our schema or in comp as of course we got order
products and each product has quantity and then the product data in a product field.
So inside of here we have the product and there we have a nested product field.
So we could all name this just P to avoid confusion.
This will be.
And there we have the product field with the title but directly on the top level object.
So directly in the object that is stored in that product's array we have to quantity.
So we can still access this directly on PPI which is the part directly in order products but then the
product data itself is nested in one additional Ampad document product.
But with these changes.
Q Are you final reload that view page.
Does looks good.
Now I see all my orders here as we did before.
Now something is wrong about the first two orders.
And the thing that is wrong is that simply these orders were created at a time where we only store the
object ID and no special object data.
So let me click quickly delete these two orders here so that we don't have them in our view.
And in our app anymore.
So now we only have valid orders here.
So this does now all work.
Feel free to play around with that.
Try adding totals for the orders or anything like that.
For now this is the state I want to work with.
I want to continue with and dessous what I want it to show you with mongooses and Langone be and you
there for now saw a lot of different alternatives for working with databases and how to work with the
data then.