So in this module you'll learn about mongoose and I can only encourage you to dive into the official
mongooses documentation to learn all about it and the many features it offers.
And I do really mean it as I said in the last lecture.
Play around with our application.
Try adding subgoals or total's to our orders here.
Play around feel free to experiment with the data and with our application.
This is what coding is all about.
In the end the official talks for more gurus and long would be or sequel Aizen sequel if you want to
stick to that should give you everything you need to dive deeper and play around.
At this point of course though you have a solid understanding of the different database solutions you
could use how you would use them.
Why using tools like sequel eyes or mongooses might make a lot of sense and how you can integrate them
into your application.
Now what exactly you use.
Which database and which features or which package always depends on your exact application.
I hope that disallowance modules gave you a great overview over the pool of options you could choose
from and what you can do with them.
We will continue with mongooses and longer DBI in this course.
However feel free to of course play around with sequel if you need that for your next project.
But we will continue with that.
We will therefore add some features from the cores do a bit more with the database when we are able
to do it.
Like for example invalidate input and build our application whilst at the same time learning way more
about node and express in general throughout the rest of this course.