It's now finally time that we start storing our data in a more correct or realistic way because thus
far we either used the mammary when we just stored the data in a variable in our node program and it
was then even shared across requests or we stored it in a file and that's also not optimal because accessing
files is pretty slow especially as we start storing more and more data in them and it's not really something
we would do in a real application.
Instead there you typically would use a data base which is a specific program that allows you that is
built for storing data and for efficiently retrieving data to Denver and this module will have a look
at the different kinds of databases or two important different kinds of databases sequel and no sequel
databases and I will compare them highlight the differences and we will actually see examples for both
in the course and we'll start with sequel awls and this module.
So no sequel will also follow in a separate module but let me first of all show you how you would use
a sequel based data base to gabber with your no JSA application.
This is what we'll cover and that will actually be a lot.
So let's dive right into it and let's learn what the different kinds of databases are and whether a
sequel or no sequel could be the right choice for your application.