We had to look at sequel based databases.
Now it's time to look at no sequel based databases.
Now the name no sequel simply means that it doesn't follow the approach sequel follows.
It also uses a different language but instead of having schemas and relations no sequel has iver focuses
her on her strengths.
So in those sequel we can still have a database and we can give this database a name shop let's say.
Now that's the same for a sequel right away.
There we all have databases now in sequel.
We then had tables users and orders and maybe all the products.
These are just examples here.
Now Infoseek Well tables are called collections but you can think of them as tables so as to table equivalent
but we call them collections in the world.
Now in collection we don't find records but so-called documents which looked like this.
And since we're working with javascript in this course here we of course can kind of see that this looks
a bit like a javascript object.
So documents are very close to how we describe data in Javascript you could say now that our documents
in our collections and what you can already see here in the user's collection Exxon-Mobile is that no
sequel doesn't have a strict schema here we got two documents in the same collection.
But the second document manual here does not have an H and that is perfectly fine in no sequel.
You can store multiple documents with different structures in the same collection.
Now often you'll of course still try to have kind of a similar structure but it's also not uncommon
for some applications that you don't always have exactly the same fields away level for the data.
You are storing in the database and that is ok and no sequel.
You can definitely store documents which are generally equal but whereas some fields might differ.
One other thing is that in the sequel world we got no real relations.
Instead we go for duplicate data.
Now that simply means that if we have orders collection here we have a nested document.
The user which also is stored as a separate document with more details may be in the users collection
and we don't connect that to some idea or behind the scenes set up relation.
Instead we simply duplicate data to be precise.
The data we need in the order is collection year.
That of course means that if that data changes we have to update it in multiple places.
If all these places need the latest update or the latest data change but that can be OK because this
only gives us a huge advantage that if we ever retrieve data we don't have to join multiple tables to
gabber which can lead to very long and difficult code and which can also impact performance.
Instead we can simply reads the data from the orders collection and we probably got all the data we
need to display on the orders page without having to reach out to collections.
And for this can be done in a super fast way and that is one of the huge advantages of no sequel.
It can be very fast and efficient.
So no sequel characteristics in general are that we have no strong data schema.
We can have mixed data in the same collection.
No structure is required and that we have generally no data or relations.
Now we can relate documents in some way.
And this is possible and we will see how to work with CONNECT that data in the no sequel module off
this course.
But generally we have no or only a few connections and instead try to copy data and have a collection
with documents that work on their own.
This is the difference.
We also got a difference between sequel and no sequel.
Regarding our scalability.
So as our application grows and we need to store more add more data and access that data or work with
it more frequently.
We might need to scale our database servers and we can differentiate between horizontal and vertical
scaling.
We'll have a look at this and in general how the two worlds sequel and those sequel compare in the next
lecture.