So we learn about sequel and those sequel.
Let's now compare them and let's start with horizontal and vertical scaling because as I mentioned at
the end of the last lecture we often need to scale our database to keep up with our growing application
with more and more users horizontal and vertical scaling.
Are the two approaches we can use to scale our database.
Now what do they mean well in horizontal scaling we simply add more service.
And the advantage of course is that we can do this infinitely.
We can always buy it and use servers be dead on a cloud provider or in our own data center and connect
them to our database and split our data across all these servers.
Of course this means that we all need some process that runs queries on all of them and merge them together
intelligently.
So this is generally something which is not that easy to do but this is of course a good way of scaling
vertical scaling simply means that we make our existing server stronger by adding more Sibiu or memory
or something like that especially with cloud providers.
This is typically very easy you simply choose a number option from the dropdown.
You pay more and you're done.
The problem here is that you have some limit you can't fit in finitely much Seip you power into a single
machine.
So these are the two ways we can scale.
Now let's compare a sequel and no sequel.
Regarding that and in general now in general in sequel we use schemas we also have relations.
These are two core correcter mystics and data is typically distributed across many many tables which
are then connected through relations.
Now regarding the scaling it's important that horizontal scaling often is very difficult or even impossible
due to the way sequel works.
You can of course add more servers but running them all on one shared data cloud.
So to say one shared data base is pretty difficult.
We're legal Schelling is easily possible.
You can simply make your server stronger but adding more servers can be very hard or even impossible.
Definitely not trivial.
So this is a problem possibly if we have multiple or thousands of read and write queries per second.
Then maybe our sequel database especially if we do very complex joins between related tables can reach
limits or can not be the best choice.
No sequel is schema less and has only a few relations if at all the data is typically not distributed
across multiple collections but instead work with merged or nested documents in an existing document.
The we of course also have a couple of collections for different features of our application typically
with no sequel horizontal scaling is easier.
Still something where you have to know what you do but there are cloud providers which do that for us
so we don't have to know the ins and outs of debt and in general due to the way it works with less connections
as on this is possible and therefore we also get great performance for mass read write requests and
no sequel can be very performant in an application with high throughput.
Now this makes sequel look very bad but the full truth is that it always depends on the kind of data
you are storing.
If you are storing where desolations are really important and where you want to have a split up across
tables and where you want to have strong schemas siecle can be perfect.
Also not every part of your data is accessed multiple times per second.
You can't have parts of your application where you manage general data.
Let's say user data which does not change that often and therefore a sequel might be very good.
There over parts of the application let's say orders or shopping carts that do change frequently could
be stored with no sequel and their relations might not be that important because you can always put
all the information that belongs to a shopping cart or to order in one single document.
And even if you do for example store some user data there you might not need to touch that document
just because the user change his photo because you probably didn't stored it along with the order anyways.
Now in this course we will build both.
We will use both because I want to teach you both.
And it's not so much about this course application but you should know how to use sequel with no choice
because maybe you need to add in your application or your work on a project where you don't decide which
database to use but you simply have to use it.
So we will use sequel first but then it will also show you how to use no sequel of Mongo baby.
So we'll basically implement the course project or the current state of the Course project with both
databases and you will see how to interact with both of them.
And let's start with sequel in this module let's install on my sequel database and learn how to interact
with it from inside our no chess code.