Now you work with sequel.
We need a sequel based database and I'll go for my sequel because you can stall and use them for free
at least in the basic version which does suffice for this course.
You can visit my sequel dot com to download and install it.
And there simply click on downloads.
And scroll down.
We don't need the Enterprise edition here.
Instead we'll go for the community edition which is to free one click on downloads there too.
And now what we will need is my sequel communities server and we'll all need the work bench.
Now you can also download combine and Stolar especially here for Windows you should just Giusti My sequel
on Windows Installer and tools which allows you to set up everything in one go.
But you can also click on my secret community server here simply and this should give you a download
which allows you to install all these things in one go.
Anyways so let's Giusti mystical community server here.
Always dive into the insulations attractions.
In case you're facing any problems on your system and then if you scroll down select your operating
system here the one you plan on using.
So for Windows you can then also download this general installer which allows you to pick the deprogrammers
you need for Mac OS.
We simply can go for this first download the DNG archive and then once you click there you don't have
to log in.
You can simply choose.
No thanks.
Just start my download to well start the download.
This can take a while because it's quite a big file.
On Windows you have the choice between downloading a web based installer which is smaller but downloads
what you need to during the installation or a complete installer which downloads everything in advance
once your download is done simply execute the downloaded file.
So even those installer.
Or does Mac DMCE archive here on ask.
Q Well continue Rudy installation wizard and I will do that.
Agreed to the license.
Leave the default installation Poth click on customize your though to choose what to install and make
sure that you doing so.
The My sequel server here.
If you're running does install or Windows you should get a different installer where you can choose
to install the MS sequel server but then also in one go install D.
My sequel workbench.
So make sure you select both for installation and click install here.
And now on both operating systems.
Dish should install it now.
Once installation is done a configuration process should start automatically there.
You should make sure that during this configuration process you do choose the legacy password encryption
which sounds insecure but which is perfectly fine and didn't you were worse than simply is not supported
by the node sequel package we're using yet.
So just the legacy password encryption and shoes next you all have to choose a password for your root
user and you can also leave.
Start my sequel's or once installation is complete.
Checked or checked if it is unchecked and click Finish
on Windows.
Simply leave all the settings as they are and click through them and by the end it should be done and
it should then also start a sequel server for you.
With the setup you chose your Indico figuration steps.
Now once installation is complete on Windows if you installed the mysql workbench you're done on Mac
or Linux.
You're not done yet.
Instead you should go back to this page where you chose my school community server and they're all installed
the mystical workbench.
The workbench basically is a client the visual client we can use to connect to our database to inspect
it and play around with it outside of our node application which simply makes debugging and developing
a bit easier.
So Tuesday my sequel work bench here and there you also can choose your operating system.
Now again on Windows if you use debt general installer you already have it download that file here again
you don't need to log in just start to download and wait for the download to finish.
So did you can again execute D-Will executable.
Once it is done finished the installation process as instructed.
By the installer and once you're done with that you should be all good.
You can now test your set up by starting the sequel workbench you just installed and then there you
should already see your MS sequel instance running.
If that is not the case.
Have a look at the attached document where I describe some common issues or in general give you some
links on how to make this work and how to bring this up.
You just need to make sure that your my sequel server is running and during installation you had a choice
to check that it should always start with your system on Mac.
You can also open your system preferences and there you should have the MS sequel option where you can
also stop and start to server to connect to the database.
Simply click on that instance and now enter that root password you assigned during the installation.
This should not allow you to connect to your sequel server instance like this.
Then once you enter the password you should be connect to your database system and right now this is
what you have basically an empty window and we won't work too much in that will of course work with
our database from inside our node application.
But this will allow us to conveniently look into our database from time to time and see what is stored.
And one thing we can do already is we can go down to schemas here which can be translated with database
here.
You could say and there we can define a new schema so a new database with which will work and it's not
complete.
You can name does whatever you want and you can also leave the opera settings here and then on the bottom
right and I know it's small here.
Unfortunately you consume in.
You can click Apply now.
This will create a new database.
You can say with which we can interact later you can leave all the default settings and simply click
apply here and now you should see that note complete thing which has a couple of tables or non right
now but where you can then later connect to and store your data in the tables that will be created here.
So with that we can continue and we can now move on with our code and start interacting with my sequel
from inside our node application.