To use sequel or to interact with sequel from inside note we need to install a new package and we do
that with NPM install of course and install and we simply bring that up to make it easier to read and
install dash dash safe because it will be a production dependency one which is a crucial part of our
application.
The name is my sequel to this is simply a later version of well my sequel.
One as you might guess and it allows us to write sequel code and execute sequel code in note and interact
with a database.
Now with that installed we made one important step forward towards using my sequel.
The next step is that we need to connect to our database from inside our application and for debt I
will close my views here and go to the utl folder we created in the past.
There we have that Pop-Tart genius following there which we don't really use anymore but we can also
create a new file in your database.
James Hall and the name is totally up to you by the way in there.
I want to set up the code that will allow us to connect to the sequel database and then also give us
back a connection object so to say which allows us to run queries for this all.
First of all import dad my sequel package and store it in my sequel constant.
So require my sequel to is to command and eat here and now there are two ways of connecting with a sequel
database.
One is that we set up one connection which we can then use to run queries and we should always close
the connection once we're done with a query.
The downside is that we need to re execute the code to create the current action for every new query
and there will be a lot of queries because we fetch data we write data we delete data creating connections
all the time quickly becomes very inefficient both in our code and also regarding the connection to
the database which is established and the performance may cost.
So a better way is to create a so-called connection pool and by the way you can learn way more about
this package.
It's options regarding how to set up connections and so on.
In the officials box for this tool for this package and you find a link to those docs in the last lecture
office module.
So to set up such a pool I'll create a new constant pool.
The name is up to you and I'll use that mystical object in there.
I will call create pool and there you all to see that create connection we could use now I don't want
a single connection but a pool of connections which will allow us to always reach out to it whenever
we have a query to run and then we get a new connection from that pool which manages multiple connections
so that we can run multiple queries simultaneously because each car needs its own connection and once
to Curdistan to connect will be handed back into the pool and it's a whaleboat again for a new query
and the pool can then be finished when our application shuts down.
So I will call create pool here and need to pass in a javascript object with some information about
our database engine.
Our database HOST We're connecting to forget all first of all to find a host so the server IP address
or name and that is localhost because it's running on our local machine here.
Then I need to find a username and that by default is a route that was given to us using the configuration
process.
I also need to find Dick secte database name because this gives us access to a database server but that
server typically has multiple databases and here our databases are our schema.
So we'll take the node complete database here so that the value here sublease node complete now with
that we simply have to enter one more piece of information and that is of course our password.
So here enter a password and then I used this password.
You should of course use the password you assigned during installation.
This will create a pool.
And now I can export this pool and it will export it in a special way actually a little called Promise
here because this will allow us to use prominences when working with these connections which of course
handle asynchronous tasks asynchronous data instead of callbacks because promises allow us to write
code in a bit more structured way.
We don't have many nested callbacks.
Instead we can use promised chains and you will see what I mean in this module of course.
So now we can always import from the database just fall to get access to that pool and to the connections
in there.
And I can show this as an example by simply going to actually yes which will of course run when our
application starts up and there let's simply import database may be stored in a constant named DBI by
requiring util database like this.
So reaching out to that new database file would just create it.
This will then be the pool basically or.
Well the pool which allows us to use a connection in it.
And if I now use this let's say here I can run D-B.
And now we got a couple of methods one of them is execute which allows us to execute queries.
We also got a query but execute is a bit safer.
So we'll use that.
We can also end it and we want to end it whenever our application is to shut down.
But we don't shut our application down.
In this case here.
So no need to call and here.
Instead we just want to connect or execute a command and we can execute a command here by writing sequel
syntax as a string.
Now of course that means you need to know sequel and I will teach you a very basic sequel here in this
course if you plan on using my sequel together with your node app you definitely have to take a sequel
course which ties into all the deaths of the sequel language because that is far beyond the scope of
this course which is of course a node course and not a sequel of course but what we could do here is
we could select everything from products.
And of course we have no products table yet.
So let's quickly go back to our work bench and your on tables right click and click create table.
And this gives you Daudi table editor.
The name should now be products and then there you can add new fields.
Remember that schema thing you add fields.
So let's work on this and finished this and execute our first little code in the next lecture.