So let's finish that set up off the Products table which I need for my first demo code here in the table
editor so to say in the book bench we can define how a product's entry should look like.
For that we first of all define the name of a field ID and the data type.
And for the ID an integer is fine.
You can also check that it should be the primary key by which records in this table will be identified
that it must not be null that it should be unique.
That should definitely be the case if it should hold binary data which is not the case if it's unsigned
so if it holds no negative values which should also be the case because that would be an integer starting
at 1 and then incrementing here.
If it is zero fill and for us important if it's auto incrementing and that should be the case because
every new record should receive that automatically.
And it should be a higher number than in the last record.
Now a product also typically has a title and they're all use of our char which is basically a string.
I'll just find that it may be up to 255 characters long and longer titles will simply be cut off.
So that's something to keep in mind.
It must also not be null.
So we have to have a value in there but I don't need any other setting here for a product.
I also want to have a price.
And here I want to have a double so that we can enter decimal places.
This must also not be now.
I also want to have a description which now will not be a bar chart.
Bad will be text and if you're wondering which data types are available that is exactly what I meant.
You should definitely consult a full sequel of course to learn more about the A-Whale data types and
how to work with them.
So here I got my text which is simply a longer text than the chart which has a limitation.
And I will have an image you are l which are also set to Warszawa 255 which means longer you Your else
also won't work with that.
I did find how their product should look like.
You can leave everything out as it is and then on the bottom right again click on apply here.
It shows you the sequel statement.
It will execute and you could execute this on your own for example in note of course to all of this
create this new table here will do in the Workbench.
So click Apply close and now on tables you see the new products table and if you click this I can hear
on the very right you can see the entries in there.
By the way you also see the sequel of Corey that was executed to look into that.
And that's pretty similar to the query we're executing here.
So now that the table is set up we just need to enter one dummy data so that we have something to fetch
and I will simply add a book here.
Ribs with a price of let's say 12 9 9 description.
This is an awesome book and also an image you are l.
Now if you've got problems copying a value and you're simply have to type it manually copying all that
didn't work for me.
Of course you can also enter some dummy value and just live with no image being displayed.
Now let's all enter IDs here though that should be generated if you don't do it.
Click on apply on the bottom right.
Apply here.
Close and now you again click on this.
I can hear next to products end the left column.
You'll see that now does one element was added here.
Now do we get a book in here.
Let's go back to our note code and there we can now change then and now this is something provided by
the fact that we're using promis year when exporting the pool.
We now get back promises when executing queries like this with execute and promises have two functions
then and catch Let's explore them in the next lecture.