So we're executing a Kouri year with execute on our pool on the products table we just created and they
edit then and catch these are functions we can chain onto the result of the execute call.
So they will execute on whatever disk gives us back and does whatever is some so-called promise.
Now a promise is basic javascript object not specific to node.
It's also salable in Javascript in the browser which allows us to work with asynchronous code instead
of using callbacks which we could also use to my sequel package promises allow us to write more structured
code because instead of having a nested anonymous function here as a second argument we simply have
then block which will then get the anonymous function to execute.
Now the advantages.
We can also write it like this.
And now we have very readable code.
Instead of having a nested code here and that nested code especially becomes a problem if we have more
and more asynchronous tasks depending on each other.
Now we all don't just have then we all have catch and there's as a function which executes in case of
an error.
So for example if the database connection fails or something like this we get the error or object here.
And this is just a modern javascript syntax where we get one argument and then we handle it here.
And I can simply log it with the console so that we at least see what the error was.
Now we hopefully end up here and we probably get an argument here too.
Let's name it resoled for now.
And it's all a log saltier then.
And now let's see what we get.
If I run NPM start to bring up that server again this immediately executes because it's part of the
Rapturists file.
And if we have a look at this we see you Optik we got back and this object we essentially all is a seeded
data that was retrieved here.
Data we do get back hasn't format of an array with a nested array where the first nested array seems
to depict our data the rows it fetched anti-Second array seems to hold some meta data about the table
we fetched it from.
So result basically is that array with two nested elements.
So we can also log out results 0 and resolved one here and if we now save this and for our server restarts
we have almost the same output.
But now it's not a nested array but here we have the first object we retrieved the row we got.
And then this ends here.
Here is the closing square bracket and then here we get the second lock.
So does this result one which with the metadata.
This is what we get back in addition allow us to work with our data.
Now obviously we don't just want to work with dummy data but let's now see how we can adjust our models
to interact with our database instead of local files.