Knouted we successfully connected our code to the sequel database.
Let's start working on the project.
And for this I'll remove this code.
And you actually asked for.
Because this was just some testing code not the real code we'll use instead.
I of course want to work on my Mols here.
Let's say on the product model there we right now already have export class which we can instantiate
and where we then for example have a Save method to create a new product.
Now even though we're still fetching product from our file for now we also have our static methods for
fetching data and dare we fetch data from our files.
Now we can do that.
But of course this is not really the set up I want to use.
I will still work with static methods for fetching data but I want to fetch data from the database and
not from a file to do that in my product just fall in the models folder.
I don't need FS and Poth because I'll not work with files and playoff's anymore.
I don't need to construct a path at the top.
We can leave the cart for now but that functionality will be broken for the moment.
I don't need my helper function here for getting products from a file because it will not work with
files anymore.
I will still create a product like this so I will leave that code as it is.
However I will delete my code for saving here will override this eventually Ali will delete my code
for deleting for fetching and for finding by ID and I want to start with fetch all now here.
I also don't want to work with callbacks anymore but with promises so I don't need that argument.
The callback argument I shouldn't need that in any of my functions here.
So fetch all.
Should now reach out to the database.
And what do we need to do to do dat.
Well we need to get access to the database.
So let's import our pool object from the database js file.
So create a new constant DBI and require database website not database but will go up one level into
utile and their database Jass without JS.
So now we get access to the pool and now fetch all we can execute a query.
And now which query do we need to execute here definitely feel free to pause to video and write it on
your own.
If you already know it well here we want to fetch all products so it seeks sect's inquiry.
We ran before.
Select everything the star stands for everything.
We could all the select just the ID and title with this syntax.
But I want to select everything all fields from products.
Now as a side note you could write select and from in lowercase too.
But I like to keep these keywords uppercase to indicate what is core sequel's syntax and what are our
dynamic values.
So we select everything from products here and now as a set this returns a promise.
Now we could add then and catch here.
But actually I'm interested in the returned value in the place where I'm calling factual.
So I will simply return the entire promise that execute returns so that we can use it somewhere else.
So now we can go to the place where we do call fecche all and that isn't the shop just fall in the control
folder there for example so we get the index page we do call fecche all but right now we still pass
on a function that previously was a callback.
Now we got no callback anymore so let's take out that render code we will need data later and remove
that anonymous function instead fecche all will now return a promise so we can add then and catch.
You don't have to add both but you typically alter one to have some error handling mechanism that will
learn about a better one in the future.
So later in this course.
So here I will again simply lock my error and not do anything else with it.
But then you remember we got this nested array.
Now we can use some next gen syntax with a feature called destructuring where I can already pull out
information off the value I'm receiving as an argument here.
In my argument list.
So here is my anonymous function which will be executed once we get data and instead of using Risaldar
anything like that which is a nested array I can use the syntax here where I pull out my rows and my
field data.
You can name it however you want and this will simply be the first element off the nested array which
would be our argument data and that will be the second element.
And now we can use these two variables which simply hold these two nested erase and therefore I can
cancel lock them but I don't need to lock them.
I instead want to render my page inside of this anonymous function.
So once we got that data and Rose should be my products because my rows here are the entries in the
products table and therefore these should be my products.
If we now save that and we go back to our running application in the server all localhost 3000 we shouldn't
see the book here and also have no errors on our console.
Now we see that book because our data is retrieved from the database.
And therefore if we were to go to the database and we for example add an exclamation mark in the title
and then click apply.
You always need to do that apply close.
If I reload my page here it has no estimation marker right now.
But now it has.
So this is really coming from the database.
Now here's your little mini task.
Also make sure you're fetching data from the database when loading the product page which right now
is broken or not working.
Because there we still try to reach out to a file which will not work.
Try to fix this on your own before we also start inserting documents or elements into the database.