Adding products is also very simple.
We got our Edmund Shayla's controller where we do interact with the product in the way of creating it
here post ad product.
We create a new product called Save and I essentially want to leave that code as it is with one tiny
change.
So first of all we have to go to the product geas file in the models folder and there to save methodis
not doing anything at the moment.
Now what it should do is it should reach out to the database and save the data there.
So again I'll use my DB constant the one up here which gives me access to my database pool to my connection
pool and I'll call execute to execute a query.
Now with sequel which we saw select for getting data for inserting data there is to insert into command
and there we to find a table where we want to insert something and I'll use the products table you're
followed by brackets where realist's different fields.
We want to insert value into.
So we have the title the price D-Mich. your L and the description and important you need to make sure
that the fields you define here match the field names you defined in your table in the database.
You don't need to specify the ID because that should be generated automatically by the database engine.
Now we're not done.
This only finds where do we want to insert something to what is missing.
We now need to values keyword followed by brackets with the values.
Now to safely insert values and not face the issue of sequel injection which is an attack pattern where
users can insert special data into your input fields in your web page that runs as Seacole queries.
We should use an approach where we just use question marks one for each of the fields we insert data
into separated with clomb us and then there is a second argument we passed to execute with the values
that will be injected instead of DS.
Question marks.
So the order of the elements we add here to this array is the order of arguments here.
And we don't do this on our own because it does my sequel package we're using here.
Will then safely escape our input values to basically parse it for a hidden sequel commands and remove
them.
So now does an extra security layer and here I want to answered this title because the first question
mark will be inserted as a value for title.
So the first element here should be the title.
Second one will be the price.
So here we should have this price followed by this image your L and this description does allows me
to insert elements there.
And again I will simply return the promise that execute yields that allows us to go back to the Edmon
Jaspal to the controller and on save I can then and then and catch again and catch hell just lock to
error.
But then I don't care so much about the result.
I just want to make sure that I only redirect inside this function so only redirect once to insert completed.
Now that we can save all our files and if we now try to insert a second product with some dummy or L
which of course will not work.
Nine ninety nine and some description and we click add product here we are redirected and this is looking
pretty good.
And if we have a look at our database and click that refresh button here we see our entries our new
entry with an all generated ID.
So this is working.
We now are able to all to insert data into our database.
Now as a next step let's make sure we can click the details I can here and therefore retrieve data for
a single document or a single entry in our database.