Were able to to save a new product and fetch all products let's now find a single product by ID.
This also is not that difficult.
We can again use our D-B pool execute a query and the query we want to execute here is select everything
from products and everything here means not all rows but simply all fields.
But now we can restrict the number of rows with the WHERE condition and where is the sequel keyword.
So dare we can X you go where products ID equals one equals sign only not multiple ones as in javascript
where the idea is equal to questionmark simply to let my physical inject devalue again the ID we're
getting as an argument here.
Now let's return this promise here.
And this is our statement for fetching a single product with all the columns though.
So with all the data that we can go back to shop J.S. and dare where we do fetch a single product and
get product Well there we still use find by ID for a given product ID.
But of course no one asked to function here.
That didn't change.
Let's strip that out of there.
Simply call find by id like this and instead and then and catch and catch we got our error which we
can output and then we got our product in the end or to be precise.
We of course got that nested array where we know that the first element will be all the rows we got
and that will just be or our product or it should just be the product.
Make sure to wrap that special index square brackets into parentheses.
So now we just need to render a function here and place it in this function we passed to then and we're
extracting a product here we're passing it to our view here.
Let's see if that works.
If I now save this and I click on details this failed.
Now let's simply console log our products here to see why it failed.
If I reload this page here's what gets locked.
And the reason why it failed is that product still is an array an array with one element only but still
in that array.
But the view simply expects one single object not an array with one object.
The solution is to simply pass the first element in that array.
And we know that there will only be one element in that array.
It's never reload this page.
We see the second product.
I just didn't add an image for that.
Otherwise we would see that too.
So this is working.
We're able to fetch a single product to.