Now you could spend hours working on this application to add all the functionalities we need to add
products to a cart or to also interact with users with orders and we can do all of that with these sequinned
queries.
We're already writing here.
The problem is degrees will get more and more complex to more complex our application logic becomes.
And at some point we'll have to connect tables because one thing we're not using right now are relations
because we only got one table.
Now we can do all that just with the sequel package and if you're a sequel or a sequel master in general
you could definitely do that for the rest of us.
There is a way easier approach to that which allows us to not write all these queries we don't have
to write any sequel code but instead only work with native javascript objects that give us certain functionalities
we need for connecting to them deleting them adding them and so on will you.
And now for third party package we can add to this application that makes our life a bunch easier.
I just wanted to show you how you generally can add sequel and write your own queries as the next step
will not write our own queries.
Instead we'll find an easier approach in the next module with sequel's.