So how bad are errors.
Now arrows are not necessarily the end of your app.
You can recover from the errors.
You can inform the user that something went wrong and that he should try again.
For example you just need to handle arrows correctly.
That is a key take away and there are different types of errors.
We can have technical or network related errors where you have very little influence on at least if
you're not the system administrator.
We have so-called expect that they are us and this is not an official term.
That is something I came up with and I'll explain what this is and a second.
And we also have box or logical errors in your code.
Now for technically our hosts are mongered to be server might be down and they offer any interaction
with the database will fail in such a case.
There's not that much we can do.
The best thing might be to show some error page to the user to let the user know that something is wrong
on our end that we are sorry and that we're working on fixing the issue.
We also might want to be behind the scenes send an e-mail to the administrators or anything like that.
We also have these expected errors as I like to call them.
There are certain operations.
Let's say we are interacting with a file or with a database that can fail.
Not very often.
And of course it's not really expect that for this to fail but that can happen.
Maybe because there are too many simul take requests to a certain file anything like that here informing
the user and giving the user the ability to retry.
Might be a good solution.
For example the validation errors which we also implement in early a module these would all be expected.
Aeros users will input valid and invalid data and for invalid data we want to inform the user give the
user a chance of retrying.
And of course we also have errors in our code where we interact with a user object in a place where
it just can't exist or at least not in all circumstances.
We we should fix such errors during development.
We should test our code and we should fix such issues of course.
These are not arrows.
We should handle at runtime.
We should not show a message to the user because these errors are not the users or the networks fault
they are our fault.
So how can we work with the different types of Ariston we have to differentiate.
There are areas where the error is thrown an error or is a technical object in a node application.
So there is a built in error object which we can throw.
That's also a javascript language features.
Basically all programming languages have such a feature.
We also can't have scenarios where we can't continue with our code but there is no technical error.
An example would be that we try to log a user in but the email address does not exist.
This is not really a technical error.
There is no error or being thrown but we know we can continue.
And so we want to check for this scenario as well and handle it appropriately.
Now for the Aeros phone part we have certain tools we can use to test code and catch potential errors
so that we can handle them gracefully.
And for centredness code that would be try catch blocks for asynchronous code with promises we have
then and catch which you already saw quite a lot from this course.
In the end in both scenarios we then have the choice if we want to directly handle the error or if we
use a mechanism built into express a special error handling middleware which we haven't used thus far
which you can use to catch errors and then return a response to the user and I'll show how this works
in this module of course Florida's scenario that no Erris frozen.
Well we just have to check values with checks for example and then we can decide whether we want to
throw an error or two kind of enter the Left world here and then kick off that error handling process
or if we want to directly handle the error which is not a technical error but where we simply add some
code that can continue with the missing input data.
For example in all cases we've got different ways of communicating with our users.
We can return an error page.
So a dedicated page that informs the user hey we have a problem and that of course should be kind of
the last resort because the end user loses all his input can continue.
We also can return the page which we know which user was on and just give some error information.
That is what we did for validating for example there we returned the page to use was on kept the input
values and just added an error message.
Or we could redirect.
For example if we try to access a page which we are not authenticated to visit then we can redirect.
So these are two different tools.
We have different ways of working with Aeros we have.
And now let's dive into our code and see what we're already using and what we can use.