So in our application we get a bunch of error handling in place already.
Let's start Andy actually.
Yes there I do already handle the case or I do have a catch block at least where I try to fetch my user
at the beginning of the request and fetch it fetch the user from a session and then store that user
object.
Still we can improve that and we will improve that in a second.
In my controllers I also have some error handling.
Let's say you off genius fall there.
I do check in log in whether his email address does exist and if not I do already return the same page
with an error code.
Actually where I do pass that information that the input was invalid We do the same with the validation
logic we added earlier.
By the way here in the routes where we used the Express validator package to add built in validation
functions so built into that package there behind the scenes this package also froze and handles errors
and allows us to simply collect all these errors which are now not these technical error objects but
which are simply we're just data managed by that package.
We collect these errors here and then we handle them manually.
That would be the right side of this slide here because there we handle orders manually or we added
If check where we check if data we got is enough to continue or not.
We get no technical error being frozen here.
These technical arrows by the way can always be seen if you have an error message down there in the
terminal.
We have no such error but we still have invalid code and therefore we checked this manually and proceed
on our own in our custom validators.
However if we have a look at that there I do fro a technical error.
For example when passwords do not match.
Now this error would normally bubble up and would be handled by express but does express validate or
package happens to also handle it.
And now it's this error handling which I want to dive into first before we then start implementing proper
solutions for the different kinds of errors we could have.