So let's dive into throwing and handling arrows.
And here I do have an error in my custom validator.
Now this will be handled behind the scenes by the Express validator package.
So let's add some code that is not handled behind the scenes.
And for that first of all take a step backward.
I even quit my development server and all temporarily add a new file here error or playground.
Chase.
I will remove that it's not related to the app but there we can execute javascript code and we can executed
with the node runtime of course and end here.
Let's create a new constant.
Some where I take two values a and b.
Whoops.
So some will be a constant that holds an anonymous arrow function A and B and I return a plus b.
And then now there I call some with 1 and 2 and I can so lock the result.
Let's say now if I do this we can execute this file with node error playground.
Like this and we get free in the console down there.
And that's of course nice.
But now let's add an error.
Let's say I only pass one argument instead of two.
Now of execute this again I get not a number but not an error not a technical error object.
Now let's say here a check is a and b.
So both has to be true ish then I will return.
A-plus B.
Otherwise I'll throw that has a built in keyword and new error and that's a built in object.
No chips with where is say invalid arguments something like this.
Now let's execute this fall again.
And now we see such an error message which we saw before in the course as well.
Here we have our own error message and then we got a call stack which allows us to find out at which
function and which line number this error was thrown and what was called the that error.
We saw that before because that is the unhandled error we've Frot an error and that is a built in functionality
following such errors and node and a lot of the packages we use also fro arrows behind the scenes.
For example nobody will throw an error if it can't connect or if an operation fails.
So such Aeros can be frozen and if we don't handle them then our application just crashes.
And that's what we saw earlier in the course too.
You might remember a cases where I did something and we got Stec and that refreshed icon and the browser
kept on spinning and nothing happened.
That was because our server crashed because we had an error which we did not handle.
Now how can we handle errors.
Well one solution for synchronous code so code that executes line by line immediately and does not wait
for anything.
So for example where we don't interact with files or where we don't send requests well such code can
be wrapped with try catch and Navarrete built a language feature.
We try a certain code and then we have to add catch where we catch a potential error that might have
been thrown and then catch we can now handle it.
For example here it could output error or all.
And then I Konsole lock my error like this.
Now if my read execute my airplane don't chase fall I still get this error here.
But I get this additional Arab-Kurd message and if I not log my error object here and execute this then
actually get justice.
So then it does not crash and log it automatically.
But we could do anything we want.
We could continue with our code after this.
So here it could.
This works.
I could execute this line and we see this works being output here.
Just to demonstrate as if I comment out try catch.
And I just tried to console lock some one so I called this with an error being thrown.
Then we don't see this works anywhere because it crashes with our error at it's being thrown and it
does not continue with our code.
So this is why handling code like this is a good thing to do because this ensures that we can continue
with code that we can handle this gracefully in our node express application.
We could send the error response here which renders a valid page without crashing everything but which
informs the user that something bad happened.
And in the end this is what the Express validator package does for us with our Frot an error in our
where Frodo's error.
In the end express validator a catch justice and then just adds it to its own error or array and allows
us to read that list of Aeros it caught.
So that is what happens behind the scenes you could say.
Now here we have a look at an error and synchronous code frilling an error which we can handle with
try catch.
Now we all have async operations that can fail of course and such operations when using promises are
handled with them and catch.
And that is what we can see a lot in our code here where I do something where a find a user I have my
then block where I handle the case that the database operation succeeded.
Then I here still have my custom case to see if we did get a user because the database operation can
succeed even without retrieving a user.
But then also have a catch block here where I catch any errors that happened.
So here for example that would be the catch block related to my find one method.
So if the database operation fails because we don't have read access because the database server is
down temporarily anything like that then we make it into this catch block.
So does this try catch just with a sync code you could say then is your success KS and catch allows
you to execute code if that fails catch right away collects all errors that are frozen by any prior
then blocks.
So if we had more data then block and our chain here catch would fire on any error prone in any Then
block or any operation executed in a then block.
That's just a side note.
So it is how we can work with arus how we can handle them all now get rid of the playground file.
You find it attached to the video if you want to explore it a bit more.
Let's now see in our application how we can improve error handling.