Let's start an app genius there I have some code where I do get my user out of a session and then I
find to user by a DNA database and then I store to found user in my request object.
So that for the entire request I can access that user object.
It's a mongoose user object and it is a catch.
Any potential errors that might be happening again because it's really important does catch block will
not fire if I don't find a user with this ID.
It will only fire if there are any technical issues you could say if the database is down or if the
user does app does not have sufficient permissions to execute this action.
Now we kind of have our own error handling in place.
And again we're not working with technical error object here but here I am checking whether we do have
a session user.
And I do have a solution for the case that this is not the case because if it would not at this check
then they could try to find a user without the session object existing and that would then crash our
app.
So it makes sense to write clever code that a wide set scenarios and tries to only execute code that
will succeed.
It might of course still fail.
And for some reason we might still not find that user even if we have it stored in a session.
Maybe because the user was deleted in a database in between.
So what makes sense to us is a check for the existence of user or for the opposite.
So if user does not exist and if it does not exist here we could also return next without storing the
request user.
So just that we are super safe that we don't store some undefined object in the User object but that
we continue without the user instead if we can find to user here in the catch block logging it is not
really useful though it will make more sense to fro a new error here where we simply wrapped the error
object we get here.
Throwing this error has a significant advantage which I will show you in a second.
But with that does looks good.
We added the extra check and if we do have some technical issue we fro a real error.
And as it turns out Express us gives us a way of taking care of such errors.
That is why I'm doing it like this.
Alternatively we could of course also simply call next year to continue without request user being set
or anything like that.
But I want to throw an error because we had a technical issue connecting to our database and that is
something that might be a bigger problem than just a non-existing user.