I add it does frozen you error in actually yes and to show you what it does let me go to another place
too.
Edmond Chester the controller and change some code there.
In there we of course have plenty of code to for example add a product and we do validate user input
which is also a form of error prevention or error handling.
We do validate that input and admin shapes into a folder there we added all our validation logic.
Now in Edmond James I'm extracting my logic.
Now let me force an error by quickly looking into my database with comp pastie graphical user interface
we used before for interacting with the database.
And then there in the shop database.
Let's go to products and let me pick a product idea here.
Now we're creating a new product.
Will also add underscore ID and it will temporarily import something from the magns package
because I want to create a new object id here and I can use mongoose types object id here pass my object
id and at the New keyword and now I will basically create a new product with an ID that already exists
and they offered that should fail.
Now let me start my application and let's quickly log in with a user here.
And add a product and here you can enter anything.
Let's look at product here.
And now it will fail.
You've got this infinitely spinning refresh again.
And if you have a look at your code where at the terminal where you ran NPM start you will see that
our server crashed because Mongo Duey fro through an error with a duplicate key problem which makes
sense because we added a product with an existing ID and therefore everything crashed.
Now of course this is a constructed scenario but just because I want to ensure that something goes wrong
at this point because now I want to show you how you could handle such a problem.
Now we are logging that error and I can confirm that does catch.
It's called by adding console log an error or a Kurt and I've saved this obviously our notes are restarts.
Let's add a product again or let's try this again.
It will fail again of course but if I click add product now and I go back to my code we see an error
occurred here.
So this proves that this catch block gets fired.
But that's great because this means that we now have a chance of handling that error.
Now what we could do here of course is we could return some 500 error page.
We could also redirect the user to any other page or we could render the ad product page again.
We could even keep the old input and that might make sense if we expect this to be a temporary issue.
So of course we could take our code from Velie dating copy all that and output it to your nick or use
a tear in the catch block set a status code of 500.
Which is a code indicating that a service side issue occurred and then we want to return added product
with at product page title and product in the payoff.
By the way should be fixed up there too.
Minor thing but make sure that the navigation item is selected.
Editing set to False has error.
Beach too true dear a message we can put our own error message here.
Something like database operation failed.
At least try again.
Validation errors can be an empty array.
We don't want to put a red border around anything and we want to keep to user input.
If he saved us and everything restarts let's try to is another time.
So let's add a new product here your
like this.
The victory and product indeed.
Now we have a better error handling because now I am returning that same page.
I give the user some error message and the user can try again but of course this year will keep on failing
because we have a fundamental problem in the code.
But if that was a temporary network issue this might be a fine way of handling this.
Sometimes you got bigger problems though and you don't want to use this solution.
You don't want to return the same page again.
Instead you really want to show an error page to show the user something bigger is wrong.
We're working on it but for now you'll probably not be able to continue.
And for such scenarios I'll add a new view next to my 404 file.
I'll add a 500 Ejaz file.
We actually already have a view for error handling the 400 page 404 page.
Now I'll add another page that will render error messages for bigger technical issues.
Not for a not found drought's.
I'll copy to code from 4 0 4 included in 500 and there I will say some error occurred and there may
be some paragraph were working on fixing this.
Sorry if we're in the can.
Vincenz something like that.
You could add anything you want here.
Now we have that 500 Ejay route and that might be something you also want to do in cases where you are
not sure if you will be able to handle this otherwise.
Now to return to his 500 page.
I'll go to my error.
As controller and all duplicate my get 400 route and at to get 500 x neither with status code 500 we
render to 500 each fall with a page title of error or whatever you want lbf can be slash 500 and is
authenticated.
Yeah we use our session information for that.
Now we have get five hundred.
We just need to add a route for it at now.
Let's go to the app J.S. because in their I use get 404 for every page for every middleware that does
not get hndler ahead of time.
Now there is one extra Rather they will add with apt get slash 500.
Here I want to use error control or get 500.
So now I define a route like this slash 500.
I now just have to make sure that we do a redirect to that route.
When a 500 occurs and we want to show that page and they offer an Edmonton and the controller in the
catch block I will indeed redirect to slash 500.
And now if we save that and a try submitting this again I end up on my 500 error page and this can be
a decent way of handling this for bigger problems.