So we are redirecting to the 500 page in this catch block and we can do this in any catch block where
we want to ensure that we do handle errors.
Now the problem is will quickly duplicate our code a lot because we've got a lot of catch blocks where
we interact with the database and then every catch block here we should redirect to the 500 page at
least.
And a lot of them we would want to do that probably because for all these database failures or permission
problems it seems to be a bigger problem.
So we're turning this page might be a good solution but replicating that code all over the place is
really what people want to do.
What we can do instead is instead of redirecting here we can throw an error this built in error object
with the built in fro function or keyword.
We do that instead of a catch block.
In this case Year of the post add product action.
So here it Frot an error and I can throw an error with a bit more details.
But first of all creating an error object with new error or I can pass my error message like creating
a product failed or something like that.
Or simply keep that error object which also has a message which you get returned by the catch block
here.
So I'm creating my own object which is built up on that now and then we can also add a new field your
age that if status code and set this to 500 for example.
And now here's something cool we can return next.
And pastie error as an argument to next.
We didn't do that before right before when we called.
Next like an app J.S. here we simply called without arguments to let the next word take over.
Well when we called next with an error or passed as an argument then we actually let express know that
an error occurred and it will skip all of the middle of weares and move right away to error handling
where and that's the middle we're all defined now.
So next error is trickier with an error object being passed instead of throwing it.
And now we can go to app chess and there at the bottom let's add a new middleware.
With app use and normally this could never be reached because we have a catch all middleware down there
but there's a special type of middleware which we haven't seen before.
All malwares we added thus far for example does get 404 action in the controller.
All these malwares use free arguments request response and next express also knows a middle where with
four arguments a so-called error handling middleware and their first argument will be the error and
then followed by the error free arguments.
Now Express's clever enough to detect that this is a special kind of Bulwer and it will move right away
to these error handling Billa whereas when you call next with an error passed to it so it will then
skip all the other middleware and move to that.
And therefore here I could now render my five hundred page or simply redirect to slash 500.
I could do that and now if I save that and I go back to my application and I try adding that product
which will still fail because I didn't fix that issue.
I load my error handling page but now with this central error handling Milward knouted we added Does
error handling code.
We can of course all repeat doesn't replace us and you could refactor it into one function of course
which you then just call in all these places for example to also send an error here where we fail to
edit or load the data for editing a product.
We can force this to fail by manually filling a new dummy error in here.
Again this is of course now kind of a set up scenario you would never write this but this allows you
forced this to fail.
It would be kind of hard to force the database to fail right now because most of the time thankfully
it works.
But now I have to say dummy error and hence if I now added a product I also see my 500 page because
I Frode a stymie error which I'll of course remove now because it does not make any sense to add this.
But then we made it to catch and there we created this error object and we called Next with it and data
again pulled and triggered a special error handling Millward.
Now in case you're wondering what the status code is doing here.
Well in this scenario I'm always redirecting to the 500 Routier But of course we could have a different
scenario where we don't redirect here but we want to render a page instead.
Or we want returns I'm Jason data something we'll do later in the course and then I would want to set
my error HBC status code code here as a response code.
So this is not the solution we're using here but this is what you could do.
And I just want to show that you can pass extra information with the object so that you can use it in
this central error handler here.
Now please note that this error handler will not execute for four or four arrows.
There we still handle this manually because technically the 404 error is simply just a valid you Arel
which we catch with our catch all handler there where we don't just happen to render the 404 page.
It's not a technically error object that gets created at any point here.