Knouted we learn about does express error handling which we can use which we added.
What exactly does Frot new era or indice catch block in the middle where you just fall due for us.
I mentioned that this will become important now.
Like does it unfortunately not do anything.
Let me start up our summer Real quick again and let me ensure did we do get an error by simply throwing
a new error a dummy error.
Here again to simply simulate that something goes wrong.
I've Frot it here.
If a fro and then block the next catch block will catch it and handle it.
Now let's see what this does.
Now to see the effect I have to log in to ensure that we do get a user session and we can already see
disk crashes here.
It slows infinitely because I have an error here.
My dummy error.
So this is now not doing anything.
The app is still crashing.
So one important take away is frilling an error here does not lead to our general error handling malware
being called and that is important.
This is true because we're inside some async code inside a promise here.
We're inside then or a catch block if you fro error there you will not reach dead.
Express error handling middleware.
The interesting thing is if you what throw an error outside of async code.
So in a place where the code executes synchronously.
So basically outside of a promise than catch block or outside of a callback.
So here if I throw my sync dummy like this if we do that.
So does this now throwing in a normal function.
Not nested inside a promise or a callback or anything like that.
If I now reload this you'll see that try to load the 500 page but it still failed.
The reason for this is really simple.
We have our middleware in place here where I retrieved my user and there I wrote the error.
But this executes for every incoming request.
Now when we redirect here we do send the new request so we kind of enter an infinite loop.
We execute this again.
It was an error.
We go to the error handling middle where we trigger and you request a solution here can be to simply
not redirect to 500 but immediately execute our rendering code.
So this code in our get 500 controller action and we could absolutely do that.
We could render our error here instead of redirecting we could render our page here and if we do that
you will see that now overload.
I just get a problem regarding my C as r token because it can't be generated based on the incoming request
because that request basically has issues here in our middleware before we set up DC as our token.
So the solution for dad would be to switch the order to make sure we set this token before we actually
do something with the user which we tried to fetch.
So now this works and now we get to error handling in place.
The interesting thing is not just that we had to switch to order though and dead we should avoid infinite
loops.
But the interesting thing here also is that here I'm just throwing an error.
And we still reach this global error handling louer.
The reason for that is that in synchronous places so outside of callbacks and promises you fro in error
and express will detect this and execute your next error handling middleware inside of async code.
So inside of.
Then catch or callbacks.
This does not work however.
Inside of that you have to use next with an error or include it.
So this is then detected by express again and this is what we used and the files and inside of async
code snippets you need to use.
Next wrapping that error outside.
You can't just throw that error.
And so if an uncommon does you will see that if I try to reload my page I get this error no matter what
I do because I still have this dummy error being thrown in I promise hands to catch log executes and
still executes.
So now I will get rid of that but I will leave this catch block as it is and you have to understand
that for one you showed a white infinite loops triggered for your error handling middleware as we had
initially here.
And second that you can Rodi error in synchronous code places like this one but inside a promise then.
Or catch blocks or inside of callbacks you have to use.
Next around the error.