Now there's one thing which I also want to cover in this module and that are the HTP status codes which
codes do we have and why do we use them.
First of all start with what the codes are.
Therefore the codes are simply extra information we passed to the browser which helps the browser understand
if an operation succeeded or not.
If you're writing an application with a lot of client side javascript or a mobile app and you will fetch
only data instead of complete HTML pages something will do the rest.
Marchal later status codes also allow you to understand if an error happened which kind of error because
you typically map certain kinds of arrows to certain kinds of status codes.
For example you have 200 status codes.
Most importantly 200 in 201.
These are all these success status codes.
They indicate that operations simply succeeded.
You have 300 status codes which simply indicates that redirection happened.
You have 400 status codes which show you that something happened because an error was done by the client
for example incorrect data was entered into a form.
Well then we returned to 422 error code.
If you remember correctly and we have five hundred status codes which indicate that a reset arrow occurred.
Now here are some examples you can find a full link with a full list in electrophoresis one for success
cases we have 200 201 the differences that we use 201 typically when we created a resource on the server.
So in a database it's not a must but it's a pattern you can use and you see often 300 like 300 Mohn
simply is a code that is used in combination with redirection to inform us.
However for example this resource move permanently or just a temporary thing whatever the 400 codes
there we have 400 one for not offending that 400 free which you could translate with not all Farai.
So you might be authenticated but you were still not allowed to do that specific operation 404 for a
page that's not found 422 which we often use for invalid input and a couple of error codes and four
five hundred.
The most common one is 500 which indicates Hey that was a service error but you got all the Abo codes
for time out and so on again in the next lecture you find a full list.
Now let's quickly scan for our code if we have a look at our code.
Let's start with the admin controller.
We really set the status code.
The default then always is 200 which is fine for this case but for creating a new product it would be
better if we not just render 422 ventilation fails.
Which is correct but that when we succeed it we all the return 201.
The thing just as if we succeeded we redirect which will use a free hundred code.
But later when we dive into creating a restful API eyes which is a different kind of node app where
we don't return H.T. email but just data there you will see.
Two hundred and one code coming back here it doesn't really make sense.
Now forget that product again we're fine with 200 and we're fine with 200 here.
If we did fetch data and we do load the page and if we try to save or update a product then we get our
validation error with 422.
And if we succeed or in all cases here we redirect which again we'll use free 100 automatically.
So all these codes here are pretty fine pretty decent.
One of the most important things we're in good practice at least is that we do a use for 122 for a validating.
Now we also have is off J.S. where I do redirect when we are trying to do something where I'm not locked
in.
Now again since I'm redirecting I'm sending free status code but of course we could add status 401 here
to kind of also make clear what the problem is.
But it will be overwritten with our free code due to redirect.
So does not make a lot of sense and that is fine here.
Later again would we have a restful API where we don't redirect because we don't route around on the
server then we'll use that 400 code and for that reason that we now most of the time redirect or directly
render a page.
We don't set that many stalest codes here.
We'll see them later again as I mentioned and we see some codes at least awls in error.
As Ray said 400 four and five hundred and does say this Cote's do not mean that our app crashes.
That's important to understand.
Instead if I do enter some invalid Routier I do get page not found.
And if we open the chrome developer tools with the network tab and a reload we see that here this 404
code can be seen.
It's also marked as read because Chrome is intelligent and the text at anything which is not a 200 or
300 code is an error but error does not mean that it crashes.
This still renders a valid page India and we just passed that extra information off.
Hey here's the page but you see that page because something went wrong.
And chrome knows this too.
For example tell us to developer tools and later when we create that restful API I referring to will
also benefit from that because there we do have a more direct interaction with our requests because
we don't render new pages all the time.
And then we can get useful information out of these status codes.
So data as HIV status codes and how they are related with errors.
Your key takeaway is a status code does not mean that the request failed or that the app crashed.
We had some problem and now we're returning information with the problem to the client.
And that is also a way of gracefully handling errors.