That's it for this module we had a look at the different types of errors and how to handle them.
You can differentiate between a couple of different errors.
There are technically errors where you get this error object and where is someplace and your application
froze and error with the fro keyword and you can do that on your own or some package or express or note
itself does this.
And you can handle these errors with try catch or with then and catch in a promise for example.
And there are expect that errors and these are errors which are not technically arrows.
There is no error being frozen at least not necessarily.
But there you could be dealing with invalid user input an invalid email or some file access that should
work most of the time but might fail occasionally depending on how you treat debt.
If you throw an error or not you might still need try catch or then catch your as well but you could
also just use a check to see past that e-mail address exists in the database.
So normally if checked could do there and if you want to Frot an error or if you were once you forward
an error in then or a catch you'll learn that you can use that Global Express error handling middleware
of which you can have multiple which are an executed step by step.
You can use that and express will automatically call it whenever you next an error or you fro an error
in synchronous code.
We also had a brief look at status codes and it is a good practice or it is definitely something you
should consider that you set the right status codes on your responses so that you don't always return
200 codes but that you instead let the browser know about certain issues.
And that will become more important later in the rest API section of course when the browser gains more
power when more UI logic is executed in the browser.
And you've got different types of status codes.
You can have success costes a 2 x Cote's redirects.
Client side arrows and suicide arrows.
And you should look at all these codes and see which code is best set for your scenario your use case.
Important.
As I mentioned when you set a status code this does not mean that the app crashed or that the response
is incomplete it's simply an extra piece of information you passed to the browser.