Here's our shop and I created free products behind the scenes so you can of course create any free products
on one or more user accounts does matter and you will have free products.
Now obviously we can absolutely displayed these free products like this.
Nothing wrong with that but let's say we have hundreds of products.
We would not want to display all these products on one page.
Instead we'd like to split them across multiple pages and then somewhere on the page off at the bottom
we'd have some controls to go to page one page to the next or the previous page.
And that is exactly what I want to implement here.
Page anation.
Now you can certainly find some third party packages that can help you with that.
And these would be fine to use but I will show you how to implement that from scratch on your own because
that is obviously how you learn the most.
So back in our project how can we implement page.
Well typically you handle this.
As I said by adding some controls which always leads to the same payoff.
So always slash products or slash.
Nothing.
But then you add a curry parameter remembered query Ravagers are these parameters you add after a questionmark
which allow you to specify optional data and you could specify something like page equals one to load
the first page or page equal to to load the second page and you would change these parameters with these
controls you add.
Let me show you what I mean.
I will go into my views folder and let's work on that slash so on that route route.
So that index each fall here and there at the bottom beneath my products.
But inside of that first if block so where I that I have some products in there I'll add a new section.
I'll give it a class of page nation because this will be the section where I managed page nation.
And my idea is to have a link here which says 1 for Page 1 and 2 for Page 2.
And here I would go to slash and have page equal to one let's say and here Page equal to two.
So here it would set a creeper amateur to value one or respectively to value two.
If I save it as and reload we can see that on the left here.
Now let's change the styling real quick.
So for that I'll go into my public folder SEUS S&amp;M to main Zia's as fall and I'll scroll all the way
to the bottom right before that at me Ikari I'll add page nation so that colossi I added to the section
and I'll set text align to center and I'll also Stollman links.
This is of course totally optional but I will Stolle my anchor text in there to have no text decoration.
So to not be underlined I'll give them a color of let's say my green which I'm using in this project
I will also add some padding of let's say 5 REM and give them a border of one pixel solid and that same
green color and all the same margin of one gram left and right.
Something like this if I knew I was safe that I have these buttons here.
Now one more thing on the whole page nations sectional at a march and top off to REM and I also want
to make sure my buttons have some hover style so page anation a habere and Page nation a.
Active sets dishtowels when I hover over them or when I click on them and there I will set a background
of this green color and change the text color to white.
Now does this all optional.
I just want to have some styling here for my buttons.
So now we have these buttons and if I click one of them you can see you are l changes.
It's the same path just slash nothing but I have an optional parameter in there.
Now with that set up here let's now see how we can work with that parameter on the back end to control
the data we are fetching.