I'm setting these query parameters and I can use that data on the back end to control which data I want
to fetch.
Obviously I do that in my controllers and they're in the shop controller here.
We're working on the index page so I'm looking for to get index controller action in here I need to
retrieve the information on which page we are.
So which data for which page needs to be displayed.
So I'll store this information in a new constant named page and then that constant will I will store
request and then we can get query parameters on the query object provided by express.
And there I can access page page because I named that query Ravager page here.
So now with that I'm getting at page number and I'll store it in this constant.
Now with that we just need to define how many items should be displayed per page.
And that's something I will store as a global constant in this file.
I could also store it in a different file export there and import to here.
But I will.
Named is items per page.
And this will be let's say 2.
It should be some number lowered and the number of items you have here so that you can see a difference.
So I have two items per page here and with that and get index.
I know that I if I'm on page 1 want to fetch the first two items.
If I'm on page two I want to fetch items free and for on page free it would fetch four and 5 and so
on.
Therefore we now need to control the amount of data we're retrieving from the database find right now
gives us all the items but we can actually control this in Mongolia.
And they offer also mongooses.
There is a skip function we can add this on a cursor and find does return a cursor to skip the first
X amount of results and here that would be page minus 1.
So the previous page number in brackets times items per page.
So if I am on page 2 I would skip the first page minus one sort of first one times items per page items.
So on page 2 if I have 2 items per page I would skip the first one times to the first two items.
I don't just want to skip some items.
I also want to limit the amount of items I retrieved though so that I don't just skipped the items of
previous pages but for the current page I also only fetch as many items as I want to display there and
this can be done with the limit method.
The limit method as the names of gests limits the amount of data we fetch to.
Well number we specify here and here I can pass items per page because that is my item limit per page
with debt if we save as quote We can reload the first page with the query parameter set to page 1 and
we only see the first two items.
If I now click on two down there I only see the third item because I'm on page 2.
I skip the first two items and then fetch the next two items and I only happened to have one other item
on page 3 if I would enter this we would not find any products because I have no items for this page
but Page 1 and 2 were just fine.
So does is the general idea behind page anation.
Now obviously the idea would be dead.
We update our page anation buttons here based on well the page we are on and the maximum number of pages
that are available or something like that.
So let's see what we can do.
There.