We are able to skip and limit the amount of items we fetch and we can't control that with Kuri parameters.
But my buttons are hard coded right now and that is not ideal of course.
Instead it robber one to you maybe highlight the page I'm currently on and then show the next page number
or previous page number Florida's.
I need to fetch more information.
I will find by products and call count here and I can also add then and catch.
The important thing is I don't need catch because I'll concatenate my promised change later.
The important thing here is discipline now not to read all the products but simply just a number.
So a number of products is what I get back into a van block function year and in that function I don't
want to kick off my request where I really do fetch all the data so will return product find in here.
With Skip and limit change after it that's important.
And then I'll add.
Then block to continue.
So first of all find to count then I have this number of products here and then I kick off my normal
find method where I don't really fetch the items and I skip and limit them here.
I'll add a variable total items and all set total items equal to name products in here.
So now I will have the total number of products stored in that variable here and what I render the index
page.
Then I want to return that information as well so not just the products but also total products and
that will be total items so that will be a number in the end and also once you pass the information
wherever there is a next page so maybe Ahaz next page which only will be the case if the total number
of items is greater than the page we are on.
Times the items per page.
So we have a next page.
If items per page Times page is smaller than total items because if we have 10 total items and we are
on page 4 then we have 2 times for 8 items which we are seeing or which we saw.
We have 10 left so there will be a next page simultaneously.
I can add has a previous page here where I can simply return the information whether the current page
is greater than 1.
If that is true then there is this page because there will be page one that is false because we are
on page one already.
Well then there is no previous page because we can't go lower than one.
I can also return some extra information like the next page and that will be Page Plus one of course
if we are on page 1 the next page would be page 2 and previous page would be page minus one.
Obviously we can also add last page to have a way of displaying the highest page number that is Marth
seal.
Total items divided by items per page.
So if we have let's say 11 total items and we have items per page or to then the result would be 5 dot
5 and then Moff seal would return us 6 which would be the correct value because we would need 6 pages
to display all 11 items.
If we show 2 items per page so not passing all that information to my products page to my index page
here to be precise and there I now want to use it.