So let's now use all that information we get back from our back end when rendering our index Ejaz page
we have all these utility information pieces is still the variables like total products has next page
and so on which hopefully should be helpful.
So let's go back to index.
Yes.
And there instead of hard coding this we can now generate this dynamically.
Now I always want to have page one here that is something I absolutely need.
Let's say the page next to it should be the current page.
So actually Eva instead of total products I should return current page year which is simply the page
number so that I always know what's the currently active page and returning current page as well.
And here I can output equals current page because I'm now getting that data in my view.
And here I will load the current page number if I should click on that link again.
And this current page will receive a c is S class of active because that will always be the active class
and I'll quickly go to my main areas as fall to give that the same style as when I hover over it.
So here I'll have my page anation a class with an act class added to it with a single dot A that will
receive the same style as when I hover over it.
Now I only want to render this one byte away if dickered page is not one because otherwise it will already
rendered here so we can add some Ejaz logic here to check if current page is equal to one or to be precise
if that is not the case.
If that is not the case
then I will render this otherwise it will not rendered this so I can now close that.
Now this will only get rendered if the current page is not equal to one like this.
Does will always get rendered to current page.
And I also want to render the next page.
Let's say so I will repeat this one more time here and this will be the next page.
Remember the next page is some information which I return as well.
Next page here so will render the next page only However if there is a next page and that is a number
piece of information I do return has next page.
So let me go back and here again if has the next page so if that is true then I will render this otherwise
I won't.
So here I just close that if statement.
I also want to render the highest page so I'll add another anchor.
Here and that will justis last page information.
By the way the act of kloshe of course not be Editor at all and not be editor here.
So hearable rendered a last page and it leads lead to last page here.
It will lead to next page by the ways and we have to adjust this link.
Obviously here it's the last page
and this last page should also not always be rendered it should only be rendered if last page is not
equal to the current page.
So if we are not already on the current page because then this link would already rendered a link to
this last page and the next page should all not be equal to the last page because if it is then this
link will already be rendered.
And does this then the last and next page simul tenuously.
But if both is not true then I will render this.
Now let's have a look at this.
And let's reload this and here the error little logical error count used to be the function you should
use.
Now it's count documents.
So change counts to count documents here.
But does Erris not coming from that.
And in this case here I got a dollar sign instead of a percentage sign which I should use.
With that fixed does looks better.
But I got 11 here and then got you again.
So there seemed to be some issues.
For one it's rendering.
The one here even though the current page is not equal to one.
The problem here is really just the data format.
We're comparing strings and numbers here.
So I should remove one equals sign.
And now this works.
And now regarding the 11 next page somehow is calculated to be 11.
The reason for data is that page here is a string not a number and therefore page plus one gets concatenated
to 1 1 so to 11.
This can be fixed by adding up Lussier in front of request queries page.
And now does looks better.
Now I can switch between these two and does is looking all right now with that error or does format
this data type error fixed.
Now what happens if I load that page without the page Corre parameter that I have does not a number
issue here.
And to fix this I can add two pipe symbols here in that one.
And this means if this is undefined or if this does not hold a true ish value then we'll use disvalue
instead with that if I saved it
and I reload this page I'll start on page 1.
And now I can jump around.
Now let's try this.
When changing the items per page to one Soledad we should have one extra page.
Now if I reload this with Page 1 be loaded I can go to page 3 and one two three.
Now I don't see a two when I'm on page free because we have no logic for it and our template right now
I could of course add that logic to all the showed a previous page for that I can replicate this and
if I have a previous page
then I can show my previous page and link to it here.
Now of course I want to know what did I have to wonder if I'm on page 2 because that would render dis
link and that would render this link.
So I don't want to render this first page if I am on it already or if it's equal to the previous page.
So I only want to render this first page.
If it's not equal to the current page and if the previous page is not equal to 1 now by the way since
I fixed that data type we can also work with double equal science here again it's not very low at this
page.
It's in the wrong place the previous page here should be before.
Does current page let's fix that.
Reload again.
Now it is looking better.
Now I can go to page to page one and that all seems to work.
Now let's add another product product for with another deck again to see how it works with four products
on the shop page.
And now I see the first page the next page and the last page to go to the last page I.S. to previous
page and the first page.
If I go to free will then I have the previous and the next page which is the last page and the first
page.
So now this page nation is working and you can always of course tweak this to your requirements or your
different needs.
But now this is looking good to me here.