So now we edit page nation to our application.
And of course you can now tweet us adjusted to your needs.
Change the items per page you want to display For example if you switched to and you reload you won't
find items on page 4 but you will find items on page 1.
And now you got all that logic in place that should allow you to display the data you want to display
and to not fetch all the data in one go.
And it's important for you to understand that since find uses a cursor.
It does only retrieve the items you need to count documents does not retrieve all.
It only counts them which is fostered and retrieving them and skip and limit all manage.
Or are managed by man would you be in a way that you only transferred the items overdue wire which you
really need.
So does this not doing some server side filtering of the data every filter set on the database server
already.
So this is how you can add pagination to your node express application.