In this module I now want to give you an introduction to how you can send e-mails from inside your node
application obviously sending emails is a crucial task in many web applications and on our Web sites.
We want to send an e-mail ofter a user signed up for example to confirm did you sign up something like
debt.
That.
I will show you how that works what sending e-mails in a note application actually means and which part
note J.S. and EXPRESS Has play in that big picture and will then implement that will then implement
a package that helps us sending e-mails and we'll send the e-mail.
Upon successful sign up.
So let's work on this in this module.