So how does sending mails work.
Well you obviously get our notes server with our code and we get our user and we want to send the email
to the user.
Now it's super important to understand and a common misconception that note and express Yes these are
language languages or frameworks run times that we use for writing our server side logic but with no
yes you can't trivially create a mailing server handling mails.
It's totally different to handling incoming requests and responses.
It's a totally different technology something totally different happens behind the scenes.
Therefore in reality you will very likely never implement your own mail server because that is a very
complex task.
Creating a mail server that is capable of handling that dozens or a one hundred thousands of e-mails
at the same time sending them and so on security all that stuff is highly complex.
So in reality you typically use third party mail service for that and that is exactly what you will
do in this Marchal too.
But I will show you how to interact with such a service to send that e-mail frood at service.
And by the way all major web applications you might be interacting with including you to me don't have
their own mail servers they are using third party providers like A.W. as well whatever it is for sending
e-mails.
So that is exactly what we will do in this module to.