So in this course I will use send.
Garrett you'll find it on sent Gritz dot com and I'll use it because they have a free entry here which
stays free as long as you send less than 100 e-mails a day.
Now there are many alternatives MailChimp AWOS s.c.s and you can google for node mailing and your favorite
mailing service to find tutorials on how to implement it.
Now I will use this one because we can use it for free.
So let's click try for free and then we simply have to create an account there.
Now once you did sign up you can quit that page here and go back to your note project and they will
now install a package I'll install a package with NPM installed dash dash save which is called node
Meyler and to interact with sent grid.
I'll also install another package in the same go node mailer Dasch send Garrett Desch transport.
That is a package that will help us with integrating Sanskrit and conveniently use stats together with
node Meilleur node Meilleur is a package debt as the names gests makes sending emails from inside no
chase a breeze with it all at it.
We can move on to the next lecture and now start using node mailer to send messages.
So let me start and start again.
Let's continue in the next lecture.