I added note Mailer and now I want to use Noad mailer to send an email or that in my office last fall
which is the only filer I will interact with it.
I will import no Mailer and stored in constant at the top.
So require node mailer like this and it will also import send grid transport.
You can name these concepts the way you want as always and this will inport node Meilleur centered transport
with that imported.
I can initialise a couple of things here for note Meilleur we need to initialize a so-called transporter
so that is essentially some set up telling node Meilleur how your e-mails will be delivered.
Because as I mentioned Noach J.S. won't do this on its own.
You need some third party service for that.
So you're able use node Meyler and then call the Create transport method and create transport.
We can now pass central to transport and execute this as a function because this function will then
return a configuration that node mailer can use to use Sanskrit.
Now two dead central transport function we pass an object where we pass an off object and this in turn
holds an object where we have to pass in the API user and API key field.
Now both our values you get from inside your central account.
So if you head back to your center grid account you can click on settings here and then a.p keys and
there create a new API key.
You want to give that a name an all name that node shop the name is totally up to you.
And I'll take full access and create this.
Now take that key and you actually only need that key.
You could have used your username and password but I'll just use the API key.
So just dead key which you copied here of course use your own key not mine.
And with that you configured the transporter
now with the transporter configured you can now use it to send an e-mail and a one to send an e-mail
or after signing up let's say so in posts sign up once I'm done.
So here when all's redirect back to the logon page here I want to send my message.
And I used to transport her for dead.
And then there is a send mail method we can execute to that method.
You pass a javascript object where you can figure the email you want to send.
For example the two fields so to whom this should go.
While this should go to our e-mail address of course from so which e-mail address will be displayed
and hearable have shop at Noad complete dot com.
Let's say then a subject sign up succeed it and then Khumalo content so the content of your message.
Now you could have a complex HVM l message.
I'll just add H-1 tag here.
You successfully signed up like Det.
So it is the message I want to send now send sendmail then gives me a promise so I can use of then and
catch or of course I simply return that and then I redirect in the next and then block so once the email
has been sent however to this up to you you could also redirect immediately and not wait for this to
be sent because you're not really relying on that being sent.
And so this will send.
And at the same time you redirect.
So whatever you want what you should do though is if that is your plan you might want to switch positions
here and still return that so that you can still catch any errors that are stemming from this.
So that here we could still log any errors we might be getting or do something else with these errors
of course with this set up at it.
Let's give it a try.
Let's head over and sign up.
And now you should use a real e-mail address of course.
Otherwise it can't arrive.
Click sign up here.
I am redirected.
And now check your e-mail account.
And in that e-mail account you should have a e-mail from shop at Note complete dot com with that message.
If you don't get it verify you entered a correct e-mail and also feel free to verify your send read
e-mail.
You should have gotten an e-mail from the Sanskrit when signing up verifying your e-mail address there.
But with that this should work and you should be able to send e-mails like this.
Now dive into the official send read docs and all the no mail or docs if you want to learn way more
about what you can do there.
Also as I mentioned Google for node Meyler and your favorite e-mailing service if you want to use a
different one.
But is this the general theme of how this works.