So in this module I showed you how to send mails with no Mailer and in this case send a third party
service.
Now one thing I also want to highlight is the way we send that e-mail here works for our app and it's
good that we don't block the redirect but then we redirect and sent the mail at the same time because
if you have application with a lot of requests and you would wait for the email to be sent before you
redirect.
You might slow down your application because you're sending a lot of e-mails.
Now depending on the size of your app and now we're talking about really huge apps you could also look
into totally different approaches.
Mary you have some server side scripts running every x hours or every X minutes that send e-mails to
newly signed up users.
Now this will only matter from a certain scale of app on and there you have different problems anyways.
But I just want to highlight that you should strongly consider not using this in a blocking way because
if you wait for it to be finished this can be slow and you have to evaluate if it's worth waiting for
days or if your user can continue even without that mail being delivered.
Now with that you learn how to send mails.
Not that difficult as you can tell.
Now let's use that knowledge in the next module and it haunts our often dictation process or our authentication
features we offer.