Welcome on of course I'm extremely excited to have you as a student in this course.
This course is all about.
No genius.
One of the most exciting Cirus technologies you can learn these days.
And in this course we'll not just dive into its basics though we will also do that but we'll dive into
exciting topics like handling file uploads page anation working with different databases sequel and
no sequel databases for example building an app where we render the use dynamic H-2 mail on the server
and building restful and even graph Q L API is working with real time data and web sockets and much
much more as you will see in the outline which will come later in this module.
There is a lot of content in this course and it definitely is no short course but it will take you from
Ciro to advanced.
No JS developer and by the end of this course you will have all the knowledge you need to dive deeper
into advanced topics and start building your own.
No child has projects and applications of course and will not just learn all of that.
In theory we will build real projects in this course.
We will build an entire online shop including checkout and payment with Dr. J.S..
So there's a lot of content to cover and I'm really excited to dive into it together with you.
Now who am I.
My name is Max Schwartz Molla and I'm a freelance web developer as well as five star rated instructors
here on you and me.
I got multiple best selling courses and no chess is a topic that was missing thus far.
Well it isn't anymore and I had a lot of fun creating this course.
I hope you have equally much fun and you'll learn a lot.
Was going through the course so let's dive in and let's start with the most important question.
What is no chess.