So let's dive into the most important question what is what.
J.S. No James is a javascript runtime.
And now what does this mean.
You know javascript it's programming language you typically use in the browser to manipulate your dom
to manipulate the page which was loaded in the browser.
For example to open a pop up a modal or add any kinds of effects because Javascript is a language that
runs in the browser that allows you to interact with the page after it was loaded and if there is a
crucial part when it comes to building interactive user interfaces in the browser.
So whatever your users see however javascript is not limited to that.
No chess is a different word of javascript you could say it is basically built on Javascript it adds
some features to it is not capable of doing some things you can do with javascript in the browser.
So it basically takes javascript and puts it into a different environment.
It allows you to run javascript code on the server.
You could say in theory not just on the server but on any machine.
So it basically allows you to run javascript not just in the browser but anywhere else like a normal
programming language like normal programs on your computer or some computer in the Internet effectively
making it a great choice for building web applications that run on servers which are just computers
running somewhere in the Internet.
So in detail this means that we can use no chance to run javascript outside of the browser.
That is the core takeaway.
Now how does this work.
Technically Well no yes uses We ate and we ate simply the name of the javascript engine built by Google
dead runs javascript in the browser.
So back to the browser we now are we simply to name the creator SKAIFE engine.
And what does an engine mean.
Well it simply means that engine takes javascript code the code running in your browser then or in notes
case which builds up on it.
Also do you know just javascript code it takes that javascript code and compiles it to machine code.
And this is what your browser does to what it does in your browser.
It does take your javascript code and compile to machine code because dad is to code that runs ultimately
on your computer.
And that can be handled efficiently.
Now this is done by the eight the eight itself is written in C++ but that doesn't really matter too
much for you.
You don't need to write any C++ code to use javascript or no.
Yes but no.
Yes basically takes that reate codebase which is written in C++ and adds certain features like for example
working with your local file system opening files reading files deleting files.
These are all things which are not possible in the browser.
You can't access your local filesystem in the browser for security reasons so it does not support it.
No chase adds these features to the eight's engine you could say.
So as you can suddenly do that now.
No Chase does not run in the browser so these restrictions still apply.
They are YOU use vanilla.
We ate so we ate only without the know as extensions.
But if you don't install no chips you can use it to basically use that extended V-A to work.
To run javascript scripts on your computer which then subtly can access these new features because they
don't run in the browser but are directly executed through that no chance runtime you could say.
So does this how that works to Gavron what no chaced does it allows you to run javascript on your computer
and it adds useful functionalities to the javascript engine so that you can do more useful stuff there
than you can do with browser side javascript.
Now one important note may be out on this point.
Also is that of course some features are also taken away in the browser you use javascript to interact
with the document object model.
So if t h t m l elements on your page.
If you just execute a javascript file directly you of course have no attached page and they for these
features are missing but this is a lot of theory.
Why don't we just have a look at this and see how we can install and use notice and what it actually
does for us.
Let's do that in the next lecture.