So we want to use no.
And the first important step is that we install it and for that you have to visit.
No yes.
Dot Orrick there you'll find an installer.
In my case here it picked the rifle for my operating system Mac OS but you will also find a Word for
Windows.
If you're wisit doing this page on Windows or you manually choose a different word and you can of course
follow along no matter which operating system you're using.
The code you write and two steps you need to take to install no Cheras are exactly the same.
You simply download the latest word in here and you then simply save it anywhere and run the installer.
This gives you now simply follow through all the steps which are mentioned in the installer except the
license agreement and so on.
So simply click through that.
Install it on your machine.
And once it is completed you already got everything you will need to ride.
No.
Yes code.
So this is super fast it's done here.
You can close this now.
And now how do we use no chance.
Well the easiest way of using it is to open up your local terminal or on windows power shell or the
command prompt in its terminal as a first step simply run node Dasch the like this.
This should show you the worship of no chance you installed.
Now with that being executed you can now use note just like death to enter a special input mode.
The so called REPL will come back to that where you can execute code and have it parsed by node on the
fly.
You can use this as a calculator simply type 2 plus two to see the result.
Or you can write whole javascript programs there.
Now I won't do that.
So you can Quintard with control.
And instead let's write a real script which we can execute with no choice so that we can all see what
we can do with it for that create a new folder anywhere on your computer and open that folder in your
favorite ID or a code editor.
Now here I am using Visual Studio code.
You can find that on code that Visual Studio dot com.
This is a great idea which I strongly recommend using.
It's FREE.
It is really belled for you such with javascript code.
It will work great and you can simply download it from this page.
As I said for free simply walk from the installer.
It's all the way Lebel for Windows and so on.
Walk for the installer it gives you.
And then once it's installed.
Simply start it and opened that new folder you create it somewhere on your computer.
This will be your project folder for this very first quake app or script.
We're going to right now your Visual Studio code might look a bit different.
I'm in fullscreen mode which is why you don't see any menu items here at the top.
And I also got two important things installed here.
The first one is the theme and you can hit command shift P or control shift P on Windows to go to that
quick command interface here and there if you type theme then you can go to the preferences color and
choose which theme you want to use and I'm using the dark plus Feme here.
So if you want to get the exact same coloring you can choose that.
And I also installed an extension.
You can view the extension menu by going to view extensions or if you have on the left a menu you can
also click on the X Chens extensions tap there but you extensions will do or the shortcut you see there.
And there I installed the material I theme this theme here I already got that installed.
And this gives me some special fall Aikins and so on.
You don't need that.
You just can use it if you want to the exact same layout and thereafter you can go back to the view
Explorer here.
Now this is then my set up I get a good ignore file here since I'll use GET FOR WORD management.
You don't need that.
And with that let's simply create a new file here with control and command and or by clicking that I
can here and then simply give it any name you want like.
First app dot J.S. dot JSC is of course important because we're creating a javascript app here now in
there.
We can run any code.
No Chase is capable of executing.
And for this I will write a simple script.
I will simply write console law.
Hello from node genius.
Now you could write this in the browser to the browser would be capable of running this and it would
lock does indeed javascript console in your browser dev tools.
Now you can also execute does with no Acharyas though for this.
Go back to your terminal or command prompt and make sure you navigate into that new folder you created
with the help of CD and so on.
You can alternatively also go back to your code and there under the.
You can open that terminal and it will give you your default system terminal already navigated into
that folder.
So that's a bit more convenient.
And then here you can run.
Note.
And now.
First dash app dot.
J.S. so that filename if you now would enter.
You should see Hello from though jazzier because this executes your code and this already shows you
that node is javascript on your computer.
This is not using a browser it's just using the internal engine.
The extended internal javascript engine used by the browser to execute your code locally totally outside
of the browser.
And of course we can all do more than just logging something.
Let's for example write this text to a file.
For this we can import something from the no chase environment.
I mentioned that it would add new features to javascript right.
You have to import them and I'll come back to the detail import syntax and which features accessed a
little bit later.
For now just follow along to this first quick demo and create a new constant.
Also give you a brief refresher about concepts and Javascript in this course and then type require.
F s f s stands for file system and disinfects simply imports some file system functionalities into Does
javascript file so that we can use these functionality Stehr we can now use F as right file sync here
to create a new file and this takes a couple of arguments and the first argument is the puff where you
want to store that file and that also includes the file name.
Now I want to created in that same folder so I will simply name it.
Hello dot text for example.
And the second argument is the data we want to put in there and there we'll just put Hello from node.
J.S. with this if we now save this and we re execute this with node first apt J s.
You should have a hello txt file here and this gives you the text written in there.
And this is something you couldn't do in the browser because it's there.
You can't access your local file system and obviously it's features like this which you need to dentals
also create a server which we don't have at this point.
By the way this is not a web site obviously is just some utility script and this is something we can
do with no chips.
Well does a first quick demo will learn all the cool features and how this works and what exactly does
send Texas for over the course of course.