So you hopefully got a first picture of what no jazz is and why you use it and what you use it for.
Now typically And also what we will do in this course you use no chase to run it on a server to write
server side code.
And for that we have to have a look at the full picture.
We have our users using a client computer with the browser their mobile phone with a browser.
Even mobile apps and we will come back to how no CIOs can communicate with these later in the course
too.
But for now let's stick to the traditional browser picture.
We get our users using the browser and there we can use H TMLC s s and Javascript javascript in the
browser to create web pages.
Right now they with a page my page dot com and they send their request to do so.
For example by entering a you are in the browser a request is sent to your mail.
Now there does server A comes into play.
We got our server some computer running in the Internet which has the IP associated with that domain
which is automatically resolved for us.
And on that server we don't want to execute some code that does something with the incoming request
and returns a response often but not necessarily always as you will learn this response is the H team
l page which a browser that in turn can display by the way it is not necessarily just h m l it's also
things like C S S files or javascript files with javascript code for the browser not for the server.
Now on the server we typically do tasks that we can't or don't want to do from inside the browser for
performance for security reasons we connect to databases for example to fetch and store data.
We do user authentication which we obviously can only do on a place to use reconned access to make it
more secure and avoid it being hacked.
We do it for input validation to see if a user entered a correct e-mail address.
The browser can always be tricked.
Users can even edit their browser or site code.
You can open the developer tools and start working on that page you're on.
But this server is of course sheltered from that.
User can't access it.
And in general we have our business logic on the server ever thing our user shouldn't see which takes
too much time to run in the browser.
Well we obviously want to deliver a fast user experience or anything of that kind.
And that is where we use no J.S..
So all the javascript code.
But this time not on the browser but on the server.
And this is where we use the many features.
No chest gives us this is how we indirectly allow our users to work with the server request response
pattern that direct access is not available.
So this is how we will use no chase and this course also we will use it to write code on the server
that returns state to our users.
Our clients can work with.
Now one important side note at this point of time no chase is not limited to running code on a server.
Its a job this could on time and you even saw first demo which did not do anything where we needed a
browser right.
We didn't spin up a server there.
We didn't do any thing which we would have reached through a browser.
We'll do that a lot for the course but we haven't done it thus far because it's just a javascript runtime
we can execute any javascript code with no chance and often that is code that runs on a server and is
executed upon incoming requests.
But you also often use no chips for over a code for example for local utility scripts or Bell tools
if you work with let's say react or angular or view or anything of that kind you actually used no yes
indirectly a lot for all the build processes.
These languages are frameworks needed because as you know Chaske is a great tool for writing utility's
scripts.
You have access to the file system so you can write and read and manipulate files.
And this allows you to do a lot of utility stuff on your computer that is never exposed to the public.
And I just want you to know that.
And I'll even have a section this course where I dive a little bit more in such built tools and non
servus language usages of note.
Yes in general and that is the most popular thing you do have no chest though you use it in the context
of web development and service side code.
So you use it to run a server.
And actually that is an important difference too.
For example with no chess you don't just write the code that is running on your server.
You also write the server yourself.
So the code that takes the incoming requests and routes them to your well over code impeached.
You have extra tools like apache or Jencks which run the servers which listen to incoming requests and
then do your speech code here.
No she asked us both.
It does.
They're listening.
And it then also does whatever you want to do in your code.
So that's important and that's something you'll see in action soon.
We also use it or we therefore also use it to run all our business logic.
So not just to listen to incoming requests but to then work with their requests data work with files
work with databases all that fun stuff.
Nocera has is capable off and will do all that in this course obviously.
And we also handle the response site not just incoming requests you will also learn how you use no chance
to send back data to your clients.
Be that H.T. mail pages.
HTML pages with dynamic content or data only in the form of Jason or Exham or even files.
So this is what we use and okay and what we will dive heavily into in this course.
Alternatives to no chase would be things like Python.
Also with frameworks like flask or Django or BHP with frameworks like level maybe or standalone vanilla
Peachi of course and more as Peter and Ruby on Rails all that stuff this basically are all replacements
for.
No yes or no chicest can be a replacement for them and there is no clear winner.
All these languages are capable of doing the same kind of stuff.
And of course they differ in some technical regards but in general it's great to have that broad variety.
The huge advantage or one huge advantage of no chase is that it uses Javascript a language which you
need so much in modern web development.
For all the Front-End for some built tools and if you demin can also use it on the server side.
You don't need to learn a bunch of different languages.
You can use one in the same language and then use that for your server side code too.
This is why Nocera is a great language to learn.
You get so much efficiency out of it.
It's also a highly performant and popular language.
There are so many jobs out there for no chess.
There never was a better time to learn it.
It's used in so many environments.
Also for a lot of cutting edge stuff but in general no chess is a great solution.
It's trending.
It's fast it's efficient and it makes sure that you only need to learn one language to write all the
code you need in a modern web application.