Noted we had a look at the basics about no chairs what we can do with it and now did we even used it.
Let me walk you through the content of this course and explain what's in the course and where you can
find what we're almost done getting started in the next module.
I will give you a brief javascript refresher just to make sure we're all on the same page regarding
the core javascript syntax but more importantly about some Next-Gen javascript features which we'll
use in of course basic javascript knowledge is assumed and will not be taught in that module.
But if you just need a refresher.
Some additional information or this next gen javascript knowledge then this is a module you should take.
Otherwise it's optional.
Now offered as a refresher or immediately after this module.
If you don't need a refresher will dive into the notorious basics.
How it generally works how we can work with streams of data and some core no chess modules.
So really the nitty gritty details you need to know about the language so to say.
And will then dive into efficiently developing with nodes.
J.S..
How you can debug your code handle errors and so on.
Now they are after all dive into Express Geass.
The most popular framework you can use for notorious.
I'll explain why we use it and why we still in it's hard use no G-S why we still learn about no chess
even though we use Xpress to us because using it makes sense it makes things easier.
You will use it if you are working with no chance but still of course we still use no chase.
With all of that now.
Thereafter We'll dive into templating engines that are basically some tools you could say that allow
you to generate HTL pages on the server with dynamic content encoded in them and that is how you can
return different pages or pages with different content.
Back to your users.
So that will be an important module.
Now their offer will dive into the model view controller pattern what that is and why we use it.
And of course how we use it and will then have a look at some advanced routing concepts.
Routing is something we'll also learn and expressed as module and we'll dive deep into the models of
the model view controller pattern.
Now after we're done with that it's time to dive into databases.
I will start by connecting our node application with a sequel database.
My sequel.
To be precise as a next step will dive deeper into that and use a package that makes working with siecle
databases easier.
Sequela is now and after having seen sequel will continue with no sequel and see how we would use that
eval use Mangu is there to also make work that easier and will then stick to no sequel for the rest
of the course but you'll thoroughly learn both sequel and no sequel no authors will dive into sessions
and cookies.
What that is why you use it and how you use it.
We'll have a look at often dictation.
So how we can make sure that users can sign up and sign in with our application will dive into sending
emails how that would work.
How can we auto generate emails when a user signs up for example.
We'll also dive into advanced authentication features and also offer accusation which means that for
example only a user who created a product can edit or delete it.
We'll then have a look at user input validation which is a crucial part in any web application because
you want to make sure that the data your users enter into your forms is correct and valid and you'll
learn how you can do that efficiently.
In this module and will then dive into error handling because errors will happen.
For example if the user enters wrong input and I will show you how you can handle different kinds of
errors in an elegant way.
Now their offer will divert to something important.
File up and downloads.
How can you handle these.
How can you write code that takes incoming files store them and is able to return files.
I'll also show you how you can automatically generate PTF documents on the server in this module.
Well then have a look at page anation.
So how we can return our data in chunks instead of all the data at once.
Which is not ideal for your bandwidth.
Will there ofter have a look at async request and I'll explain what that is and how we can handle it
with no choice and will then dive into payments.
How can we accept payments from a service called Strype J.S..
Obviously something we'll need in any shop we built and thereafter will dive into a different kind of
application you can build with no chairs.
We'll dive into rest.
AP eyes and one module does not sound like a lot of content on this very important technology.
But actually I got two modules on that and we'll also dive into file uploads and rest API.
Authentication page anation all that stuff.
And additionally these modules will build up on the entire modules before that because you will learn
the arrest API does not differ that much from a normal node application.
And I will show you in detail which knowledge you still need and how you need to change some things.
Not that many actually to turn an existing application into a rest.
API now.
And once we're done with that I will dive into a more modern javascript feature.
A single weight and how you can use that in your node application and will dive into web sockets and
socket I O does that technology or a set of technologies that allows you to add real time functionalities
to your app.
So for example if one user sends a message and you instantly want to notify an every user you can use
WEP sockets for that.
And I will show how it works in this module offered as Marshall will dive into a different kind of API
as we had a look at rest API as well and have a look at graph Q API eyes graph Q is a very modern and
popular way of building API.
It has some advantages over rest.
API is also some disadvantages.
And I will dive into graphical and how it differs from rest API eyes in this module and I will show
you how to build a graphical API from scratch with no genius and this will be quite a big module even
though its only one block on this slide.
Now there often will have a look at deployment.
How can you take your application you build all your node code you build.
How can you take that and move it to a real server in the web and ensure that it runs there.
This will be shown there.
There are also dive into things like setting up SSL encryption and once were done with that I'll have
a short module on note.
JS functionality is beyond creating web service with it because you can use it for other things too.
As I WILL mentioned there.
And then we're done.
I'll end the course by giving you some next steps potential ideas on how to continue and by the end
you will have learned a lot about nodes J.S. and express and the many things we'll dive into in this
course.
I hope you are as excited as I am and with that let's quickly move on so that we can quickly get to
the point where we write code.