Sahnoun and you learn what's inside this course a whole lot.
As you can see let me explain to you how you can get the most out of this course because this is really
important to me.
I want to make sure that you learn a lot.
Now obviously you want to watch the videos.
Now that seems pretty obvious but this is a video on the main course.
Watch the videos at your speed.
This is really important.
You can use the playback controls here and you want me to fine tune the speed speed me up if I'm going
to slow reduce the speed a bit if I'm going too fast.
Also make sure to occasionally jump back to older sections or videos.
This is our normal process and learning.
Sometimes you need to reiterate concepts you learned before you want to use that on the Mont. nature
of the course.
You don't have to go at the speed I.M. you don't have to go lecture by lecture and then never go back.
Use the tools you got here used to course to its fullest potential and use the on the Mont. nature in
this course.
We will also build projects and you will find a lot of exercises and assignments.
I encourage you to do this of course you can all just watch meet code and just watch my solutions to
the assignments.
But you will learn way more if you try to solve these things on your own.
And if you actually code along now.
One important note for this is of course that you want to do that also at your speed and buy.
Well of course all of following along the videos but also make sure to Google for problems if you hit
any.
Not because I don't want to help you I will help you if you need help but because this makes you a better
learner you need to be able to solve your problems on your own.
And I see too many students who have to ask first research later mentality and this is not really that
great for you.
This makes me learn it better because I get challenged a lot which is great.
But you learn more ultimately.
So definitely try to solve your problems on your own.
It will help you a lot.
Also use all the course resources you find in there.
That's not just the videos.
That's also the attached source code which you find attached to the last lecture of each module which
you can use to compared to your code if you're facing any problems.
And again this is a great way of solving problems on your own by comparing the solutions and finding
out what went wrong on your own.
So use all these resources.
Also make sure to use the additional links I occasionally post and some lectures where you can research
a bit more about certain topics and dive a bit deeper in cases where you're interested in that topic.
Now last but not least this course like all year to me courses has a Q and A section.
You can post questions on that yode.
There is a Q and A button at the bottom of the video or in the course dashboard d general Q and A section
and you can search there.
Make sure to all the search to Q&amp;A before you post often a question has already been answered.
But you can also post there if you got a question.
Now the thing about asking is asking is easy answering is hard.
So try helping.
Obvious to take this opportunity of answering to questions of other students simply because you again
get challenged.
And if you're wrong that doesn't matter you'll be correct then you'll learn again but you will learn
so much by being forced to think about a problem.
Articulate a solution and the best of all.
You also help students so help each other.
I will also help you of course but if you do all these things you'll get a lot out of this course promised.
But with that let's leave this first module and continue with the course.