Number four we finally dive into the javascript refresher or optional in case you skip that into the
notorious basics.
Let me dive into two different ways of executing your note code one way of executing it which I briefly
mentioned earlier in this module is the REPL replow stands for read reading user input evil evaluating
user input friend outputting a result and L loop for returning and waiting for a new input and the REPL
is what you use.
If you just type node into your terminal here I am in the terminal or on Windows to this what your command
prompt and then if you just type a node with node installed you are now in the REPL which you can identify
by the fact that you now don't have that full pop your computer name at the beginning but just dead
greater than sign.
And there you can execute node commands like console lock 2 plus 2 or also writing interacting with
files.
You can import a file system there just as we did it previously in our file and then we can use that
to write a file synchronously and so on.
So that will all work here.
And this is of course an environment where we don't store our code and files.
But you write our note application with every line.
The lines don't work independent from each other.
So I can now use the filesystem package for example.
Now that I imported one line earlier but once I quit out of this Prose's with control c I'm done.
Does this not saved anywhere.
Does this not a file I can execute again and therefore is a great playground.
The alternative to running code is that you execute files as we did it before and as you will basically
do it for the rest of the Course.
This is the alternative to using the REPL when you execute files.
The advantage of course is and that is why we use it for real apps that we write our code in advance
and we can always execute it and when we build a real app we want to save our code of course in files
which we can then deploy in the end which we could share with our developers and where we can also pause
our work and pick up later.
And we never lose to code we write but the REPL is a great playground because we can use it to run some
commands to try out certain things because we execute code as we write it and therefore these are the
two ways of running your node code.
Obviously we'll go with the store code and files approach and discourse.
But whenever I say REPL I'm referring to does direct input way which I can recommend for trying out
some features but not for writing real applications.
That is not what you would do.
I just wanted to get these two ways out of the way.
We'll focus on the left one here and with that let's dive into writing some code with the next Martial's.