You did it your belt an amazing no.
J.S. application and then this course we actually built a couple of applications and we're typically
not just doing this for our own practice or to do it on our PC only Instead we of course want to deploy
this application into the web so that it is reachable by our people.
Because as long as it's running on local host only you can reach it.
And that is the idea during development of course.
Now in the US module will move from development to production and you will learn how we can prepare
our project for deployment.
There are some things we just want to adjust or where we want to make sure that we don't skip them.
Well then of course also walk through all the important steps and the configuration you need to do to
deploy your project to a hosting provider.
And we'll talk about security because dad obviously is connected to deploying your app because as soon
as it does not run on your own computer anymore you obviously have to make sure that some things just
are well secure.
So let's dive into all these things in this module.