Now obviously in this course we built a couple of different applications to be precise.
We built an application with service he had rendered the use and that includes the possibility to return
just HTML pages or as we did is to use a templating engine like Ejay s and obviously we built two API
eyes.
We built the rest API allograft UL API.
Now how do we deploy these two types of applications.
One with the use and one without the use.
First of all we have to keep in mind that how the application behaves what it does with incoming requests
and which data it accepts and returns does all our logic.
This is all code we wrote in the end when we look at it from a technical perspective.
In both kinds of applications we start a normal node server and we use a node framework.
In this case the most popular one express and therefore these types of applications have the same hosting
requirements.
We dont have to make a difference here because in the end when we move our code to a web server then
there we also just want to do the exact same thing we did locally will start our node server and wait
for incoming requests and therefore we dont have to differentiate between these kinds of applications.
When it comes to deployment we simply deploy our code start to know its server and we are good to go.