How do we then prepare the code for production.
Now this obviously always depends on the kind of application you're building.
In general you want to use something which is called environment variables and I will show you what
this is.
In our concrete projects in this module no worries use environment variables instead of hard coding
certain values like API keys.
Poor numbers passwords and so on into your code.
Also make sure that if you are using some third party services like Strype that you use the production
API keys and not the development keys for example Strype which we used gave us a testing API key while
that is obviously what people want to use as long as we test the application as soon as we deploy it
we want to use the production ready API.
And that is something that all depends on the third parties or on the third party API as you might be
using.
Now we also might have some mechanisms to handle errors or log something and there we want to make sure
that we reduce the error output details.
We don't want to send sensitive info to our users.
So if something fails if some error message is frozen we want to make sure that it does contain as little
information as possible because the users of our Web site should of course not get any insights into
our source code.
Now by default and in the way we built this project or these projects of course will not have problems
with that because if we use the default express error handling middleware and the default errors and
the custom errors we build also don't contain any sensitive information.
Then we are fine but if you're building an application where you create your own error objects maybe
with a lot of data added to them you should make sure to strip some of that data out of these custom
errors.
When you deploy your application or when you prepare your application for deployment regarding the responses
your application sends you want to make sure that you set secure response headers.
There are some response headers some headers you can add to any response which don't hurt which prevent
the declines from doing certain things certain sniff things and so on and they are for setting these
headers won't hurt.
And I will show you in this module how to easily set these headers and how to find out which letters
that are.
So will implement some best practices there.
Now in a typical node application you might also be serving some assets some javascript some C-s as
files and they're adding compression can be a good idea because that will reduce your response size
or therefore also your response time because the client has to download less.
And most modern browsers and so on are able to download compressed so Sept assets and unsub them on
the fly directly in the browser.
So this is not some fancy mechanism where you would have to do a lot of manual coding.
It's actually pretty straightforward and the browser does a lot of the work for you.
You also want to configure logging so that you are aware of what's happening on your server.
Since we're now not testing the Sarette anymore but real users do interact with it we certainly want
to log interactions into log files that we can look into at any time.
We feel like it.
So there that is a thing went and so did we can stay up to date about what's happening.
And last but not least esus LTL apps.
So encryption off data in transit is also something we might want to look into thus far in this course
be used and roll to the server and therefore our communication with the server was not encrypted for
testing this is obviously fine.
Now for a production ready app it's strongly recommended that you do encrypt your connections and therefore
I will also show you how to turn data on in your node express application in this module.
It's also worth mentioning that the last free points year compression logging and SSL are off the handled
by your hosting provider and I will talk about that when we choose a hosting provider because often
are typically you want to use some managed service where these things are all unmanaged for you so that
you don't have to worry too much about that.
I'll still show you how to enable it manually but it might be worth noting that you probably don't have
to do that when deploying your application.