Know author debt theory let's go back to our project and this is our shop.
So does this not the rest API does not grant you an API.
This is a shop as we built it.
And you can find this snapshot of it attached to this lecture now in there.
Let's first of all explored that environment variables thing I was talking about and we can start the
capture file what would we control in an environment variable.
And what is an environment variable Now environment variables are a concept supported by no chase where
we can pass certain configurations certain values into our node application from outside.
So we don't hard code certain values into our node code.
Instead the values will be injected when our node service starts and that allows us to use different
values in development and production and also to conveniently change devalues in production without
having to redeploy our entire code.
And a great example can already be seen here that connection string here this connection string allows
us to connect to our mongoose cluster.
And obviously we have some hard coded values here.
The username and the password for this user.
And then also the default database if we want to change anything there.
Well then we have to change it in the code and redeploy it.
Additionally if we ever share this code with someone like I do with you you know these credentials now.
They won't matter much to you because I changed my password after I quit recording this course but of
course in a real application you can't change your passwords every time you shared the code with some
coworker or anything like that and therefore you want to use node environment variables here.
Another place where we would want to use one is at the bottom of this file here where we set the port
where it should start in development we use freezer.
And we can basically use any number that is above the thousand hour range but in production we want
to let our server or our hosting provider set this port because that isn't the end thing.
A service that does open our app to the Web and that does configure all the network settings.
So there we don't control the port number but the hosting provider does.
And now for example for something we want to control an environment variable can be found in the shop
controller there at the top.
I have this stripe key.
Not only is this the development key which we have to exchange for the production key but it's also
not a good idea to hardcoded in here for the same reasons as it was with our mongoose data.
So let's use some environment variables and using them is straight forward.
Now first of all alternatives is connection you are l into a template literal by replacing the single
quotation marks with back ticks.
Now it's still a normal string but now we can inject values by using dollar sign curly braces.
And now here we can x' environments very close on the process object is an object not defined by us
but this is globally available in the node app.
It's part of the node core runtime.
Now on this proses object we have the very helpful nth property and that is now an object with all the
environment variables.
This node process knows there are a bunch of defaulted wireman very little but we can also set our own
ones.
And here let's say I want to use the Mongo user environment variable and I'll replace this text with
it.
Now I also want to replace the password.
So here I'll use Mongo password
and I'll remove the password here and it will show you how to set these environment variables in a second.
Of course the database here we can replace that with Mongo default database.
Alternatively you could of course make that whole connection string and environment variable depending
on whether that string changes regularly or just the values side of it.
Regarding the port are also go down and here instead of setting 3000 also Prozess and port or if that
should be undefined free 0 0 0 0.
Now most hosting providers or all those providers that managed it for us will automatically inject the
port environment variable.
So most of the time we can rely on that being set and for local development we'll still fall back to
3000 because there will not be set now for stripe.
If I move to the shop controller I also want to use an environment variable here.
And I will use process and stripe key here.
With that I replaced a couple of things with environment variables where it makes sense.
Now if you scroll through all the code you might find aberrations where you would say OK I want to set
that from outside.
I don't want to hard code that but these things which are now exchanged are definitely important ones.
Now we do try to read these environment variables in our node code.
How can we now pass them into node while we do that when we run our node application with no one we
can provide a configuration file.
You can simply add on Node Manoj Jason fall in your project root folder and there provide a Jason document
opening and closing curly braces in there at the end.
Object.
And there you can now set your environment variables like Mongo user their de-value should be Maximillian
Mongo password.
So all these variables I tried to read in my code and that should be the password.
You just well removed from your app.
Yes file
and also Mongo database in there.
I will now use shop like this.
So now I edit the environment variables for my Mongo D-B connection string here and that should be named
Mongul default database ICSA Let's rename it here to.
And besides DS Mongo things here we could set the port.
But there we have a default value after D2 pipe symbols.
We all fall back to 3000.
Now for Strype we also want to inject something and there we should sign into our dashboard and in that
dashboard go to developers API keys.
Now here for the server you will need dead secret key and you want to move that into your node one package.
So there I named the environment variable Strype key and that is how I should name it here to so bad
would be the value.
And now that if you run NPM start it should still start and should still connect.
I get an error at mongered evil database is not to find because of course here the connection string
it should should be Prozess ends Mongul default database just as it is in all the other places.
Thereafter everything starts just fine.
And now we have a running application using his environment variables.
Now these are still the development values but nonetheless we have that set up.
Now of course we're not always using gnomon and especially when deploying to zap will not be using it
because there we don't.
When I restart the server on every change because it will not change to code anyways so what I'll do
is I'll add a new start script to my package touch of snowfall.
I'll name it.
Start colon def.
You can name it however you want.
You could just name it to death whatever you want.
And there I will use Node 1 and in my main starred strip.
I just want to use note.
This however will now not used at node non-JS and fall.
So if you want to pass an environment variables here you also got different solutions.
And typically when using a hosting provider you can set up the environment variables in the dashboard
of your hosting provider.
That is something we'll see later.
But if you're not using that well then you can.
As a simple solution simply take decie value pairs you want to set up and add them in your package Duchessa
fall in front of the start script.
So there you would use Mongo user equals Maximillian like this.
And you would do that for all the values you want to pass in.
So now we can do the same for a password Mangu password you simply separated with a whitespace Mongo
password.
Equals this Mongo DB fold data base equals shop and thus.
Key equals.
And now I need to get that Strype key here.
Copy that move here and now we are obviously a very long startup string.
Again typically will not pass it like this but now it would run NPM start it should still start and
connect without issues to the long would it be database.
Because now we are running this with our environment variables here.
I also want to highlight one special environment variable which you can set manually and that is so
special on which I just want to log here on Prose's and there is the note and variable.
And now if I quit my server and restart it U.S. on the find here.
Now again this will be set automatically by hosting providers.
You can of course also set it on your own and hosting providers will set this to production.
Now if a restart we see production being locked here and this is a special environment variable even
though it's not set by default because expressed Yes we'll actually use that by default to determine
d environment mode and if you set that to production express Chase will change certain things.
And for example it will reduce the details for errors.
It froze and in general optimized some things for deployment.
So you want to set those when running your app in production.
And again hosting providers typically do that for you.
You can always check out the official box of your favorite hosting provider to find out if that is the
case.