Now I did mention on the slide that you also want to exchange testing keys for production keys and narrowcast
that would be that Strype key we're using here through environment variables which we do set in the
Nordman and in the packaged or Jasonville.
Now obviously that always depends on which kind of API eyes or third party services you are using maybe
in your app you use no service at all and therefore this is not an issue for you.
With Strype what you want to do is you want to click on that to switch to public or to production ready
data.
Now you need to activate your account here to be able to do that as you see and to activate your account
you have to fill out some information including some payment information.
And therefore I will not do that here.
But if you were to deploy this into production you need to fill it all out and once you filled it out
you will be able to switch that toggle here here at the top end see your life data your production ready
keys and you should use these keys in your code.
So wherever you are using the test Keys right now you would have to replace them with the production
ready keys and data is just a Strype example Abra API.
You might be using might have a similar behavior.