Now we already prepared some things for production.
Let me now dive into that secure a header's thing and for will use a third party package which is called
helmet and you can use it to secure your node express applications.
Now you can dive into the official Box Office package to learn more about it.
And in the end what this will do is this package will add certain headers to the responses you sent
back and it follows best practices for doing so.
You'll see which attack patterns or which security issues these are against which it protects you by
setting the right headers.
So definitely check that out to learn more about these hackers and why it protects you against that
using the package.
It's very easy though.
In your project you just run and install dash dash save helmet and then this will be downloaded and
you can use it as you see here by simply including it as a middleware and then it will automatically
run on all incoming requests and the deferrals will have a chance of adjusting the responses as you
learned.
And it will then set its headers so you can simply go to your Apicius file then and there import helmet
by requiring it like this.
And then as a next step you simply you add this line here ofter you initialized to express app maybe
in the place where Redan also set up all our middleware down there.
Here we can use app use helmet and execute this as a function and this is it.
Now with that if I run NPM run start cold and death my new script diad it to use node.
Everything runs as before but now actually if I wisit localhost 3000 to your and I hope my network tab
and a reload page I can see that on this response I have a couple of headers being set and there are
some special headers which were added by Hellmut here and you can always check that by temporarily commenting
out helmet to automatically restarts and I'm using gnomon.
We had 11 response headers before I now reload this.
We just have 6 because now some special headers are missing.
And that is something you should consider doing.
Read through the official docs to learn all about the headers.
It is adding but it's definitely worth looking at that and probably worth using that.