Now with response hetero's added let's make sure we serve optimized assets and for that we can use another
package.
If you google for node compression you'll find that expressed serious compression middleware package
which makes it easy for you to add compression to your application.
It's actually super easy but you can learn all about the configurations you could add if you wanted
to here in this official documentation.
But if you want to add it in a very simple and standardized way you just run NPM install dash dash save
compression like this package is called compression and after you install it you go to your app js file
and there just as we imported Helmut will import compression by requiring it here and we then add it
as a middleware.
So let's maybe edit right after Hellmut here by running compression as a function as well.
Now you can configure it as mentioned in the official docs but you can just run it like this.
And now for that to see in effect I'll comment this out and save and the notes are there for reloads.
And now I open the network to happen I'll reload my page.
Now these are the size of the esus we're downloading especially have a look at main CSSA and Main.
J.S. obviously these are not super big but still this is the size of yes it's as we download them by
default.
Now I'll comment that back in that extra package and save it and now is very low at that page you will
see that DS as it's got a bit smaller and obviously this will matter more if you have more content assets
in your application that you need to search.
So this is compression in action and this is worth considering especially in apps where you have a lot
of CSSA and javascript code you are serving to your users or in general where a lot of files are served
to your users by the way.
Image files are not compressed here because that actually makes it longer to load them.
But this is a nice addition.
I also want to note that again most hosting providers you might want to use have some support of compression
built in or might at least offer this compression support which you can conveniently add there.
So then they will compress assets on the fly and you don't have to do it with your own middleware and
then you actually shouldn't do it.
But in case your hosting provider does not support it or you're building your own server then this is
a nice middleware which you can at.