Now we had a look at compression and hetero's now logging is also something that matters for debt.
I'll quit my server and I'll install a new package with NPM installed ash hash safe and that is called
Morgan and that is a package that makes logging request data.
Really simple.
Now after adding it I can whip's restart with NPM run start death my node one server and now to use
Morgon all imports this year and the last Fall I'll require Morgon like this and now we can use it as
a middleware.
Also before we handle all the requests so also maybe up here we app use more again and we execute this
as a function and pass the information on how to lock this into this function.
Now you find more in the official docs that simply defines which data is being locked and how it's formatted
all go with combined.
And now if it's safe that and I reload this page here you'll find some logging data here in the console.
You see detailed logging information about the incoming request that we had a get request which browser
I used which operating system and so on.
Now obviously we typically don't want to see that in the console when we deploy our application.
Instead some files would be nice and to lock that two files we just have to add something here.
We can create a new content the access log stream use the node file system which is a core module which
we have to import by requiring
FS year.
And now with that we can create the right stream with create write stream.
And this allows us to then define a path best with path chosen seen from our current folder on to let's
say access door locks so did we all rights to locks into this file.
We will add a configuration here where I said Flack's to a which means append.
So new data will be appended to that file and not overwrite the existing file but added at the end of
the file so that we don't just have one lock statement in the file but we continuously add them to the
file.
And now this right stream can be used by Morrigan and we simply passed it's from Q Morgan in a second
argument here we can set a stream value in that object and we set that we're not here but in the Morgan
function your.
So here we set the stream and we set that to our access log stream here.
And now just falls stream will be used by morning to log our requests and they offer it with a reload
this page.
We don't have to lock here but we have this new access log file and in here we see deadlock data and
that is of course how we would want to lock that.
But also as mentioned on the slide often logging is done by our hosting providers.
So then this might not matter for you if you want or have to do it manually though this is a nice package
where you can of course configure more as you can see in their official docs which allows you to log
your request data to files.
So did you always know what's going on on your server.