Now last but not least before we don't really ship our application server to a hosting provider I want
to have a look at SS l.
T l s and DL asks simply do you mule or worse off that.
Ellis the term more people know however both is about securing your data that is sent from a client
to the server because when we communicate between client server we typically exchange data.
Now we can have an attacker third party whose ease dropping on that data is technically possible.
Of course not super trivial but possible and therefore does attack or could read your data which you're
sending from the client to the server which is of course a problem.
If we're talking about credit card data or anything like that.
Hence we want to protect that data and we do that with SSL Teall as encryption.
Now one such encryption is in place eavesdropping is not possible anymore because while the data is
readable as long as it is in transit and it will be decrypted on the server now to enable that encryption
and to be able to decrypt it we work with a public private key pair.
Both is known to the server.
Now that public key is asked the names of gests not something we have to protect the private key is
however the private key will ever only be known by the server because the private key will later be
important for decrypting the data.
The public key will be used for encrypting now in SSL certificate.
We bind that public key to the server identity.
The identity is simply something like the domain the admin email address you set to get data when you
create a certificate dead asss certificate therefore connects a public key and a server and send stat
to the client to the browser so that the client also is aware of the public key and knows that it belongs
to that server.
Now typically you will use a certificate of Florida to you for that though you can create your own SSL
certificates too and will do that in this module.
But when you create your own keys then the browser does not actually trust you that information in there
is correct and that is when you get informations or warnings like hey does page uses SSL but doesn't
seem to be secure.
Do you really want to visit it.
Hence in production you would use a esus certificate provided by a known certificate authority witched
browser trusts and therefore you have a real secure and trusted protection.
Nonetheless the way it works always is the same.
We have that public key part of that certificate certificate idealy is not created by you but by a trusted
authority we will trade it here on our own though because that will be free.
Dead public key is then received by the client through death certificate and now the client can encrypt
the data which it sends to the server and the server can decrypt the data with that private key and
only that private key can decrypt that data.
And this is how that works and how that secures your data in transit.
Now let me show you how this works in practice.
Now to set up a SSL connection on your own server with their own certificate.
Again you should get one from an authority once to apply that to production but for testing this we
can definitely play around with our own one.
We need to create a certificate and we do it with a command named open SSL on Mac and Linux you have
that available by default.
On Windows you don't.
But there you can find it by googling for open SSL windows and then dead.
Second link here.
This binary link leads you to a page where you can take the first link to Essel pro WEP and there when
you scroll down you'll find installers that install this open SSL tool on Windows too so that you can
follow along with the commands.
I'm about to run on Windows as well to your version here install it and once you have installed it you
can run open SSL rec dash notes dash new dash x 5 0 9 dash key out server door key dash out server dot
cert and this will give you that private key and the public key packaged up in a certificate.
Now once you hit enter you will be asked a couple of questions and there make sure to choose valid values.
Though that does not really matter too much but the idea here is that you connect your identity D'Ken
the identity of your application to your public key.
Though again your own self-censored defecate will not be accepted by browsers anyways.
For production you should not use that option still.
Let's fill it out with some truthy values.
And one important value is just common name.
You must set this to localhost otherwise the certificate will not work because this has to be set to
your domain.
So if you were to use your self-signed certificate on the server you deploy your app to and you host
this app on example dot com then then you would have to set this to exampled up can.
Again typically you request a certificate for your domain by some authority and then they will do this
for you.
But if you create your own one used the domain your app is running on and locally that is localhost
and this certificate will be denied and he will not be accepted.
If you set this to an average value now after you did all that you'll find two new files and folder
service cert which is the certificate and server key which is the private key not a private key will
always stay on your server.
The certificate is what we send to the client in the end.
Now to use that in Aperture Yes.
First of all have to import a new node module and that is the h t t p s module which allows us to spin
up and HTP s server.
Thus far we directly or indirectly through app listen used to Depay.
Now we'll use HTP s to you is that I need to read in my files and I will do that up here.
I will read in my private key by using the node file system package which you need to make sure you
import in this file.
Here you need deadfalls system package and there you can read a file synchronously.
Now this will block code execution until the file is read and you'll learn.
Death typically does is not what you want to do.
But here I actually don't want to continue with starting the server unless I have read that file.
So here I will read deadfall synchronously and the follow on to read as server dot key.
So my private key file is at a number constant which I'll name certificate and that will be f as read
falls sync and then of course it's my server thought cert file.
Now with these two files read in we can scroll down to the place where we start to server with app..
Listen and I'll not use app list any more but all use HD as this new package we just import it and there
create server to create the HTP as server.
This now needs two arguments.
The first one configures the server.
And here we have to point it at our private key and certificate and the second argument will be our
request handler.
In our case our express application so the second argument will be our app.
The first argument will be a javascript object where you need to set two things you need to set the
key key and you set that to that private key.
Constant we created a second ago and you also need to set the search key which you set to date certificate
constant we created a second ago and then we listen on that server.
Now with that if you run NPM start it will start your server.
But now using SSL encryption and if we now go back to our application and really reload localhost 3000
this will fail because by default you use to DPI.
If I use HDD as localhost 3000 it will fail because the browser does not accept that custom or that
Self-Signed Certificate as you learned.
But if you click on advanced your you can proceed to localhost and now again the browser does warn us
because it does not like our self-signed certificate.
But technically we are now using SSL protection and this is how you enable it.
But just as with logging and compression typically you would set this up differently.
You would let your hosting provider set this up because technically the hosting provider often also
has its own service in front of yours and the servers of the hosting provider don't use SSL and to traffic
between your app and the in-between servers does use H2-B because it's blocked or it's not available
to the public anyways and the hosting providers fronts Yrs. would implement this logic so you wouldn't
write that code on your own.
And indeed here I will fall back to my old code where I just had app listen because we'll need that
later when we deployed because we will let our hosting provider manage SSL.
But if you ever need to do it manually is how you do start a node server in HSDPA smote.