So I'm back on Hiroko and I created an account which is why I'm in my dashboard now.
If you haven't done it definitely do so.
Click on sign up create a new account enter your data and you should end up on a similar dashboard and
have a create new app button somewhere.
Now when you click that all you Roco you can give your app a name and I'll name it.
Note complete to me the name is up to you of course.
You can choose a region.
I'll go with Europe because I'm located there but that is up to you of course and you can then simply
click on Create app.
Now with that clicked You can now choose a couple of different things.
First of all we can ignore the pipeline feature here.
The deployment method will use Hiroko get.
Now what does get get is a tool which is not part of Heroku but used by Hiroko get a version control
system and as such it's a tool which you can use.
It's totally optional but it helps a lot with saving and managing your source code.
It allows you to work with so-called commits braunches and remote repositories to name some of its most
important features commits are basically snapshots of your code which you can take.
But when you can always switch so you can always go back to the older worship of your code and have
a look at it and then go back to your most recent one or rollback to an older commit.
So this allows you to revert to older snapshots easily or while safely added to recode because you can
always go back.
Now you can create commits offer you fix some bugs after you add new features and so on.
Braunches also allow you to not just have one history of snapshots but multiple histories for different
workings of your code.
So you could have the monster proj where your production ready code is in and then you want to fix box
or add new features in braunches.
So did your main code is untouched.
But when a new feature done you can do something which is called merging and merge the new feature branch
with your main branch so that you have one branch which you can put back into production again.
But it allows you to work on different features in different braunches without affecting your main finished
code for now.
And this allows you to basically separate your development workflow from let's say the new feature or
by fixing to production workflow remote repositories.
That simply means that your code is not only stored locally as it is by default but that you can store
it and it's commit and branches in the cloud and that of course means that you can protect against loss
of local data and you can also access your source code from different machines and share it with average
developers of course and you can also use that feature to deploy your code automatically.
And that is what Hiroko does because you will essentially use Hiroko as a remote repository.
Which means when you push your code to dat remote repository to Hiroko it will then be taken by Hiroko
and it will be put into production and a server will be spun up based on it automatically.
That is what get us and that is what Hiroko uses here.
Now that means that you will need get and for that you can simply google for get and then it says link
here.
CNN.com.
And there you can simply click downloads and downloaded for your operating system.
Simply download the installer for your operating system here and walk through the steps presented there
and thereafter you'll have good install.
I'll check the documentation in case you are facing any problems and also attached this vigil.
You'll find some free links to get you started with good.
In case you want to learn more about it for deployment.
Only you don't really need to become a good expert though.
You only need to install once you did that.
Let's continue with the rest of the deployment process your.