Knouted we created our account here and we learned that we'll use get the next steps on Hiroko to use
its sealife its command line interface and that of course now is Heroku specific on our hosting providers.
You might simply be able to drag and drop your code let's say as a sip file into some part of the dashboard
user interface of your hosting provider to deploy it.
Hiroko just doesn't use such a drag and drop alternative instead.
Hiroko uses that command line interface which allows you to run your code or to deploy your code.
The command line by typing on commands.
So let's download Heroku Seelye here.
Make sure to follow the instructions on the page that opens in case you're facing any problems here
you also get informed that you require get.
So definitely make sure to check that out as well if you have problems.
Now I'll go with my Mac OS version air and then I will quickly walk through the installer dir and install
Hiroko on my system.
Once you did install it the next step is to run this command and you run this in your normal terminal
or command prompt.
I'm here in my code and my node project but you can run it from anywhere.
And there I will type Hiroko log in.
This should not work and you can now log in with your account data.
So if the same data you used to log in on the Web site no one who did log in the next step is to turn
your codebase.
So your project you have been working on in a good repository so that you can add Roko as a remote good
repository and apply to it.
You can do that with these commands here now.
I already have a good repository here so I will omit did get init command and I will just use Hiroko
get to remote Dasa a and then the name of my project and this will essentially added as a remote project
and also set my remote project you are l as a remote repository on the local codebase.
Because this then allows me to run these commands to create a new commit a new so-called snapshot which
you need and then this push command to push my code to Hiroko.
Now I set Hiroko as a remote branch.
Next in your package dodgiest and follow of your project you want to add a new entry the engines entry
anywhere maybe above the scripts and there add note and now set the work.
No chance you are using.
You can detect that by running node dash in your project folder or anywhere on your computer actually.
You see for me it's 10.0 9.0.
You might be using a different word than simply enter it here and this will now use that word even when
it installs staed on that remote server.
We are going to deploy it to you now.
Additionally in Access for Hiroko you may want to make sure you are using compression because Hiroko
does not offer you to set up compression on the fly over hosting providers do that.
This one does not do it so do it on your own.
Also make sure that you are not trying to read in our certificate and private key for SSL so common
that out because these files will not be deployed because will not use SSL.
Here you should not be spinning up your own HTP vs server because we will do that through Rocha's managed
server or you would do it for you Rocha's managed server so spinup a normal HTP server instead.
Now with that changed.
Make sure that you also add a new file and that is Hiroko specific.
The proc file without a file extension and there you simply add WEP colon node.
Yes and this will instruct you Roko to execute your capture last fall when it tries to run your application.
Now for different hosting providers this might differ of course and there you simply have to check their
documentation to find out how you'll let them know which script or which command they should execute
to run your app with all that set up.
Make sure you add a dot.
Good ignore file because this will tail get which folders.
It should not actually include in its snapshots and Dir the node modules folder is important all your
third party packages are stored there and we won't deploy that.
The cost dead will just increase the size of data we have to transmit over the wire.
Instead this will automatically be recreated on the Roco because he Roco and that is the case for all
hosting providers pretty much do install your dependencies on the server after you deploy your code.
Because keep in mind that any package don't Jason.
We of course have a list of all the third party packages we're using and the words we need.
So this will be taken by the hosting provider and it will install all these packages on the server.
And that is why we always use to install dash dash save because that added such entries to the package
chase and fall.
Which now can be used during the Limond with all that it create and use snapshot by typing get at DOT
and then get commit Dasch M and there any message you want between double quotation marks and I will
simply type prepared for deployment.
Close that and hit enter.
And now you simply run get push Hiroko monster and you hit enter and this will now upload all your code
to Hiroko and they're also as you see install all your dependencies.
That is what it's doing now and it should automatically detect that it's a node application because
you have a package don't chase and fall.
So you should not be getting any arrows here and it will now step by step.
Spin up your server and install the dependencies and so on.
Now with that you can go back to your dashboard and click on over there and you should see that succeeded
build and you can now click on open app.
This will open your app in a new tab and most likely this will not really succeed.
And the reason for that is that we deployed our application but now if you type Hiroko
Lawks in your terminal you will see what went wrong.
And to be precise and the error message you will see that it failed to connect to the database and that
makes sense because all our node environment variables which we rely on for example to connect to the
database are now not set anymore because in the proc file we instruct jarocho to just execute the app
Chia's fall.
And this will not pass the environment variables only one environment variable is passed by default
by Hiroko and that is actually node.
And this will be set to production.
That is something they do for you but all the environment variables are not set.
Now we have to do it on our own by simply grabbing these names and going back toward dashboard and there
on the dashboard.
You want to go to settings for your app and then go to Conficker VARs and there you can now add your
own config wars which are essentially the environment variables that are passed into your application.
You simply add them here step by step as key value pairs.
So all that data we previously passed in as part of our restart script we now pass that here as environment
variables Mongar user Mongul password all is of course the default database.
Let's add it here.
That was shop and also describe key where you should use your production Ready's stripe key of course
as you learned not the testing key necessarily knowledgably Ed does that too.
And now we have all these environment variables edits your lives alone won't do the trick.
Well we also need to change something on our mongered be set up in our case here because we are using
that hosted Hmong would be Atlus solution if you remember.
And then of course now depends on the database you are using and there you have to remember that under
security you have to white list IPs which are allowed to connect.
Now you need two wide list IP off your running application.
And the thing about Roco and its basic version here is that we don't have a static IP assigned to our
project.
Instead it's a dynamic range.
Now attached you find some resources that help you for example assign a static IP if you have such a
range.
We only can do one thing on an IP address.
We can allow X from anywhere.
Keep in mind we are still secure by username and password but still for a better set up I would recommend
that you also ensure that you sign a static IP.
As I mentioned you'll find some helpful resources on that attached to this lecture or the pending on
your hosting provider.
You might be using a hosting provider that gives you a single ID anyways.
Running long would be on the same server as your web project is not really an alternative because a
database server is all not very trivial to set up especially if it should be able to scale and so on.
Now if that changed go back to your overview dashboard of your app and restart your server there by
going to more restart all diagnose a Diokno is essentially dead.
We're chill's server and they're after Let's try reloading our application here and now there you should
see a running app.
You should of course also be able to log in and all that fun stuff.
So essentially you should be able to interact with it just as you were able to do with that locally.
But now it's running remotely.
And as you can see it's automatically served y h to the p s.
Now on jarocho in case you want to stick to that hosting provider you can also change things.
You can use your own domain your own SSL certificate and all that fun stuff.
But this is it for now.
This is the essential setup I want to show you here.