Now we got a running application now that is how we deploy our application to Hiroko Heroku is just
one possible hosting provider.
So definitely explore alternatives.
Check out the documentation for your favorite hosting provider to learn the exact steps on how to get
your code onto it and which additional configuration you might need to do.
That always differs a bit but it never differs that you need to get your code onto that server there
and spin up your notes server and pass your environment variables that is always the same.
So check out the docs for your favorite hosting provider.
Now this of course was our shop application.
It was not the rest API and not digraph API.
But there I will not show you specific deployment videos because actually deploying these does not differ
there.
We still have a normal node server write a note express application so we can deploy it in exactly the
same way.
The only thing that will differ is that we can't really click Open app. anymore.
Well we can but then on the starting page will not see much because there are no service side rendered
views.
Instead we have the API running where we can send requests to and will then be our front end application
or our mobile application where we have to adjust.
You are able to send the request to our now running hosted application and not to localhost anymore.
So there in your application you'll have to exchange your you or else your and use your hosted domain
and not localhost.
But that is the only thing.
And then the front end app or the mobile app is deployed differently anyways.
A mobile app is sent to your users for the app stores as a front end application as this one built with
re-act typically is deployed as a static web application and that is something you can learn in my re-act
angular and so on courses.
You simply built this project with the build script you can find in package Chaisson in this case it
would be NPM run build and this will then spit out a new folder with all their built and optimized code
and more on that.
In respect of courses on these frameworks why it is required and so on you learn all about that there.
And then you would take that code.
In this case in the build folder and shipped that to a static web post like for example AWOS as free
and then serve your app on a totally different server then your node application is running on because
as you learn many times in this course there is no strong relation between your node API and your Front-End
mobile app whatever it is.
So that is how you would deploy that.