You already learned a lot about note Jay asks and how to build amazing applications with it and the
Express framework it builds up on know genius.
You'll learn a lot about reaching out databases handling requests sending responses rendering templates
working with files a lot of crucial things that you will need for any node application you're going
to build.
Now I want to move away from one important thing that we always did thus far and that's the rendering
of templates with Ejay S..
It's a common thing to do that in a lot of node applications but there also is a very popular alternative
kind of or a very common over kind of node application that you will work with or that you will build
as a web developer.
And that are rest.
API is now in this module you will learn what exactly arrest API eyes are why you would use or built
them instead of the classic node express application that we built thus far where we rendered the use.
You will learn what the core rest concepts and principles are and we'll build our first rest API in
this module too.
So let's dive in and let's understand what rest your eyes are and why we would well use them.