So now we know what arrest a few generally is or which problem it solves.
Let me give you a big picture of how it works.
We have a client and the server declined as a mobile app where our single page application on the server
we built our API.
So here we build an API for these apps we might be building.
And one advantage by the way is that we can use one in the same API for multiple clients.
So we might be building a web app and a mobile app not that uncommon these days.
Most companies have mobile apps and web apps but we can use one at the same API because both apps mobile
and web app use the same data of course.
They might present it differently and that is what I was talking about about the user interface being
handled by the front end by the client.
They might present it differently but they work with the same data.
So that is our API we might be building or we have any kind of app including our traditional web app
which just needs a service API or we might be building our own service API maybe to also sell our service.
Maybe were building a stock API where any application which we might not even know is able to Corbie
data from.
And we just sell access to that API and that is our business model.
So in all these cases we obviously exchange something and does something we exchange is data.
As I mentioned before only the data not the user interface and that of course leads us to one important
question in which format do we exchange that data.
We learned about HVM LDS far but there are different kinds of data we could attach to a request and
a response we can send plain text for example we could send some L or we could send Jason and there
are other formats too.
But these are some well-known formats H-2 himself cores look something like this so we can send H.T.
email code and this is what we did thus far in the course when we rendered Ejay as to what we essentially
did is we sent team l code to the browser because the view was rendered on the server and the result
of that rendering process simply was-I age female page simply was aged hemol code.
So this is how we could send data H-G mail code contains both the data and the structure of course the
H team l elements see us as Styles who might be adding that all adds structure and the sign and what
is between BHM elements is our data.
So therefore does all it contains our user interface.
It defines how our user interface should look like.
Now the problem is of course that if we just want the data we got all the overhead h team l content.
Its unnecessarily difficult to parse because even though DHT male elements are of course kind of defined
and regulated how we use them and how we well structure our document is not really enforced onto us
so its unnecessarily difficult to parse.
If we just need the data we can of course send plain text.
The thing here is this is only data of course there is no structure.
There is no design element at it and therefore we make no UI.
And that as user interface of course we make no UI assumptions.
Still if you want to transfer data like this its unnecessarily difficult to parse because text is easier
to understand for humans but for computers it isn't.
There is no clear pattern in the text and therefore it is not really a great way of exchanging data.
SML looks a lot like h tim L and actually h tim L is a special kind of Exham all you could say the differences
Exham allows you to use any tax.
And of course allows you to transfer data.
And it's also not making any UI assumptions because its not possible by the browser.
The Exham elements are totally made up by you.
The good thing is it's easier to read by machines then plain text.
You can also of course define clear structure there but you will need a special SML parser because traversing
Frue and SML node tree is kind of challenging not impossible to solve but you need a special parser
and all these elements of course add some overhead to the data you transfer.
So there's a lot of extra text that is only required to read your data.
That is not really your core data though.
The last data format and you might already guess that that will be our winner is Jason looks like this.
And we already used that in the course when I had a look at asynchronous requests.
Couple of Martial's ago and now this also is just data.
It makes no UIA assumptions and it's also machine readable.
The good thing is it's a bit more concise than XM.
And it can easily be converted to javascript and that is of course a huge plus when working with no
trace on the server.
But also with well javascript in the browser which happens to be our only programming language we can
use there.
So therefore this is our winter data for met Jason is our winter data format.
If we just want to transfer data and see the most common format in any API you are communicating with
these days all the formats are not asked great for transmitting data.
Jason is there for business is what we will use.
But its important for you to understand why we use it and I hope this became clear.