Now do we learned what the core idea is and how we transfer data and that data is king in arrest API.
Let's have a look at the routing.
So how do we communicate between client and server.
So we have client server and on the server we got our sort of logic we reach out to databases and so
on.
Now we send the request from the client to the server and how do we do that.
Well in a traditional web app as we built it thus far.
And of course we did it of course by simply adding a link on our age HTML page for example or we had
a form with a button and we defined the form action and the method.
Well it's not that far off for rest.
AP AIs we still send the request.
Q A combination of HTP method also called HTP word and a path onto a server.
So what we defined thus far still will be used kind of we still find such payoffs on the server on the
server side routing where we wait for incoming requests and we also define certain HGP methods we want
to handle forty's pause so that not all requests can reach all POS.
These requests would be sent from the client through when working in the browser through Asynchronous
JavaScript.
So with the fetch API for example or with Ajax and on mobile apps and so on we all get special clients.
The core thing here is we in the end still sent normal requests.
These are totally normal requests that just don't expect any HTL response and we send a combination
of HTP method and Poth and this is how we communicate with our server.
Now in the rest world or in the API world we like to call these things your API and points.
So when you hear me talk about an API endpoint I'm talking about the combination of a HTP method like
post and get and the respect of Poth these already and points we to find on our rest API.
And we defined a logic that should execute on a server when a request reaches such an point.
Now talking about HTP methods there are more methods than just get and post I did mention this before
in the course but when working with the browser only and not with javascript in the browser but just
with Fornes and links then we only have GET and POST available.
These are the two methods the browser natively knows or the browser H.T. mail elements no.
So to say when using asynchronous requests for javascript or when building mobile apps and so on and
using their respective HTP clients you have access to more HTP methods.
And we actually already saw that in the asynchronous requests module of course besides get which is
responsible for getting a resource from the server and post which is responsible for posting a resource
to the server which means create it on the server or append it to an existing let's say array of resources.
Besides these two methods which really use a lot for the course we have access to port which we would
use if we want to put a resource onto the server which means you want to created or overwrite an existing
resource.
Posts will never override or should never overwrite.
We also have access to patch which is used for updating parts of an existing resource so not override
it entirely necessarily but update parts of it.
We have access to delete which allows us to delete a resource on the server and also there is a special
options HTP method which we will use to in this module.
Indirectly though it is sent automatically by the browser and there will come back to it.
This basically is a request which the browser will send automatically to find out if the next request
tries to do.
For example delete something if that is actually allowed and it will come back to that.
So these are DHP methods.
We will work with the methods we typically work with when building a rest API.
Especially the first five ones the orange ones are important.
Now let me also highlight that in theory you can do whatever you want when a request with a certain
method reaches a certain path.
So for the rest world we should use a POST request to create or append a resource.
No one is stopping you from deleting something on a server because ultimately you only define a method
Poth pair on your Cirus site and then you run any code you want.
And what happens in that code is not restricted by the method that was used to execute that code.
You can restricted yourself and you want to implement the rest API that follows these ideas here but
you don't have to.
And that's just important to highlight.
It's common and it's a good practice it's a best practice to use these methods in this way because then
anyone who's using your API clearly knows what to expect to happen on the server for a given method.
But in theory no one is stopping you from doing something else.
So these are the HTP methods.