We're almost done with the theory part.
Now there are some core principles that are indeed defined in theory and that are important for you
to keep in mind where at least there are two core principles.
I want you to keep in mind when building rest API is the first one has a uniform interface principle.
This simply defines that your API will have or should have clearly defined API endpoints you remember
endpoints were the combination of HTP methods and postes with clearly defined request and response data
structures put in other words your API should be predictable and if possible and if open to the public
it should all be well documented.
So people should know which data does your API expect which data does it give back which endpoints do
I have.
And the thing that happens when a request reaches to end point should of course not change over time.
It should be predictable it should be clearly defined.
The second important principle I want you to keep in mind is to state less interactions principle.
And this will be super important when we later talk about often dictation when building a rest API the
server and the client are totally separate that they don't share a common history.
So no connection history is stored and no sessions will be used.
Therefore because every incoming request is treated as if no prior requests were sent.
The server has a look at every request on its own.
It does not store as session for a client.
It does not care about the client at all.
Actually that is also a cool thing about resting your eyes.
You can build a rest API.
Open it up to the public like to Google Maps API is for example and you don't care about the individual
client.
You just say hey here are the endpoints I have.
Here's the data you get back for each and point.
Here's the data I expect from you for my endpoints and then I don't care about you.
I don't start a session with you.
We have a strong decoupling of the client and a server.
Even if they were to run on the same server because we're building our own API for our own Front-End
we still would decoupled both so that they work independently and just exchange data.
This means that every time we set up a new endpoint we have to make sure that works in the pendant from
prior requests.
And a typical problem here is authentication where once we locked in future requests should be treated
as locked in.
And I will show you how to solve this in this course too of course.
Now our principles which are less important which you dont need to learn by heart is to cashable principle
which means on your arrest API you could send back some headers that tell the client how long the response
is valid so that the client may cached a response client service separation is mentioned again here.
Its more thinking about the data storage client and server are decoupled as a set and decline should
not worry about persistent data storage.
Therefore the server will be responsible for this.
We may have a layered system which simply means as a client when we send the request to an API we can't
rely on that server.
We sent it to you immediately handling the request to server might instead forward the request or distribute
it to another server.
Ultimately we only care about the data we get back which should of course follow the structure that
was defined by the API code on the monitus alost optional principle.
And this basically just means the rest.
I could also for some endpoints transfer executable code to the client.
Now to be honest in reality you don't see that too often we're mostly talking about well normal data
we're using but still these are the best principles the top two ones are the important ones which will
have great implications especially on authentication.