Now with all of the theory out of the way let's build our first simple rest API and for that I mean
a brand new folder.
I only did one thing and there I ran NPM in it and confront all the default settings.
Since I'm using version control I also added a good or false so that I can ignore an upcoming node Marshall's
folder and that is it.
Now to build a rest.
API how do we start.
Well as I mentioned all the things you learned are still important.
We build a node express server just as we did before.
And also by the way of course you don't need to use Express you could build just a node server API but
you have to do a lot of request parsing and so on on your own as you learned before in discourse and
you can use our frameworks to there even our specialized arrest API frameworks.
But we will use Express which is a great all rounder and therefore I will install as a production dependency
with dash dash save Express we need express jast to build an API conveniently.
So this is our first dependency we'll install into this brand new project here.
Now with that installed I'll install another package and that will be a development dependency with
dash dash save death.
Node 1 because I still don't want to restart my server manually after every change.
So let's quickly install that package now.
With no one installed Let's go to the package adjacent file.
Let's add a start script in the script section and let's execute more apt Shazier to start.
Actually as with node one aperture does not exist yet.
So let's add it and then there we'll set up our node.
Yes server.
So what do we do in here.
Well first of all I will import express by requiring express like this.
Then I want to create my express app by executing express as a function and these are of course the
exact same steps we executed before in this course.
And last but not least we can listen to incoming requests.
Let's say on port 80 80 this time not free.
0 0 0 0 isn't all.
Need to add later for something else.
Let's use 80 80 for now.
This is a very simple server that we could now start that will not do anything of course.
It has no routes to find but this is our simple possible no express server.
Now to add some routes and to do something with them I will also install the body parser as a production
dependency with dash dash save so that I can Parus.
Well in-coming request bodies.
And now let's start adding some routes we could add them in here with app used to handle any method
or app get app Post app put and so on to handle specific HTP methods for specific postes.
But I will use the express router again and it will also create new routes folder which you wouldn't
have to do but this structure still make sense separating routes and controllers.
You just won't have the use anymore.
The views folder will not be recreated because it will not render any views anymore.
We'll just exchange data.
So new routes folder here.
Let's say we're building a simple block where we're a simple messaging social network block like application.
And we have some feed routes.
So like the news feed or something like that where we simply are able to create new messages show existing
messages and so on.
So all creative feet J.S. fall in the route's folder and in there we set up our express router by again
importing expressed into a disk Faltu because we need something from that package in the fall and then
I create the router by calling express router as a function and I will export the router at the bottom
in between we can now to find some routes and I want to start very simple with a Get route.
Q. Let's say posts where I serve my posts later on.
Not right now but later on.
So here I have my posts and of course I now need my logic that should execute when I request righteousness.
They are for all create a new folder controllers and in there I'll add my feet just fall as well.
So feature Yes and controllers now in there.
Let me export a new function get posts which of course and that also does not change gets or request
the response object and the next function could call to let the next Militaire take over and in there
I want to send the response and this will be the first part that gets interesting.
Before we write that code in my routes feet J.S. fall I will import my feeds controller by requiring
it from the controllers folder and there from the feed file.
And I will assign my feet controller get posts function your as the function that should be executed
for this route.
Now to be able to reach that route we need to register the route in Abdias which is our starting fall.
So in there I will import my feed routes by requiring them from routes feet like this and then all we
have to do here is we have to use these routes used to forward any HTP method will filter them out in
the route's fault then like with this get function.
So forward any incoming request to feed roundlets say or let's say we only forward requests that start
with Slash feet again.
Does this logic you already learned about.
So now any incoming request that starts with Slash feed will make it into feed routes.
So into this file and there we handle one request right now.
Slash posts.
So in total slash feet slash posts would be handled right now.
As long as it is a get request.
This kind of request would get handled by this controller.
And now let's talk about the response and how we could send a request to that route.