So I did find my basic set up for and you know express rest API.
We have our route and its controller and now of course we need to return some data there.
So instead of the controller get posts we want to return some data because you learned rest if your
eyes are all about data.
We will not call rest render it in here because we will not render a view you will not see me call as
render any more again because rest API is simply don't render the use because they don't return h tim
L and it rendered the U is H.T. mail instead will do something we already saw in the async request module
discourse.
We will return a Jason response Jason as a method provided by express HHS that allows us to conveniently
return a response with Jason data with the right headers being set and so on we can pass our normal
javascript object to Jason and it will be called Word to Jason format and sent back as a response to
the client who sent the request.
And there we can send anything you want like post which could be an array of posts where we have a title
first post and some content.
This is the first post.
And of course I'm just making up things here.
This is of course just some dummy data.
So we called Rest Jason and this will send a Jason response.
Now when sending Jason responses we all want to send the status code explicitly.
200 would be the default but will also work with different status codes for this module and we want
to be clear about the status code.
Our response has so did the client we have an easy way of handling it because you always have to remember
that the client now has to render the user interface based on your response and therefore especially
error codes are super important to pass back to the client so that the client can just have a look at
the status code and find out.
Should I rendered my normal user interface because the requests exceeded or did I get an error or.
And I want to render an appropriate error interface.
Previously Nicoise we sent the whole interface so the client didn't have to worry about that.
Now the client has to.
And therefore setting the right status code is important.
Now with that we have some logic in place to return some dummy data with NPM start.
We can now start up our server here and now we have it running.
And now we can wisit a browser.
And for now we can simply enter local host 1880s slash feed slash posts.
So this path we defined and you should get some Jason data here.
If you open your developer tools
and you go to the network tab there and you reload that page you all see that request here.
And if you inspect it you of course see the response body.
But if you have a look at the headers you'll see that in the response headers we see that application
Jason was set automatically by our server because we used to dat Jason Meffert and we indeed get back
to conduct we find here we can see it here too.
So this is a quick and easy way of testing this.
Now obviously our users would never wisit it like this.
They could if we don't require authentication at least.
But this is of course not how we intend our API to be used.
Instead we'll build a user interface that will then use this behind the scenes and render a beautiful
UI automatically with that data.
So directly accessing the data like this is of course not the plan.
Now before I come back to the user interface part though let me show you how we can easily and conveniently
test our arrest API even without entering this into the browser.
And Ford Ed let me do something.
You couldn't enter into the browser.
Let's define a post round.
So besides being able to get Polistes we typically would also have some routes that allow us to add
new posts.
Now if we quickly think about our different HTP methods then for posting new posts post would be a great
HTP method.
We could also use port that would not necessarily be wrong.
Port would also be a valid method to be used for creating a resource but especially when we're talking
about posts and not something like user data which only exists once but posts.
There might be multiple posts and therefore adding or appending sounds good to me and hence I want to
use the post method instead of put if we were to manage to user data here then maybe put might be better
because there we need to create or write the resource.
So post is and hence I will name this post post which sounds a bit strange.
It's just my naming convention.
I have DHP method first and then basically the object that's at gets created.
You could name this totally different.
You could named as create post if you want to.
Let's maybe name it like this because it's Cleator.
Then I have my normal function that of course does not change.
And here we would of course reach out to the database will do so soon.
For now I'll just note that we have to create that in the database and I will just return the response
assuming that we did create the post.
So I'll send back a Jason response and there we might be having a message like posts created successfully
and we sent back some post data.
And now that is at least data I want to parse from the incoming request.
So I expect to get a title lets say.
And I still parsed it on the request body.
So essentially what we always did froths course and then might be extracting a content to also from
request bloddy just what we did for the course.
And here I return to create a post with an idea that was generated automatically let's say.
As long would he be does it for us here.
I'm just doing it with some dummy code and the title which I received and the content and does could
just be the cause of confirmation that it was stored in the database successfully.
Which of course it wasn't thus far but which will add now.
First of all I also want to set a special status code here with the status method.
I want to set it to 200 in one.
The default would be 200.
And this would not be horribly wrong but 201 is the better status code to use.
If you want to tell the client success a resource was created just 200 is just success.
201 also indicates that we created a resource.
And of course we did hear at least in theory.
So manually setting this makes a lot of sense.
With that we're sending this success code.
Now what is missing well a way of parsing that data I did install body parser in an early lecture but
we also need to set it up.
And now here's one important thing you need to remember that we are working with in-coming Jason data.
We expect our clients to communicate with our API with requests that contain J send data just as we
return Jason data Jason data is the data format we want to use both for requests and for responses.
And therefore I will use my body parser of course.
That's why I installed it.
So let's require it here in our Actually yes file.
But when I initialize it I initialize it differently than what we used it for.
And the majority of the course because Dare I initialized it by calling you are L-N coded and configuring
that.
Now this is great for data formats or for requests that hold data in the format of X W W W form you
are encoded.
You might remember we saw that in early Electress too.
Now this is the default data that data has submitted through a form post request.
We don't need that here.
However we don't need form data.
We have no foreign data.
Instead we want to use body parser with the Jason method which is able to parse Jason data from incoming
requests.
So this is good for application Jason as is the official name that you will find in the header.
And this is how the data will be appended to the request that reaches our server.
So we need this middleware to parse incoming Jason data so that we are able to extract it on the body
because that will be added by our body parser does body field on the incoming request.
With that we can extract all that data but how can we now test this.
We can create a form in which we submit because then we would be back to X W W W form you are all encoded
data and it would not be a realistic test because you just don't use forums like this when working with
rest API eyes.
Instead you can use a very handy special tool and that is postman.
Now we will build or work with a real front end very soon.
No worries.
So we'll not be stuck to some helping tool for the rest of the chorus but it's still a very useful API
development tool which you should be aware of.
It's free to use and you can simply google for it to get it from get postman dotcom there or you can
just download postman and walk for the installer.
Again you don't need to pay.
You don't need to sign up.
It might ask you for that but you don't need to.
Once you did load it you end up on a starting page like this you can just close that window and you'll
then end up in a user interface like this one.
Now you can read the official postman docs to learn about all the things you can do but in the end what
you can do is you can enter.
You are all here then choose your different HTP methods and you see more than I showed you but you won't
need most of them.
They're not required for typical crud operations.
So you can choose your method here and then send the request.
You can also add your own headers and you will see the response in the area below this.
So here I can send the request to local host ADHD which is where my notes are reruns on and then feed
slash host.
This should be the route I want to reach disk controller on.
Now for that I first of all need to create the route.
So in my feed routes fall all at post route for Slash post where I used to feed controller create post
action.
So this will be reached through a post request to feed slash post.
Let's configure such a request to your feed slash post as exactly where I'm sending it to.
And now I just need to switch to the post method.
Now with that switched I also need to be able to send some data and you see that the body tab now got
enabled with Get it was disabled because get requests can't hold a body post requests can't hear you
can now choose your format and we don't need any of these.
Instead I'll choose rawe.
And then there in the dropdown Jason application Jason.
So now here we can write some Jason data.
And Jason has a format where you have to sit around in curly braces and then you have key value pairs
where if you're writing it manually the keys have to be wrapped in double quotation marks.
So here we can see what we expect to get.
We expect to get a title and we expect to get a content.
So we want to pass these two fields to our server.
So here we can pass the title and this can be my first post.
We're actually my second post because we use the first one as a dummy post and or get route and then
here we have the content business the content of my first post or my second post of course.
So does this now my request.
We can now click send and we get back a response which looks good because it's the response I find in
my control or action with this message and the post that was created.
And this is now the data we would typically use in our receiving client.
You all see the headers that were sent on the response these were set automatically by express especially
application Jason matters of course and this is now how we can test all our end points because we can't
just enter them here and then switched to HTP methods pass any extra headers or bodies we might need
and therefore we get everything we need to test our API.
Still we will also work with a real Front-End so that we have something beautiful to look at and to
see that in a real app.
But this is a tool you will use a lot.
We're working with rest.
API is.