Know before we conclude this very basic starting March with rest.
Let me show you something important which you need to configure on any rest API or building which will
not only be used by tools like this one or by code that runs on the same server and it can demonstrate
what I mean by going to code.
Pen case you don't know code and it's basically a service which you can use for free to write simple
HTL javascript and CSSA snippets or projects can share them easily with other people and we can simulate
a very simple front end application here.
We can create a new pen for that.
And here you can write as you see H.M.S. is this and Javascript code.
Now I'll not need C S S because I want to keep it simple.
And this is a great playground here now because we can simulate a front end app here because a front
end app if it is a single page app will only use H female C S S and Javascript because we don't write
any suicide code in there right.
So in here we might have a normal button a button we use to send the request to the back and here we
could get our posts and I'll copy that but then also duplicated to create a post that is of course just
a very basic dummy code.
We'll build a different project for the rest of this course.
But now I have to but this year in my pen as you can see now let's add some javascript code to do something
with them and for that only to get access to the Spartans.
So I'll give the first one an idea of get a second one an idea of post just to keep this really simple.
So my get button can be accessed with Document get element by id and then it's get.
And the second button of course is the same with post-soul name it postpartum and I'm looking for the
element with the id post.
So I just want to get access to them so that I can register a listener.
So on the Get button I can add an event listener for the Click event that shouldn't be and make a request
to my back and all define an anonymous function here and in there I'll use the fetch API which is built
into modern browsers with the fetch keyword where I can define a u r l to which a one to send to HTP
request.
And in my case that is HTP localhost 1880 slash feet's slash posts.
Remember that is simply this route I find your so want to send a request to det route or to that and
point as you learned by default does is a get request when using the fetch method.
And then we might have ever a success case which we can handle and then block or we have an error if
we have an error I'll just log my error here in the then block we actually get back a response object
where we still need to wait for the body to complete because it will be streamed in.
So I've rest Jason we can wait for this and then automatically can we did to Jason content or to a javascript
object.
And then we change a number of then block where we will have that javascript object.
Because as I mentioned on the slides adjacent can be can word to really well-to javascript and the Jason
method does just that word.
And it waits for the body to be streamed in.
And then I can console log my response data here.
Now let's open up the developer tools.
Clear Cleary's existing arrows here which were only CRID was to was still typing and you don't need
to save anything.
It saves automatically and click get posts and you should get a no access control allow or rich in headers
present error.
This is an error.
You see a lot when building modern web applications.
Modern single page applications and it often leads to a lot of confusion.
This error is also called a coarse error and you see the word cord's down there.
Now what is coarsen what's causing it.
And most importantly how can we solve it.
Course stands for a cross or region resource sharing and by default this is not allowed by browsers.
So if we have a recline in the server and they run with the same domain and the domain could be localhost
3000 important to port as part of the domain if they run on the same server we can send requests and
responses as we want to without issues and that is why we had no issue before in the course we rendered
our e-mail files on the server and therefore they were served by the same server as you send your requests
to.
So we never had any issues.
So this works however if client server run on different domains like the client on localhost 4000 which
is a different domain and 3000 then we'll have issues.
And of course in production you would run on my app thought com and let's say my API dot com if you
send requests and responses here you get problems you get a chorus error because it's a security mechanism
provided by the browser that you can't share resources across domains across service across or regions
as it's called here.
However we can overwrite this because this mechanism makes sense for some applications for rest.
A eyes it typically does not.
We want to allow our server to share its data.
We want to offer data from our server to different clients and these clients will often not be served
by the same server as our API runs on.
Take Google Maps you're not running your app on Google's service.
Still you can access it and the same is true for your own API and even if you built both the front and
the back end you will often serve the two ends from different service because you can choose a server
for different and that's optimized for Front-End code that really serves that really well and you serve
your service code your note code from a different server so you will have different domains different
addresses there too.
And therefore we need to solve such a coarse error or we need to tell the browser here which runs on
codependent this case here.
We need to tell that browser that it may accept the response sent by our server and to tell the browser
we have to change something on the server.
And this is a common gotcha.
A lot of people see that error and want to solve it in their browser side javascript code.
You just can't.
You can only solve that on the server.
So if we go back to our service side code we just need to set some special headers.
We want to set these headers on any response that leaves our server.
So the app yes file and general middleware is a great place.
So here before I have forward requests to my routes where I will ultimately send the response I want
to add headers to any response so I'll set up a general middleware in AB G-S which gets my request response
next function.
And there we have set Hetter we can conveniently add a header to a response.
We don't sent the response yet.
Set header does not send it.
Jason does rendered it but set header does not set header will only modify it and add a new header.
And now there are a couple of headers we need to set.
The first one is the access control allow or Richen all separated with dashes so Access stash control
Dasch allow Dasch original data is the first header we need to set and we want to set it to all d u
or else all the domains that should be able to access our server.
So we could add code Penn Dot I O here but often you will just set to do start to a wildcard that allows
access to from any client.
You could lock it down to specific domains though if you wanted to.
If you have multiple domains you can separate them with commas.
But I will go with the wildcard.
I will also set another header and that ISDE access dash control Dasch allow Dasch methods header.
Here we allowed a specific origines to access our content our data.
Now we allow these origines to use specific HTP methods because by just unlocking your regions it would
still not work.
We also need to tell the clients their origins which methods are allowed.
And there you can allow Get post port patch delete you don't have to allow them all.
You can only allow what you want to be usable from outside.
Now there's one last header I want to set I should set and that is access stash control Dasch allow
dash and now I'm talking about the headers.
Our clients might set on their requests there.
You could also use a wildcard where you can specify a specific matters.
Now there are some default headers which are always allowed but you especially want to add the content
dash type header anti all Farai sation header so that your clients can send requests to hold extra authorization
data and a header which will need later and that all have to find a content type of the request and
that will become important soon to with that edit we need to do one last thing we need to call next
so that the request can now continue and can be handled by our routes.
But now every response that we send will have these headers and therefore if we save our server side
code and we restart the server and therefore we go back to code open for clear these errors and it click
get posts again.
Now it just works as you can see because now we set the appropriate course headers on the server.