Now we learned about course in the last lecture.
Now let me show you how it affects our post requests.
So I'll use my post button to also add an event listener dare click like this.
And there I'll also use to fetch Methot to send a fetch request to the same as asked before but it ends
with Slash post because I'm targeting this.
You are all here which is just post not posts.
So if you named differently you should of course use your path here since it will be a POST request.
I need to pass a javascript object as a second argument which allows me to set some options.
Specifically I want to set the method to post here to send a POST request and then I will copy that
code from up there for handling the response so that I can well extract the data or log a potential
error for now clear dat and I hit create post.
I get post-trial successfully but if we inspect the post object we see that the title and content are
missing.
Now that makes a lot of sense because we didn't send that data.
Instead on the post request and declined we also want to set a body object and that object will hold
the title
code pen post and content created wya code.
And whatever you want to clear that.
Now I click that button again Hmm I still don't see that here.
Now on the service side nothing goes wrong here but actually on the service side if I would go to my
controller and I would log title and content here or used to node debugger to see their values if we
locked that in it click Create post then we'd see that.
And the find gets locked here.
So we are not able to extract that data.
And the reason for that can be found if we go to the Network tab and have a look at this post request
it was sent there in the request headers.
We see that the content type was text plain and that is the problem it should be application Jason.
But we all just see that the request payload was not Jason data which in the end is just text but in
a special format.
But deaded was a javascript object which just can't be sent where which can't be handled.
So there are two things we need to do.
First of all on the body I will call Jason string ify which is a method provided by default by javascript.
It will take a javascript object and convert to to Jason we can see that immediately if I click Create
post again and we inspect that request.
The payload now is indeed text in the Jason format but we need to tell the good server that our account
that type is of type application Jason.
And therefore besides setting the body on the client all the add headers or one header the content type
header content dash type which is application slash Jason.
And now with that that click Create post again.
Now in the created post we see title or title and content because now that data is sent and extracted
correctly because we send it in the right format and we inform the server about the content type.
Now this also allows me to demonstrate what happens if I would comment out does header here the access
control allow headers header on the service side.
If I save after commenting this out and try to create a post again I fail because I'm not allowed to
set Content-Type.
I do allow it as by adding this header on the service side.
So this is how you communicate between client and server.
Of course the client code differs depending on the client you're using.
Does this javascript code using the fetch API.
There are different ways of sending asynchronous requests.
For example you can send Ajax requests through libraries like X years and if you were building a mobile
app you might have a totally different object or a helper methods for sending such requests in Android
in swift and so on.
So this client code differs does the javascript code using to fetch API the server side code does not
really differ.
You want to make sure your clients can communicate and that everything works just fine there.
Now before I conclude this though one more word about the post request we're sending just click.
You might see that I actually have two requests being sent.
The second one is our post request what does the first request.
If you have a look at it and we see the responses just post OK.
The headers are interesting though we can see that in the general part.
The method here is options and that is the last method I showed on the slide earlier.
I mentioned it would be sent automatically by the browser and all.
For example by many mobile app Cline's What is the idea behind options.
The browser simply goes ahead and checks whenever the request you plan to send which is a post request.
That is why here to request headers which are generated automatically by the browser.
It checks for the post request it checks if Dad will be allowed.
Otherwise it will throw an error.
This is simply a mechanism the browser and many of the clients use and there is not too much you need
you to do to make this work.
It just works out of the box.
You just want to make sure that you set the right course.
Headers here you can add options to yell out methods but as you see it was able to make this request
before.
Does this not really something you need to do.
But you can do it but the important thing is that you are not confused by that extra request.
It's simply a mechanism the browser uses to see if the next request which it wants to do the post request
will succeed if it is allowed and this is all I want to tell you about cores and client server communication.
For now.