That's it for the basics of rest your eyes will dive much deeper into recipes and build a real project
with the rest AP in the next module.
The core concept and ideas are dead rest.
AP eyes are all about data no user interface logic is exchanged blue eyes are normal no service though
and that is really important to keep in mind we're not building a totally different kind of apple of
a sudden just the data format and the way we send responses changes because now we simply expose a couple
of points which is a combination of H and P methods and payoffs.
But we did this before too.
We just have more methods available now and we exchange data and adjacent format for both requests and
responses.
We don't return HTL pages as a response anymore.
Rest API eyes are decoupled from the client staff where they are totally decoupled.
They don't share any connection history or story any connection history.
Now when we have a look at the requests and responses it is important to understand that you should
attach data for requests and response in adjacent format and that you should let the other end know
by setting the content type header.
Just as automatically when using the Jason method in the browser.
It depends on which method you use when using the fetch API as we did.
We had to set it manually when you would use x Yes.
And never a common library in browser side javascript for sending async requests.
It would be done automatically.
Corse errors are also something we had to look at.
They occur when the API and your client are sitting on different service different domains and they
want to exchange data.
You fix them in quotation marks because they are a security mechanism.
But you can bypass that on purpose by setting the right course hatters which basically tell the client
hey it's fine.
I'm a public API.
You may use my data.
These are the basics.
Now let's dive much deeper into that.
Use different HTP methods adult syndication and so on.
By working on a real project.