So it's time to dive deeper into your recipe eyes and build a complete project or a complete back and
forth project as arrest API.
And in this project we'll have a look at things like authentication and other interesting things like
image upload and so on.
So what's in this module in detail will plan our rest of your eye or I'll show you a project for which
you will need want and will then build it together of course.
So in detail we will implement all the corrupt operations our project needs.
So creating reading updating and deleting items in a database and so on.
That is what we'll do here will define all the rest API endpoints for days and so on will add validation
on the server side to make sure that only valid data gets stored in our database.
We'll add image upload so that we still can store images even though we're not rendering views anymore.
And finally all dive into off indication which will be very important and very interesting too.
So let's dive in.