Attached to this video you find a new project and this is now not a note.
J.S. project instead.
Does this now a react.
J.S. project react.
J S is a front and Javascript framework.
It runs in the browser and it allows you to create such a single page application which I mentioned
in the last course module.
You can simply download the attached project extract it into a new folder and then navigate into that
folder in a terminal or simply open that folder in an ID like visuals you code and you know and then
inside of that extract that project run NPM install to install all the dependencies off the project.
Now I mentioned that this is not a node.
JS project.
Why do we need to run NPM install then.
Because it's pretty common that we manage any dependencies in javascript projects even for browser side
projects with NPM with the node package manager.
The packages I'm installing here are only packages that are getting used in the browser.
Though there are no note express or anything like that packages beneath them.
Indeed if you have a look at the package digests and fall you'll only find re-act related packages here
which do run in the browser so don't be confused by the fact that we're using NPM these packages here
still only run the browser and we're just using NPM to install these packages because in modern front
end development you have very complex setups you have very complex package dependencies and using a
package like NPM can speed that up.
Now once you ran all of that you can run NPM start to start a development server which is now actually
a node.
JS server serving your application but it's not related to the node server.
We will build.
It's not related to our back and this is only a dummy development server which simply serves the belt
wears on off our front end application so it serves a simple H team l file.
What you can actually see in the public folder this one which does not have a lot of content which is
what I mentioned earlier or in the last module actually that single page applications have very trivial
h html files but we have some hooks here which are used by the re-act application which is built in
the source folder.
There is the source code that will be mounted onto DS hooks here automatically in the browser which
leads to an application like this.
You will see an error by default when you first start is up will fix Deandra from the module and there
you will see this interface and this interface is now fully rendered through react.
J.S..
If you inspect the source codes if you view the page source you will find th's female page.
I just showed you with these hooks and then a couple of script imports at the bottom and if you inspect
the DOM though you will see way more.
Tim L elements and these are all rendered dynamically by react so by the browser side javascript framework
and if you want to learn more about reac I get a whole course on that of course.
So check that out.
Will not ride re-act code here.
Almost all the code will work with is already prepared by me.
We'll just have to tweak some things as we create our rest API.
But this is the front end we'll use to Gabr with our rest API.
And the ideal of course is that you get a feeling for how front end and back end.
So how do you react when the rest AAPI are decoupled and can still work together now.
So this is the project we'll work with.
It's a very simple social network blog messaging like application.
We can have our users status which you can update here.
We can create new posts here we can later also added and delete posts and little later all the add off
indication.
Right now nothing is working because I got no back and attached.
It is also the reason why we have an error message right at the start but we will get rid of that throughout
this module of course.
So this is the front that and this is now a front and I want to connect to my backend So lets now see
which kind of restfully API endpoints this front end could need before we then start implementing them
step by step.