So let's analyze it is re-act application to find out which rest API endpoints we want to pro-white.
No you don't need to know re-act for that.
No worries.
The app G-S fall is essentially our entry file where our re-act application starts or where it basically
starts rendering the first screens.
And there we all have some logic on which we'll have to work on later.
For example for logging users and will later have to insert a real u r l here that allows us to do that.
And the same for signing up and so on.
Now in the pages folder you'll find a feed folder and there to feed J as file is what's responsible
for this page with the new post button and so on.
There we all have a couple of routes.
For example here where we fetched a state of the currently locked in user.
But then also additional routes for loading existing posts here where I want to reach some of you or
else that serves up some posts but also later down hooks or methods where we can add it to user status
where we can also add new posts or added existing posts will do this and to finish added hndler and
where we can delete posts something we'll do in the delete post handler.
There you always see I have a couple of fetch methods set up but the u r l is always missing and that
is something we'll have to do of course.
We'll have to add our own you are l and make sure that this works or that we have to respect the endpoints
for that on the single post screen here.
We load a single post if we click on it and there indeed.
We also want to reach out to the backend and fetch data for that single post.
So in short which end points will be need.
And now I switched back to my rest API which we started building in the last Chloris module.
You all of find this snapshot attached to this video.
There I already got a route for getting all posts and for creating a new post.
That is great.
We will also need routes for getting a single post for editing a single post for deleting a single post
and will also need routes for logging a user in signing users up so creating new users for viewing the
status of a user and for editing the status of a user.
These are the routes we will need.
And with that let's start working on that and let's implement them step by step.
We already got a route to get posts and to create a new post which does not sound like the worst start.
Let's maybe continue with DS so that we can start implementing the appropriate code in our re-act application
to get posts and to create posts.