So let's start working on the rest.
API again.
And for that all Ron NPM start in my rest API note J.S. project 2 and that is all that the reason why
I'm using different ports by the way here I'm starting the application on port 80 80.
My front end application automatically takes port free thousand and this simulates dead these two ends
of my application are served by different servers.
In the end which is a pretty common scenario sends front and only applications like re-act can be served
and so-called static hosts which are optimized for applications that only consist of html javascript
and C-s s and hence you might indeed have two different service even if you created both the back end
and the front end.
So we have different ports and therefore we have different domains and therefore we definitely need
our course headers.
Otherwise nothing would work.
And with that we can now start working on our fleet routes.
We actually got two routes already slash posts and slash post for creating a new post and for getting
existing posts.
And now let's add some logic so to our controller actions to actually return something useful and to
enable the user to create new posts.
Let's maybe start with getting hostes because that would allow us see at least some dummy data.
So data something useful for that and get posts we actually already return a list of dummy data posts.
Each post has a title and some content.
Now it's of course always up to you how you want your data to look like in an application in this application
because my front than I expected.
I went to have a post which in the end consists of a title which has a user attached to it a creator
or an offer which has a creation date which has an image and which has some content.
This is what I want to put in my front end.
So the data we store on the server should have all these fields in the end.
Now we don't have to start with the full package though.
I already have a title and content here.
Now let's maybe add some image you are ill here.
And Ford at all trade and you images folder.
And for the moment I will just copy the image into that folder.
Later we'll of course at image upload our copy in my good old duck image which I used before in the
course.
And here it is the lovely duck Che pic.
And I want to serve that duck.
So here is an image you are L..
I will actually provide images slash duck Dolce Peck as a POF because that is my local path on the server
here it's missing my domain and so on will have to attached as on the front end.
Business now a post as I could serve it if I know saved as we can actually fetch that data with a get
request to local host 1880 slash feet because that is what we have as a filter to reach to feed routes.
So slash feed slash posts.
Now let's try it out in our Front-End application there.
We fetch our posts and the feet js file in the source pages feed folder in there you should find load
posts function.
Load posts is a function that is called by the react code and so on in the end and what we do here is
I also support page nation which will add later.
For now I just want to reach out to my u r l which is HTP localhost 1880.
Written like this.
And then slash feet slash posts like this.
So this route just talked about and the rest API.
This should fetch all these posts then.
Here I just checked if the status code is not equal to 200.
Which would mean that something went wrong and then I've Frot an error which is handle in your react
application.
Otherwise I extract my body and then here I have my body and I use some re-act logic to load that body
in the end and to hopefully display it.
If I save dat and I go back to my application I'll get an error regarding the name.
You offer name which is missing.
I'm not supporting users yet so this will be a problem for the moment and will also get an error regarding
the date eventually.
So to a white this we should go back to our controller and add some dummy data for this too.
Let's add a creator object because that is what I'll be looking for at my react code which should be
an object with a name where you can enter any name you want.
Later will of course connect us to a real user in the database.
And let's also add a date.
And here you can simply create a new date with Will new date like this.
Last but not least you also want to add some ID and that should be underscore ID because I'll be looking
for under square ID in the Front-End code.
Andy re-act application.
Because later we'll use mongooses again here and that of course or Mongo to be in general and that of
course simply adds IDs with underscore ID.
So here you can enter any ID you want.
Now if you save that update that controller code and the server therefore restarts you can reload and
you'll still get that error.
Which is related to our status or user status which we still can't fetch.
But if you simply click that way you see that first post here and that is looking better than before.
The end with a date is a problem because actually the fuel to be named created at not date there was
a tiny mistake on my side on the server.
It should be created at.
With that if you reload you'll see this post.
So fetching posts works.
Of course it's just dummy data though to work with real data.
I want to be able to create new posts by clicking new posts so that is something we can add as an nextstep.