Let's make sure we can create new posts so that this new post button does not only open the mobile but
we can actually add a new post.
For now with our D-Mich. upload so let me go back to my rest AAPI.
And there we already have a Create post route of course so we can continue working on that.
We expect the title and the content there.
And for now this is the only data which I will really need to worry about because well as I've just
said we'll not worry about the image.
For now you can pick an image here but ultimately even though it's previewed here it will not be uploaded
but it does not matter.
We can implement this in a way that at least to Thailand content is uploaded.
For this we already got our route in place a post route 2 feet post and there we then extract our title
and content and we.
Well for now basically echo back that message.
Let's try that.
Let's go to our front application so to react code and in there.
Let's simply go to the
feet js file and dare you should find a finish.
Add a handler function.
Is the function which is responsible for handling the case that we clicked on.
Except here once we entered a ballot title and content.
By the way here I also got validation emplace front end validation which is not the matter of course
because it's not related to note at all.
It's just a user experience thing that we use browser side javascript to validate the input right away.
You can learn more about that in my re-act course if you want.
Still worth noting that we have some validation place here not validation on the server though.
So for now except I want to reach my slash feed slash post route for dad.
Here we have to edit disks you are l.
This you are all here will actually be required later.
When we start editing posts for now we want to create a new one.
So here you are.
L will be HTP localhost 88 is our back and you are l slash feed slash post.
This is the route we set up on the backend.
Here we send a fetch request to Dad you are l and we need to configure that request because it will
be a post request.
So the method here can be post.
But actually all right does in a more flexible way to.
Because when we later edit this will use a different method.
So here I will create a new variable method which is set to post which you then later could override
in here.
So here are not hard code posts down there but instead use my method variable.
I will also need to add a body to data which I want to set and that has to be adjacent data so I will
use Jason string ify fly it to convert a javascript object Jason.
And then I pass a javascript object here and does javascript object.
In the end should hold the code which I want to well send to my back and in object.
For now I simply want to set my title and that can be extracted from post data an argument.
I received this function so post data will hold the data the user entered.
Post date title and then here all the content to post data content.
So this is again what we add and the re-act application.
Last but not least to send his request in a way that the Saranda stands that we need to add some heteros
here where we set the right content type.
So you're all set content type 2 application Jason to inform the server that I do indeed send some adjacent
data.
So with that I'm targeting the rights you are l and then sending Jason data and I'm sending a Tideland
content.
This should be everything I need on the server.
So let's save this and it should reload automatically as long as you keep NPM start running here and
there for well it reloaded the appere and let's create a new post the title has to be at least five
characters long such so has the content she was a file otherwise you're not allowed to submit this.
Even though the Folles not getting uploaded right now.
Except now you will run into an error here which is related to the front end missing some crucial data
it needs to update everything correctly.
However let's go back one step and let's actually console log rest data here we're still in that finish
edit handler just in the then block off her fetching and save again.
The app will reload and you can enter something into that new post mode again.
Testing again and hit accept again and you'll get that same error.
But before that error you'll see a log which actually proves that on the rest API everything works correctly.
You get back that post created successfully message and the post with the data you entered.
The error is simply stemming from the fact that on the server we're not doing everything we expect to
do because we're not creating or we're not attaching a user We're not creating a date and so on.
These are all things we can fix though by going back to our controller on the server and there when
we create a new post or when we echo back that post.
First of all it should have an underscore Id not a ID.
It should also have a creator field which is again a javascript object with a name of your choice.
And later this will not be dummy data anymore but real data.
So we add this creator and we should add a created field and that created at field is simply a new date.
And now with that being echoed back if we saved that service code and we reload the front and application
we can test this one more time click accept and now we dont get an error.
Instead we see our post there.
So now we indeed do create our data on the server or at least we fail to do so.
And when we return that back to the client where we can now render it no editing will not work though
we can select it for editing at least at least the leading will alternate work and viewing will never
but we got our basic flow set up.
Now since we're creating a new post here what is missing on the server though.
At least two things are missing and what is missing.
Well validation server side validation.
We only got client side validation but that can always be tricked because users can see your browser
side javascript code.
They could disable it.
They could basically find ways around that.
So it's not a safe mechanism.
It's only meant to improve user experience.
So we need to validate on the server.
And of course we want to store the data in a real database so we should add Mongolia or sequel's solution
again.
And that is what we'll do over the next lectures.