So validation and the database is missing now I'll start by adding validation here for debt.
I'll quit my suicide and start process because I need to install a new package and I'll use the same
package which I used in the valley in March of Loftus course they have.
You should definitely watch Dead module to learn how validation works because I'll not repeat everything
here.
We all read you learn it after all.
So you're all just installed at package which was express validator.
That is a package that helps us with implementing validation into our node express applications.
After that is installed you can restart NPM start and now do you remember how you add it.
Have a look at this Modula just mentioned.
If you don't you go to your routes and there you add some middleware which does that validation for
that.
First of all need to import something from the Express validator package and they are from the slash
check sub package and that something is Stever to check method or the body method to check the request
body or with the check method.
Also the headers to query parameters and so on.
I want to check the request body here now for a get out validation makes no sense because no data is
submitted.
But for the post route it makes sense and then I'll add an array of middleware that will be applied
which will be related to validation there.
For example I will use body to check the title field.
Now the title field can be validated in any way you want.
I can tell you that on the front end however I am validating that title field and you can see that the
components feed feed edit component that I am validating this to have a minimum length of five characters
and to be non empty which is of course the case if it is at least five characters long.
The content always has to be five characters long.
So that's just a little side note on what I'm doing on the front end and the back end should of course
meet that same pattern.
So my body title will first of all be trimmed to not have any whitespace in there and then I'll use
t is length validator with an object to set a minimum length of five.
Now this is the title now after a comma I'll add my next middleware where I will validate the content.
We can also trim that and basically set the same validator.
Obviously you can be more creative than that but I just want to re iterate how validation works and
really show you that it works in exactly the same way in rest your eyes because you build honorable
node and express application in the end.
That does not change here.
So with that we added these two validation steps for our incoming data for title into content and now
we can implement some logic to send an error if our server side validation logic is not met for this
we go to our controller to the features file and control us folder and there we also need to import
something from that express validator package.
So here I also require express validator slash check.
And thats something which I am importing here is the validation resoled function with that import it
in create post.
We can simply create a new error constant and use that validation result function on the request it
will then automatically extract any aerostat validation package.
Gabbert we can check if not Eris is empty which means we have errors.
If that is not empty we have errors and then it will return a response with a status code of 422 which
is of course our validation failed status code where I send some Jasen data.
And there you can have a message of validation failed.
Pelley de Shen failed entered data is incorrect or whatever you want it will be on your Front-End to
do something with that message or not and you could add the error osier by using that Aeros constant
and then using the array method to extract an array of errors and also add this to the adjacent object.
So with that we're returning this response of validation fails.
Now thanks to our clients side validation with the correct rules we could not reproduce that because
I'm already checking for a minimum length of 5 on the front end.
But if we increase the tidal minimum length to 7 for now on the server.
Now if they go back to the front end and I enter a title which is only 5 characters long and therefore
long enough for the client side validation but too short for the service side validation which is of
course a mismatch.
You don't want to have in a real app but it's great for testing.
If I do that.
Except here I actually get an error creating or editing a post failed.
That is an error message just showing on the front end.
But if you have a look at our console lock in the def tools we see a 422 error here and if you click
on that were taken to the network tab we see that Regt request and if we expect that we see our response
here and that indeed has that message we sent on the service site validation failed and so on and it
has this Aeros array where we see that the title failed.
So you see that the server side validation is working and that is all I wanted to show you here.
Of course I revert back to 5 characteris minimum length on the server now too so that the client side
validation logic and to server side logic are in line.
Otherwise we would have very bad user experiences because users get the feedback that their input is
correct and that the server would throw an error.
So with that we added validation for this post route and now we can move on to adding a database.