So time to add some database logic and I will again use Hmong would it be an mongooses.
And I will use the same Mongo D-B Atlas server we configured earlier in the course.
So go back to that long would be module if you want to see how that worked.
And if you want to use my sequel or something like this you can of course also take the knowledge you
gain the sequel related modules of the course and implement your own sequel's Lucian here to follow
along smoothly.
You should use Muang would you be though.
I will again use the mongoose package.
So let's install it with NPM install dash dash save mongooses and that will be required to connect to
the database and to then of course also create our mongooses models store data and so on.
I'll restart NPM start there after and now.
First of all let's connect for this let's open the app js file and let's import mongoose year by simply
requiring mongooses.
Now as you learned in the Mongo D.B and the mongooses modules of discourse we Dennis stablish a connection
by using mongooses connect here and now we need a u r l a connection u r l.
Now as I mentioned I'll use the same connection.
You are L I used before in the course.
So that does not change.
I will just copy that.
Here it is.
That is my Atlus server to which I can connect and this now establish a connection and then I can add
then in a catch block catch in case this connection establishing fails.
Then I want to lock the error.
But if we are successful if we are in that then block here then I will start my node server and start
listening to requests.
If we save that it now gets restarted and it should succeed.
You can ignore this deprecation warning here by the way.
Now we're connected to mongooses or too much would he be fruit mongoose and now what can we do.
Well we have to create some models to work with right because that is how we interact with the database
ultimately.
So let's create a model's folder here in our node rest API and I'll create a post js file in there to
define how a post should look like.
They're I will simply import mongoose by requiring mongoose from the mongoose package.
We can then extract the schema from that mongooses object that schema constructor and use that to create
a new post schema.
You can name that however you want but you use new schema to now define how a post should look like
in your database and in your application.
Now you can of course define this in whichever way you want.
I want to have a title in there which will be of type string and you learn all about that schema declaration
thing in the mongoose module so I'll be walking through it a bit faster.
So type will be string and let's say it's required.
We then also will have an image you are.
Or image or however you want to name it and that will also be a string.
It will be you are pointing at that file and this will all be required.
Now will also have a content of course.
Where the time is string as well and which also is required so thus far not too exciting.
Now I also will have a creator here and that will later be a link to a user.
For now I don't have that.
So for now it will just be an object and be required.
But this is only temporary will change does later.
So this is my current set up.
Now I will pass an option to the schema constructor which we haven't seen before we can configure this
and in that object I'm passing up a second argument to the schema constructor.
I can add the time stamps key and set this to true and Mongoose will then automatically add time stamps
when a new word is added to the database when a new object is added to the database.
So we automatically get created and updated at timestep out of the then.
And you can learn more about that feature in the official mongoose stocks of course.
Last but not least we now need to export this.
And you'll learn that we don't export the schema but a model based on the schema.
So I use mongooses and then the model method to create a model based on a schema.
You can name that model however you want.
I'll name it post and therefore this will create the post database and I will export my post schema
here or use my post schema.
So this is the model defined.
One important note about my connection string by the way in app J.S. there.
I'm connecting to a database and I will connect to my messages database you can name as however you
want.
So now we'll connected the database.
And thanks to this bottle there mongoose will use a post's collection for us when we start using that
model.
Well speaking of that let's start using that model in the next lecture.