Well speaking of that let's now use that model.
We're exporting it here.
Let's now use it in the feed controller.
There we first of all need to import it.
So you're all import posed by requiring it from my models folder from the post file.
And now we can use that post model in create post after we validate the input here.
There I will create a new post with my post more as a constructor.
We pass a javascript object and there we define basically what we do down there so we can cut that and
move it up here.
I don't need to set created at because mongooses will do that for me.
Thanks to that timestamps option we set here.
And of course I don't need to set underscore ID because mongooses will create that for me as well.
Thailand can't that should be passed and the creator as well for the moment.
So now you'll learn that we can't just call safe on the model to save it to the database.
And this will give us a promise or promise like object where we can catch any errors.
And here I will lock the arrow for now.
Will later add real error handling of course and I get a result which I also want to log here.
And I will also send my response whips in here and the then block I'll send the response to 101 is to
stay this code.
The post op check here however will be the result object.
I get back here because that should be my created post.
If we now save that server side code and we go back to our front application we should need to change
anything in our re-act code.
Instead we can't just try this.
Does does work.
Let's use an image upload.
Still does not work we'll do this later checking it.
And this seems to fail.
If we go back I see parve image Eurail is required.
Which makes sense because in my model I set image yourself as a required property.
So my field controller when I create a new post I should also add the image you are all here.
And for an hour that can point to images doc JPAC will later add file upload.
As I mentioned so my mistake we should add this on the server side make sure we store an image yourself
so that we meet the requirements of our model.
And now let's try this again.
Does that work.
Take the doc Andrews some conta except this looks good.
Post created successfully.
And there we see indeed.
This is the data or the post which was stored with the Creator the content does automatically generated
created at and updated at timestep thanks to the time stamps option ante automatically generated ID.
So that is working.
And on the server side also get no error.
I only see that created object being printed.
Thanks to Kohn's a look.
So that is working fine.
Now isn't next step we can work on serving that image and on except that image uploads and on handling
dead error.