So let's make sure we can surf that image and in a future also accept image uploads now for serving
that image.
We have to make sure we serve the images folder statically at least is the approach I want to use.
You learned all about that in my file uploads and downloads module and the general logic there still
applies.
So check that out to learn more about that in Aperture.
Yes I want to set up static serving of my images folder for that up there after I registered my body
parser all use another middleware and I will do that for any request that goes to slash images here.
I'll use a middleware built in to express the static middleware which I use by calling the static function
and now want to serve my images folder for that.
Let's import the POF package to core POF package node POLITES And then here we can use lbf joined to
construct an absolute POV to that image as folder by using the special name variable which is available
globally in note.
Yes and gives us access to the directory path to that file to the aperture Yes file.
And in that same location asked is actually as file we find the images folder.
So we can pass images as a second argument and POF join will construct an absolute path to this image
folder and that is the folder will serve statically for requests going to slash images.
With that we should be able to use our image in the Front-End code or to see it.
We saved at server side code to view the image on the front end however will need to be able to click
view here because the image will only be included on the detail page and that however will not work
because we need a route to serve a single post which we don't have yet.
So we'll have to postpone this.
It will actually be what I work on next.
But before we do that I want to set up proper error handling in the feed controller right now when I
catch an error here.
I logged it and there when I validate the input I return an error response manually.
You can do that and you could also return your own error response down there but you'll learn that you
can set up a general error handling function in express checks.
And I want to use that function.
Now how do I use it though.
Let's maybe start with validation instead of for turning a function manually here.
I will create a new error object
with new error and the message I set up here is the message I'll pass to my error object.
I'll then also add my own custom property which you can name however you want and I'll name it.
Status code and set this to 4:22 Now I will throw that error and I can remove that return statement.
Now what does throwing an error do here.
It will automatically since I'm not doing this in an asynchronous code snippet or anything like that
it will automatically exit the function execution here.
And instead try to reach the next error handling function or error handling middleware provided in the
Express application.
We also got another possible error and that is in here if something goes wrong with storing the post
there I don't want to lock the error.
Instead here I will check if my error has a status code field which it will not have.
But theoretically if I had more complex code where a fro my own arrows there might be some error that
has it.
So I'd check if that exists and if it does not exist hence the exclamation mark here.
If it does not exist I will add it and I will set my status code to 500 then because it's some service
side error.
Now you learned that since I'm inside of a promised change.
So instead of the async code snippet throwing an error will not do the trick.
This will not reach the next error handling middleware.
Instead you have to use the next function here and past the error or to it.
And this will now go and reach the next error handling express middleware.
Now the last step is that we registered at middleware and we do so in app J.S..
There let's go all the way to the bottom off all my routes here and let's use a new middleware which
has this error handling definition of getting an error or as the first argument and then request response
and next this will be executed whenever an error is frozen or for Warda with next.
And here I want to log it so that we as a developer can see what's wrong and an easier way.
And then I'll extract my status code here.
From error status codes from that error object I'll extract my message from error message.
This property exists by default and it holds the message you passed to the constructor off the error
object.
And now I can return an error or a response with the status code off the status.
I extract it and we can set this to a default value or 500 with disinfects by the way.
So in case this should be undefined it will now take 500.
So we return this status code and we use chase and data of course where I have a message of the message
I extract that.
And now I have this general error handling functionality which should work which I can quickly validate
by going to my feed routes and changing that validation logic again to 7 for the time as a minimal length.
And now let's try to enter a title that is not long enough.
And let's see if we now still see an error.
We do we still get that are being thrown with the right status code.
So this works even though I'm now using my custom error handling function which is a bit of a more elegant
way of handling errors now.
So it is working.
Let's now move on to creating the route for getting a single post so that we can finally also see if
we can see our image.