So it's time to add a new route in the feet.
J.S. file in the routes folder there.
I will add a new Getaround and that will be around for a single post.
So the route is get slash post and then we need that dynamic parameter slash post ID for example because
we'll encode the ID of the post.
We want to fetch any you are.
So this is my payoff.
Now we need a fitting controller action.
So lets go to the feed controller and then there are export by GET POST controller action with request
response.
Next
And here first of all let's extract the post ID from the incoming request parents.
So there I can get my post ID host ID here this property Im trying to access has to match exactly the
name address sign and my route so post that year after to call it Sonam extracting bits I'm extracting
that post ID here.
Now we have to find a post with that ID in the database.
So let's use our post model and use to find by id method to find a post with this post ID.
We don't have a van block or a catch block depending on whoever does Fales we're not in the catch block.
I'll use that same logic as I used for creating a post.
I check if we have an error say this code.
If not I added and otherwise I just.
Next my error.
And yes you could be factored into a single function which you don't always use.
So here I have this error handling code in the then block here.
I will get by post and first of all I'll check if this is undefined so if this is not a true ish value
if it is I know that no post was found and then I'll actually Frot an error so I'll create a new error
object code not find.
Post all set the status quo to 404 because that is not found error.
And now I'll throw the error.
This can be confusing because I'm inside of then and you've learned that you should use next in there.
But if you throw an error or inside of a then block the next catch block will be reached.
And that error will be passed as an error to the catch block.
So all I'd do with throwing is I end up in dysfunction and dare I do indeed.
Next the error.
So I just always use that function.
That's all I'm doing.
I still throw an error if I can't find the post.
If I do find it I will return a response with a status code of 200 which shows that it was a success
where I do return some Jason data with some message.
You don't have to set the message by the way this is purely optional of course where I say post fetched.
And of course my post like this some returning the post I'm fetching here.
As a propertied post in that object.
So now we have that controller action in place.
Now as they go back to my route's I can assign that controller to dead Routier.
So feed controller get hosed is the action I want to use and this will not work however because in my
front end I fetched the wrong post so fetch some dummy data because in my feed controller get posts
I'm not using the database.
I'm instead just returning dummy data.
Now since we are using a database now since we have added a database we should of course fetch data
from there as well.
So for that let me use Post find to find all posts and then I have an error or a success case if I have
an error I'll use that same logic I used down there to add a status code if it does not exist and then
next the error.
If I succeed I get some posts here however and now I want to return these hosts so I will send a response
with a status code of 200 where I sends adjacent data and that Jason and data will be an object where
again I will add a message which you don't have to fetched posts successfully.
And most importantly I'll add my posts of course and the posts I add here are to posts I fetched with
posts find.
So these posts
now we can get rid of that response down there with our dummy response re format this.
And now we have dislodging in place to fetch the actual posts we have in the database.
We now saved it.
We go back to the front end and reload it should load that post.
Does that work.
Now of course we will not want to be able to click on view and see that single post for which we already
added the route.
We just need to adjust our front end code.
So do you react to code to load that single post and you do that in the source pages feed a single post
folder in a single post js file in there.
You have component that MT which executes when the page loads essentially where we extract the post
ID from the u r l in the front end and now we just need to target the right u r l here which is of course
HTP localhost.
Slash.
Slash post slash and then that post ID.
With that we have a get request that should get us our post.
If you now save that and you click on view you should load your post here.
However the image is not displayed.
The reason for that is that we're looking for the wrong you are out or that we're not using the image
at all to be precise.
In the front end in the same component that Mount function you just worked in.
In this set state block here you should add an image key and it has to be named image because that is
a key I'm looking for in that fronted application in the average code which I prepared.
And there you one am also defined at your end of your server so localhost ADHD slash and then use wrests
data.
Post.
Accessing the response data there depost property which we do use to store our post in an get post we
have that post property here which holds our post.
So this is what I am accessing now into Front-End and their image.
Your out that is to Keenum how it is stored in the database.
Add a comma there after and saved it and now this page should automatically reload and you should see
that duck of course.
We didn't upload that.
I prepared it but at least you see it.
Now you can go back to the feed and see your posts here.
Will get that error message later too right away.
So with that we got this in place.
Let's now work on image upload next.