We're making very good progress we're able to create posts view posts view a single post upload files
validate content.
All great.
Now what is missing.
We want to be able to edit posts.
We want to be able to delete posts and authentication and users and connecting posts to users.
This is all missing now.
Let's continue with editing and deleting posts before we dive into the indication and user related things.
So for that let's go to our feed routes in our node rest API project and there I'll add a new route.
I want to be able to edit post Snel and Frenette.
I will use a new HTP method which we haven't used before.
Editing a post essentially is like replacing it replacing the old post with a new one will keep the
old ID but that is it since will replace a resource are used to put Methot here and to put method is
one to learn about in the last module but which we haven't used before because we have normal browser
forms.
You're not able to send it through a synchronous requests triggered by javascript.
You are however now we need a u r l here and D you are l Wilby slash post and then also the idea of
the post encoded in the Eurail.
So Colin posts.
Now we all need a controller action to handle that.
The important thing about port requests and the same is true for Patch requests.
By the way is that they also have a request body just like post requests.
But you can also have parameters in the.
You are out.
Well that would have been the case for a post requests too by the way.
But the important thing is we have a body forty's request we can add or request body and dad will hold
the actual post data that I want to will use and that I want to use to replace my existing post.
So let's work on the controller now in the feed controller at the bottom I'll add a new action and I'll
name it update.
Hostname is up to you but this is what I will do.
Will update the post in there.
Does this function in any here in this function.
I can.
First of all retrieve my post ID from my request parents because we just added that there right in my
route.
Host ID is a parameter which of course I can extract.
Now when updating a post I also will extract my title so request body title I will extract my content
request body content and want to extract by file my image.
You are el However for that you are l.
We have two options when updating the first option is and that will be our default.
That image you are l is part of the incoming request and it's just some text in the request body.
That would be the case if no new file was added.
If no new file was picked then my front end code has all the logic to take the existing you are l and
keep that but we might have pix a file.
And in this case request file will be set and I can now set image your L equal to request file path.
Does the alternative after all of this at least one of the two should be set.
So if image your L is not set at this point because we were not able to extract it from there and we
did not make it into this if statement then we should follow an error.
So hearable prepare and you error or no file picked I'll set my status code to 4:22 and I will throw
that error here.
So that's my first piece of validation.
Will add more validation of course.
Normally we should have a much yourself however now I have one little mistake here by the way.
This should be image here whatever tree from the front end.
And we need to tweak our fronted a little bit too.
They're in feet.
J.S. and source pages feed veejay.
When we load all posts so load posts that is when we basically load to post data from the server including
our image you are l.
Now we then sent word a poster in the front end so that the rest of you react application.
The rest of the code I prepared can handle that we need to tweak this line a little bit.
Dear you should X-ists rest data posts but we have to map this which set default javascript Methot into
a different kind of array or every element has to be changed a little bit.
Map takes a function that executes on every element in the array and it gets the element which in our
case is a post as an argument and then we return.
Well the updated word is not that object so I return a new object here where I will use a spread operator
to get all the properties off my post object and then I'll add the image Poth key here which is post
dot image.
You are l.
Now image you are.
L here is referring to the property I am storing on my service site.
They are restoring the poverty image in the image you are l key.
You could have named it differently if you named it differently here.
You would have to name it differently here.
Now I'm storing the original Pasquier because when I'm viewing a single post for example I do extract
that image your L and I append my U R L to the domain.
Now the pop should be well just a path without a domain.
Because I'm keeping that here and this will get very used later when we add it.
This food is added motile.
Behind the scenes this POV will be stored and if I don't choose a new file here this path will be submitted
with my added that post and there the POF will be stored in a property named image.
You can see that in the components to feed edit component under feed feed edit.
There you could see all the internals if you know a little bit of react.
You can see the internals and see that of extracting my image path and I'm storing it in an image key
ultimately.
I don't want to dive too deep into react but this is what I'm doing on the front end and does was one
adjustment that was required and on the service side we can now extract our image from the body and
either does a set or we selected a new file in which case a file will be found.
So now we can continue working on update post and we can continue working.
First of all adding more validation which we do in our route's of course.
Well there I will copy that array from my post route and I will add it here.
So for my ports route I also want to validate the title by the way we should switch it back to 5 characters
of length for both posting and putting.
So I will validate these two things.
I'll not validate my image because data done directly in the controller action and I don't need to do
any validations for now.
So with that added Let's go back to the controller and let's copy the validation logic from the post
route where I gather all my errors and then I check for Aeros not being empty.
And then I would Frot an error.
So before I extract anything else I'll check these things in update post whether I have any errors and
if I have of Frot an error.
If I don't have errors I continue check the file and if we make it down here.
So after all these if statements then I know I have valid data.
And now we can update it in the database to update it in the database.
I will find my post by ID for the post ID which I extracted from the U R L then I can do something or
we might have an error or if we have an error all reused add error handling logic you find in Abre places
in our actions.
So I'll add my status code and the next error if I am successful.
I know we have no database error.
I still need to check if post is on the find.
Which means you didn't find a post in which case I will also Frot an error just as we did for getting
a single post.
I can copy that logic and again if you are copying a lot of code.
You might of course also refactor that.
I liked the more we're both.
To make sure we all understand each step we take in each action creator.
And if we make it past this if Geck inside of the van block then we found a post and then I want to
update the post of course.
So here I'll set my post title equal to the Tyla extract that I'll my post image.
You're all equal to the image your ally extracted and I'll set my post content equal to the content
I extracted.
And then I can return post save here to save that updated post back to the database.
Overriding the old post but keeping the old ID.
And then here we get the result of that safe operation.
And here I want to return a response with a status code of 200.
We didn't create a new resource so it's not 201 with some Jason code or some Chaisson data where I say
post updated maybe and where I return that updated post which is stored in the result in the end.
So does this now the updating logic here.
There is one more thing we can add and that is some logic to delete the image.
For that I'll add a little helper function down there.
Clear image which is a function that accepts a file path as an argument and then I will use the file
system package no chase offers.
So important at the top by requiring f s.
And with that imported in that clear image function you're all.
First of all construct my file path for which I'll also import the POF package by two ways.
Let's import that at the top to and now the fall Poth can be constructed by joining Der. name then going
up one folder because we're running this inside of the control folder which is not where you will find
images.
So we should go up one folder to be in the root folder and then we look for whatever file path we got
here.
So image hasn't been the image name would be the case in our application.
And I could then use the unlink function to delete that file by passing the file path to it and we can
also log any error message.
And I want to trigger dead Cleator image function when ever I uploaded a new image.
So inside of my update post action creator right before I save my updated post maybe I'll check if my
image Eurail which is the to the image.
If that is not equal to post image you are l.
So to the image you're all I stored in my post before.
If they're not equal it obviously changed so I uploaded a new file and that is where I will execute
clear image and past the old image.
Also the old path as an argument.
Now with that we got all in place you're in the controller.
Now we can go to the route and there we still need to register that controller action on the port route.
So on the feed controller access update post your That's one important step.
And on the front and so into re-act code we also need to do something there in source feed feed.
J.S. Indee
finish edit handler function where we need to adjust our code.
Now there we set up our form data which is correct for updating as well.
But if we are in edit mode which will be the case if we make it inside this if statement due to the
logic I configured on the front end we want to send the request to localhost 88.
Slash feed slash post slash.
Now we need the post ID which we get from this state added Post dot underscore ID.
That is where it will be stored in my re-act app and I'll set the method to put because we create the
port route.
Now with that we can save all that and try it out and hopefully not get an error.
Let's add at the second dock here and add a couple of exclamation marks and both title and content.
Let's not choose a new file.
Looking good I see my estimation marks there.
I see them in the content as well.
Here I get a confirmation message should looks good on the back that I still only have one image.
Well that makes sense because I didn't replace it anyways.
Let's now replace it by editing that same doc again.
Let's not change title and content but choose a different file.
Maybe that coffee mug click except post update it is looking good.
It's not a duck any more so the title is not correct but on the back end we only have the coffee Magno
so updating seems to work.
And of course we can confirm this by viewing that image as well.
There we are all to see all the updated data.
So that is working.
And with that only deleting is missing before we can finally start working on authentication.