To ensure that we can also delete posts.
Let's start our node rest project and add a new route.
This will be a daily draw using the delete HTP method.
We register such a route by using Routier dot delete.
Now here the payoff will be slash post slash colon post ID Florida leads route's you can send up body.
But as with all routes you can of course encode data into d you r else.
And as is what I'm doing here.
Now the route is one thing.
Obviously we all need a control or action.
So let's go back to our feet controller and before a clear image I'll export my new action which I'll
add which will be my delete action so I'll name it delete post-tour will be my standard middleware with
DS free arguments being passed to the function.
And then there are first of all extract the post ID from my request parens as we did it multiple times
for the course.
Then we can use to post model to find a post by ID and that will be my post with this idea of course.
Now why would I find it by ID first.
I can of course also use Post find by id and remove.
Well I will use this eventually but later once we added a user I want to verify whether dead user created
the post before I delete it.
Simple First of all find the post with success or not and if I have an error I'll use that old error
handling code I had before and then block.
I'll have my post where I will check whether the creator is currently locked in user so check.
Locked in user.
This is something I can't do yet because we have no locked end user obviously.
For now there is one thing I can do though.
I can use clear image to access to post I retrieved and delete the image for the image yourself that
is stored there.
There is one other thing I actually should do and that is I should check whether that post exists so
I can copy that logic from up there where I see never post as on the find.
And if it is on the find I fell in error.
Now if that's X-C that I delete the post image and then I return post find my ID and remove because
now I will remove it.
And here I passed my posts ID again.
I can add one more then block with the result of that operation.
And then here all know whatever that succeed it and most importantly I'll return with a status code
of 200 which means yes we were successful and a Jasen data package where I will just say deleted post
in a message.
Of course you could send any data you want.
So with that my delete post action is configured here in the controller back in my route.
I can now use my feed controller delete post and assign it to to to delete route.
And now we just need to work on the front end and hook up does route.
So they're in the feet.
J.S. fall which we worked on a lot already.
You'll find a delete post handler in there.
You simply need to update dead you are else use see in their so let's replace you r l with HTP localhost
A-380 slash feet slash post slash and then post ID which is an argument we'll get in this function.
Now important we want to send a delete request.
So we need to pass a second argument to fetch here and set the method to delete and that is it for now.
This should now send such a request.
When we clicked the delete button.
So make sure you save this and you back in code and thereafter.
Let's go back to defeat and let's click delete.
Maybe on the first item now after reloading it's gone here and the doc image was deleted as well.
If I reload this app which also should not fetch it again.
So it really seems to be gone.
So now deleting all that works.