Know before we actually move onto authentication there's one more thing we can do on the front end and
that is page anation.
So splitting our list of posts across multiple pages.
Now I want to do that first.
Now for that we need multiple posts so let's quickly create a couple of posts like a cup of coffee choose
that cup match which fits it quite well.
So tasty whatever you want and click accept and let's add another post a real doc because I replaced
that image of the other doc.
So maybe it's time to add the number.
Does is a duck click accept.
And now you see here I only see two posts on the front that I don't see any more posts and that if I
reload I see free however but I actually want to limit debt.
I want to limit the amount of posts I see there and instead pass some information to the front and that
allows the Front-End to show some next and previous buttons at the bottom.
Now all the logic for this was already added to the front end but on the back and I need to return different
data I need to page 8 my data that we should dive into our controller and there into the get posts method
or action because that is where I fetch all posts of course and that is where I want to implement page
nation.
Now it turns out that in my front end feeds J.S. where I load my posts so the load posts Methot there.
I actually do is set some pages.
I have my own page anation logic in there and I can pass that page data back onto my backend.
I want to do that through very parameters and I want to do that in load posts in the front end code
here or in my Or else I'll add questionmark page equals to add a page query parameter and I'll add this
page variable which I'm creating up here and is will be managed internally in my front end app so this
will be either 1 or 2 or whichever page I'll try to load there.
So 8:09 page query parameter to my back end and there I now need to extract it to implement page anation
So in my get post action here I can extract the current page by accessing request and then query parameters
are stored in the query object and then page.
I'll set this to one as a default.
You saw his syntax a couple of times.
This or syntax checks whatever it does is undefined in which case it would assign disvalue.
So did there always start on page 1.
Then I'll set the per page value to two and a DUDAS.
Because I have the same value in the front end.
Now of course you could find a more elaborate solution where you pass that per page data from the back
end to the front end so that the front end can adjust dynamically.
But here I want to show the general setup and how this works.
So I am hard code per page here and I have hardcoded it in the front end.
Now I'll create a new variable total items which I'll need to determine how many items I have in the
database because now I'll add a new find request and I will add count documents here to find out how
many documents I actually have.
This will not retrieve the documents it will just count them.
Then I can have success or fail if I fail I'll have the same logic as before cell and check the status
code added.
If it does not exist and forwarned the error if I succeed then indice then block in this function day
or I'll know how many items I have and all stored add value in my total items variable.
I created that variable so that it can now also used that data in other functions than this function
because any here in this then block I now want to return my old fetching logic.
So did I.
First of all count and once I got the count I actually find the documents and retrieved them.
So here I will return this and all that logic so this then block.
Essentially I'll cut that out.
I'll remove the catch block and then block after the first then block and does catch block.
Well now take care about both counting and then this internal finding.
However here I will not just find of course I want to add page nation and the logic is the same as before.
We can skip a certain amount of items with the Skip method and there I calculate the current page minus
one times per page so that if I am on page 1 This will result in S.R.O and I skipped no items.
If I'm on page 2 This will result in one and I skip all the items that were on page 1.
I also want to limit the amount of items I retrieve with the limit method.
And here I take per page.
So the amount of items I want to have on each page does is what I now return in there and then the posts
here are well limited amounts of posts in my response I now don't just to return to posts.
Though in my front and I also have some logic to take the total amount of posts into account sauted
in my re-act front then I know when to show the next previous buttons for it and I'll add another argument
to the data that I return in response.
I'll add total items in there.
I'll be looking for this total items property my Front-End code.
So you should get this right.
Not misspell it.
And the value will be my total items variable so this variable value which I assigned here will be stored
down there.
With that if I saved that back and if I reload the Front-End you now see a next button here to click
it to load the next page.
We only have one item and it can go back.
So now I have page anation added as well as you saw in the same way as before.
Because rest your eyes are not dead.
Defriended the end just handled differently because we have a separate front end.