Now we worked a lot on our posts.
I now want to work on my users.
And for that we first of all need to add a new model in our node project.
There are add a user js file where I define how a user should look like in my application.
So here all implored mongooses And of course feel free to do these steps on your own.
We did them a couple of times.
I will access my schema here and then I'll define my user schema with new schema here.
And we'll add some properties of course by the end our export mongoose model which I'll name user headstall
will get stored in a user's collection which uses this user a schema.
Now how should a user look like.
Obviously that is totally up to you to fit my front end a user should have an e-mail which will be of
type string and which is required a user.
All that will have a password which is of type string and which will be required.
A user also will have a name in my application type string and required you guessed it and a user here
all it will have a Status Status all of type string and required that is this thing which costs this
error in the front that all the time because he couldn't loaded.
Now a user will also have a couple of posts so I'll add my posts here.
This will be an array.
And now each object in that array will be of type schema types object ID because this will be a reference
to a post and airfreight at this ref key and at the post model.
So all store references to posts in my users are on my users.
This is how users should look like if you want you can also add the time stamps.
I don't need them here.
So now I got my model set up we can use that model to set up sign up and later also a log in route.
So let's create a new route and all name that user genius or maybe off Jay ass because it will be authentication
related in there just as before we import express by requiring Express
we then create that express router by calling express router as a function like this.
And we have Chloris export this router now in between.
We define our user or our authentication related routes and there for example I want to have a post
route and you could argue that was set up put route maybe.
Let's let's go for a put down because actually we create a user once so we could also say whether it's
new or we overwrite existing data.
We put the data but both would be fine.
Here we'll have Sign-Up as a route let's say.
And then I need some controller of course.
Now I'll also add validation and to actually reach these routes we have to go to the app js file and
there where I import my feed routes I'll duplicate this at all settable off routes constant where I
import routes all and then at the bottom of the file where I have my feed routes.
I'll also add slash off to forward requests that start with Slash.
Often the path to off routes.
Now we are able to reach these routes and now we need the controller.
So let's work on the controller and add validation in the next lecture.