I will create a new controller off JSA that is related to my users to my user data to my all indication
logic and in there I'll first of all import my user model by requiring it from my models folder the
user file.
Now we need at least two actions here and the first one is of course the action to sign a new user up.
So all named this action sign up and I'll get my request my response at that next function.
And then here I want to add all the logic I need to create a new user in the database so for.
Let's extract the email from request body email lets extract the name of the user from request body
name and lets extract the password from request body password.
Now obviously to extract all of that we need to know that it's there.
So we should add validation for this.
I'll go to my all routes again and just as in feet.
J.S. I will add this expressive validator check.
So I will copy that import from feed J.S. and add it to all.
J.S. and on Sign-Up Alden added an array of validation related middleware.
I'll check my request.
Body and their email field whether it is an email can also just to bring this back into memory to find
our own messages if we want to.
Please enter a valid email.
This would then be stored in the error or object we can retrieve.
We can also add our own custom validator here to check whether the email address already exists for
this.
I'll import my user model so require data from the models folder and then cast them and you'll learn
dad in the Valley Days Marchal by the way in case you want to dive deeply into that again.
The custom function or to cast him validator method here takes a function as an argument which reduced
the value we're looking at.
And then an object from which we can extract the request as a property with this destructuring syntax
and does function then it should return true if validation succeeds or return a promise.
If the validation actually uses some async task.
So if the validation does something which takes a little longer as an error case.
So I will return user find one and I want to find one user where the email off that user as stored in
the database matches the value of the e-mail we're looking at.
Now then I have my user document here so my user object as I've found that in the database and if data
is set and that's the only case I'm carrying about.
If that is set then I will reject a promise so I will return promise reject and that will cost me validation
to fail.
All other scenarios will cause it to succeed and they're all return email address already exists.
That's just a number validation we can add.
Of course I don't just want to validate the email though.
So let's all validate a number of fields in the request body.
Before I do that though just one step I forgot.
I will normalize the email as well.
But now I can look at our body fields like the password the password can be trimmed and should then
have let's say a length of at least 5 characters or whatever you want and I'll add a number check where
I'll look into my body there to the name.
Trim it to remove excess whitespace and this should now not be empty.
With that I got all my validation logic added.
Now that I'm here I can also already import my controller.
So my off controller can be imported from controllers off and now I'll use that off controller as the
last middleware on my Sign-Up route.
And reach out to the sign up action in their now validation was added Now back in the off controller
we want to collect any validation errors right at the start.
And for that I need to import something
from the Express evaluator package again.
And that will be that validation result function which I require from Express validators slash Shekh.
So this validation resoled function here and I collect arrows by calling that and passing the request
to it.
And now if not errors is empty so if we got errors then I noticed something went wrong or did I have
errors.
And in this case I want to create a new error where I say validation failed something like dat and I'll
set a status code of 400 22 and it can also maybe pass some data a new property all at where I store
my error or array like this.
And then I can throw my error here.
Didn't do that before but this would allow me to keep my errors which were retrieved bided validation
package.
I now just have to go to actually yes to my error handling function and there retrieve the data from
error.
The data property and also add does Tuta response him standing in case of an error.
Does is totally optional but just to show how you could keep your original arrows and past them to the
front end as well.
So now I'm doing this I'm doing that validation frilling an error if it fails if we make it postes does
if we know we have all that data we need and now we can start storing the user in the database.
Now there are parts of the authentication module which still matter here.
And one of them is that we should encrypt data password.
So let's finish.
Sign up in a secure way in the next lecture.