To stored a password we should hash it so that if someone gains access to our database the password
is not stored in plain text format.
All install a new package which we used before and that is Biek script J.S. which allows us to hash
a password in a secure way after this was installed.
We can rerun NPM start and now in my off controller I'll import be tripped by requiring it from the
big crypt Jr's package in there.
So in down there in my sign up action I'll use be tripped and there the a hash method to hash out the
password which is plain text you're with assault of 12.
So a strength of 12.
So to say.
And I'll then continue or face error osier.
Now I have an error here somewhere.
Then it'll be a service site error.
I'll copy the logic from before.
So from my feet J.S. controller where a just check for the existence of a status code if no status code
exists.
All set.
Five hundred and.
Well Frode an error like this.
In the then block however we'll have our hashed password and that is the password and I want to store
in the database.
So here are now create a new user with the help of my user or constructors so my user Maalik created
from mongooses and I'll set the fields I need to set on the user.
So that would be email password name status.
Actually we can change the status year from required true to default off I am new.
So now we don't need to setted when creating a user instead.
Every user will start with this status this year just a little adjustment.
With that we don't need to set the status but we do need to set e-mail password and name so the email
is to extract that e-mail password.
ISDE hashed password not the extracted one but the last one to Securitas and the name Asti extract that
name.
Now last but not least I will call save to save to the database and I will return that so that we can
add a number.
Then block where we get the result of that database operation and here we know it will have succeeded.
So we can return a response with a status code off 200 and one because a resource was created where
I can return some Jason data with a message of user created and then maybe the user ID which I can extract
from the result which is the user object result that underscore ID.
So now we're creating a user here.
Let's now save that and to seed it on the front and we need to go into the front end code in there to
the app js file.
And here first of all we need to correct our u r l and I also need to change something so did we start
in unauthenticated mode.
Currently we are starting as if we were authenticated.
I'll have to change to it in the front end too.
Now first of all in the sign up Handler let's fix that u r l and there the U R L will be local host
ADHD slash off slash Sign-Up that will reach this Routier right.
Because it's slash sign.
And we only end up there for requests that start with slash off.
Now we find a put request here on the back end so we have to set the method in the second argument in
this object we pass to fetch.
We have to set the method to put.
We also need to append some data and that data will be of type application Jason.
So we should add the content type header and set this to application.
Jason last but not least let's at the request body and here will need to use Jason string ify to convert
an object to Jason and that object will be a javascript Optik with the e-mail which we can retrieve
from off data email off data is an argument we'll get here.
And I wrote the code to make sure that we get the data the user entered.
So we'll get the e-mail.
We'll get the password.
So let's also extract data from off data and we'll get the name from off data.
So everything which we extract on the service side this is now all passed to our back and now in app
just stroll up a bit more to the very top here in this state.
Now a change is off to false.
So did we start on authenticated now.
When you when the page reloads you start on the logon page and you can switch to sign up and there.
Let's create a new user can enter any name you want.
And I accidentally hit enter which is good because we now see validation is doing its job.
But now let me enter a valid password which you should remember and click sign up and it still failed.
Let's see what's wrong here.
Let's inspect for which field we're getting this indeed.
By inspecting the network tab and then here we see OK all three fields give us the error.
That's kind of a strong signal that the data is simply not passed to the back end at all so something
seems to be wrong there.
Indeed we can validate just by clicking on headers.
There we see there is no request payload added to this request.
And that's simply a little mistake on my site in actually as an affront to the code in Sign-Up handler
here Lura extract off the e-mail and so on.
That should be sign up form dot e-mail at value and the same for all the other fields too.
So let's add sign up for him in front of that and thought value at the end the same first name.
Does this how the data is stored here internally in the re-act app and this how we should extract it.
So let's give it another try.
Let's The email address and name and password.
And now this looks much better.
I get back user created I'm forwarded to the logon page here in my front and I get that user ID.
And of course we can always use.
Would you be Compaq's to take a closer look at our database.
There I got this message just database.
If I reloaded now I got a user collection in there.
And here I have that user.
So that is working.
The user also has a starting status.
Now we have no posts of course.
Now we can continue and we can work on logging the user in and that will now be the interesting part
because I already mentioned that authentication will now work differently.