To implement authentication we first of all need a fitting route.
So in the off J.S. route Routier I will add a new route post route where I will lock the user in so
there will be slash log in.
We could add validation here but I don't really care about this because I will check to email password
pair anyways so we can all directly go forward to our controller action.
So let's implement Dad let's work on the controller action now for Dad in the off file in the controllers
folder.
I'll add a new action which I'll name log in which of course is a function with request response next.
And then some logic and then hear ask before all retrieve my e-mail WIPs from request body e-mail all
retrieve the password from requests bawdy password and I now first of all want to find out whether that
e-mail address exists because if it does not then we already know that you can't log in.
So I'll use my user model and find one to find one user where the e-mail equals the extracted e-mail
I got here.
We can succeed or we can fail with debt if we fail we'll use that same handler we used for.
So we'll throw an error because we're failing of course means that we simply had some network error
or some error with the database.
If we make it into the then block we had a user object but that does not mean that we found a user it
could be undefined if no user was found.
We basically always end up in the then block if no error is Frode.
So here I'll check if user is not the find and if it is not the find all create a new error object where
I add or where I add a message all of a user with this e-mail could not be found anything you want.
We're all set.
Status code off and now you could choose different codes you could go for 4 or 4 because no user was
found or for a one for not affiliated and then all Frode at error.
If we make it past this check we know that we have that e-mail address.
Now we need to validate the password for us all quickly create a new variable loaded user and store
my user in that variable so that I can use it in other functions later to not use Be trip again and
they're all use to compare method to compare the password the user entered with the password I got stored.
So with that hashed password so user Your password is password and looking for all returned is because
this will give me a promise and hence I can add a number of them block here.
Here I get back.
True or false depending on whether it is equal or not.
And if it is not equal of course then the user did enter a wrong password.
So here all create number error or wrong password maybe
and I'll add status code.
All four hundred and one again and fro dead error.
But if we make it positive check then we know the password is equal to the password the user entered.
So the user entered a correct password and now we need to generate such a Jasen web token.
Let's do that next.