So we're at the point where we know that the user did enter valid credentials.
Now we want to use that information to generate such.
Jason Webb token which I showed you on the slides for that let's quit the server here.
No it's server.
And let's install and you package the package.
I want to use is called Jason weap token.
One word does is a package which allows us to conveniently create such new Jason web tokens.
We can now restart a server.
And we need to import this into this file.
So your all important stored in a constant name JWT the name is of course up to you.
But Jason Webb token package or do you object it exposes now down there.
After checking the password I want to generate a new token stored the token and a constant name token
and then here I'll use to take the package and there sign method.
This creates a new signature and packs that into a new Jason web token we can add any data we want into
the token like for example we could store the user email.
So access to a loaded user e-mail and user id access to load a user underscore ID.
And since it's Mongo D-B object that year let's convert that to a string.
So now I'm storing some user data and a token.
Of course you should not store the raw password in here because that would be returned to the front
end to the user to whom the password belongs but still not ideal email and user ID should be fine however.
And then you need to pass a second argument which is that secret so that private key which is used for
a signing and that is now only known to the server and therefore you can't fake that token on the client.
I'll enter a secret here.
Typically you want to use a longer string like some super secret secret or even longer.
Also check out the official box of the Chaisson web token and to learn more about it all.
Also set a firm argument where I configure this and they're all set expiry time of one hour with this
syntax so that the token becomes invalid after one hour.
Now this is a security mechanism you should add because the token is stored in the client.
Now of course biot a client to whom it belongs but technically that token could be stolen if the user
does not log out another person copies the token from his browser storage and then can use it on his
own PC forever.
Well not forever now at least because after one hour the token becomes invalid.
So this is a good security mechanism which is like an Nye's finds a nice balance between usability where
you would want infinite sessions and security where you would want to limit this to like one second.
Now this is all a nice in-between solution which is pretty common.
So now we have a token which we can return to the client.
So here indeed I will not return a response with status code 200 where I add some data.
We can add a message if you want but I will only add that token which I generated and a user ID and
that is my loaded user Daut underscore ID to string now that data needs to be provided because India
react.
I gave you.
I'll be looking for that idea and I'll be storing it by the way should take 1 hour.
Because in that react to app log you out after one hour and all that storing and so on will be done
by the front end.
Now I'll show you how it gets stored in a second of course.
So let's now go back to our off route and connect our loggin route to our off controller and there the
log in action.
And now with that let's go back to the front end and work on the code there as well.
So in the front end here and the aperture has filed where we have to sign up Handler.
We have to look for loggin handler here and we should fix D or L there.
Q You are L is localhost 80 80 slash off slash log in.
We need to pass an object where we now also change the request method to post and where we pass our
data.
So just as with signing up we can actually copy that logic from there the headers and the body copy
that and move it to log in.
We don't past a name in the body though.
But password and email will be passed.
Now there is another small adjustment required here.
You can actually directly access off that e-mail and off data password.
Now if that's saved it go back to your re-act the app and try logging in with the credentials you created
a couple of Electress ago.
It should work.
This error still is coming from the status which will fix soon.
And here we all see that I'm logging something we see that token that was generated and the user ID
in your chrome browser dev tools you can also go to the application tab and there a go to local storage
select your domain and you will see that token here.
That is the token we generated on the server.
The data is data I'm storing here or that was stored way back by our application so we don't need that.
That has nothing to do with our app.
We have the expiry date which I generate on the client.
You know when I should remove the token because it expired and this is the token itself.
Now you can also take that token and was it JWT dot I O they are you can learn more about Jason Webb
tokens First of all and you can also paste your token into that area on the left.
And this allows you to look into your token you don't see your secret but you can now validate it.
If you enter your secret which you chose on the server some super secret secret then you should end
up with that same token you copied in.
And indeed if I replace it it does not change.
And here you see that payload data you add it on your server side.
You could theoretically extract that on the Kaline too.
And that is why you should not store super sensitive data in there.
But this also shows you that if I try to generate this token on my own let's say I also edited like
change to email address the token changes on the left and therefore if I added this it will not be validated
because now the token is not the same as it was when it was generated on the server with this secret.
So if I try to generate my own one with a different secret I'll end up with a different token and if
I try to edit the data in there I also do so I can't mess around with the token in the client.
The server will detect this disease how we can log in and how we work with tokens to know whether we
are locked in.
We're missing one important piece of information though.
We have that token.
Now we all need to attach the token to requests that require authentication because right now.
Well I am locked in I only see these options after logging in but theoretically deleting editing and
so on does not really care about the token we should change this.
We should also connect new posts to our user and we should make sure that only users who created a post
can edit or delete it.
So still some work to do.