Knouted we're generating a token and we're passing it to declined.
We need to make sure that the client can pass back to token to the back and to the rest API.
And we didn't check for the existence and B validity of the token before we allowed a request to continue.
So for example on our feed routes on all these routes none of these routes should be public.
So if no token is attached to the incoming request we should simply block access here and this is what
I'll work on now for that I'll add new middleware.
I'll create a new middleware folder for this.
You could place it anywhere though and I'll name it is offcut.
That is the name of my file in there.
I will import my Jason weap token package because we'll need that package to validate incoming tokens
then I'll export one function in that file that will be a normal middleware function request response
next so that I can use it as a bit lower.
And now first of all I need to extract the token from an incoming request.
Now currently we are not attaching the token to any requests.
How could we attach it if we go back to our front end let's say in feet.
J.S. for loading posts we want to attach to tokin.
How could we do that.
There are a couple of options you could add a query parameter something like Token equals and then enter
your token value there and then append query parameters that would be a valid option.
Nothing wrong with that.
You could include it in the request body but that is not ideal because for example get requests have
no body.
So that is not a solution.
You should use unless you never have often indicated get requests a great solution is however that you
use a header.
It keeps your.
You are beautiful.
Of course it might not be the most important argument but still it keeps your.
You are as beautiful and a hatter makes a lot of sense for meta information like.
Well the token which it isn't yet.
So let's add a second argument in the load posts function in the feet.
Yes file in the front end.
A second argument there to the fetch method.
And here I will add some headers to this request now I will not add the content type because I'm not
sending any data here but I will add the authorization header.
Theoretically you can add any header you want but this isn't an official header header you officially
use for passing authentication information to the backend.
And please remember that on the back and in the capture file where we added our course headers.
I did and able.
The authorization header you need to have that enabled for this to work.
So I'm setting my offer I sation ahead are there and I'm setting it to a value which is not just a token
but actually barer whitespace and then this Rops token allows you to get the token and you react at
why barer.
Well this is just a convention to kind of identify the type of token you have and a barer token is simply
an authentication token you typically use bearer for Jason.
Web tokens.
It's not a must.
You could actually work without that but it's a common convention and day afer I want to keep that convention.
So this is how I could add my token to that gueth posts request on the front end.
Now on the back end to extract it it is all middle where I will create a new variable.
Or a constant token and then access my request to get method.
I can get some Hetter value.
The header is do you all for my sation header of course and there I will get this barer whitespace token.
Now I'm only interested in the token of course so I will split on the whitespace which comes after barer
and I'll get a second value with just a token then.
So this is the token.
Now I will try to decode it so will actually use a try catch block because it could fail and I will
create a new variable here decoded token and decoded token will then be JWT and there we have the verify
method.
This will both decode and verify or token UAS.
You also have a de-code token but this will only decode it and not check if it's valid.
So definitely use varify here and then you pass that token which you extracted from the header and then
that secret and that has to be the same secret you used for assigning the token of course.
So the same secret you used in your off controller this one.
Otherwise you'll not get a matching result.
So this is a secret which we will use for validating the token.
Now this could fail.
So here I'll have a catch block.
And there I want to add a status code to my error of 500 and then I will throw the error here.
Since I'm in the middle where now the expressed error handler would take over overwise we know that
decoding worked and null check if it is undefined which would be the case if it didn't fail technically
but it wasn't able to verify the token.
In this case all create a new error not authenticate it.
Add a status code All four hundred and one and throw this error.
If we make it past this check we know that we have a valid token however and that we were able to decode
it.
So now I'll just extract some information from the token the user id and I will store it in the request
so that I can use it in other places where this request will go like in my routes and they are all just
X's to decode a token which now simply well is basically the part on the right.
Here we can now access that data since we decoded it.
So there I can now access my user ID field which I stored in the token.
This will be useful for later.
All Freising access to for example deleting posts because now I know to user ID stored in the token
and that should match the user id of the post.
We tried to delete later and then I can forward this request so will ever have an error.
If we have no token attached or everything will be fine.
Now we can add that middleware to our routes and I will add it to my get posts route so here get posts
should use that milah where they are free.
First of all need to import it by requiring it from the middleware folder is off.
And I will add it like this year.
Now I only can get posts if I do add a token.
First of all let me show you how does Fales if I remove this header.
So this extra configuration on my get posts request and the front end if I remove that and I reload
the page I get fails to fetch posts and into console log all to see that your
Because it fails to read split of undefined.
We get a technical error because in my middleware it can't get anything from that header because the
header is not defined.
Therefore we could add extra check here and first of all get the header off.
Header would then be request get all Frye's sation.
And if this is undefined.
So if he can find the header then I will already create an error here.
Not authenticated because we don't even append to tokens so we certainly are not authenticated.
I can set my status code of four hundred and one which is better than 500.
And I can Frode an error and then down there.
We know that we do have all headers.
Now we can split it so that's the improved way of handling get.
Now if we reload on the front then we still get that error.
But technically we now have a four hundred and one error which is better.
Now I can add that code back where I add a token but let's try adding some rubbish here which is not
a valid token.
Now if the reloads it still fails and fails because now the the Chaisson web token package has a problem
with the format of our token.
So now let me revert to an ad develop token and now as does reloads now our posts load because now we
are validating this.
We have a valid token indeed.
So this is now how we can validate on the server side how we can check whether the token is valid and
then grant access.
And now we just have to do that for all our routes before we Denne also make sure that all users who
created something can delete it because right now of course.
Well I can delete everything as you can see.