We add that this is all middleware on the server.
Let's now protect all feed routes with it not as super simple we just copy that middleware and we add
it to every route we have there as the first middleware before we do anything else because of no token
to stare.
We don't even need to continue with anything else.
Every route should be protected here.
So we simply add this to every single route.
Now once you did add it to every route you have to make sure that you passed the token on the front
end.
So this headers set up where you add does offer a sation header.
This is something you now need to add in a couple of places in the front end.
For example our edit handler Stehr there on the fecche request we now should also add some headers and
the headers should contain are all for I sation token
if we scroll down further we also got the lead post handler.
Well there obviously we also want to add some headers and that one had or we want to add is our offer
sation token of course we can all the fecche single posts.
So in this single post js file in the front end code where we fetch a single post we all want to pass
that second argument to fetch add our headers and there at the all right sation header.
Now we should be able to navigate around as long as we are authentic hate it.
But I also want to lock down access to ensure that I can only added and delete posts which actually
create it.
Now in the last lecture I deleted all posts.
So let's make sure that we first of all connect posts and users when we create new posts.