Let's connect posts and users for days in my back and code.
First of all I'll go to my post model and there we have that creator object.
Right.
Well that was like intermediated l solution.
Now that we know users in our application creator will no longer be of type Object type schema types
object ID because I will store a reference to a user so this will now be a reference to a user here.
This will also be required true.
Not required string what I had before this was a mistake of course.
So now we have a relation between posts and users.
We store the creator of a post in every post we create and on the user model we add the post to the
list of posts for that user.
That of course means we now need to adjust our feed controller in the place where we do create new posts
there and create post the validation which we do at the beginning still is.
All right but then before I create the post I should get my user ID.
Now I remember in my is all middleware I do actually stored it in the request object.
I get it from the decoded token.
So we have that user ID available here.
Now with that information all set creator equal to request user ID that will be a string not an object
ID.
But mongooses will take care about that and convert it.
So now we create a new post assigned to that user.
Now once I saved the post I'll not immediately send the response though.
Instead I now also want to add that post to the list of posts for the given user.
Therefore I'll import my user model into that feat.
J.S..
Fall requiring it from the models folder of course.
And uncreate post.
Once we did save the post all used at user model to find to user by ID for the request user ID.
So for the user id extracted from the token then I'll return this and close this.
Then block and add and you then block.
Right now get that user that was created now and this second then block here I now have a user system
not the user which was created by the user which was found.
I have that user with just the currently locked in user and now I can take that user object which is
a mongoose model here in the end and I can access the post post-office user.
Keep in mind to use remodeler has a post's property I can access these posts and I can push the newly
created post.
So this post here I can push that posts object to that user and mongooses will do all the heavy lifting
of pulling out the post ID and adding debt to the user actually.
Now I'll also add a new variable at the top which I'll name creator which is uninitialized.
And once I found a user I'll store the user in that creator variable.
Now what do I need that for.
Well I do update my user here.
That means that here I will also call user save and I will return that and hence we need a number.
Then block where I get the result of this operation.
Now in this next block I'll sent my response and there I will not just send the post but I also want
to set information about the Creator.
So here I'll add a creator or a key and that will be let's say some object with an ID underscore ID
of creator underscore ID and name which is creator name.
So I'm just passing this extra information with the response.
And if I want to do that I have to do it for a variable
so now posts get saved and get connected to users in both directions.
Let's try that out.
Let's save this code go back to the front end there.
Let's create a new post.
Good old duck again.
Let's add a duck image a duck.
How lovely.
Click except here.
And I get an error.
Let's see what's going wrong.
I do get back a response with a post.
And the problem is that post holds my user data actually which is a mistake.
Ms And of course the post I am sending back here is not the result the result here is to user which
updated it here post should be the post model.
The Post object I created up there.
So that's my mistake.
I do create a post there I stored it in a constant.
I can reuse that constant down there to send data about that tree and post back to the client.
So let me save that now.
Still what we'll see is in the database that go to the post collection.
It was created though because it only failed when it came to sending back the correct data.
And there we see that it's all connect to a user which ends with ABC.
If you have a look at the users is as user and they're in posts we all find the ID of the post which
ends with 6 E5.
Yep that is correct.
So this worked now.
Only a minor mistake here regarding that data I sent back.
Let's simply give this a try again.
Here's our post.
Let's add a cup like this.
Superhot and now this works without an error.
So now we are able to connect posts and users.
Let's now take it a step further and make sure that editing and deleting is only possible for posts
that belong to the currently locked end user.