To check whether a user tries to edit or delete a post which does not belong to him we should go to
you on the note rest.
AP I project we should go to our feet controller and there find are up they didn't delete Moffats of
course.
Let's start with updating a post in there.
We find a post by idea which is all right of course and we should keep in mind that for a post the Creator
will be the ID of the user who created that.
So even if we do ever post here we want to check whether that creator ID is equal to the ID of the currently
locked and user so Id ID that belongs to the token we received.
So here I'll check if Post creator is equal to the Creator to string to convert this to a string is
equal to request.
User ID so to the user id I got from my token if that is equal am allowed to continue if it is not equal
hence we need a exclamation mark here.
I'll throw in error so here I'll try it a you error.
Not all for just.
Set the status code to four hundred and three which is a good status code for offer isolation issues
and I'll throw that error.
Now if I saved that let's check that.
First of all let's delete a post which we are allowed to delete.
Like dead duck.
If I delete that now deleting obviously works because we never added any logic to prevent it.
Now let me log out and create a new user.
We need a different email address.
Well let's first of all try the same one.
It should fail so here all just use max and it fails.
Now let's use an used e-mail address and it succeeds.
Let's now log in with that newly created user.
Now let's try editing because that is where we did at protection the cup which was not created by that
user this failed with a 403 error.
Let's now log in with the user who did create it and let's now try editing with this user and this now
six seats.
So now we have this first check in place.
Let's now also added to our delete post logic there there.
I find my post at the beginning and before we continue here I basically want to implement that same
check.
I'll check the creator which is the ideal of the user and compare it to the user id extracted from the
toolkit and if they're not equal I will throw an error.
So now only offer us users should be able to delete the post of course.
Make sure to do that before you clear D-Mich..
Now after saving this let's go back and delete this and it succeeds because this was the right user.
Let's log out let's log in with this user let's say.
And create a new post doc
with the image and some content and let's log out and log in with the average user the user who did
not create it and let's delete that there and you see that fails.
No I didn't implement an error message there.
And of course you could also tweak the Front-End to not even showed these buttons if you're not allowed
to edit.
But my idea here is to show you how you can protect us on the back end.
Since of course this is a node course.
Therefore I deliberately let you do that so that you can see it that we can prevent this on the backend.
And indeed we can't delete this now.
With the wrong user.