Now talking about deleting there's one more thing we should do in case we do succeed we should clear
the relation of posts and users.
If we refreshed the post collection we only have one item there.
But if I have a look at my users they're now the first user has a couple of posts.
And the second user has so to because right now we have no logic to clear posts.
When I lead them to clear relations and we should of course do that.
Now how can we get rid of a relation Well we delete the post anyways so there's nothing we need to do
there.
But on the user we need to pull our reference to do that we should find to user after we deleted a post
let's say so here or find a user by ID and I can use my request.
User ID here.
And I will return as user object in there.
Well let's grab that code and add a number.
Then block where I will have that user mongoose model fetched from my database.
Now in there.
I will use my user model and there the posts array and then there is a pull method mongooses gives me
there I need to past the idea of the post I want to remove.
Now I deleted the post already here but the post idea is still available of course so I can pass post
ID here.
Now I can call safe here to save that updated user and return that grab the response one more time and
add another.
Then block with the result of that operation.
And here I'm done with clearing the relation.
Now to see that in action.
Let me actually get rid of all users manually by using Mangu to be calm pass.
Also get rid of all posts and log out here and let's create a brand new user because we cleared all
users
like this.
Let's log in with that user and let's create a new post a duck used at DAQ image it Dexron for sure
except.
And before we do anything let's go back to Mungo's add to monkey be compas I mean there we can see that
this post has this creator and this user.
More importantly has this post in his posts erased.
Now I'm locked in with the right user Let's click delete.
This worked and now if I refresh posts we got no posts in there because I deleted the only post we had
and then users desir is now also empty.
So now we're clearing this as well.