Now what we've learned how to add users to our application.
Let's take a step backward and let's have a look at the important topic that is related to any visitor
no matter if he or she is of any kind or not interacting with your website.
I'm talking about handling user input and most importantly that will be the topic of this module validating
that user input.
They are offering us more.
It will have a look at why validation is important.
So what do I mean with validating user input and why would you want to do that.
And of course how can we validate user input.
These are the core things and I will show you how you can ensure that the data you work with is really
that data and in the format you expect to get it.
So this is what will dive into in this module.
So let's see what exactly validation is and why we would want to add it.