So why would we want to add some data or input validation to our application.
Well if we have a user interacting with our Web site then we typically have a lot of Foreigns on any
web application we build in our example project for example we have a forum for signing up.
We got one for signing in and we got one for adding products.
And the bigger your application is the more data you will need from your users at some point of time.
So we have that form with which our user our visitor off the Web site interacts with.
Now in the end when this form is submitted with a POST request as we controlled it in our forum then
that request is sent to our backend.
By the way you could also configure it to send a GET request.
But the key thing here is a request with the form data is sent and we're already doing this in this
course because this is a crucial task in any web application.
Now on our back and Soller node Jasc code we then typically interact with a database or maybe we write
that data into a normal file but in the end we take that data which we receive and we want to store
it.
Now this is exactly the part which can be dangerous or problematic though right now and yet we got no
kind of data validation.
So if a user in our current application would try to log in with something that is not a valid email
address we would allow that.
We're not preventing the user from entering something incorrect.
The same is true for adding a product we don't care about what the user enters and does us what I want
to change in this module will add some validation as an extra step right at the start of our node.
JS Cote's right at the start when we handled a request on the server definitely before we store it in
a database and this validation can then ever succeed and allowed data to be written to the database
or to a file or allow it to be handled by the rest of our node code or we reject the input and then
basically return some information to the user prompting the user to correct the error.
So this is what we will work on in this module and I will show you how to validate and how to provide
a good user experience.