So I'm back in our project and there for example we got the first cases where we could add validation
to log in and to sign up pages there.
We want to validate for example on the sign up page the email address is a valid email address with
an at sign and domain ending.
That's the password for example is at least six characters long.
Whatever your requirement is and that the confirmed password matches the password.
That would be helpful too.
And later when we create a product where we for example enter a u r l we might want to validate that
this is a valid u r l.
So these are all things that we can add with the help of proper validation and that is exactly what
will dive into now.
Now to add validation will use a third party package.
The package will be using is called Express validator and the Google for Express validator to find these
official docs which are always worth checking out.
You find quick command on how to install it and then you find a link to the full official box which
is a separate web page where you learn all about using it.
And this is really a good idea to dive in because I will introduce you to this package if you want to
learn all the ins and outs about it.
Definitely check out this documentation.
So first of all install it with this command here.
So just using NPM as we did it for other packages too.
So back in our project code which is to code I've finished with in the last course module we can simply
entered this year to install express validator into this project and once it's done we are ready to
use it.
So let me restart my development server with and start and now let's find out how we can use Express
validator.
And let's start with our often dictation routes for that.
So here we obviously have our off controller with the different controller actions and we got our routes
folder with the off js file.
Now typically you want to validate on your post or your non get Rochlitz because you want to bellyache
whenever the user sends state and that is not the case for our get droughts for example.
But for posting the log in data or posting the sign up data I want to validate that data and it will
start with the sign up with post sign up with this route.
Let's say we want to add some validation to that route and we want to ensure that our e-mail here is
an email the password is at least let's say five characters long and that the confirmed password matches
our password.
These would be some nice checks which I want to add here.
Now you add that with that package installed in my office.
Fall in the rabbits folder I can import something from that package.
Let's name that expr validator or whoever you want to name it and require express validator here.
However the import looks a bit different.
We import a Suppe package because express validator is basically made up of a couple of Suppe packages
you could say that we need to check package which is the packet you use for.
Well all the validation logic you could want to add.
We can also use a next gen javascript syntax because X validator which we import will be a javascript
object and we can use a feature called destructuring where we use curly braces on the left side of the
equal sign.
And then you add some property names which you want to pull out of the object dead.
This would give you so here and you can find it in the official docs we'll get a check function actually.
So in the object which we import and which we would have stored in expr validate or otherwise there
will be a check property that holds a function and we can import validation result that we don't need
to here will need it later.
There are other functions you can import.
And again the official docs are a great way to dive in deeper.
What this does is in the end it just gives us a check function which we import from this package here
and now adding validation to a router is really simple for this post route.
If you want to add validation we add an extra middleware.
Remember you have that path and then you can add as many middleware request handlers as you want and
I'll add a new one here and I'll add a new one by adding my check function calling it here.
And check this function will in the end return a middleware So here ident just entered a field name
or an array of fields which I want to check.
Now how does this work.
Well I can simply add check.
And then the field name.
Now we can have a look at our Sign-Up view to find out that for example there will have an email field.
So it's does name I'm looking for.
We have an e-mail field in there so email will be the name of that field in the requests we're receiving.
So in our off route I can check email now does tell us middle middleware the Express validator does
I'm interested in confirming dead e-mail value or order.
I'm interested in validating that value.
We don't call a method and this will in the end then return a middleware that is understood by express
checks.
So we call a method on this object which is returned by the check function that now allows us to do
all kinds of checks.
For example is e-mail.
Now there are a bunch of built in methods and I will show you where to find him in a second.
What this will now do is it will use this package to check the email field on the incoming request and
it looks for that field in the body in the query parameters in the headers and then cookies and it finds
that field and then checks if that is a valid email address.
That is the first step.
Now with that we have this middleware in place now we can go to our controller here under control as
of course and implored and number part of that package.
So your I will also import with this destructuring syntax because this packet just exposes a bunch of
stuff and I only want to get some specific things and I import from Express validator check here as
well.
And there we now need to import the validation result validation result will be a function that allows
us to gather all the errors.
Prewire validation middleware like this one might have flown or might have stored.
So now we just have to go to the post Sign-Up route because that is where I did add my middleware in
here.
I can now simply extract my errors and stored them in a constant errors by calling validation result
on the request and indeed request does express validate or middleware which we added here will have
added error that can now be retrieved with this middleware and you off Jaspal the routes folder we are
collecting arrows so to say we're in dismissible or we'll store some aerostat found in an error object
so to say and this validation result function will go food it arus object managed by the middleware
on the request and will then collect them all in this Aeros constant and we can then use that constant
to check if we do have errors.
Now how does that work.
Well we can simply check if errors.
And then there is a method we can call their isde is empty method and is empty will return true or false
depending on whether we got errors or not.
And if this is not empty that's why I add an exclamation mark to check to even worse if it is not empty
then we could return a response where we set the status quo to 422 which is a common status code for
indicating that validation failed.
So it isn't error status code.
It will still send their response judge just to have this different status code and then we can call
render here and render the page again.
And I don't redirect here because I want to redirect upon success.
If we fail I will render the same page again.
So here I will render the same as I do in get sign up here.
We can copy that render message that render call here I should say.
We do that same rendering here without rest just render it rendered that same page or sign up.
And I can also add my my error Stehr the error message and not message like this but I can output errors.
And then there is an array function which I can call to return an array of arrows.
I'm active and we can all the output this year with conc a lock to get a feeling for what's in there.
Aeros array like this let's see what we got in there.
Now if we save all that with that place with Bittle where any error collection mechanism.
Let me address something here.
Test which is not a valid email and let me hit sign up.
Now I get a message here which is the default browser validation because I set this to type e-mail in
my
Sign-Up view here.
I have type e-mail and this adds this default browser validation.
Now one thing you can do is you can at no validate to the overall forum Velia date.
To disable this check.
Now.
If you want to add it because it is a nice client side validation that can improve the user experience.
But here to see how it works without that.
To allow me to make deliberate mistakes I will disable it for now with no validate added to the form
not the input but to the form.
And then if I reload that page and I do enter something in it again I can submit.
Now don't be confused by the error message.
This is to be expected because we don't get a message we get an error rate of errors.
But if we check our suicide console we see that Descanso log where I log an array of the Erstad was
like that gets me dead.
And we get the square brackets It's an array an array of objects.
And in that object we find out which parameter will last a problematic one.
What value was entered and which message was generated by the validation Millward.
And this is a message we can use to output an error message if we want to.