So we added a very basic validation and we get back a message which you want your output.
So this already shows us how we can work with that validation model where we see had rendered that page
again and now we just need to make sure we don't output Object object here.
But a real error message we can do that in our sign up view of course.
Here we got our error message thing and the error message which I am outputting here is simply an object
because it's that array and not a single field in there.
Now we just need to adjust some figure and then the controller instead of returning an array.
Let's say we always want to return the first error message.
Obviously you could change just to change the overall logic.
And you need to change it in a control action step 2 to output all messages.
But for now let's say we simply take the first one which we are guaranteed to have because we'll have
at least one error and then there the message and now it is safe that and I do send just test again.
Now I get invalid values.
That is how we could output that message.
We cannot just output the message.
We can also customize it.
And we have to do that in the place where we added to our middleware.
So in the route's file off-Terra is e-mail.
You can add do you with message function and this will always refer to the validation logic that was
right before it because you could add multiple checks here.
You could also add is alphanumeric to check that only contains numbers and key characters number characters.
So you could add multiple ones but with message will always refer to the validation method right in
front of it.
And there you could add please enter a valid email something like debt and if you add this with message
here you will see that if I enter just some text here I get.
Please enter a valid email.
So this is a way of working with the messages and also customizing it.
And I also mentioned that you can add more validators.
So let's have a look at this in the next lecture.