We add a D is email validator.
Now there are way more built in validators available from which you can choose and you'll find them
when you visit the Express validator page because they're If you check the official docs to which this
link points you'll see that in the end it's wrapper around devaluated or J.S. validator.
So that's another package that was implicitly installed with express elevator and here on the docks
a validator J.S. which is a different package which was installed.
You'll find all the built in validators and what they do and how you might configure them if possible.
And you see this is the one we're using is e-mail.
This is what I'm using here.
We could configure it to change different e-mail formats you want accept or not accept.
We can check for emptiness.
We can check whether something is a full domain or a full.
R l.
We got all kinds of things we can check if a value is in a certain array of possible allowed values
if we have a certain length will be important for the password.
And so much more.
So there are a bunch of things we can check and definitely go through this list to learn more about
the built in validators.
You can also add your own validator though and to demonstrate just real quick.
Let's say we're not just using is e-mail.
I also want to make sure it's a specific e-mail.
I want to have for data can add custom here and now a validator is in the end a function like dis a
function receives the value of the field where checking so the value in the email field and optionally
an object from which we can extract things like the location to which is was sent the POF or the request
object in case we need to extract more from the request.
Now in this function you want to throw an error or when validation fails.
So here we could simply check if value equals and let's say it should be test at test dot com because
we don't want to allow that.
That's just some dummy logic here.
So if that is the case then I'll throw an error by calling Frode new error with a mass of this email
address is for bidin something like that.
Of course this is very arbitrary that I'm checking for exactly that e-mail address.
But this is how you can generally write your own validators in case the many built in ones don't suffice
your requirements.
So now if I save this we should see that if I reload that page and I enter test the test of come I get
this e-mail address is forbidden.
If I test to a test dot com then I get invalid value though.
The reason for this invalid value here simply is that if we do succeed we should return true.
So we throw an error if we fail.
We could return false to go with the default error message or we throw an error to have our own error
message or we return true if it succeeded.
And now you will see that if I enter test to this work.
Now this will actually be stored a bit strange in the database now because I entered a new user with
invalid password with an empty password but we didn't add any password validation yet.
The key takeaway is that you saw how you can add your own validator returning true if it's fine.
Returning false or frozen error if it's not and how you can use to many built in once.
And of course that you can chain them off each other to add multiple validators to one in the same field.