With our basic validation in place let's now find out how we can check for equality in our passwords.
And for that I of course want to check my confirm password field.
So in my sign up view I'm talking about this field with the name confirm password.
So let's go back to off J.S. to that route and let's add and you check for something in the ball you
have to request.
So basically for to confirm password field here now in there I want to check if that is equal to my
password.
And how can I achieve this.
Well I could do it by adding a custom validator here that custom validator which receives a value and
then extract the request.
Have this destructuring syntax.
And if they're in there I check if the value of confirmed password is equal to the value of request
for the password.
And this is why you might need access to the request object.
Because here I need to extract the password.
So this field value from the request body in my custom validator and I can check if they are equal or
to be precise if they are not equal and if they are not equal.
Well then I want to throw a new era where I say passwords have to match like this.
And otherwise I return true.
And this is how we could check for equality of two fields.
I'm checking whether my confirmed password is equal to my password was that if I was saved.
And I do enter a valid email address this one is already taken but I'm not validating for this with
this package.
So this should be fine.
I do enter a valid password and I do enter.
Let's say a number theoretically valid password though we're not checking for langue for anything like
that.
Unconfirmed password so anything would do it there.
But the important thing is this is a password that differs from this one.
You can make this really clear by adding more characters.
For now it's sign up I get passwords have to match.
So this is now working.
If on the other hand I try to take an e-mail address.
But again that's not validated by this package.
But then a try valid equal passwords.
Then I only get my e-mail thing but the validation with that validation package succeeded.
Now it's also worth noting that I did not add the our password validation like is length and is alphanumeric
to the confirmed password.
Even though that applies to the confirmed password too of course.
But why did I not add it.
Because we're already checking it on this main password.
And then we're checking for equality.
So we implicitly have this check here unconfirmed password too.
I don't care if confirmed password is long enough because it has to equal that password and that password
is checked for its length.
So I got in place here and therefore I am protected against any errors on this site.
So this is now how we could check for password or any field equality that you might need in your application.