Our Sign-Up validation is looking pretty good.
But there is one thing which we are validating in a bit of a strange way right now and that is the fact
that the e-mail address is taken or not.
Right now I'm doing that in my off controller and there by the way we will not need a password any more.
We're checking this ahead of time but an off.
Yes I do check for e-mail existence here.
Now logically it what makes sense to check that as part of our validation right.
And the good thing is we can do that.
Let's grab this code where we find one user here let's grab that code.
And let's head over to the off office followed in the routes folder in there.
Let's first of all import our user model by requiring it from the models folder and then from the user
file.
So we need that.
And then here on my e-mail field I got this custom validator.
All common does code out because I want to keep it for you as a reference but now we'll add a more.
Well a check that makes more sense.
I will add my code here where I find one user with that e-mail address.
Now that e-mail address on the right side here is the value of course which you are validating because
we're doing this on the e-mail field.
So value will be the entry email I'm searching for that e-mail.
And then here if I have a user document Well then I will not do it with this flash message and so on
anymore.
Instead I'll just take that error message and inside of this if block which is inside of my then block
here I will return a new promise reject call that promises a built in javascript object and would reject
a basically throw an error or inside of the promise and I reject with this error message I used before.
What this means is that now ofter does then block I could add and never catch block to catch this but
I will not do that here.
Instead let's close our function curly braces and the normal brackets with a custom function.
And now what I'll do is I will return user find one.
Now what will this do.
The Express validator package will check for a custom validator to return true or false to return a
fro an error or to return a promise.
If it's a promise as that is the case with this because here we ultimately return a promise because
every Then block implicitly returns and you promise.
So if we return a promise then express validator will wait for this promise to be fulfilled and if it
fulfills with in our case nothing.
So basically no error Dennet's treats this validation as successful if it resolves with some rejection
and Yanto which will happen if we make it into the if block then express validator will detect dis rejection
and will store this as an error.
This message will then be stored as an error message and this is how we can add our own asynchronous
validation asynchronous because we have to reach out to the database which of course is not an instant
task but express validator will kind of wait for us here.
So now we have our own async validation of place and now we should still check for email existence but
we don't do it as a controller anymore because Dare I will in the end get rid of that entire user find
one thing here instead of will instantly start with B crypt and I'll also remove one pair of brackets
at the bottom and this semi-colon and this catch block and now what I'd do with yours I instantly started
with hash in my password and so on creating that user because I can rely on the user to not exist already
inside of my controller because I do check for its existence ahead of time in my off JS route with the
help of that really Deshaun middleware.
So now let's go back and let's add a email address and a valid password.
All the user added already exists and indeed I get e-mail access already so that is great if I however
do add an email address that does not exist yet and I do enter valid passwords I get my Sign-Up page
here.
My log in page.
Because a user was created successfully so does know works and does how you can add async validation.