Knouted we learn a bit about how we can validate user input before handling it.
Let's also work on the user experience side of things because right now when signing up for example
let's say you enter an e-mail address and you enter a password but the passwords don't match or do e-mail
is already taken.
Then we give you that error message which is great but of course all the input is lost and that is a
horrible user experience.
So typically we want to keep the input we want to keep the data the user entered and that is exactly
what I want to work on next.
Keeping that data around.
Now how can we do that.
Well we're dead Let's go to these controller actions where we do handle sign up and sign in.
And let's maybe start with signing users in there we do return this page when we enter incorrect data.
And we sent that status quo error message.
By the way we should of course also do that for logging in.
Now that I see that I forgot debt status 422 should be adhered to.
But in the end what matters here is that we render dead view and we include the error message.
But of course to keep the data the user entered we should send this data back as well.
So what we can do here is we can send maybe old input Kia whatever you want.
And that could be an object and does object could keep it could hold to email and to password.
So I have two key value pairs here where I essentially store the email and the password which I retrieved
from the incoming request and I sent that back to the page we render when we render it.
Due to this error so that I can render it on the page and output it there.
Because what this allows me to do is I can now go to my Sign-Up page and by the way I should also output
confirm passport which you can retrieve from request body.
Confirm password here and the sign up route.
So does a number of fields that we enter so we should return it.
And now when we have the invalid input we get these values back in our view.
And so now if I go to my Sign-Up E.J. s file we can basically output the data there.
So for example for the e-mail input we can add the value attribute which HVM supports and we can output
our data there so we can use as Ejaz syntax to pre populate this with some data and data here would
be old input.
Daut email if we do that we save everything and I reload the sign up page
I get an error though and resisted when I was a disk for the first time from my get sign up action I
don't rendered the old input.
So here when I rendered the sign up page I don't have old input.
So what I should do in their stead is dear.
We can also pass our data out with email being equal to an empty string.
The same for password and for confirm password so that I enter empty values for these fields when we
get loaded for the first time and I enter the old input for the case that we have that validation error.
And with that if I now reload Sign-Up this works and if I now do enter something here which is incorrect
for some reason then you see that it's kept the old e-mail because we returned that with their response
and we Denne output it in our view.
And of course we should do the same for a password and confirm password so your password I output all
input data password and four confirmed password.
It is old and would not confirm password.
So outputting that fruit Ejay as syntax and therefore Now when I enter something invalid again.
Now we still get that error message but we kept our old data which is a much better user experience
of course.