We're now able to keep the old user data and as you see it was relatively easy using that value we attribute
and ensuring that we simply return the input the user entered.
Now you can also do even more on your front side.
For example you could give these invalid inputs a red border that is also something you often see that
you just have to keep in mind that you have to use that information which you're getting to pass it
to your view and then render something different based on that information.
So in our case for example in the Sign-Up road we do have our errors array here right here where I output
my error array and that errors A contains all the problematic fields.
Now we then return an error message based on that array.
But of course we could pass another key here validation error or whatever name you want.
And that could be just arus aere.
So the full array is now returned as well.
In my render function so non-return not just a first message which I picked to show but also the full
array of errors.
Now as always this means that I should go to my Iver's scenario get sign up and also rendered it.
So validation errors here would be an empty array because I got no errors.
And now we know it's an empty array.
If we load that page without errors or we have an array of inputs that do have real problems.
So how can we now benefit from that array of errors.
Well we can go back to our Front-End and there we could change the styling off that input based on the
existence of an error or for that input.
Now how can we do that.
Well let me structured is over multiple lines to make it a bit easier to read.
And then here on this input we could assign a conditional C-s as clause that sets invalid styling.
So we could add classier.
And now we use Ejay as syntax to output something there.
And what I want to output here is that I check my validation errors which is that array of errors which
I just talked about and there I tried to find which is a built in javascript method we can call on arrays.
I tried to find an error where error or
param is equal to email.
Keep in mind this these are the error objects in that array.
They do have a pair in the field which holds the name of the problematic input.
So here I'm trying to find an error for the email input because I'm on the email input here in my team
code.
Now this will ever return.
I'm the find or Nahlah if I don't find it or it will give me that entry I'm looking for.
So I can check if that is not false ish.
So if it is not undefined or anything like that then I want to add invalid as a class here.
ABA wise I will not add anything.
So just an empty string because that should be text that is added as a C as is class.
Now that I should get that invalid class on my input when I do have an error or for email control.
Now to see something I'll go to my a public folder real quick to see s s and their to forms C S S and
in there let me now add the invalid class which is a class at just defined in my template.
And let's give it a border color of a.
Now due to the way C is s works I should also be more precise here and say if a form control input has
to KLOS in so this C is as selector.
Let me save it and let me sign it again.
And now we see this red border because if we inspect this element we see that indeed the invalid C is
as class was added and now that is a pattern which you of course can repeat in our view.
We can go where we can take that logic here for adding a class we can add that to any input.
Obviously not just to the email.
So here I'll do it for my password and I'll simply check for the password control here.
And of course you could find other ways of implementing this.
Just one example.
But it is an example of where we would now also marked a password read if it is invalid.
And the same for a confirmed password of course there we can also simply restructure dad for readability
reasons for nothing else than that and then simply add this CSA is classier based on the Confirm password
field.
And how has that changed.
If I had sign up here these are all red.
The password is not because it's actually valid.
If I would enter a two short one they're all red.
And now this is another way of enhancing the user experience.
Now feel free to play around with that and find your own solutions.
See what else you can do.
I just want to give you the ideas on how you can utilize that information.
The server side validation package gives you and of course you all see how you can pass that information
to your front and.