So we've worked in the user experience.
Now that's all the work on the user experience of logging in because right now if a log in.
Well I don't get any highlights here and if I do log in like this and my hazard has to be valid then
my old data is lost.
Now of course this is a great challenge for you.
So if you're free to posti video and tribes on your own you have to basically do what we did before
though there is a little extra twist which is all to show you of course.
So here's your chance to pause to video.
We'll do it together dear ofter very successful.
Now let's try this together and we start in the off controller.
But now in post log in of course because that is up there where we do Gabr validation results for the
log in screen.
Now if I render responds with this error code which you don't have to set as you saw but which is a
good practice to set to be very clear about what went wrong.
If you do all that then of course you can also pass some old input on this route here.
So old input here would contain e-mail which we extract up here there.
And of course the password which we extract and pass that in a key is named email and password.
Back to you.
You can also set your validation errors if you want and set that to errors array like this.
Basically as we did it for the Sign-Up Rod there's just one difference.
We also have some errors that stem from us entering invalid e-mail or password.
So basically when we try to log a user in for which we don't have the database or word a password does
not match.
Now in such cases since I don't use my validation logic here and since I redirect to make sure that
we treat this in a uniform way we should also return our rendering here because in the end we have an
invalid input here as well.
The error message then just is this error message and hence we don't need to flash it anymore so we
can't get rid of that flashing the old input is definitely something you want to keep here as well.
And validation errors.
Well there we have to add some objects with param and that in this case it could be parent email and
parent password if you want to make sure you don't show what exactly led to the error.
But of course you could also just leave that out and kind of only give out that message.
Keep the old values but don't mark any thing as a rat simply to not give away what exactly failed.
If you wanted to do that.
So here I'll just return the error message.
And the old input.
And now I will copy that again and down there where I also redirect with my error message.
Well I basically do it in the same way as up here.
And yes you could refactored this in some way but now with that if we save that we just have to work
a little bit on the log in screen and on the logon screen we of course want to pre populate these fields
with their old values again.
We do this as you saw with the help of Ejay us by using old input email here
and then the same for the password here old email password.
So these two Ifill's setting the value attribute on these two inputs.
That is what we need to do here to return these old or used as old data.
And then the controller would just have to make sure that we set this old data.
We also need to make sure that for the first time we load this with get log in.
We also set
the old input.
In this case here to an object where the email is an empty string and the password is an empty string
and all set validation errors here to an empty array so that we don't get an error regarding disk not
being found when it's first rendered and now over reload this page.
If I go to log in page again this works.
And now if I try to log like this I get an error but the old data is kept.
And now if I enter a valid password but one which is invalid then you see we all keep the old values.
Now we can also add the red borders if we want to why reusing that code from an Sign-Up Ejay us there.
I used that code for setting osseous as class and I do the same on the log in each class page.
So there let me Sblood all these fields up and then at the class here.
Look for email in this case and some on the e-mail input here.
And of course let's do the same for the password down there.
Let's split that at the Clauss and your password is actually correct already.
So now if there is one last check if I do enter just invalid credentials in the sense of no user is
found for this then nothing is marked as read.
But if I enter something invalid like this where the password is too short.
Well then I do give it at the red border and this is the setup I'm using here.
Obviously you can add justice to your requirements.