That we learned a lot about validation and providing a good user experience.
Now sometimes you also want to sanitize user input.
Now what does sanitising mean for one on this validator page.
So the packet which is used behind the scenes you don't just find all these validators you also find
a way lable sanitizers here and there you will see what they do.
For example what you can do is you can ensure that there is no excess whitespace in a string passed
by the user on the left or on the right.
You can normalize the e-mail which means it's converted to lowercase and things like that.
So there are a couple of things you can do to make sure the data you get is not just valid but also
is stored in a uniform way.
So with without extra whitespace or anything like that.
So sanitising inport is all something that makes sense to be done.
Cross-site scripting attacks annotation which is a security feature is by the way is something I'll
cover in the security module this course so you'll focus on the visual sanitization for now not on security
relevant sanitising.
So this is what you can do.
Now how does sanitising in Port work though.
Well you do it in one step with validating.
So in the reality folder and the off-Terra has fallen our example let's say the email here I want to
make sure that it's stored in a normalized way.
So lowercase not starting with the uppercase character no X whitespace.
Well I can do it just by changing a number Meffert offer my validation logic and there I can call normalized
e-mail which is one of these built in sanitizers which I showed you for the password we could trim it.
So here we could trim the password to remove excess whitespace course we can do the same for the sign
up here.
Besides our check here I also want to normalize to email once I'm done with it with sensitise with validating
and for the password I want to trim excess whitespace.
So again this is something which I can do here to sanitize user input and to see the result of that.
Let me actually connect to my database real quick with the help of combis my visual user interface here
and there in the users.
I get a bunch of users because I created some users for this module let me delete a couple of entries
here really quick just to clean this up.
Well actually delete them all.
And now let me create a new user.
Keep in mind I added sanitization.
Now if I enter test at test I'll come like this with an extra blank offered this and I enter my password
here with an extra whitespace at the end so I'll blank at the end.
Then I do already get an error because for signing up I do actually trm my password here but I don't
trim the confirming password.
So should trim does as well.
Otherwise the whitespace is removed here and indeed it is just one character shorter Niva sign up both
passwords were changed and we keep in mind the email started with a capital character and also had extra
whitespace.
If I now reload my users we see the email is stored with a lowercase T at the beginning and without
that extra whitespace at the beginning and this is not simply the case because I sanitized the input
so sanitising data is all something which makes sense to ensure that your data is stored in a uniform
format and well that your email address is look equal and so on.