Now did we learn a lot about validation.
Sanitising input.
Let's practice this one less time for adding a product and for editing it as well and there feel free
to again possed a video and try out some things on your own add your own first validation steps offered
a pause do together of course and you're free to add any validation that you want to add that looks
good to you for the different fields we have here.
Your offer I'll show you my suggestion on how we could validate this.
So here's your chance to post a video
successful.
Well let's try it out.
We get for it.
What's your title image your price and description.
Now what would make sense to be validated here.
And again there is no single true solution here.
You can have different requirements for deep your building.
Now I want to have a title which should be alphanumeric so only normal alphabetic characters and numbers
should at least be let's say free characters long D-Mich. you or else should be valid.
You are l.
The prize should be a floating point number so a number with decimal places and the description your
should also be not alphanumeric.
There should be special characters like the exclamation mark should be allowed but it should be at least
let's say 5 characters long and with that information let's add validation to the Edmund J.S. fall which
is where we have eddys post routes for whip's for adding and for editing for them.
First of all let's import the body or to check function whichever you prefer.
By requiring
express validate or slash.
Check and then let's edit here to add product there.
I'll add an array to group all these mealworms together and then all validate my different inputs.
Step by step.
Let's first of all have a look at the views real fast so there at the added product view and there we
see we got a field named title one named image Eurail one named price and one named description.
So these are the four fields I want to validate.
Title image your price and description.
So back in the admin controller excuse me in the aplan route not the controller in the route.
I'll start with the title.
Now there you're free to add whatever you want.
I will add is alpha numeric as a validator and is length should have a minimum length of 3.
Let's say we can also add some sanitization and trim excess whitespace at the beginning or the end of
the title.
Now this is the title I want to validate.
Now copy this and continue with the image you are l.
However there I will check is u r l.
That is the only thing I want to validate there.
That this is valid.
You are L and that is a number built in validator that checks whether dis fulfills the characteristics
of a u r l.
Then I'll add my validator for the price here.
Now for a price I want to have I could check it is numeric to allow either integer values or floating
point numbers.
But there all this is float to ensure that this has to have some decimal places.
Now I'll add my last days here and that will be on the description and there I just want to trim that
and have a length of at least let's say 8 or 5 characters whatever you want.
You could also add a max of all you of course.
Let's say we have a max of 200 or 400 characters something like that.
No added validation to adding a product are already copy that and edit to edit product here to the post-road
edit product as well.
So dare I edit the exact same fields because we'll be editing the exact same fields there.
So I want to have the same validation emplace.
Now with that in place let's go to the Abin controller and make sure we collect these validation errors
and return them for that.
Well first of all import something from the Express validator by requiring express validators slash
check and there I want to import the validation result function and then post at product here before
we create new product.
I will actually collect all my errors by passing the request to validation result and will then check
if not errors is empty which means we do have errors and in that case if we make it into this if block
I will actually render my edit page.
So here on get edit page I will call this render function you're in the end.
But I'll do that in this if block I just edit.
I'll also set this status code of 422 which is a good practice for indicating to the browser that some
data that was passed was incorrect.
I'll have ADD product as a title
and now if we have a quick look here at added product we see that there we already set the value.
If editing is set to true and then we are put product final product image you are.
Now we can tweak it as a little bit.
I'll still set editing to faults because we still are not editing and I don't want to change anything
else on the page but what I will do is all set my product here equal to an object where I do set the
Thailand's on Tuesdays fields to these inputs which I did fetch so at the title the image your L and
also the price and the description Trudy's fetched inputs so that we can use that old data in the way
we are already using it.
But I'll now add a number field here has error or maybe and I'll set this to true here.
Now that simply means that I should ensure that has error is all set and other places where I render
it as page like here where I set it to false for get at product and for get edit product down there.
I will also set it to false.
So it's only true right now if I'm in the if block of my post at product road here.
Now in my view I can now take advantage of this new has Arrowfield and I can say I want to output the
existing product title if I'm editing or if his error is true.
So that is my alternative condition here to ensure that the old data in this case then is output like
this.
Now of course it would also be nice to display some error message so we can grab that from the logon
page and check for the existence of error message here above my form and output it.
If we have one this just means that again back to my routes and not to my routes to my controller and
the Edmond Chia's file we should have an error message which simply is null by default.
And here in my IF block where I do have validation errors I will set the error message to errors array
the first error which we are guaranteed to have.
And they're DMSO Schieber property property as we did before.
And of course all those that error message here when we get the added page there I set it to null and
now with that if I hit add product to your I get invalid value because I set no custom errors.
But it did to be rendered this never entered first book here then kept the I ad at product it still
gives me that old message of invalid value because I never set my own one.
You could of course do that with the techniques as showed.
We also have no red borders because we didn't at that logic yet but it is reloading the page it's not
submitting the request and it's keeping all the data which we did input.
Right so this is not thrown away and that is of course worth a lot.
We can of course also edit products and for this.
Let me quickly add a valid product.
This also allows us to test whether this works
and it looks like it failed but actually if we go back we see we get double headers sent error which
is stemming from my Edman controller I should return is otherwise after sending this error response
that we continue with the rest of our code which I don't want to.
If I had ADD product here.
This still fails though.
The interesting thing is if I go back to my product's collection first book was added before though
while that was added because I did not return in case of an error as I'm doing now.
So now the returning works but still I get this invalid value.
And if you want to find out for what I get it I can log errors array here so that we can have a look
into this Aeros object if I add this again no it fails of course we see it's the title the title failed
somehow the title somehow is valid in a way that tells us that it does not fulfill our criteria.
And the title for adding a product should be alphanumeric have to length and be trimmed.
Now the thing is my alphanumeric check the whitespace here is NEVER alphabetic character nor a number.
So maybe we should just check if it is a valid string because that will allow whitespace as well.
And now if I had ADD product now this succeeded and it did add it therefore And I've got two first books
here.
Let me delete this real quick.
Now if I try adding this again though maybe a second book
it does work.
And now it also shows that image correctly so seems to have been a bug.
So this is now working now we added validation for adding this.
And how is it for editing FedExed animation mark here.
This is except that we see the exclamation mark up there.
And if I now enter something incorrect like the price is missing Well then this seems to break it doesn't
continue.
And indeed I do have an error down there.
Which makes a lot of sense because what didn't we do yet.
Well we didn't at our error collecting an error returning to the editor's note.
We only worked on and thus far post ad product.
So the next video will take care that for editing a product we also get validation errors instead of
a broken app.
When we do submit invalid values.