So let's now make sure that when we added a product we don't break our app as we're currently doing
it.
If we enter something wrong but that we instead simply validate the input.
Well we are validating it already because I do have all my validators added on the Edit product route
and the routes folder but any control or action that belongs to that we should also repeat the code
from adding a product.
So all that code where I fetched the arrows and then check for the existence of arrows we should grab
that and add it to post edit product as well.
And there before we start doing anything.
So before we find a product before we do that I will actually use my validation errors if we got any.
And then pre-rendered a page with the title of edit product editing set to true because we are still
in editing mode.
But has a are all set to True and the product data populated like this with the values the user entered.
And with that if we save that that's all we have to do because we're reusing the same view we use before.
So we already got everything we need for outputting the arrows.
And now if I do leave out that price field I get a title is not defined.
Yeah.
Here when I try to set the date on which I return here in this post edit product actions it's all named
updated title updated price.
So we should be using that.
So let's use updated title here updated prize updated image your L and down there it's update desk.
So this was all a mistake on my site.
These values which I extracted were named differently.
Now after renaming that if I try to submit this again now I simply get invalid value again.
You could override that default message in the way I showed it earlier in this module.
We all see that our image your L was lost.
Yeah but simply because I assigned to incorrectly I assigned the price to the image you are l and the
other way and the other way around.
We should of course do it this way.
And now if I update this now all the data is kept and I still get this error.
So now we get this validation in place too.
Now one thing we can do of course we can again set dead red border by repeating dat same way we did
in the log in or in the sign of pages we get our clocks here we conditionally add a C S S class and
we do the same and added product.
So therefore this input
I do at my class when there is an hour for to title input the same of course for the image you are l
and all the other inputs so that does not change here for the image you are el.
I do get to see us as Clauss here if we do have an error on the image you are el.
Let's do the same for the price of course.
Real quick.
Split up what we get thus far.
And let's here check the price to see whether we at this invalid see us as close to a text area it's
exactly the same.
We just need to do one little change to our C-s s code because here I'm checking for description and
Sodhi invalid class might be added to that text area thus far in my CSSA code in the forms see is as
follows.
I only add or change the text color if invalid was added to the input.
Now we should simply group a number of selectors at a number selector to that group.
And simply check whether in Validus added either to an input or two in text area.
And in both cases give it a red colored border and with that in place we now just have to make sure
that we pass these validation errors which we are checking and added product now that we passed that
with our responses.
So in the admin controller starting with get add product there are validation errors should be an empty
array because we got no validation Arison this place for a post at product However here we should have
validation errors which is equal to arus array.
So does Aeros which we did fetch for gueth edit product.
There again I will pass validation errors as an empty array because we have no errors here when we just
get the page.
But for a post edit product when we do return our error page basically then I want to set validation
arrows back to errors array like this.
And now we do pass that data.
So for now update here you see this is read only interesting pieces the title is read as well.
Well that makes sense because here I still have something in my validation set up in the routes folder
here alphanumeric.
We did remove dead if you remember because it should be is string otherwise to whitespace to blank is
not allowed.
So if I change that and I had update now I actually fail and do fail.
Because the cost to object id failed for that value.
Now what's wrong here.
Well keep in mind for editing we need that hidden input where I do have my product ID right.
And I do load that product ID when I first render this page.
But if I re rendered it due to a validation error or so due to this render function in my IF check here.
Well then I only said title image price and description.
I also need to set underscore ID though otherwise it will render the page.
But if I try to submit it that ID will be missing and I need that ID because I extract it here.
So what I should do is I should simply pass underscore ID here and set this equal to fraud ID which
I am extracting when this is submitted the first time.
So now I'm passing underscore ID.
And this means that if I now go to admen products editors and let's say I changed the price.
Works.
But now let's also do something that breaks validation.
So now this was reloaded due to our failing validation.
And now if I added this it will still work because now we all did store and re render that product ID
and that is how we can add validation and provide a relatively good user experience.