You'll learn about a brand new type of back in the application you can build with no as a restful API
and you'll learn that it's not that far off from the server side rendered no application we built before.
The only major difference is how you handle requests and response data.
You send Jason data now with that out of the way.
I want to dive into something totally different which is applicable to any node application not just
to restfully your eyes.
I want to dive into the async a wait keywords which is relatively new javascript language feature which
you can use again in any place in your node.
J.S. code this does not have to be used in a restful API you can or can not use it anywhere.
Now I will explain what's up with these two key words how you used them and why you would use them.