So what is a sink a weight all about a sink and a weight are two key words which are part of the core
javascript language.
They're not an exclusive part of the no js runtime.
They are also available in modern browsers or in Front-End projects.
They're not part of no Jasp but you can use them in notorious projects.
The question of course is what do these two keywords do.
A single away it allows you to write asynchronous requests so requests where you have some operation
that takes a little while and comes back later in a synchronous way and you see there is an asterisk
off Duras synchronous way because async in a way it allows you to write asynchronous statements in a
way that looks synchronous but it still isn't a synchronous request.
Now this is of course very abstract.
So let's simply dive into our existing notorious code.
And let me show you which parts of it you could change to use async going to wait and then it will become
very clear what it does.
I'm back in my note.
J.S. back end application year.
And let me point out that as I mentioned you could all use a single weight in you react application
but this is no re-act course.
So I will leave this code untouched and we'll go back to my node application.
Now how can we use a sync.
And the weight.
Well if you go into your feed controller you'll see that there we have an asynchronous operation post
find how can you see or how can you identify asynchronous operations.
Well for example when you're using.
Promises Promises are a typical construct that help you deal with a synchronous code because promises
were like that post find gets executed and count documents all that gets executed immediately.
But then does actually count documents returns a promise or a promise like object and you don't use
then to define a function that should be executed.
Once this operation here is done and since we access the database here does typically takes a bit longer.
We're talking about milli seconds here.
But still it doesn't happen instantly.
All the opposite this line and does line get executed after each other instantly does operation does
essentially not take any time at all it's so fast.
Javascript can wait for it to complete and move onto the next step right away here.
It will not wait for that to complete.
And that is why after this statement javascript would actually move on with the next statement in line.
So if we had a statement on the same level as Post find we would continue with that.
Now in this case we got on but if we would have some code there like a console log or anything this
would execute right away probably or very likely before this or this code or this code was executed.
The reason for that is that with then we define code snippets or we define functions that should run
in the future.
Once it is longer taking a synchronous operation is done and it's called asynchronous because it doesn't
happen instantly but it takes a little while callbacks which we used earlier and of course are a number
way of working with asynchronous code.
So here are two four account documents.
You could actually and you'll see that your and the documentation that pops up you could define a callback
function.
So here you could define a function that gets executed once it's done instead of then.
And we don't use callbacks because in there.
We want to use that code and then we would need a call by each year in the Find function and we would
nest all these callbacks leading to very unreadable code.
That is why you often prefer promises even though you could do it with callbacks because there you have
one then block after each other and it's very readable.
Still it can get more readable with a sink in a way.
And that is what I want to show you in the next lecture.