Snotted we had a brief look at how asynchronous code can be identified and what is important about asynchronous
code and that you can use callbacks and promise us to handle asynchronous code knouted we learn all
that.
Let me introduce you to async a wait to use that you first of all have to prepare and the async keyword
in front of a function like this arrow function here.
So this function where you plan to use a wait keyword.
So where you want to use these two key words they always are used together async in front of the function
and then you can tweak this syntax.
You can write this syntax almost as if it would run synchronously.
You can get your count a new constant or variable you create by a waiting post.
Find count documents and then you would get rid of this then block here.
You would instead continue here where you directly store your total items here to be precise.
You can get rid of this line now and you get rid of this return statement.
Instead you continue with the next line.
Most find limit.
This gives you back a list of posts.
So what you currently have in that then block and you again write it like this.
Posts a weight Post find and then this whole statement that in the end would be followed by a then block.
Now get rid of the then locked like this.
Let's comment out.
Catch because that is something we'll care about in a second.
And now as a reformer this does our adjusted code or does this using a single weight.
It does now looks like the normal javascript code right but behind the scenes a sync a way it takes
your code and transforms it into the old Then like structure we used.
So it uses then behind the scenes we just can't see it.
And we have this more convenient way of writing our asynchronous code.
Now I haven't used this discourse thus far because I think that if you're relatively new to javascript
or note this can quickly lead you to think that this works just like the Agricole lags and that doesn't
always keep in mind a weight just does some behind the scenes transformation of your code.
It takes your code and adds then ofter it gets the result of that operation and then stores it in total
items and then moves onto the next line executes that inside of that then block it creates here implicitly.
So basically the exact same code we had before this is done by a single weight behind the scenes.
But if you know if you understand this then this can be a syntax you might prefer.
You don't have to.
You can absolutely use the other one with them and catch but you might prefer this one.
Now back to kaching.
How do we handle errors now.
Well since this now runs almost like asynchronous code we use try and catch.
So we try something we try some code this code here to be precise and we then catch an error or
like this which we then handle in there with the code we previously had instead of catch flies this
therefore you still have to.
Next and the error here because keep in mind behind the scenes this gets converted to then and catch
us.
We used it before but now with that we have transformed this first snippet where we used promises to
sync a weight and we can see that if I now saved it and I go back to my running application let me quickly
log in and open the developer tools to see if we get any errors.
And I currently got no so quickly create one test post.
We'll take that duck again.
This is just a test.
Let me add except here and it looks good.
Now if I refresh.
We definitely fetched a post.
And this still works.
So all that code still works.
We also get no error here on the back end.
And now we transform to a single weight.