So we are using async await everywhere now.
And there's one important thing I want to highlight here for all these Mangu is operations which is
the primary thing where we use a single weight you have to understand that Mangu is actually with operations
like Count documents or find does not return a real promise but a promise like object where you can
use then and catch and also a sick wait that is supported by mongooses even though behind the scenes
it's not a real promise.
Doesn't matter too much for you to be honest because you use a sink and a weight and exactly the same
way you would use it on a real promise.
But I also don't want to hide that fact from you.
You could use a real promise by changing access.
After all these mongooses operations software find ofter count documents.
If you do that then you get back a real promise.
We don't need that year because while that promise like object behaves in exactly the way we want you
do have the real promise with the beach trip library though when we have our password here we get a
real promise.
And as you can see well you'll see nothing you see no difference in the way we use a wait.
And you also had no difference.
You previously used then and catch.
So that is what I mean you don't need to care too much about that.
I still did want to mention it.
More importantly I want you to take away that a single weight is a nice alternative to using it then
and catch it's not better it's not faster.
Behind the scenes it's basically the same code.
It can be more readable to you but you must never forget that this still are asynchronous steps.
The javascript code execution behavior doesn't change because of that.
It does not block execution.
It simply wraps all the code off-Terra in a wait statement in the Zenn block.
You would have to write otherwise.
So this runs inside of the implicit then block.
This statement creates.
This is how you have to think about that.
So never forget the Ds are asynchronous operations because that is really important to understand.
And you can absolutely go with the then and catch lock were used before.
So with the old promise style if you prefer it I like it for teaching because it's clearer that we have
some operation to to wait for and that the line offered that would execute first here does is less clear.
But if you are aware of how async code works this can simply be a nicer syntax to look at and it's up
to you which syntax you'll use for the rest of the course.
I'll write new promises or I'll stick to that.
In a way it's index for my node application for do you react application.
I'll leave the code as it is with then and catch.
You could use azing in a way there too.
But again this is no re-act course so I will leave it there as it is for node will go with async await.