So nodded We added our fall pick.
Let's work on the back end.
And for that I'll go to my Edmon controller which is where I do handle the creation of products.
Also the editing of products which will work on later but for now let's focus on adding a product.
And here we are extracting data from the incoming requests.
Now I renamed my file picker here to image.
So the input name is now just image and this means that here when I try to retrieve it from the body
I should also target the image like this or we can keep this name because it will fail anyways if I
now submit this like debt and click add product I get invalid value here.
And the image you are Dazs fail because I do have my routes and the app and routes I do have some validation
place where I say D-Mich. your L should be a U or l.
And clearly it is not so let's remove that validator for the host at product route and let's try this
again.
And now we simply get an error.
So the error handling is working and the error we're getting is simply stemming from the fact that we're
not able to extract our image correctly.
I can show this to you if I console log image you are all here in post ad product and this controller
action and I tried to submit this then you don't see anything here.
It fails to log anything there because we failed to extract that image from the request body.
And why is that.
Because keep in mind you'll learn it is a little bit early in this course for extracting the content
off our incoming requests.
We set up a middleware in app Japs were using a special middleware this body parser middleware and this
middleware uses or expose's a couple of different parsers and we're using the you are encoded parser.
Now you are at encoded data is basically text data.
So if a form is submitted without a file.
So just with text fields no matter if that text field then stores a number a u r l or line text but
it's all encoded in text when it is submitted.
This format is called You are encoded.
And actually we can see that if we open the developer tools and go to the Network tab in there if I
do click submit here this failing requests at product request.
If we have a look at our request headers we can see that the content type is application and then SWW
W4 you are encoded.
And this basically means it tries to put all the data as text into its foreign body.
We can see that down there just for data tidal price and so on.
And just image does is invalid.
This is basically an empty text because it can't extract our file as text because a file is binary data.
Now because of that because of that failing extraction we need to work with this different.
We need to parse our data differently and the body parts that we're using here does not give us any
parser it does not include any parser that could handle file data as well.
We need a new package for that.
So let me quit that server and let's install a new package with NPM installed dash dash save and the
name of that package is Mulder.
Mulcher is a number third party package that parses incoming requests.
But this package parses incoming requests for files.
So it is able to handle file requests as well or requests with mixed data with text and file data.
We'll still keep body parser because we still have like for example our sign up form where we only submit
you are Ellen coded data but now we'll have to use a different encoding and that starts with our form.
So back in the view the added product you there I'll change my formula a little bit.
Besides to class and action here I'll also add a new field.
That's the Anke type field which all set to multipart form data application X W W O W form you are eling
coded as to default.
But now we'll switch to multipart form data which is simply the content type telling the server that
does submission to this request will not contain plain text but will contain mixed data text and binary
data and Mulder the package we just installed will be looking for incoming requests.
With this type of data and will then be able to parse both the text and our file.
So does this what we get there or what we will need.
And now with all that prepared let's use Mulder in the next lecture.