So let's use mulcher now on our back and we can restart the server already because we installed that
package.
And now let's go to our admen controller and let's work on post at product here.
We want to use Malteser to extract incoming files now Mulder is actually not a package which we will
use in here instead just like the body parts that we use here.
Mulder is some middleware which we execute on every incoming request and then simply has a look at that
request.
CS if it's multipart form data and tries to extract files if that is the case.
So it is some extra middleware we add.
And therefore we can import a tear in our Apicius file.
We can import mulcher by requiring it from the package like this.
Walter and thereafter we can use it.
So maybe after the body parser we can use mulcher.
Mulder has to be executed as a function and then we have to call another method on that.
And that simply defines if you expect to get multiple files or only one file and we will only expect
one file.
So we use a single method.
And then we define the input name which will hold Dhaval in our case that is a match.
And this is not a random value.
I'm using image here because in my view this input which holds the file so does file picture here is
named image as well.
So with that we initialize Mulder.
And let's now see if that works.
Now to see that we need to know how multiple actually store the incoming file and for that let me go
back to post ad product and instead of extracting request body image let me x' a request file here and
let's see what this gives us.
I will also console Lauck image you are now.
Now let's save all that and see what that gives us.
If I now try to add a product again I'll choose that same file from before enter any values up here
like at product.
And I still get an error.
Now if we go back we see something interesting though indeed here.
This part is what I lock here.
So what we see is that Malteser seems to have done something.
It seems to have stored something in that file property on our request object.
And that is what we print here essentially and it's stored the name of the field where it extract that
that it detected the file name it detect that the MIME type.
So which type of file that is.
And that buffer here is essentially how node handles the binary data.
You'll learn about streams and buffers earlier in the end.
Does this deal resolve off the streambed data file basically was sent to our server as a stream or was
handled as a stream to handle it efficiently if it was bigger and then does this collected data in a
buffer which as we learned is like a bus stop.
It gives you a way of working with the stream data here in this case it's the combined streams and data
and we could indeed work with that buffer to turn it into a file.
Now you can actually configure Mulder a bit differently.
We go back to objects when we set up mulcher we can pass an object to the malware function and then
we can set some options.
And one option is the best option.
Now here we could specify slash images or just images like this.
What this will do is that when I again add a product here and don't worry that it still fails because
we're trying to store to follow the database right now and we'll do all kinds of stuff with it for which
our code is not prepared but the upload works.
But with this option set you also see that the output down there change a little bit.
We don't have the buffer because now Mulder is able to do something with the buffer instead of just
buffering it all in memory.
It can then turn that buffer back into binary data you could say and it stores it in this Poth year.
So indeed if you have a look at your folder you should not have images folder with some file in there
now that file has some random hash name does not have a file extension and is not recognized as a.
But indeed if I changed it and I at PNC at the end does this DMA app loaded.
So this does work.
All we now need to do is we need to tweak the way this file is named and that is something we'll do
in the next lecture.