We added Mulder and as you can see Mulder is able to accept our incoming data extract the files and
stored them for us and then store information about the file upload in his request file object here
which we output which in the end contains this data.
Now all we have to do is we have to ensure that our data gets stored correctly.
And for that we specify the destination folder.
But we can do more.
We can set the storage keyer which gives us way more configuration options than just the d'Este option.
Now for that to configure a storage here I will actually set up a new configuration object maybe up
there.
File storage name is up to you.
It's a constant.
And the value will be something I get from the mulcher package there.
It's the disk storage function disk storage is in the end a storage engine which you can use with milter
and there you can pass a javascript object to configure it.
It takes two keys it takes a destination and it takes the file name.
These are two functions which Mulder will do and call for an incoming file.
And these functions then control how that follows handled regarding the place where you store it.
And regarding the naming So destination day four is a function we can make the arrow function which
will be called by Mulder which receives the request object to file object and a callback which you have
to call once you're done setting up the destination.
So this is all to interact with Mulder.
So in there you can for example call the call back with Knol as the first argument.
That would be an error message you Frot to inform haltered that something is wrong with the incoming
file and it should not store it.
But if that is null you tell Mulder that it's OK to store it and then the second argument is the place
where you do want to store it like that images folder.
Now file name also is a function.
So it's also an arrow function where we all received the request object some data about the file and
a callback which we have to call to let mulcher know how to name it and there we can also call this
with NULL to still inform Mulder.
OK we're fine story please.
And then the second argument is the file name which we want to use.
And here we could name it image.
But of course that would be a bit boring.
Instead we can extract file and then there is the original name object which holds the original file
name.
There also is a file name object which holds this random hash.
And what we can do here is we can of course combined as we can for example say I want to ensure dead
if we have two images with the same name they don't overwrite each other.
So we'll use that file name which is auto generated by Mulder.
And then I'll concatenate it maybe with a dash in between with the original name with dad.
I also insured that it and with that extension and now I set my own name here by calling that callback.
Now we just need to inform haltered that we want to use it as storage engine and we do this by setting
this as a value for the storage key into multiple options.
Now with that if I go back and I added my product again.
So the same input boat and she's elected.
You will see that in those images folder you have undefined boat Bianchini.
Now it's simply undefined here.
Instead of that random hash because since we did set our own filename with this function your multitude
does not generate that hash.
But all we can do for example is we can use the current date.
So new data to ises string gives us a snapshot of the current date and that should also ensure uniqueness.
If you need more you can use some third party package that does give you a really unique hash.
But with this we're now storing files with the right extension and a unique name.
And this gives us more power because now we can control the Poth and the filename.
And of course we can also use that for even more because maybe we want to validate that we only support
certain MIME types.
Let's say P And she's and K-Pax but not gifts or PDA apps.
Let's do that in the next lecture.