Now we added our Mulder configuration to rename our file and to control the storage place in detail.
Now we can also add a filter to mulcher to only allow certain kinds of files.
And for that 2D object when we configure Mulder I can add the file filter function here.
Now I'll again create a separate Konst up there to make it easier to read file filter will simply be
a function.
I'll use an arrow function near where I get the request.
Some follow data and a callback which I have to call and in there we should call the call back with
NULL as an error and true Drew if you want to accept Dead Files if it should be stored or false if we
don't want to store that file.
Now how can we determine whether we want to store it.
Well we can write any logic we want here.
And I would check if the file MIME type is equal to an image slash PMG or if to follow MIME type is
equal to image jpeg or if the file MIME type is equal to image J packed with an e.
If any of that is True's if I have a file which is of that type then I will accept that some will call
the callback with true as a second value.
Otherwise I'll call the call with Falls as a second value which means I'll not accept that file.
And now we can use that file filter and pass it as a value for fall filter in our options here.
And we have dead set up.
We got some logic here that should filter out invalid files.
So if I go back no and I submit a form here with let's say my boat pinchy I succeed here will I get
an error here but I succeed because it stores to fall.
But if I try to submit a different value let's say I'll pick a PTF year.
You can use any pedia of any non image file down you see I only get undefined here and that undefined
is stemming from my admen control or from this line.
So then monitor did not store anything.
And that is how we can filter out files.
Now I will remove all these files up there and I'll also clean up my database soon because right now
we're not storing the data appropriately.
And that is the next step we should do of course.