So I'll just quickly clean up all my products here because they're all stored in an incorrect way due
to well how it worked with the files in the past.
Let me remove all these products and now let me go back and here in my application and post at products
in my admen controller there I now want to handle that follow correctly.
So first of all image year will be an object of this format with information about the file and where
it was stored.
So where the physical file can be found and now it wants to save that.
First of all I would check if image is set because if it's undefined then that means that Mulder declined
to incoming fall.
So if this is not said if it is undefined Well then I want to return a response with statis 422 because
I then have an invalid input so I want to return that response.
At product editing fault has errors.
True.
Where I pass in my old data not the file or only title price and description and the error message is
attached file is not an image let's say.
And validation arrows can be an empty array.
I won't mark anything as read with this change in place.
We can already validate this.
If I now try to upload an image I succeed.
So I don't get my same form again if she was a PBF though then I get attached falls and all that image.
So this is we're rigging and that's now all the work on the case that we do have an image and we want
to store it.
Now the file already gets stored on our file system.
And this is how you should store it.
You should not store data like this in the database files should not be stored in a database.
They are too big.
It's too inefficient to store them in a database and carry them from their store files on a file system
as we are doing it here.
But of course you need to store something in a database.
You need to store the path to the file.
Right.
And data is something you can construct here with the information given to you and the file object and
you can then simply pass that data to the database.
So if we made it after our entire validation year I know did I have a valid file and valid input data
and then all create my image.
You are again and in that image you are l.
I will use my image data which is that file object we get from Mulder.
And there we have information like the file path.
And it's this path that is interesting to me of course because it is the a file on my operating system.
It is Spaf idea for one to use later on when fetching that image.
So does pop is what I'll store here in the image you are l and therefore I can store image.
You are all in the database again.
So if we now save all of that and I do select a valid image here and I hit add product this now works
again.
Display it does not work will work on this in a second but saving does work.
If I have a look into my database for the products you see does is the part that was stored.
Now this is looking good.
But of course here if we inspect this we see D-Mich. is not really rendered because it can't find this.
It fails to fetch images and then well this name and the Network tab we indeed find a 404 error when
the browser sends the request for this image.
So now we are able to store data.
Let's also learn how we can surf data well almost before we serve it.
Let's work on editing this because this is a number parred which won't work correctly right now.
Right now when we load the ad page what we do is we load the page and we sent back the data we need
for displaying it of course.
So that means we rendered the added product page with product data that includes our image u r l which
is of course fine but ultimately here we don't see the Eurail and we don't want to change d you r l
when editing the product instead.
Here we have a new file picker.
Now you can of course configure this to work in any way you want.
But here I want to have a behavior where if we choose no file here we simply keep the old one and we
only overwrite it with a new file.
If I do choose and you want here so to do that I'll go to post edit product which is where we do handle
incoming data.
And of course here we again can retrieve request file and stored at an image constant Just as I'm doing
it here and when we add the product there I'm also retrieving this file extract that by Mulder.
Mulder will do the same for post edit product so I can extract that there to store it in image.
And now this image is the thing I need to check if it is on the find.
Then I know no file was saved.
And in this case this means I want to keep the old file by the way the same will be true if I upload
a PDA.
I will simply keep the old image.
In that case.
So we don't need to throw an error or return an error message.
Though you could of course do that if you want.
If you always want to force a new image.
But here what I'll do is instead all.
First of all added my validation page which I return and I'll not return D-Mich. you are all here.
We don't need that.
Just as in poll post ad product there we also don't need to return it because there is no in which you
are.
We render in our edit page any more.
But if we make it past our revalidation year when we store the product or when we update the product
I should say this image your L does not exist anymore.
Instead here I want to see if I really need to set that.
So I'll check if a match is there if it's not undefined in which case I'll set product image.
You are able to image path so the same logic as I do have it in post at product there.
I also said image you are all too much lbf but in post edit product I do it conditionally and if the
image is undefined so if no new image was passed I simply don't set it on the object which had an update
and since I updated.
And if I don't set this I will simply will not update this field and I can't prove this to you.
If I can update this product here now I get an invalid value because I forgot to adjust my validation
loop in the route's folder for editing the product.
I'm still checking for image you are EL-TIBI you are l but this field does not exist anymore so we should
remove that from the edit product route validation logic and now the submit is again.
It just works.
If I now choose a different image doh and before a select does let me quickly show if I update my database
here you'll see that image your l did not change.
If I select both to now which is the same image but a different file name and technically a different
file therefore I update this.
And now if we go to that database and we refresh we see it set boat 2.
So now we got that editing option in place too.
And now we do handle the file uploads in the way we need to handle them.
But of course handling file uploads is only one thing.
We also want to be able to see that image.
So to download it kind of and that is what I focus on in the next ELECTRESS.