So how can we ensure that all our beautiful images are also served to the client that they are downloaded.
We've got multiple options for serving files and I will walk you through all of them now.
Option number one which you would typically use for a scenario like this where you have files that are
publicly available to everyone.
Like our product images is that we simply serve our images folder in a static way.
What does this mean.
This means you go to app chase and there we already are static serving a folder we are serving the public
folder with the express static middleware.
Now we can serve more than one folder statically and remember statically serving a folder simply means
that requests to files in that folder will be handled automatically and the files will be returned.
So all the heavy lifting is done behind the scenes by express then I can duplicate this middleware and
now also serve the images folder just like this.
And with this little change if I save that and the server and therefore restarts if we reload this page
we still fail.
Well if we inspect that failing request we see that it tried to get the image from admen slash images.
The reason for that is that I'm on the admin route here.
Admin products to be precise.
So it's only replacing the last part of my path with that image.
Eurail the solution for that is pretty straightforward.
In our view products Aegis where a do show my image we suddenly need to add a slash at the beginning
which will turn this into an absolute Poth.
So it will not appended to the current pov but driver create a new POV with only our domain and then
the POV which gets rendered here and I DUDAS and products.
And of course also on my shop page.
So on index Ejaz.
So basically everywhere where I do render an image I add a slash at the beginning.
The alternative would be to store that lbf in a database with a slash at the beginning of course might
have been easier.
But I want to show you both ways.
So here I'll added in my views also here in the product list Ejaz fall
like this and all the product detail follow of course.
There we all have an image.
If we change all of that and I now reload this page I still fail and not a reason for that is something
different.
The reason for that is that the POF now is correct but my image is here in the images folder are served
incorrectly in Aperture diasporas set up this static Miller.
Keep in mind what I taught you earlier in this course we basically point to a folder there like public
images and we then tell express surfed of files from inside that folder as if they were on the root
folder.
So we would see that image if we go there and we see the POF under which it try to find it.
If we open that in and you tap we can find it of course but we will see it if I remove images there.
And the reason for that is that express assumes that the files in the images folder are served as if
they were in the root folder.
So slash nothing.
Of course we want to keep them in the images folder and keep the POF like this.
And for this we can simply adjust our middleware here and say if we have a request that goes to slash
images that starts with Slash images then serve these files statically and now slash images into a folder
we assume for this static serving.
And now with that if we save that and we reload we see our image here.
So now we got that working and now we got a static way of serving our files and that is a great way
off serving the.
Now I want to do something different though.
I want to add this to the cart ordered it so that I have an order and I want to download an invoice
for that order and that will now work differently because invoices will not be public fault's that everyone
should be able to access.
I want to be able to access my wise.
But no one else should be.
So let's focus on this in the next lectures.