So serving images statically is fine but we don't want to serve only images or only public files.
I want to serve an invoice and that unwise should only be available to me.
Now for that let's start with a dummy in was and I'll create a new folder for that.
All Nemat invoices.
You could of course put all motors and invoices ends on into a parent folder like data to not have them
all as root level folders.
That might be something you want to do on move the invoices and their images is kind of like a special
case but my private data should be maybe somewhere else.
So I'll put it into the data folder which was redundant until now.
Now it's not anymore.
And I prepared a simple PTF which I'll move in there.
Now this is a really simple PDA.
You can write it on your own.
It's just holding some text looking like this.
So here is my NYS that has to be diethyl I'm serving now.
Later we'll also generate this dynamically.
Now we won't.
Now I just want to show you how to surf it.
Now obviously we could make our in folder here statically accessible but that's not what I want to do.
Now first of all let me work on the orders view to make sure we have a link to get that invoice.
So for each order this list item here which we have let's maybe add a dash and a list item and in there
let's add an anchor TAC which says invoice and then it should be pointing at the invoice.
So now if we reload this page we have in Y's here as a link.
Now I want to be able to click this and download the invoice.
How can we do that.
Well since I want to handle this privately I need to set up my own route for working within Wise's because
that will then allow me to check for things like user authenticated and so on.
So let me go to the route's folder and in there under.
Shop because it is a customer feature not admin related under shop here I'll add a new route.
Orders.
And then maybe NYS ID or order Id maybe because deep in ways that say we'll have a name of that order
idea.
Ultimately
we could name does fall differently we can name it invoice and then let me quickly up look up my order
ID to make this all work correctly.
Got a bunch of orders in there but this is my latest order order which I just placed the let's grab
that text idea here.
And and add that to the invoice name here.
Maybe after a dash we have the order I'd use something like this.
So this is my end was and I'm getting the order ID in this route I should be protected authenticated
to see that's all protect this route and then I'll use my shop controller and there I get in wise control
or action which I have yet to at.
So that's why I've crashed here because I don't have that action yet.
In the shop controller bought bottom maybe let's exports get in twice a year and that will be our default
middleware function with request response and next.
And in here I now want to return that file.
First of all I need the wise idea for that order ID excuse me Order ID will be a request and then it's
encoded in the u r n l so it's parents and then order ID that is what I specified here in my routes
file order ID that's the name and therefore I have to retrieve it by that name in my controller.
So Order ID here.
Now have an order Id file name or d d NYS name will be looking for will be in my stash and then my order
ID and then thought PTF right.
That is the format in which all our invoices are stored let's say.
So now we need to retrieve that file and we can retrieve falls within those file system.
We use that before in the course already.
So let's start using it again.
Let's import it fault system by requiring fault system this is a core not an old module if you remember
you don't need to install a package it's already included in node and the file system allows to do things
like read files which sounds like a thing that makes sense here.
So let's use the file system and read a file.
We know it will be found in the data folder.
Now the payoff your should be constructed with the Poth core module so that it works on all operating
systems.
So let's also import path by requiring lbf and number of core node module the module and let's construct
that path to the invoice so I'll have my anywise Poth and all treated with lbf join and I'll be looking
for the data folder that the.
That's the first element.
Then in Wise's folder and then the invoice name the file name.
So this is the POF which I want to read.
So I'll pass that invoice path to read file read file then gives me a callback.
So a function which it will execute once it's done reading that file.
So here I will even get an error or the data data will be in the form of a buffer.
Now of course we should check if we have an error.
And if that is the case well then we simply next to it so that the default error handling function can
take over Otherwise if we don't have an error.
Here old returned by the way so that the error code won't execute.
So if we don't have an error then data should be my my file right.
So then I can call wrests send.
Which is a function provided by the Express Middler my data.
Now theoretically that should be the file.
Now let's see if that works.
And to make it work we have to use this route in our anchor task.
So in orders each as and this anchor tag we'll be looking for Slash orders slash.
And now we need to output something dynamic with each base and that is the order ID because that's what
we're looking for in the route.
So the order ID is simply order underscore ID which we use up there already.
So lets output that here.
Let's say that and reload that page and now look.
That's lictors in wise here.
And I do get my download option here let me save that and try to open that file.
And indeed it should open as a PDA where you should be able to open it as a PTF But of course it was
not the most convenient way of downloading this.
We had a strange name right.
This strange cryptic name we don't have TPD ethics tension and all of that.
So we can certainly improve that.
Let's do that in the next lecture.