We have our code for downloading a file and this file is now only available if we are locked in.
Now we can improve the way we return this however we can pass some extra information to the browser
so that it uses a different file name and also with the right extension for this we'll set some headers
so we can use set header for it.
And first of all we can set the content type to application slash PTF because that is what it is here
where it's like this.
Let's see what this does.
If I save it like that and I now click this button now I open it in the browser.
So this already changes to behavior.
It already gives the browser some information which allows the browser to handle isn't a better way.
And for most browsers simply open them in line.
So in the browser so that's great but we can't pass more information.
We can also set a number header and that is the contents Dasch disposition.
This allows us to define how this content should be served to the client.
We can set this to inline to still tell the browser to open it in line for example if I'd change it
like this nothing changes but we can also for example add a file name here so we can add semi-colon
and then file name and set this equal to in double quotation marks to follow them you want to serve.
So in my case it would be in wife's name right.
So we can also said follow them equal to double quotation marks plus in wife's name plus closing double
quotation mark contained between single quotation marks final saved is and I click this button.
Now we don't see a difference with the name when opening it in line because it's open and liberals are
anyways.
But we can change in line to attachment for example.
Now if Dad adjusted if the key going in was the download menu opens again.
And now here we have the proper file name with the proper extension.
And this is how you can control how the browser should handle the incoming data.
Should it automatically open it should it instead let you download it.
So I'll switch this back to inline.
But keep the following here.
And now I have a set up where only offene could add users can request this in ways we can still improve
that.