Now how can we improve does serving of the data.
Well first of all read now this is only available to authenticated users because on my route here I
have to is all middleware but every user could view that.
I don't have to be the user who placed that order however forward in order.
I of course know which user belongs to it.
I have the user id here so we can add an extra check in our middleware in our controller action here
to see if Ford is order to use or is eligible of downloading it.
Now how do we do that while we use the order Mungo's model find that order by that ID in the database
and then check if the order user ID is equal to the ID of the currently locked in user.
So here I can check order and then find by ID and I pass in my order ID I have then and catch your.
Now as you know in here we can simply Next an error to use the default error handling function.
And here we'll have our order element though that could be undefined if no order for this ID is found.
So if no order is found then I will also return next with a new error or maybe no order found whatever
you want You can't handle this differently.
If we do have order however I want to check if the order is from that user who's locked in.
So then I can check if order user and then keep in mind in the User object we have user ID field so
if Dad user ID to string if that is equal to request user underscore ID solve the currently locked in
user 2 string if that is equal I am allowed to access this if its not.
So if I'm checking the opposite if it's not equal then I will return a new error.
On all for riced something like this.
And only if I make it past these two checks only in this case I want to read that file.
And output it
so if an hour saved is in existence.
It works if it changes for a year to it two.
I get my error because now it's an invalid your L and if I copy that original you are l which was correct
and I do log out and I tried to access this while some locked out.
I have to log in and if I log in with a different user or let me quickly create that user
and then log in and then tried to access this order.
I also get an error.
I have to be the correct user.
Now of course you could show a different error message but that is only something you can tweak.
I only want to show you how you can protect this and then you have this option of controlling that access.
So here this all works just fine.