Knouted we learned how to save files and how to return them in different ways statically.
As one big fall or as a streamed response let me show you a little bonus so to say where we can create
a PTF on the fly on the server.
Instead of serving that hard coded PTF you're.
Let me created on the fly instead.
So I will delete my NYC year and instead when we get the invoice for an order I don't want to serve
a file that already exists but I want to generate deadfall based on the real order data for that.
First of all will check if we have that order and if the user is allowed to access it.
But of course this will now change.
Well actually the name will be the same and I will store it in the same way.
But I now can't read the file.
I need to create it.
And how can we create a PTF.
Well there are third party packages which we can use which make it a lot easier and PTF kit is a very
prominent or popular package for creating PD apps on a node j s server.
I strongly recommend checking out their documentation to learn more about all its menu options because
it's super powerful it can do a lot of stuff so definitely worth having a look at this and we will use
it to create the very simple PTF in this course.
Now for documentation it's important to know that this documentation uses coffee script which is like
a superset to javascript.
It's not supported by node.
It's just a tooling for writing your code.
It's compiled back to a normal javascript and therefore this documentation can be a bit hard to read.
In the end you could say something like this new document here we would have curly braces after it.
The choir would be using curly braces so some stuff here looks a bit different but I will show you how
to use it in this module in this lecture actually let's start by installing it so I will simply run
and install dash dash save PTF kit.
That's the name of the package.
You'll find these instructions on the official page NPM install PBF kit and then we can start using
it.
Once it's installed let me start that server again.
And up there in my shop.
Control or file all import PTF kit by requiring PTF kit.
So this package we just installed actually pedia of kit expose's PTF document constructor.
So let's maybe name it like this.
So PTF document.
The name is up to you but this is closer to what this package really exposes.
Now I want to create a new PTF document.
When we get in Weisse at this point here.
So let's create a new PDA with Doc whatever you want to name it by calling new PTF document and that's
what I meant.
You need to add normal parentheses as you always did for all constructors.
So now we have an UPDF document.
Does actually also turns out to be a readable stream.
Therefore what we can do here is we can use the PDAF document.
We can do two things.
First of all we pipe does output into ridable followed stream.
So create write stream as a function we can call on the file system package and two that we pass a path
where we want to write it to the invoice Poth.
In my case and this ensures that PTF we generate here all gets stored on the server and not just serve
to the client.
So we create debt and of course all of them want to return it to the client.
So all also piped the output into my response just as before.
The responses are ridable read stream PTF talk is a readable one so we can do that.
Now we have this set up and now whatever we add to the document will be forwarded into this file which
gets generated on the fly and into our response.
Now let's start simple and let's now use pedia of Doc and that's called the text method which exists.
This allows us to add a single line of text into the PDAF document.
So here let's add hello world maybe.
And then you have to call PTF Dawk to tell node when you're done writing to that stream because you
have to be done at some point right.
So here you simply call and.
And when you call and DS ridable streams for creating a file and for sending a response will be closed.
So to say or we'll know that you are done writing and therefore to follow the saved them to a response
will be sent.
And now with that saved just make sure you all change your set up down there at the bottom.
I will keep the headers but I will not pipe and you file because we now will pipe the file up there
when we create it.
And I just need to make sure that I set my response hetero's accordingly.
Now with that if you save debt and you click on that in Weisse link you should get a PTF with hello
world in there and this PTF also can be found here.
It might look a bit strange here but you can open it with a normal PDA reader and it sure looked like
a PDA.
So this is how you can create a PDA on the fly.
Now the next lecture Let's actually populated with some order data.