So let's create a more useful piaffe now.
Now you can configure a lot and the official box of PTF kit are the place to go to learn more about
that.
But let me show you how you can generate some nicely looking PBF in little time.
For example let's set a font size here of 26 and then add some text.
This text will now have this font size and this will have text of inv..
Now saved is
and reload this page we get in was written like this.
Can pass an object as a second argument here and configure does.
For example you can set underline to true here on the text in ivory Lotus.
We have the underlined text.
So of course you can style way more or you can even add images and all that stuff.
Now I'm happy with that title.
I'll simply add some dashes as to next line here.
And then there ofter I want to have my different items.
So I have to loop through all the items that are part of the order in this order.
I only have one product but I might have more products and actually of course do that they go to products
I can add this product with a card twice and I can quickly create a new product broad to and boring
as I am I'll use the same image for 29 bucks product 2.
Let's quickly create that product and then off recreated it I can add that to my card as well.
And then I could order dys and I've got a brand new order now by the way I placed it in Y's link next
to the Order not next to the product.
Now did ABBOTT Look at it but does matter we can change this later.
For now this will always lead to the same way so does not matter too much.
Now I have multiple products in there and I should loop through them when creating the output so I can
add a for loop or simply access.
Keep in mind we already have access to the order here since you fetched it from the database.
I can access order products and products AYSON array because we store at did this products in a database.
It will be an array of objects where each object has a quantity and then a product key with more detailed
information.
So I can loop through my products for example with the for each method which has a built in method provided
by javascript.
I'll then get information about my product and I can now output some text where I print.
Prot.
Product distend a detail object and in that product we have a title for example so I can output the
title here.
Then let's say we add a blank and a dash in a blank and then I have brought quantity right because we
have the quantity Kear directly on the product itself.
And then I add let's say times character and then we want to output the prize.
So I'll have let's say a dollar sign.
And then last but not least I'll have the product price.
So this field here of course you could all use next gen javascript's index with back ticks to make this
a bit easier to read.
I think it's maybe easier to understand how we are concatenating this from hard coded values and dynamic
values.
And now we should be outputting a line of data for each product in that order.
Now let's also add some at the bottom and we can calculate that on the fly here.
Let's total price starts at zero and if we are looping for all the products any ways we can use that
to also update our total price cost total the price will then be the old total price plus the product
quantity times the Prod. product price.
So basically what we print here is text will then also add it to our total price here like way this
can be written in a shortcut with this operator.
Now this will always add the result of this calculation to the old total price.
And then here outside of the loop once we are done calculating the total price Alexa's my PTF Doc I'll
put some text here and that text will be total price dollar sign and then simply total price like this.
With all that let's save that.
And that's like an invoice for the second order.
And here I get my in was which looks like dis.
Now of course we can all reverts to font size
here by setting font size to let's say 14 so that we don't use that super big fund for all our text.
Now by adding this line inside our loop
I am sure it does look like that.
And then maybe just some stylistic thing though it will not become super pretty.
I can add maybe some more dashes here to separate the list from the total surprise and set the font
size off that total price a bit bigger to maybe 20 safe dat reload as it is now.
Obviously this is not the most beautiful invoice we ever saw and you can learn way more about how you
may styled it in your official box of PDAF kit.
The important thing is the data in there is correct.
So the data does look correct.
The total price is correct and does is how you can generate data on the fly and how you can then return
it in a response and also save it in a file because that is important to we do both at the same step
and I believe its very interesting to see which power no Chavez has.
What you can do with it especially when all is playing around with the features of rewritable and readable
streams like here where we are creating a PTF on the fly and we were streaming it both into a file and
back to the client.