Now in this module we covered a lot.
And we work with files a lot.
Now one thing you might notice is that whenever we for example change an image or when we delete a product
to a file belonging to that product the image belong to the product sticks around.
Now obviously you can always delete files with the file system package.
There you also got options for deleting foz.
You could delete false whenever you added a product when you override the image.
So here if you are inside that if block and we set a new image you are l.
Then we could all the kick of a function that goes ahead and deletes the old image by fetching dead
from the product first because we're fetching the product here so we can get access to the old image
lbf by fetching that POV and then using the file system to delete that old image and we can of course
also lead to image when we delete the product.
So let's add this functionality as a last step now and for that I will go to my utile folder
and add a file Jaspal where I will add some help or functionality.
They are all import to follow system so the fault system is imported here and I'll have a constant which
holds a function which I'll name delete file disfunctions should accept the file path and debts.
Let's see in here I can use the filesystem package and there.
You'll have to try and link Methot it deletes the name and default it is connected to the names or deletes
a file it does Poth.
So here I pass fall POF and then this has to call because we know with an error if it fails and in here
we can simply check if we got an error.
Then I want to throw it again and then it should bubble up in our default express air handler should
be able to take over.
Otherwise I'll not do anything here.
So it's like method.
I can always call to pass and fall apart and delete that file.
And now we can use that in our admin controller.
So let me import my file helper here or requiring it from the utl folder and the ERDA file file and
I can use that file helper.
For example in the place where we added a product if we are and is if block and we know will replace
the image you are l.
Then before I do so I will use Fall helper and call my function there for dead.
I need to export that though.
So in here I want to export delete file.
This will hold my delete Falah constant.
So does function and now in the Edmond J as controller.
Here I can call fall helper delete file and pass in product image.
You are also the path to dat file and now does chaud fire.
I'm not waiting for this to complete.
I continue with my eyebrow operations.
I'm doing this in a fire and forget manners.
I'm firing this function and I don't care about the result.
If I wanted to I would have to pass my callback here so a function which then continues with the rest.
In this function here.
But I simply fire it like this and I will do the same when we delete a product.
So in there when we do delete it here I also want to delete the respective image.
And for that I first of all need to fetch by product of course so I will have find my ID in here.
Find it by Prod. ID.
And then here I have then and catch and catch I can next any error I get and then block I will have
access to my product.
So here I can then ex you by fall helper.
I should of course all the check if product is not set in which case I'll also return next with a new
error product not found.
And otherwise I delete that and it should only trigger delete one here after I found this.
Otherwise we have a race condition where deleting could finish before finding is finished and that would
be bad so we'll grab that delete one code move that here and return it to return to Brahmas return by
delete one.
And then I can actually replace that catch block with my old then and catch block and does will catch
arrows in any of the then blocks and it will also make sure that at first find the product once I have
found it.
I delete the image and I assembles heinously start deleting the product itself.
Let's save all dead and let's see if that works.
If I go back to Aben products here and I delete product one this is cleared and here I also have one
much less if I delete the second product it's only free images so this works.
Diablerie images are still sticking around because previously when I started deleting products and so
on I did not have that logic in place but now this works.
Fetching my wise or generating it on the fly were.
And thanks to the fact that we store a snapshot of that in the database.
It even works after the product was deleted.
Which is of course the way we want it to work.
With that we have a really nice setup here.