That's it for this module you'll learn a lot about files.
You'll learn how to add file upload functionality both in the form and then most importantly on the
back end by using Mulder this nice middleware which automatically extracts files from incoming requests
and store them as specified by us and which also is able to filter out certain file types if we want
you.
You learned how to store files both for adding and editing items.
So how to manage debt and you of course also learn how to download files how to surf them statically
with the help of that static milah were expressed as ships with and how to make sure that this uses
the right path.
And alternatively or depending on your requirements how you can surf false as a response in a route
like with get order here in the shop J.S. controller where we saw multiple different options of serving
a file that already existed for example by loading it into memory and then returning it.
Or that you could scream such a file instead.
Or you can even generate Follett's on the fly if required depending on what your application requirements
are and then you learn a lot of things about how to work with files with streams with responses and
this hopefully helps you implement fall related features into your next application.