Let's first of all start with the payment process how does this work.
Well it's a pretty long process.
We start by collecting the payment method.
So the credit card data typically we don't have to fight it is to credit card data.
Correct.
Is it expired.
Is the number correct.
We don't have to charge it and offer we charged we have to manage payments.
So that includes things like fraud protection.
Also managing disputes and so on.
And last but not least we of course have to Prose's the order in our app so in our research side code
for example that we stored in the database there.
Now all the payment related things here are pretty complex tasks both from a legal and the technical
side and therefore typically you outsource them.
And by the way even very big companies outsource this Strype is a very popular company offering payment
services.
It offers a great integration it's super easy to add to any application as you will see in this module.
How does it work.
Well we have our client and our server.
So that is all the code we own and we wrote and then the client will collect credit card data.
We'll do that with the help of Strype and we'll send it to the Strype servers which are not owned by
us but by that company to validate that input once it is valid Strype will return a token to us which
basically and or which includes that credit card data and confirmation that it is correct.
We sent that token to our server.
So to our code and in our code we create a charge or we charge this payment method then with the help
of Strype again.
So we create a payment object a charge object we sent that to stripe with that token and with our price
included and Strype will then do the actual charging to the actual managing.
And we will get a response once this is done and then we can also continue with our code and added this
or stored in the database and so on.
So this is generally how that will work.
Now let me walk you through that step by step.