To add payment to our application let's work on that.
Check out Ejaz fall with which we never worked thus far.
I want to go there before I actually placed an order when I click on order now in my cart so I'll go
to this page first.
For that I'll copy the content of cart.
Each has added and checkout Aegeus to make sure that I have my default hat.
I'll get rid of that style sheet though I don't need it here.
I want to include the navigation.
The main content will be totally different though.
I will keep my body however so it might end here.
So with that I have everything set up to have a basic checkout page.
Now let's first of all make sure we reached it before we start adding stripe.
For that we need a new route of course in a shop G-S fall.
Here we have our create order route and in the end what I need is a new router I get route which we
can check out there.
I want to be authenticated because that we can only buy something if we are locked in let's say and
then I'll use my shop controller and there get check out which is action I still have to create an in
that get check out page 10 will have the possibility to create an order and so on.
So for now let's just add this and let's work on our controller down on our shop controller and there
I need a get check out Methot.
So maybe here before Post order because logically comes prior to that I'll have get check out with request
response and next and in there I want to render my check out page so we can of course grab one of our
other Rander functions heater
rendered that here I will render shop slash checkout.
The pov can be checked out but doesn't really matter we don't have an obligation.
Do we want to highlight here we can check out as a text.
And of course we had some data for to check out.
Now what do I want to return here.
Well endian.
I will need the same data as I have in my cart so I need my products here which I do have in the cart
so I can actually copy that entire code from get to cart.
I guess and add this year and now just make sure we use shop.
Check out lbf check out and here.
Check out but besides that I also need to calculate the total Let's say so total sum or whatever you
want to name it and that total sum of course can be retrieved from our product data.
Because in the cart or in the products here we have in the cart.
You have to keep in mind that products is in their range of products where we have the quantity and
then a product ID field with detailed data about the products because we populate this product ID field
with the detailed product data so therefore the total sum can be generated by looping through all products.
So you can do products for each
and create a new variable total which is zero initially.
And then there total is equal plus equal does shortcuts to add something to the existing total So total
plus the product and then there is a quantity field times the product product ID price and then its
just total which I passed to my view.
So that's all the data you should need to check out you.
So now back in March check out each fall.
Now I can indeed grab that on the list for rendering a list of items.
Like does I'll go for all my products.
I'll remove the delete button though it's too late at this point let's say we can of course always cancel
the check out process if we want to though.
Actually I'll delete this entire form therefore this is my unordered list and below that we can add
a death with age to tag of total.
And then your output total sum.
Now let's have a look at that and to have a look.
I need to make sure that cart Ejaz when you click order now I don't submit this form here.
So we'll actually comment this out.
We don't need data anymore.
But instead I want to have a normal anchor tag here where I say Order now where I simply point at slash
checkout.
So this new route we added and I'll just give Does a class of button to look at it like a button with
all that added.
Let's go back to our page.
Let's go to products here maybe add to the cart and click order now and does this now.
Well a page here.
Now it's not looking super beautiful I'd say.
I need to include dead carts as fall again because since I'm reusing the rest of the code here we could
create our own style sheet but I want to keep this relatively short since I'm using all that.
I of course all a one to use the same Stahl's.
Now if I reload this check out page here this is looking OK.
The total could be placed in the middle maybe we can do that by giving this Dave a glass off centered
which is a utility class and it's early and of course and now we have this checkout page.
Again you can always work on the visuals but it's not so much about the visuals here.
So we have this total and now I want to add Strype and for that let's first of all set up an account
with them.