You can simply google for Strype and you should find their page and they have a really great documentation.
By the way in case you want to use it so definitely dive into developer documentation.
But we can simply click Create an account here and then create an account real quick.
Now once you got your account created you can already get started.
First of all you need to Velvet date your account so make sure you click on that very fine e-mail link
you get in an extra e-mail and once you did that you're ready to get started.
Now Portland and developers you'll find a bunch of API keys which you will need to add Strype and we
are seeing special testing data here which is fine for our development if you want to build a real application
we want to push it to production.
You would switch to your life data here for this you have to act with your account though will not do
that here will work with the test data to get started.
So now with all that we can actually click on home and click on Accept first payment here to dive into
the official box and learn how we can accept our payment.
And the cool thing is this data here is actually already populated with our data as with our publishable
key for example.
So that is that key you saw under developers API keys that are keys you need to send with your data
to let Strype know to which account this belongs.
So your business data set up at a code set that we can already use it we can add that to our check out
each last fall.
So there let's add a new.
Let's add this form here.
We now need to target a route on our server.
So maybe check out with a post request here or since we already have that
create order this post request so now I'll use this method.
And then there is only a script which will in the end create the input fields for the user and this
will use a script provided by the Strype company which makes using it very convenient.
Now of course we need to populate this with the amount that we can use each year to input our total
sum into the script.
Yes this works you can input data into a script with SJS you can enter a name here any name you want
all at your order
all the items you ordered.
You can set the currency to that to USD and you can leave the defaults for now.
Now with that if you now reload your checkout page you'll have to pay with card button there which was
created by that stripe script.
Now by the way also give this div a class of centered to centered at button.
Now with that added for reload the button this year if you click that it will open is modal here.
All controlled by stripe where you can now enter your payment data and how important is now that I see
it.
That's a common gotcha.
The amount you enter is entered in cents.
So total sum is now treated as cents.
We have to multiply that of course with 100 to get the right amount.
So if I now reload and I click pay by card.
Now I see the right amount here.
So that's important.
You entered the amount in.
So now we have that order field.
And how can we now continue Well if the user now enters his data.
And you can use this dummy card number 4 2 4 2 4 2 4 2 4 2 4 2 4 2.
So 4 times 4 2 4 2 any date in a future year and any code if you do this you can click pay.
And what this will do is will now generate data token Frue stripes Cirus an automatic is send a request
to your back and which now fails send the request to your back end.
And then there it will try to handle that as you see it sent the request to create order.
So we'll have to work on that.
But create order is the right route.
So now does what send the request to you to back into the create order route.
And now there we have to continue because now there we will receive some special data and how to continue
is also something Strype tells you if you scroll down on the QuickStart page you're two step two you
see a code snippet and you can switch to note here to see how to handle the data on the incoming request
and you'll see that the incoming request will have a stripe token in its body.
We can copy that code as well.
And then move to our controller and there to shop Geass of course.
And now we're interested in proposed order.
Now here in the end I now have my Strype object which requires a stripe package which I need to install.
We need to install that and which then uses disk token which is again the token from our API key section
in our dashboard.
Now let me quit my server and quickly install Strype with NPM installed dash dash save stripe.
We need to packet's year because we're importing it here and we're using something from that package
we can of course also move that up to the imports you're like dat.
Make sure to be executed as a function though and pass your key.
That is not your publishable keep your secret keep right away.
And by the time you are watching this I've already switched my keys so no need.
I'm trying mine.
Then we're extracting the token from the incoming request and then we're creating such a charge object
here.
Here again you need to enter your amount in cents though and this should now be done not with data center
of the request because that could be faked by a user.
But of course you should fetch that data from your server again.
So here where I'm fetching my user and I've deden getting all the info for my cart I am creating the
order and I'm saving my order in there.
I will also create my charge object with the stripe package and the amount is now something I can calculate
in there too because there I can have my total sum which is zero.
And then again I loop through all my user card items here with for each that will be my products and
I'll have the same logic as before.
Total sum will be the old total sum plus product quantity times product product ID price.
So I'll calculate the total sum like this and I'll then add my total sometimes 100 B costs and send
here and then here we could use something like time stamp description off the order username whatever
you want.
I'll just name it.
Demo order the sources to tokin which we extract up here so that token which includes the validated
credit card data.
And now with that this year we'll already send a request to the service and charge our payment method
there.
So make that charge.
You can also take that charge and do it here.
Once you have the result where you will know the ideal of your order because then you can actually add
some metadata here which is a javascript object where you can pass any arbitrary data you want to matches
order with the charge.
It will be stored in your Strype account.
So here we could have order ID and there I could have assault underscore ID that should be id ID of
the created order.
Now I'm making my charge down there.
Important to have the total sum available.
I need to create that variable outside of that then block function.
Otherwise it would only be available in there but I need it outside of there too because I knew that
in the next to then block and now I'm creating my charge off to restore my order.
Now with that in place let's go back to our application and pay with card
entered a dummy card data someday in the future and any CBC code you want.
Now we still get this error.
Now this error has a relatively simple explanation in shop James.
I'm trying to retrieve my Strype token from request body.
It should be rec body because I named his argument rec.
So that is something I did wrong by just copying this in.
And now if you go back and we try to sent this again I get another error but this time it is related
to Taurasi as a token and by the way a great way to see the original error message is to add a console
log and logging the error in the error handling function here because then you will see that I get an
invalid SRF token and that makes sense because for the requests sent by the Strype modal sobeit it modal
we entered our credit card data in this request does not include our C SRF token.
So just check out form does not include it.
Now you could include your hidden input field there but that wouldn't do anything because Strype creates
its own form and you end in an I-frame which had loads but that also means that Strype takes care about
securing that form.
So this is not this for which you are bad into your document there Strype renders and loads as it cures
its own form.
So you don't need to pass to see SRF token.
That just means we have to disable SRF token protection for this post.
Create order route and to do that all cut the route from my shop yes routes file and I'll move it directly
into app.
There.
I'll add the route above my Alber routes here and I'll replace router with app because we only have
the app available in this fall.
There we also have a post method to only trigger this middleware app on post requests.
I filter for a slash create order and still want to use is often the shop controller so I'll need to
import both in my app G-S file as well.
Let's go to the shop routes file copy these two imports.
Shop controller and is off go back to app Agis And then there at the top maybe below my Aero controller
I'll import these two files.
The import path needs to be adjusted because now I don't have to go up one level.
I already am in a folder I need to import this him or I'm in the parent folder off DS folders to be
precise.
And with that added If I go down now here I have this route.
Now Israel still has C or protection added to it though because I have my C as Earth middleware here.
The idea now is did I initialized as Mutlu were ofter this route which should not be checked so it only
to read it's ofter does will be affected because remember the requests treadles Fruita middleware from
top to bottom.
So SEUS are of protection only gets added ofter this route.
So if you have exceptions of which you typically don't have too many.
But if you have exceptions like this one place it before you enable this middleware.
Now one important thing I have another middleware where I set this see is our token here.
I need to copy that Middler remove as a token assignment up there and add Ed Miller off dry and able
to see as RF protection removed is locked in extraction here and then set C a sort of token here and
with debt.
This route should now be excluded.
And now finally if I go back and I pay with card
I can enter my card number here
and submit this request.
And now I do end up on orders.
I see my order here.
My card is empty and if I go to my stripe dashboard and they click on payments they're I don't see anything.
I go back to see an error here in my log for the note and there we see that object id basically was
the problem.
I tried to send some extra data in my shop controller to Strype here the result ID I should convert
to a string.
Otherwise this can't be added for my charge failed.
Now this is a.
We need to fix.
So after fixing this.
Let me go back to my application and create another order by adding this to a card ordering it now.
And now paying
now does looks better.
No I got no error here on Knode and now if I have a look at my payments dashboard reload this page I
see my payment for $22 with my demo or order and my extra meta data here.
You order ID.
So that's the idea of the order as it is stored in my database and this is how you can add payment.
Of course the Strype is very powerful can do a lot of things.
You can also improve this by catching errors that might be occur due to charging as we hit it before
though this bag is fixed and then you might want to roll back orders you placed in your database.
You can do way more with Strype.
Check out their official docs but they hope that this is helpful for showing you how you can integrate
payment with Strype easily into your application.