In this module I want to dive into a very important aspect of building web applications back and applications
like the one we're building.
We want to follow a certain pattern for structuring our code.
And with that I don't really just mean how we split it over a files or how we write to code but I mean
how we logically separate our code and two different functions it fulfills or of different things it
does.
We'll dive into the MVC pattern and you'll understand in this module what this actually is and how we
can add it in our project.
And of course we'll not just added to the existing project but will also advance our project to get
closer to that online shop we're building.