We added our products controller in the last lecture.
Now let's also make sure we handle the 4 0 4 route with a controller.
In theory does this of course is not required totally optional but it's a good practice.
So definitely possed a video here and try this on your own before we then do that together.
Make sure to decide which controller you want to use a new one or the existing products controller and
how you would extract you for 0 4.
Here is the 404 page logic into that controller and connect the existing route to it.
Good luck.
Where are you.
Successful.
Let's try that out and for that let's first of all identify where we are rendering that 4 0 4 route
and that is the various file here at the bottom.
Now we can absolutely leave that code here.
It's very simple and there's nothing wrong with it but to be inline with our average code is that when
I put that into a controller now it's clearly not related to products because we can have many features
on our page and every path can fail or the user can enter any random path.
So instead I'll create a new controller here.
And you can name as however you want.
You can name it for 0 4.
J.S. I'll name it.
Rr DOT J.S. and in there I will export a function with exports and then I'll name it get 4 or 4 a page
or you get 4 or 4 to be in line with get products which I have in our controller and now it will cat
dead function here.
This middleware function from actually yes an error.
J.S. this is what I will store here and get 404.
This is my function where I returned the four or a page.
And with this I just have to go back to actually yes.
And then there I will simply import my controller.
So Konst error a controller is imported by going to the control as folder and there too the error.
JS file and we can now take that air or controller here and down there on app use.
I will simply put aero controller get 4 0 4 just like this as a reference to this function.
And now this is all in line with the Alber routes and with the Alber products controller.
So this is now the controller being added.
And with that we get Due's and controllers.
Let's move on to the model next.