With controllers and news editors it's time to care about the model.
The problem with our model is that we.
Well we have a very simple one.
We manage our products array here and a product is simply created on the fly as an object that looks
like this.
Now in the end that product represents our data.
We have products in our app later we'll all have our things like a user.
But for now it's just a product still.
We can find a model for debt and for this is let's create a new folder in our root project and name
it models.
Now all these names are exchangeable of course but this makes the separation really clear.
We get controllers we get the news we get models and that makes up the NBC pattern.
Now they're all at a new fall product.
J.S..
Now please note it's not products here because I want to represent a single entity because in the end
our core data is a product.
Sure we all have lists of products with which we work but the core thing that makes up the app is how
a product looks like which fields it has doesn't have an image a title that is our core data a list
of products is boring it's just will more of that type a single product is what defines our app in the
end or part of what defines the app.
Now how does this mall look like this is totally up to you in the end you kind of find us in which ever
way you want.
You can for example simply export a constructor function here.
So a function which a name product and you call that to create new objects based on that using our ears
5 constructor function.
But if you're using NexGen javascript as I'm doing it here you can instead create a class you can create
a class named product that looks like this.
And does this now Ole's export it.
And in case you're not sure what a class is.
Check that javascript refresher at the beginning of the course.
I do explain it there too.
Now here in this class I wanted to find the shape of a product and for this I'll first of all treat
the constructor function.
So here I want to receive a title for the product which will then create from inside my controller.
So here I get my title and you can name this title of course and it will then create a property in this
class.
So basically like a variable in the class you could say you do does this keyword and then does tieless
equal to the title I'm receiving as an argument here.
And these names don't have to match and to avoid confusion Canal's named as t here.
So I'm creating a property in this class.
This allows me to then create an object based on this class where I can pass the title to the constructor
which we call with new.
And then this will get stored in the created object.
But obviously I don't just want to be able to create objects with a title I can Dudas with the current
curly brace Sendak's too.
Instead here I want to be able to create my or to store my product to an array of products and fetch
it.
And for this I will reintroduce my products array here and we will change that later when we use a real
database.
But for now let's go with this approach and I will add a safe method to my class here by calling Savir
by typing save adding parentheses and then curly braces.
So it's like a function just without the function keyword.
So this is now a method available in this class and in the Save method.
I want to store my product in this array and I can do this by reaching out to products and then calling
portiere just as we did it before in the controller and assembly simply push this because this will
refer to the object created based on the class and that is exactly the object I want to store in desir.
Now obviously I also want to be able to retrieve all products from that array.
And I also want to do that for my product model however whereas save makes sense to be called on a concrete
instantiated object based on product I also want to have a fetch all method which is like a utility
function you could say this is not called on a single instance of the product because it should fetch
all products and I don't want to create a new object with the new keyword with some dummy title just
to fetch all existing products and therefore I will add the static keyword which javascript offers which
makes sure that I can call this method directly on the class itself and not on an instantiated object.
And then in here I will return this Boob's products like that.
Now does the model finished.
Now lets move to the products control file.
There I will first of all get rid of products here at the top and also of products push down there because
now I want to use my BODIL.
I also don't need that anymore.
So they got no products aere related logic left in this fall.
Instead I will now import my class by adding a new content product and you can names however you want
but the convention is to use a capital starting character for Clausius and in the end we do just import
diskless.
So I will add the capital of character and does control a file too.
And they do import a class by requiring this from the models folder from that product Chia's file with
an added imposed add product.
I will now create a new object based on this class blueprint and that is what classes are in the end.
They are blueprints so we'll create a new product a local content with new product and there I will
pass request body title and that simply takes the title I have here as a name on my input which is submitted.
With this we create a new product based on our CLOs.
Now there's one additional thing that needs to be done though.
I want to save debt and I can do that by calling product.
Save this we'll use that save method we find and it will therefore for now pushed it onto desir.
Now with that in get product to Osmo to fetch all products sultry the new local content products and
now it will use that static method because it don't want to create a new product where I would have
to set up some dummy title because I don't create a product here.
Instead I just want to use product and call fetch.
All this should give me all the products and now I have my products here and if I save this it should
now work if I go back and reload this page.
I get cannot read.
Property length.
That makes sense because fetch all returns this product which is incorrect.
It should just return products because we are returning dis array not some local property of this class.
There is no product's property.
So after fixing this and removing this down there now is very low.
This does works and if I now try adding a first book.
This again works now using a model and was does might look more complicated right now.
And it certainly is because we're just using our dummy storage here.
Does this great once you really got more complex models with more fields with more methods and where
you don't store them in some random array.
But where you got the whole database connection logic and so on to you then put that all into your model
and you don't have to care about it in your controller and it actually simulate this by moving away
from our erase storage here and move towards a file storage at least before we then later in the course
also use a real database.