So let's make sure we can save our product to a file and not to does it read here anymore.
For this when we call safe here I want to save it to a file.
And of course in that file I want to have all products the old ones and the new one.
So therefore First of all we need to be able to work with the file system.
So I will import FS from the core FS module.
Now that file should then also be created in special POF so it will use the path tool.
The POF module to construct a path that works on all operating systems.
Now here in save I will then create my POV and I will do that with Poth join.
So using the POF core module.
And I named this piece so that they avoid namespace clashes and the pop should be my root directory
and we actually still have that helper function.
But if you deleted it you can of course recreate it as we did before or simply copy this code here if
you want.
You also find it attached to this lecture again in case you deleted it.
I will simply copy that logic here.
And move it in there.
But of course I could absolutely simply use my helper function I created there but this is of course
just a root directory in there.
I will have a new data folder and I will create it ahead of time so that we don't get permission issues.
So I'll have added that data folder to the project folder and then that data Fuller I want to store
my file.
So that will then actually be a file and that should have a name of products and I will give design
extensional Jason because I want to store my data in Jasen format.
OK so that's products now to store a new product in there.
First of all I need to get Dijk assisting array of products.
So I will first of all read that file.
So let's use F as read file and read the entire file content of a file.
And by the way for very big files there are more efficient ways because you don't want to read them
all into memory before you work with them.
You can read them as a stream them.
There is such a function.
You can create a read stream with this function but we can read the entire file here does OK.
And they will read the file at disport which is that fall I'm interested in.
And then I will do something once I'm done reading it.
And there we even get an error or we get data that we get the the file content.
You could say that will be a buffer though.
Now let's lock the file contents here.
And let's see what we get if we now call save for go to add product and I'll type something here.
It crashes and it trashes the scroll up because products is not the find and fetch all of course in
save However it didn't throw an error but we get undefined here as you can see.
And we did get undefined because this file simply doesn't exist.
There is no content in it.
Therefore you can see that here we've got no file with that name.
So reading it therefore a kind of failed.
And if I add an error here to print the error we get.
And I tried it again.
So let's go back to at product click that we scroll above this arrow message here you see does this
error message.
We're now logging with this line.
And there we see no such file or directory.
And that makes a lot of sense because indeed it does not exist as I just mentioned.
So obviously if it doesn't exist then I also want to continue and I can I will simply check if we got
an error and this will be NULL if we get none.
But if we have one then I simply want to create a new empty array because we have no existing products
chase and fall.
So we got no old products stored and otherwise I'd want to use the existing one put in other words I'll
add a new variable here which I'll name products.
And initially this is an empty array and it will actually keep it as such if we do have an error.
But if we get no error.
And then we'll add an exclamation mark here.
So if he got no error if this therefore is null.
So if he got no error then I want to read the products from the file which I extracted.
So therefore here I noted follow content will be something it should be the content of my file.
And since that is adjacent file I will store it in Jason format there so then it will set products equal
to Jason which is a helper object existing in vanilla node.
JS So you don't need to find this on your own.
And there we have the Parse method which takes incoming Jason and gives us back a javascript array or
object or whatever is in the file.
So here I can parse the file content and that should work.
Or at least we should try that.
So now I know that product will be an array either the one I read from the file or an empty one and
therefore we can now append our new product there.
Several called products Porsche and push my new product which is this onto it now important to ensure
that this refers to the class you should use an aero function here because our wise this will lose its
context and will not refer to declasse anymore.
We have to set up though where I do use an aero function.
This should refer still to my class and therefore now I can push this onto this erate ever to the new
one or the one I read from the file.
And now the remaining work is that I need to save it back into the file.
So I again will use to follow system module and now will use right file and I will write it to the same
path as where I read it from.
And I will put my Jason data into it.
So I get will use that Jason Helper Object.
And now there is the string you find method which takes a javascript object or array and converts it
into Jason.
So that this has the right format.
So they're able take this products array and convert this Jason.
And then this gets written to the file.
And here I also have a callback where I may get an error or it will simply lock dead error here to see
if that works with all that.
Let's go back.
Let's go back to the ad product page and click this button.
This error of course still exists.
But now if we stroll up let's see if that worked here.
That is looking good and in data we indeed see a product Jason file which does contain that one product
we created.
Now that was D.
We have no old data case.
Let's now go back and add and Nashbar product product here.
And see if that also works by scroll up.
Well we also see it here I guess this also worked out just fine.
So this is where again we are able to read a file append data to the existing data or create it if it
didn't exist yet and therefore our data storage in a file seems to work.
Obviously it's a very basic storage but better than nothing.
Now obviously we also want to be able to fetch the data from there.
So in fact all I want to read this file here I will read the file at my Poth And I also will therefore
get my hour or to follow content use an arrow function here and this will then hold that data I want
to use that if I got an error here I want to return an empty array because then I got no products right.
I always want to return an array because that is what fetch all expects but it should at least be empty
in case of an error.
And of course you could also throw an error message and show one but here it'll just be the empty array
otherwise.
And I don't need the else block because after return we would have finished the execution of this function
anyways so ofter does if block I will return my parsed and that's important.
Otherwise it will just be a string.
My parsed file content and this is important to keep in mind because dizzier isn't the end retrieved
as a text.
So to return it as an array you need to call chase and parse.
So now I return my file the content it up parsed form and therefore I get rid of the returned product
statement here and it will now always return my objects on my list of products.
So let's see this in action let's save this and reload this page here is not the find makes sense.
I'm trying to reach read something from this pov but that part is only defined in the Save method.
So for now let's copy it.
We can of course refactor that but let's copy it for now.
And now a very reloaders page.
I still get this error and does can now be very hard to debug or to understand.
But do you know what's going wrong here.
We'll fix it in the next lecture.