Now we added that found storage logic to our model.
Let's now fix this a little bit or improve the code in the model we're reusing some code.
And if we reuse code that always screams for some refactoring and indeed that is what I want to do I
will create a helper function and store it in a constant and I'll name that helper function get products
from file and this helper function will do this.
Lbf construction here for me and it will also read the file.
So we'll basically do everything I do here and fetch all this and it will even get my callback here.
Because I do execute that year and ultimately returned us because the issue of disk grows is taking
some time and we need to inform the caller of dysfunction about when it's done hasn't gone away.
So I still use the same pattern of having this helper function which receives a callback which it executes
once it's done reading the file.
With this get products from file is really just all I execute here and fetch all.
So I simply just call this in full ward to callback.
Now for save however it means that here I can also call get products from file.
But here I don't forborne any callback because instead I have my own logic here.
I do retrieve my products there and that's essentially the same logic I do have in get products from
file either return an empty array if I have an error or I parse my content.
We did it the other way around.
But in the end it will result in the same result.
So I'm only interested in this logic here.
Then you can remove dead and instead just take this code here.
And then create a new anonymous function where I know that I will get my products because this again
is still callback function.
It is the function it will pass as an argument to get products from file.
So it is what will get cold here.
So this function will get called in will receive an empty array or the array with the data and a ship
by the way add a return statement here to make sure that we never execute this code after having executed
this code.
That was an error we had in the code before.
Alternatively you simply wrap the above code in a Else statement either of the two.
So here I'll use the if else approach.
But now if that the callback will get executed and we'll get desire of products.
And now here in safe I do have this anonymous function which receives the products and in does anonymous
function.
I will then put in my code where I append a new product and make sure to always use aero functions so
that this never loses its context and always refers to to the class and therefore to the object based
on the class.
And then I write to the file.
This means I can get rid of this line too.
And now we get a slimmer wurden because we're reusing code but it still should work if I reload here.
Loading product seems to work.
And if I add a second book even though it's the fourth one this crashes because P is not defined yet.
The payoff here in Save that is a problem the POF is not defined.
Because I'm only defining it in my helper function now.
Now there are various ways of fixing that.
One of the easier ways is to simply create this as a global helper constant here p so that they can
use it and the entire file you can of course go for different solutions and pass it around into functions.
But now tipoffs should be available in the safe method and in get products from file.
And with that if and I'll reload and try this second actually fourth book again.
This now works.
So now we are able to elegantly work with our products stored them in a file fetched them from there
and all of that through a model.
And that is the MVC pattern implemented into our project.