For this module I'm back in the application or a project we worked on in the last core section and you
can find my state that hatched to this video so that you can start to write at the same point as I do.
So it is just the code we wrote over the last lectures.
And one thing we constantly had to do in the last section or throughout this course was that we always
had to run node app J.S. to start our well app where our node application with that file.
Now this is certainly ok and not too much work but it actually is possible to define some scripts in
a note yes project that can help us with tasks like this.
We can also use them for other tasks but especially for this they can be useful right now.
And for that we have to use a feature we didn't use thus far.
We have to use NPM and PM stands for node package manager and it is installed together with no JS So
you don't need to do anything.
You got this installed already.
Now we will also use NPM to install some additional third party packages to our project soon so packages
that are not included in nodes core.
So not part of nodes core modules but we can also use NPM to initialize a so-called node project or
to add some extra features to it.
To be precise because we obviously already got a node project here but now in this project in a terminal
navigated into this project you can run NPM in it.
Now this will not delete your code or anything like that.
No worries.
Simply hit enter and you'll be prompted with a couple of questions here.
It'll ask you first of all for a name of your package.
And for now you can simply translate as with project name.
Now you can pick any name you want the part in the parentheses here.
Always ISDE suggestion the default.
It will pick if you don't choose your own name.
So if I just hit enter here it will take dead evil.
So you can basically do that for all these questions.
For the description you can leave that empty.
Then it will have no default text ever but you can also enter some text like complete node.
JS guides does this what does Corps's and then define an entry point with FS For example you can leave
the task command and do you leave that empty keywords you can choose some if you want.
You can put your name into the offer field though it is also not required and you can always choose
a license.
But if you don't plan on sharing this project publicly.
This it doesn't really matter.
So with this what you get is disk package start Jason File and there you also see all these settings
or configurations you just set up and you can of course edit them there too.
So if you had a typo in your description you can't just edit that here.
Now does this using the Jason format which is a special kind of data format which basically looks a
lot like javascript objects and it pretty much is based on that.
There is one important thing to understand though.
The keys are always put between double quotation marks and so are the values except for numbers or arrays
or true or false which are not put in these.
But that's too much.
For now we can ignore that for now just so that you understand what you got there.
It's basically a configuration file for your project.
Now what does this configuration file give you.
Well let's clear the console here.
With this configuration file you'll see that we got a script section there which has one default script
that won't do anything for an hour.
You can add your own scripts here and I will tell you how to execute them too of course.
For that let's add a comma after this test script and add a new script name which has to be put between
double quotation marks and there let's name it start now.
Start is actually a special script name as you will see in a second.
So make sure to type correctly and then between quotation marks.
You type a command to should be executed.
So this is a command which you could all type down there.
And there we always have to type.
Note EP J Julius.
So let's now Portes dead between dishtowel double quotation marks here.
Note app dot.
J.S. like this.
Would that save deadfall.
And then you can run NPM start start is a research to name and this will always look for such a start
script.
And if you do that it will as you can see here just execute note at chess.
So does the same you had before but now you can always just well run this command instead of running
note.
Actually it's not that much of a saved characters but a few at least.
And it's also good practice because of you ever shared this project.
It's pretty common that people just have to run NPM start and they don't have to guess which of your
javascript files is the entry file.
So you can quit this with control C of course as always and I mentioned that this would be a special
script name.
You can add more scripts all that without using a special name.
You can indeed choose any name you want.
Just make sure to always wrap the name in double quotation marks and that it does not contain any blanks
or white spaces.
So for example we could have start the ash server.
Now this can also run node apps.
Yes so it will do the exact same as descript and therefore it's of course redundant.
But I want to show you something.
And now if you try running NPM start Dasch server you'll get an error.
You basically get an error that does this not a known command and indeed it isn't because just typing
the script name here will not work.
Start.
Just a special case as I mentioned.
Indeed for normal scripts with their own custom names you have to run NPM run and then your script name
so NPM run start server will now also start the server.
Now as I mentioned this is of course redundant and can start is way shorter but I want you to understand
how you can add your own scripts.
Now if you worked with something like angular or react or view or any modern front and development workflow
you will have seen that you use such scripts a lot to trigger build workflows for your projects for
example and indeed you can use that for all kinds of TASC to want to execute.
But for now I will not dive deeper into that and if you haven't worked with angular or react that's
all.
No problem.
You will see what I mean.
Later in the course when I explore nodes functionality as a build to a bit more.
For now let's just use that NPM start script to start our application conveniently.