So in the last lecture we added a script to start our application and does it's nice to note and we
have this scripting functionality now with such a package Jason fall away level.
So therefore with this being managed node project you could say we can also do one very important thing
we can install third party packages because a typical node project looks like that you have your local
project with your code obviously and you use a lot of core node packages like DFS package or D.H. to
DP package we're already using.
But often this does not suffice.
And in the next core section we will install one big party package actually because you typically have
such dependencies third party packages.
So you want to use some functionalities some code which you didn't write on your own but which is also
not included into no chase packages could help you with parsing incoming requests validating user input.
Anything of that kind.
Now we will use Express in the next lectures or in the next module be precise body parser is another
package we'll use for all this cores and there are thousands of packages a way lable that offer all
kinds of utilities you can add to your projects.
So did you don't have to reinvent the wheel.
These packages are available from the NPM repository.
That is a cloud packet repository where all these packages live.
And you can conveniently install and manage them via NPM.
Remember that tool that shipped with note and this is exactly what we will do now to install a first
little utility package that will speed up our development workflow.
Because right now what we have to do is whenever we change our code we have to quit the development
server with Control-C and restart it.
Right.
So if we have it running with NPM start now remember it is our new command to start the server.
And I would change something here like for example here I fixed that slash head right.
Whenever I do this I have to save this and for my change to have an effect I have to quit the server
with Control-C and restarted.
Now it is a bit cumbersome because we just want to be able to type and then hit save.
And it should automatically restart and right that would be a great workflow during development and
to achieve this we have to install a third party package that gives us just as functionality.
Now how do we add such a third party package.
We do that with the help of NPM and there we get the install command.
So just as we had run to run one of our scripts install installs a third party package.
Now how do we install it.
First of all we have to know the package name.
And if you're wondering well how do I know the package name.
Well that comes with Courcelles like this experience or by simply googling for certain problems which
you want to have solved and all the Zohn you find to read where some package is mentioned.
Now I can tell you for does auto restart mechanism.
There is a package called Node 1 written like this.
By the way you can always search for NPM and then the package name if you know that name and you will
find an entry on NPM Chaske dot com.
Now it is just the package page basically where you find a description installation instructions usage
instructions how to configure it because most package has give you a easy way of using it and then always
give you configuration possibilities.
You'll see how popular the package is.
What's worse it's using if there is an extra little home page where the source code can be found if
it's open source.
So you find a bunch of stuff here pretty useful.
You also see how many words are existing.
And by default you will always install the latest version by the way.
But let's go back to installing it.
Before we dive deeper into this whole NPM thing.
So we want to install it and this command would install it.
But don't hit enter yet.
You can define how it should be installed because packages which you install can be divided into development
packages so packages which are mostly help you during development and production dependencies.
So Pecka chest it helps you for the app as it's running on a server for example node Mohn would be a
development dependency because we only use it during the development process.
Once we install our app on a real server we don't need it there.
The real server which is running somewhere in the Internet of course shouldn't restart.
And it also doesn't have to because will not change its code dynamically.
And you can basically tell NPM which kind of dependency this is just does not make a huge difference
and you can omit the setting but it helps you understand which package is used for what now you do this
by adding dash dash safe dash death.
If you had just save like this does would install it as a production dependency.
So a package which we really use and use in our code and work with and with does we're indicating that
this is only at something we used during development.
There is a third option by the way.
Dash G will not install it in this project but Clovelly on your machine.
So did you can use it anywhere.
Now let's first of all install it with save death like this dash dash safe dash death.
Now what this will do is it will downloaded from any member of Pozza Tory and install it into this project.
So not globally on your machine but into this project.
So now you see you get a report here that it finished successfully what it did and it gives you a couple
of new things in your project.
It gives you that node modules full or the package lock Jason file and it updated the package up Jason
fall.
There we see that the new def the pendency section was at it and that stands for development dependencies.
As I said you can differentiate between different dependencies.
We'll see production dependencies later too.
And there you see that gnomon was installed and which version was picked.
Now regarding that character here.
Well this basically defines how this package will be updated.
If you rerun just NPM install without defining an extra package name because this command stand alone
will simply go for all your packages mentioned in package deal Jason and install them and it would automatically
pick a later version if available.
But more on NPM and packages can all be found in a separate module.
Later in the course.
So this is basically how we now install this.
And the question is Where is it installed.
Well that is the node modules folder.
And actually that is a huge folder as you can tell the reason for it is this dead.
For one we got node Mohn in there.
If we look for and we see it here.
Now this is basically the source code of the package or the belt weren't off the package we installed
and does package simply happens to have a couple of peer dependencies.
You can see them here and here.
So we got a bunch of dependencies in there and Ds and their dependencies are all installed.
That is why you could end up with quite a big node modules folder but you can always delete that node
modules folder if you need to free up space.
Now you can use that package but you can then rerun and install if you start working on that project
again and it will re-install this package and all its pure dependencies and therefore recreate the node
modules folder.
This is how packages work in node projects.
So you need that node Marshall's folder was still using the packages but if youre not working on the
project you can delete it if you want if you need the free space and then just remember to rerun NPM
install once you are working on the project again.
The package lock Jason File by the way just stores to exact weapons I installed today so that if you
share your project with honors they can actually get these exact words to instead of the latest versions.
But again more on and PM in a separate module.