So for now we got Dad gnomon package installed and it will just work because it automatically installed
all the dependencies.
This package needs in turn.
So how can we now use it.
Node one is a utility tool and it allows us to run our application our node application through this
package here which will run node apps.
Yes and he in the end but who will also watch our files for changes and restart the process for us if
we do change something so we can simply change start here.
So the note I have aperture has command to gnomon app.
Yes and this will look for a node Mawn tool which you will find in this project because we install it
here as a side note.
If you were to run node one actually down there you would get an error that this command is not found
because its only installed in this project and not globally on your machine but the terminal will try
to find us globally here.
It will work because this will look globally.
So if you now run A.P.M. start this will simply start the node server and outputs some extra information
and if you now go to your routes she has fallen out at something.
Lets just add an extra line and you save that file you see it's restarting.
And this of course is very convenient because now we dont have to spend time on manually exiting and
restarting.
Now is this done for us.