Syntax errors can be very annoying.
But most of the time they're not that hard to fix.
Let's add a simple syntax error here an app chase let's simply remove d t in concert.
Now all of a sudden this is an invalid keyword.
It doesn't exist it's not a keyword.
And we already get some help in the ID which is showing us something is wrong here.
Now if we hover over this we see that a semi-colon is expected.
And actually this is not that helpful.
And this is simply because we to do code things so that this is a variable.
And since we have a variable in the same line we should close this with a semi-colon.
And now it actually doesn't show an error but let's save this and let's try running our app with end
start without me call and B get it and you will see it right away.
Crashes and in there we see unexpected identifier Condes server.
So in the end was it doesn't clearly tell us that we forgot duty here because it's not smart enough
to understand that this is the error here.
We still see that the error seems to be stemming from this line.
And in such cases as dumb as it sounds you should simply take a closer look at this line and see what
could be wrong there.
And you should quickly be able to see.
I've got a t here.
So these are syntax errors.
Abra Aeros would be that you maybe go to reroutes shares fall and let's say you forget a closing curly
Brasier.
Now again we're just to decode Das complainant's does show an error over there.
If we chumped there we see at the end that the closing curly braces are expected.
Now it's not expected at this point where it's showing this message but it's expected somewhere in the
file and once it can be cumbersome.
You should then check your block statements like this if statement and see if they're all closed correctly
in to do code you also get some help because if you click next to such up call the brace you'll see
that this line gets highlighted and that actually shows you where it thinks that this is getting closed.
And this is far too much at the bottom here.
For example again if you run this you will see that a trashiest And there you also see unexpected token
and it points us en route.
Yes.
And then you see the line number two.
So here it points us the line 52 and it basically shows us the same place as well suited code which
is the wrong place.
But in such a case here you should really take the ID help see that error message and then go through
your follow and see.
Hmm where could I be missing a character or where do I have an extra closing curly brace or something
like debt.
And eventually you should be able to find this error and Thale for of course fix it.
So syntax arrows should always result in the error message and then that can sometimes be hard to find
them.
Often it's like a typo a mis typed variable name of a variable that therefore doesn't exist or missing
or extra characterise but you can find them and it just takes some time to go for your fall.