Now we work with the debugger a bit and offered his lecture.
You'll also find a lecturer with a link to a more detailed explanation of the debugging capabilities
Visual Studio code gives you don't learn them by heart but feel free to explore them to get the most
out of the debugger for you.
Now there are two things I want to show you or I want to draw your attention to.
One is something you already saw.
That's at a break point again and again I submit this.
I already showed you that you can execute code here in that D-Backs consul at the bottom.
So you don't Chessie to consul locks here you can also execute code here.
For example you can type variable name here.
So something which is a way level in your code at this point of time in general is something which you
can find in local or in block here or in global.
So the things you find here like message you can also type that down there and hit enter to print its
value.
And this is of course Nadra useful for printing because you can see the value on the left.
But as I show you for PARSE body you cannot just print the value.
You can also run operations on it that will not affect your code as it's running but that will allow
you to look into it or try out some transformation before you add it to your real code.
So whatever you run down there does not affect the code you run up here but it is nice for you to understand
your code.
The other thing I want to show you is that for now at the moment if we change something in our code
here let's say we add a blank line our debugger doesn't restart bad with node Mawn we actually have
a package that does allow us to restart.
So it would be nice if the debugger would also restart if we change our code.
Otherwise just behave differently than the rest of our app and we have to restart it manually now to
restart it.
Let's go back to the explorer view for a second.
We have to go to debark and then add a configuration for node.
Yes this adds dot to be is code folder with the launch base and fall.
And this allows you to configure debugging for this project and how it behaves can click or add configuration
to see some demo settings you can get but you can also just type in there and one setting you can add
as restart and you can set it to true.
You just have to make sure that you also add some refuels.
For example you have to make sure that no one is used for dead you set the runtime executable not to
node which would be the default but to node one.
Here it's now dual use Node 1.
And it will restart the debugger when a change is detected.
So the not just the server is restarted but also the debugging process here by the way in this configuration.
You can also define that it should always start with the actually as follows.
So that you can even have to route's chase files like that while starting debugging and it will still
go for the capture useful which is more convenient than always selecting the file you want to debug
first before starting the debugger and you always have to pick the fall because that starts your server.
So you can say I'm going to look into drought's chess fall salts start with that.
It always has to be the objects fall because you always have to start the entire server.
So here you can define that it will always pick that no matter which file you have currently open.
You can also change to console where things are locked to to the integrated terminal with just a normal
terminal.
With this if you save all of that and you now start dividing it fails though.
And the reason for this is that it will not use a local node.
But it looks for it globally.
Now to add it globally you have to run an install node Mawn dash G.
And now important on Mac and Linux you might need to add sudo in front of this.
On Windows you don't get the right permissions to install this that you might be prompted for your password.
And now it will install Nodong globally which makes sure that if you ever run node one in the terminal
now it will not fail with a not found error but instead it will find it.
And therefore now you can also run in this debugger here which will use the global worsen and you'll
see it now opens terminal starts node one and if you know at a breakpoint somewhere and submit does
again it still works.
Ask before just important.
You now see the terminal here.
Laux all the things you can still use to debug console to output messages though so you can still work
with this.
As I showed it to you as a does is not stopped from working this still is something you can use but
in the terminal you get the normal output and you have to use a terminal because if you now change something
it restarts the debugger and node and these are two separate processes.
And if you stop the debugger node one has to quit separately or asked to exit separately and you do
this by adding control.
See here and this couldn't be done in the debug console which is why you have to funnel this to the
terminal.
So that's just something to keep in mind.
You have to stop that process separately which you can do from the terminal which is why if you are
using that node on process you should use the integrated terminal and you can read more about that in
that detailed visual studio code debugging article.
But now you have a set up where you have a debugger attached to your program that will restart if you
edit something where the server will restart.
If you added something and where you have now all the tools you should need to debug your node app and
hopefully solve any errors you get.
Now one important note for the rest of the Course I'll mostly use and him start and not have the debugger
attached all the time.
I will only use that if there is some error a one particularly D-bag with the debugger and one of find
with the debugger so you can use it as a default always on option.
I prefer to not to use it to not have that extra panel and so on.
But really just use the server and work on that.