There's one more feature about the Nocenti bagger which I also haven't shown you yet but which of course
don't want to forget if you start debugging your.
And here I just used the shortcut and you place a breakpoint anywhere in your app and then do something
to trigger that break point.
I showed you that you can look into all these variables and that you can look into them in the debug
console without changing them while sometimes you might want to change them.
And that can be done by going to the debug view here and then by simply typing in there.
Now for example the parsed body holds this string and you can't just change it.
And now this will affect the runtime as conceived you hover over this.
So now if I just resume execution with my code which doesn't have a back right now and I go back to
my explorer of view here then you will see that as stored testing here which is de-value I added it
in the debugger so you can actually manipulate the values Stehr off the variables and so on if you need
to.
You can do that because this of course allows you to make sure that you can quickly test something.
This is just another useful feature which I wanted to share with you since it can help you with debugging
your code being able to untypically some values there.