Now in this Monch year we had a look at how we can have an easier time developing or building no chess
applications I guess.
And as we started with NPM the node package manager which allows us to manage our project and mostly
it's dependencies but also which added this package done Jason and gave us the opportunity of adding
scripts there.
So with NPM in it you can initialize a new project you basically add a package.
Jason with that command and then you saw that you can use scripts to define shortcuts to commands you
run all the time anyways.
We also use NPM to install third party packages though because node projects typically don't just use
the core modules for your own code but often you want to pull in third party packages utility packages
like gnomon as we did here but also as you will see in the next section.
Real big packages that we use in our production code express japes is what will end Stalder.
You can install different kinds of dependencies which doesn't really make a difference you could use
them all even without specifying any of these options but it helps you keep track of which dependency
you are using for what.
Dash dash safe and dash dash safe def allow you to differentiate between production and development
dependencies and global dependencies with dash she can be run from within the terminal without getting
a command not found error.
Speaking of errors well.
In your code you often have errors.
That is absolutely normal and there are different types of arrows.
You can have a look at syntax runtime and logical arrows are different categories of errors.
I identified Sendak's and runtime errors.
At least fro hopefully helpful error message.
And you should read these messages and look at the line numbers they give you because data off helps
you find out what went wrong and how to fix this logical errors often are more difficult to fix.
But you can fix them often with a lot of testing and possibly the help of the debugger which you learned
how to use with the help of Visual Studio code in this section.
Speaking of debugging debugging can be a helpful process because you can use via's code or debuggers
of over IDs that can be used with node to look into your code whilst it's running and step through it
step by step.
You can analyze the variable values at runtime and you cannot just look into them but you can also manipulate
them as you learn.
You do all that by setting breakpoints sauted you define when your code execution should stop and give
you an opportunity to look into the code you can find more than one breakpoint at a time and you should
manage them cleverly.
Keep in mind how note code executes dead.
It's not line after line but deaded works with callbacks and is event driven and therefore if you want
to look into a callback you have to add the breakpoint there and not right before it with all that you
hopefully get useful tools that help you build your no chase applications.