So let's start with resetting passwords.
Obviously that's a common thing you need to do in applications.
People forget passwords.
You want to offer them a way of resetting them for that we will need a new view and some new routes.
Let's start with their view maybe.
So in the off folder I'll add reset Ejay last fall you can name it however you want.
You could name and password reset.
E.J..
Yes of course I'll copy my log in Ejaz code pasted in there.
But of course adjusted a little bit.
I'll still leave the error message here because eventually I might display one.
I don't want the password field here but I need to see or token and any email field because I want users
to enter the email for which they want to reset the password.
Then here I'll label this button reset password like this.
So now we have that reset Ejay as the new.
Let's now go to the off controller file and add some new actions to it.
So export a new action which I'll name get reset.
That should simply render that reset page.
So here we have the well-known function with the free arguments and in there all use response Rander
and will render a page just as we did it many times before.
So I'll just copy that from up here to type less render a page off reset.
Is the view Porth here.
The path to your L will be just slash reset.
Let's say title of the page could be reset password.
Now regarding the error message.
I'll also copy that this code here where I extract any message that might exist and pass it to to view.
And with that we get decontrol or action.
Let's now create a fitting route in the off route's file.
Here I will add and you get route to slash reset and use off controller get resets your.
This is the route I want to load when we request a password reset.
With that we just need a way to reach that route and that would be on the log in page of course there.
To load a form we want to offer a reset password link.
So here I'll add a new link which leads to slash reset where I say reset password like dat.
Well that's all the wrap that in some Dith and give div a class of center it does as a class.
I did find earlier in the course no back on the log in page.
If we reloaded we have reset passwords here.
Now you can work on the styling if you want.
The main thing is if I click on it I'm taking to my reset password page.
Now the idea would be that you enter a password and then you receive an email with a password reset
link.
Now let's start working on that in the next actress.