So we want to be able to enter the email address here and then receive an email with a link that allows
us to reset the password.
Now for that we need to first of all create a unique token that also has some expiry date which we will
store in our database so that the link which we didn't click includes that token and we can verify that
the user did get that link from us because if we just well let the user now change their password we
got no security mechanism in place so we need that token to put it into the email we're about to send
to only lead users change the password through the email that contains that token.
That's an additional security mechanism.
So let's work on that tokin creation date for that.
First of all I'll export a new action in my off controller that will be post reset so that will basically
the action that should get triggered once we clicked that reset password button of your and in there
I need to generate that token.
Now note J ass has a built in crypto library which I can use for debt.
So name that tripto and require crypto like debt does is a library that helps us with creating secure
unique random values and honorifics but we'll need dead unique secure random value here.
So here in post we settled and used that crypto library which I stored in a constant here.
And I will call random bytes to generate some random bytes I want.
32 random bytes and this will call a callback function years that is the second argument a function
will be called once it's done there.
Either get an error or a buffer a buffer of bytes.
Now I have an error here.
Then I want to return redirect back to let's say reset and we could flag the error message here if we
wanted to also lock the error so that we can debug it.
But if we make it past this check we do have a valid buffer.
And then we can generate a token from that buffer simply by using buffer to string and there we just
need to pass hecks because that buffer will store hexadecimal values.
And this is information to string needs to go to a word hexadecimal values to normal ASCII characters.
So then we'll have a token.
Now that token should get stored in the database and it should get stored on the user object because
it belongs to that user.
So let's first of all go to your user model and there I'll add two new fields.
I'll add a reset token and I'll just assign a type of string here.
Now important this is not required because not always this token will be there only if we requested
a reset and will have a reset token expiration or however you want to name it.
And that will be of time date.
And now I want to store Des's token on the user which we plan to reset.
So first of all I need to find that user in the database and I'll use the mongooses user model for that
to find one user where d e mail matches the email we're trying to reset and dead email which we're trying
to reset can be extracted from the request for the email field because on our reset the new heater we
do have that email field.
By the way important the action here should be slash reset to reach the right route but with that business
prepared and now in our controller I'm finding a user who has this email let's add them and catch handle
any potential error we might get by logging it for now.
And then then we should get a user or undefined if that user does not exist.
So any here I want to check if we don't have a user.
If we don't have a user then I will flash a message such as you learned in the authentication module
onto the error or key no account with that e-mail found or whatever message you want to show.
And then here all return a redirect to slash reset.
If we make it past this check then we are looking for a e-mail address that is stored in the database.
And now for that user who will which I retrieved for that e-mail address I want to set the reset token
equal to the token which I generated and I will set the reset token expiration equal to date now which
gives me the current date and time plus one hour.
And this now has to be expressed in milliseconds.
So you should use three million six 600 thou Malis seconds.
This will be one hour since I'm assigning these two fields and we can call user is safe to then update
our user in the database.
Let's return this so that we can now chain and number then call here number.
Then block which will execute this function when users save succeeds.
So at this point of time we know that the update user was stored in that database and now we want to
send that token reset email.
Now I showed you how to send e-mails in the last lecture and the last module I mean.
So make sure you go for that because I will now use that transporter again which I created there.
The node mailer transporter which we use for sending email.
And it will send an e-mail to the e-mail of the user which we found so to use her e-mail excuse me to
request bawdy e-mail we can say so to the e-mail we're requesting the reset for the subject could be
password reset and now any HDMI all the code.
I'll use a next gen feature back Tick's which allows me to write multiline strings which makes it easier
to read.
I'll add a paragraph where I say you requested a password reset so users should be worried if they get
that.
If they did not click this link to set a new password and you could include more information like the
fact that this is only valid for one hour.
Now this link here does will be anchored tech leading at some your el and that you are l will be in
our case your localhost 3000.
And then let's say reset and then the token which we have now since I'm using this back takes syntax
I can dynamically embed values with a special syntax.
Use dollar sign curly braces.
And now I can inject variables and their values into this string and the values of the variables will
be placed in that string.
So here I can now output that token which we generated here.
So now I am placing that in the U R L because that token then what will later look for in the database
to confirm that this link was sent by us because only we know the token.
So this will send an email and at the same time I will redirect back to the starting page let's say
because the next instructions are received in the email of course.
Now let's try this out in the next lecture.