So let's give this a try this reset back and it's for did we first of all need to make sure that our
newly added control or actions can be reached.
So we added get reset route.
Now we also need to add post reset route so that this reset password button actually works.
So let's add this route and execute post reset that action we worked on.
And with that the reset password page let's first of all try out an incorrect or Al e-mail one which
does not exist in the database and we get this message which is great.
Now I use a real email which you used for signing up and clicked reset password or you should be redirected
back.
And if you check your emails there you should have a password reset email with a link.
If you click that link you should end up on a page not found error but you will see that were on reset
and then some token and that token can also be seen in your user collection here.
This is the password reset token which restored.
So now we just need to add some logic to add does route extract that token valid date wherever we have
a user for the token and then offer a form that allows the user to set a new password.
Let's work on that next.