So we got to tell can let's now add a form which allows to user to enter a new password.
And for that I will go into my views folder again the all folder there.
New password dot Ejaz or however you want to name this and they all use my log NHS page copy all that
content into here.
And then let's just maybe grab our password field here remove to e-mail for sure you can't add you email
re-enabled a button to update password.
You need to see SRF token the action here should be maybe new password whatever you want.
A POST request to new password reset password does not make any sense here.
So let's remove that link.
And now we got a prepared password page.
Now we want to load debt.
So we need a controller action exports get new password maybe where we again have the free arguments
we all know and love and in there let's render a view.
So I'll just copy that rest surrender method.
And I want to render my off new dash passwords new path is new.
New passwords and your the title can be new password.
I also will add my code for extracting a potential error message if I should work with one.
So now I have my get new password action.
Obviously I don't just want to render a dead view here though.
I also want to check whether I find a user for data token which I receive here because this will be
the page we load for this page where we do have a token.
Indeed you are.
So let's retrieve that token.
First of all by request from request Perens token.
Let's say we'll need to add a route later that and Cote's the token in a token field in our parameters
and then all of find one user where it is token fits now.
Our tokens are generated in a random non guessable way.
You can also enter random tokens and start editing passwords of Abra users and even if you could you
would not know to in email addresses so here or find a token with the reset token field which we add
at your reset token.
So looking for Racette token being equal to the token I have your end we want to make sure that it's
still valid from a date perspective so that the documents find does not just fulfil this criteria but
another one to add more criteria with Colma that the reset token expiration is still well higher than
the current date.
For data I can use a special operator wrapped in curly braces.
Dollar Sign G.T. stands for a greater than and I can simply compare if it's greater than now for the
current date and time only if the token matches and the token expiration is still greater than now so
the token expiration is in the future.
Only then I have to use or I wanted to find.
So here I'll add then and catch log any errors I might be getting.
And then the then block I get the user for whom we want to reset the password.
So it's here inside of that.
Then block that I want to render my new password the You and I want to pass my user ID to that view
so that I can include it in the post request where we will update the password.
So here I will include user ID too.
String maybe to convert it from an object ID to a real string.
So now we render a new password and on the new password page I will duplicate my hidden C is our token
field because I'll also have a user ID field now which is also hidden right output.
Dead user id I'm passing into the view so does input is new.
With that hidden user ID and it will output that user ID will need deadfall to post requests when we
want to save our new password.
OK so with that let's go to our routes to offer routes here and let's add a new get to Routier to get
new password route where I will use the get new password controller action.
Now it's not just new password by the way or it will not be new password at all it will be reset.
But then there will be a token.
So you are Ls reset and then a dynamic parameter.
The token parameter and it has to be named token here because in that get new password off controller.
I am looking for token in my parents so token here which I'm looking for in request parens means I have
to name it token here as well.
And with that let's go back and reload this page.
And now I'm on that update password page which is looking good now and next let's add the logic to updates
that password.