We added a page that allows us to enter a new password the new password due here and there we will send
a POST request to slash new password.
Now we need to add that route and controller action as a next step so that the existing user password
can be replaced with the new one.
So back to the off controller let's add a new controller action.
The post new password action and you guessed it which arguments we have in that function here.
And then enter here what do we need to do.
Well we need to extract the new password from request body password and that is request bawdy password
because the new password view I'm storing the password in a field named password and will need to extract
that user ID or two so that user ID is also something user ID is equal to request bawdy user ID.
We need that as well.
I also still want to have that token because otherwise people could start entering random tokens here
and still reach that page and then maybe change users on the back and by entering random user IDs and
that hidden input field as well.
So I want to have that token and therefore you password also add a neighborhood input field password
token an output password token here.
So that is a Number field and I need to pass that token into my view.
So that is something for get a new password for this action here.
I need to pass password token as a variable into the view and it will hold the token I'm extracting
from the U R L here and that is the token we originally generated.
So this is now all the past and this is not also something I can extract here the password token request
bawdy password token extract that from that password token field here.
OK so now we got these three pieces of information in here.
Now I want to reset my user so I will again find one user in my database and I'll find the user.
Where do we set.
Token is equal to the password token where the reset token expiration is again greater than dates now.
So the same logic as I did up here and where d id is equal to my user ID.
I'll then again add then and catch log any errors we might be facing here.
And then I'll have my user that fulfills all these criteria.
And then here I want to assign a new password to the user.
Now obviously for that I'll again hash it because that doesn't change.
It still should be hashed.
So I'll again use the script hash pass in the new password and my number off salting rounds twelth and
I will return this year and then add another then block the hashed password where I can stored it on
the extracted user.
However the user is an argument in this function but I need it here to be able to access it in this
function as well.
I will create a new variable up there user or reset user end a will store user in reset user so in that
variable because that variable is defined in disfunctions scope.
So I can use it in this and in this function.
And now I can use reset user in here too.
And I can use it to call resets user and set the password equal to the new Hash password.
And for the Reset user I will also set reset token equal to now.
And I will also set reset target expiration to null here or not to now set it to undefined.
So these fields here are not required anymore.
They don't need to store any values anymore.
Once I'm done I can call save here and return that in here.
I'll then have my result of that save operation.
And once he did save I can now redirect the user back to the log in page with that new password.
You could also send the number email confirming that reset if you wanted to.
And now she is saved.
Let's reload that password resetting page here.
And let's add a new entry and you password click Update password and I get a page not found which makes
sense obviously because I have when you post route but I need to register it as a route.
I have my action or I should say I need to register it as a route.
So in the off G-S file here we need to add a new post request to new password and execute off controller
post-New password there.
That is important.
Safe that.
Then simply go back to the page where you have that token in the U R L enter your password.
Let's also quickly reload our users collection before we have safe and kind of memorize de-value here.
It ends with x y w y and click Update password I'm on the logon page.
And now if I reload my users collection that password here should change and it doesn't allow get a
reset token on it's gone.
I also have no error here.
So it looks like password resetting was successful.
We successfully assigned a new password.
Now if we try going to reset with some random token then this will not work and we're not doing proper
error handling there.
I'll have a whole module in that because we essentially failed to find a user for that token.
So this all works.
We can start changing values of random tokens off of random users.
So this will not require.