So we worked a lot on resetting passwords.
Let's now work on offer I sation.
And with that I mean that not every authenticated user is allowed to do everything.
A good example would be this one.
I'm not locked in.
Now let me log in with this user here test a test that can here I might be able to add a product and
I can delete products but right now I can delete all products no matter if I created them or if someone
else created them.
And the same is true for editing them offer a sation means that I restrict permissions all a logged
in user.
So every user might be able to add anything to the card including products created by the user but you
might not be able to delete and edit products which were not created by you.
So for now I can do that.
But that's exactly what I want to work on next.
So that we can do this.
Now how can we implement that.
Well when I create a new product let me quickly do that.
Remember I'm locked in with test at test dot com.
This was created by test at test dot com when I created this product here.
We have it here and we can see it in the product collection obviously it's linked to the user with an
ID that ends with E 5.
And if we have a look at all our users let me delete this one here.
Then we see this is the one with E5.
It is to test to test that user.
Now if I log in with my test to account so test to hear
then if I go to Aben products I can also edit and delete that.
And that is exactly what I want to prevent.
Let's do that in the next lecture.