So how can we at all for I say.
I sure that I can't delete or edit this book with or this product with the wrong account.
Now we do have important information stored on the product.
We know which user did create it.
So in the end we just want to check if it's currently locked and user is the user who created that before
allowing any edits to that item.
And that means that on the admin controller where we render our admin list here get products here.
I only want to render products that were created by the locked end user because there is no sense in
showing products on this page that were not created by the user because were in the admin section.
You are not able to do anything with it if you weren't a creator.
So authorisations simply means we restrict to permissions and we can do that by restricting the data
we return for example.
So here when I find products I dont find all but Ill add a filter and filter for products where the
user ID is equal to the user id of the currently locked in user so user ID is equal to request user
id ID.
And keep in mind request user exists because we do extract that user in actually yes in a separate middleware.
Here they are.
I do store the user request.
User so I know that only products which were created by that user should be retrieved with that change.
If I reload this page I find no products for test 2 but if I do log in with my other account with test
at tests dot com and I go to Aben products I do find that book.
So that is the first important step forwards.
The problem is I could theoretically still issue requests behind the scenes where I do try to delete
a product which was not created by me.
So more protection is needed.
Lets add that next.