We're restricting the amount of products we can see.
And that is one great step forward.
But it still doesn't mean we can't send requests somehow by by creating our own pages where we still
try to delete a number product.
So we should also add protections in our post actions like in post edit and post delete product there
we want to check that the product I try to delete is really created by the user who is currently locked
in.
So in post edit product there I might want to add a check.
Once I found the product it should be added that where I see if I'm allowed to edit that product.
So you're in the then block where I have that product fetched from the database there I will quickly
check if product user ID is not equal to request user ID because if it's not equal then this means the
wrong user is trying to edit this.
So here I don't want to return and simply redirect back to the starting page let's say because we try
to do something fishy here.
We don't want to continue.
So all the code will now not run.
We would still go into that.
Then block though as you learned because the next then block is still executed even if I do redirect
here.
So to circumvent this I'll add.
Then right after his savior.
So I nested then block so to say and now we have protection place that ensures that we can start editing
products that don't belong to us to quickly check this all temporarily remove my filters so that I can
see all the products again and I will log in with the wrong account.
So if test to and now what we should see is that when I edit this and add a couple of exclamation marks
and click Update I'm redirected to edit wasn't saved because I essentially ended up in my extra check
here and it was redirect that back but with out saving the changes because this code was never executed.
Now let's try the same for deleting before I reset my filter here for deleting.
I also want to check if I'm really allowed to delete that product and we can easily implement this by
changing our deletion method here and use delete one.
And there I wanted to lead the product where the ID is equal to the prod ID but also where the user
ID is equal to the request.
User ID.
So both has to be true.
Now the Product ID alone is not enough to user id also asked to match and therefore even if we have
a valid user id it will not delete this product if the user ID does not match.
So if I saved this and I go to Aben products with the wrong account still and they click delete.
You see the product doesn't go anywhere.
Still there.
Now let me add that filter and get products again so that we can't even see it.
And now we have the best possible set up because now we can really only see it in that account where
we are able to interact with it.
So if I do log in with that valid account there I do see it and there I now all this should be able
to edit it though if I try that it fails.
So let's explore what's wrong here in the next lecture.