Editing fails here.
And do you have an idea why it fails.
It fails because of my check here.
I compared the product user ID to request user ID.
Now we have a type problem again I should convert both to a string because I'm all checking for Typee
quality.
So with this change both converge to a string and not does strange object id thing with this emplace.
Now if I log in or if I'm locked in with the right account.
Now I can update this and I can also delete this.
So this now all works with the right account.
So with the account who created it.
But it will not work if I log in with the wrong account because of a log in there.
So this is now their account which did not create it.
I can view it on the normal pages.
I can add it to my card if I want to but under Edit products I do not see it.
And even if I would see it I could not interact with it.