In this module we had a look at some advanced authentication related topics Namely we had to look at
password resetting and there it was important to understand that you of course have to implement password
reset in a way that prevents users from resetting Random User Accounts.
Therefore we implemented such a short lived password token so that it's not valid forever.
To reduce the chance of it being generated by some brute force attack and therefore our Reset token
is a great mechanism to identify the user for whom we want to reset the password to tokin has to be
generated in a way that is random.
Unguessable at least in a reasonable amount of time.
Hence the expiration date and unique.
And in this module we implemented a token in exactly that way.
We also had a look at all Farai sation and off recession is all about locking down access for authenticated
users because just because you're offended that you're not allowed to do everything you might be locked
in and you're using the account but you can't edit my course because you are not the creator of the
course and that's the idea of authorization and that is also what we did in this module when we ensured
that only users who created a product can actually do edit and delete it.
So off session is a crucial part of most applications.
And together with authentication which is the surrounding topic of having users in general you can really
control which Wiznitzer can do what in your web app in your web site.