So let's work on that log in page and forget First of all add new routes file which all name off J.S.
and in there I want to manage my authentication related routes.
Now for that I will first of all set this up in a similar way to my eyebrowed files which means I will
set up the Express router.
So let me simply create that here.
We don't need the admin control though so we have that router and an export led router and for now I
need one get out in here get route for Slash log in then which will load the log in page.
So slash log in is what I want to handle here.
And as always we have our request response the next function here for handling that incoming request.
Now in order to reach that route we of course need to register it in the app js file and in app J.S..
First of all let's import that route.
So I'll duplicate my shop routes name them all routes the name is up to you of course and it's in the
off file in the routes folder.
So that file we just added and wifi off routes there.
I would simply add them below my shop routes just like the shop routes.
I have no leading filter.
So every request will go in there and anything which is not found in the shop routes will therefore
go into the off routes and the off routes it will handle.
Slash log in this route here now here.
I simply want to render a page and I want to render a page in let's say off folder and just as I do
this in the shop controller here I will also create a off controller for dad.
So let's maybe duplicate does get orders action from the shop controller added here.
And let's name it.
Get log in.
And then I don't need to find any orders or anything like that.
Dead of course can be removed.
I just want to render something.
I want to render off log in here.
The possibility slash log in your orders Well I will simply nameless log in and I don't pass any other
data.
So it's a really simple controller action in my office last fall and with that in the off Chia's file
in the route's folder I can simply import dat.
So here I will import my off controller by requiring that from the control of folder and the website
off file there.
And then here for log in I will not use the function but point at my controller with the get Logan function.
Ok so now we get the same setup we used for the other routes and now we have that log in controller
action which will render the log in page with the appropriate title.
Now let me head over to navigation.
E.J. asks a real quick and make sure that this gets highlighted when we are on the page.
And for that I will copy that class assignments that see is as class assignment editor here.
And the payoff should be slash log in or whatever you assigned in your controller action.
With that out of the way let's add that folder and file in the views folder.
So we'll add an off folder here and in there a log in.
E.J. last fall because that is just what I try to render my controller right there.
I tried to render off log in.
So we need to have that lbf and file in our views folder and for that I will really just use my product
me in my admin edited product page because there I have a form and I will move that into the log in
Ejaz fall.
I will include head yes.
I don't need to product C as s but I need the forms.
C S S.
I will include the navigation then this year will receive a new class we can name this log in form and
see how we have to adjust the styling for that.
Then the action here well that action will always be the same.
We don't have different modes here.
The action is always log in and we send the post request to log in route and then here let's say we
have an email address we name that field email here and we give it an ideal email.
It's all of type email and all of type text.
And let's not start with a default value so we don't need that here.
And we all need a password let's say let's add password to your name this password and give it an ID
of password and to type here will also be password so that the characters are hidden.
And with that we get rid of this value here.
Now we don't need the phone controls so we can get rid of these form controls.
Also of the hidden one for now and let's simply add a button at the bottom which is of type submit and
which simply says log in.
So really simple form with all of that in place.
If we now click onto that log in button we are in d loading that log in page.
Now the styling is a bit off because we need to style that log in form and that our real quick ad.
And you see as a file which I'll name off SEUS as an in there on the log in form.
Let's have a look at the product form.
I think we can just reuse that style here.
And yes we could have therefore all Azel like refactored it into a global style but I'll just do it
like this and then log it Ejaz.
We now just make do need to make sure that we do also import that new offices as Falah just added.
So if you now reload this this looks pretty good.
So now we got this in place.
And as I mentioned I will not implement a full log flow right now.
We'll do that in the next module where we dive into authentication and everything that belongs to it.
But here I want to show you how we can use a cookie to save information that this user is locked in.
And that will continue in the next lecture and see how we can use cookies.