So in the last lecture we edit this log in a form which you can reach by clicking on log in here on
the top right corner.
And you can simply download the attached code to have that same starting project.
If you download it.
Just make sure that you use your database credentials here when connecting to the database because mine
won't work for you obviously because I shut down the server after I'm done recording.
So I edit this log in page and will not implement authentication right now.
We'll do this in a separate module but this is a great Dhami scenario for using a cookie because let's
say when we click that submit button here the log in button we will actually send a log in request to
the backend because that is what we stored in the log in form here and off log in we are sending a POST
request to slash log in.
And since we do that we should handle this and we want you in a real scenario validator to e-mail that
password in this module will not do that we'll just assume that the input data is valid.
Because it's not the topic we'll focus on for now.
So let's add a new controller action first of all in the office last fall and all named post log in.
Now in post log in I will get my log and data e-mail password and so on and I don't really care about
that data so I'll just assume the user is locked in and will then redirect to just slash.
However And now that is important.
If we do it like this and we add a route for it is of course to our off route file.
So here is this post a post request to slash log in and we used to post log in controller action.
If I do this and then click on log and here I am indeed forwarded to the slash route.
OK.
So this could mean we are authenticated.
Now let's say we want to store that information that the user is authenticated.
How could we store that.
Well you could say I go into my controller and in post look and where I do lock to use written I stored
that information in my request object is locked in because we are already doing a similar thing.
Actually yes.
Right at the start we fetch our one dummy user and stored it in the request so that we can use it for
the rest of that request.
So in all the routes and controllers where we handle that request we can do the same here and set it
to true by default right at the start it will not be set.
So the value will be undefined which is treated as false and that is the information I need now to validate
whether that works.
Let's actually go to our views and deer in the navigationally chest.
I commented out to rabbits for which we could say we need to use or to be authenticated.
Let's comment them in but only render them if the user is authenticated.
So how would we go about that.
Well we could use Ejaz for that of course and we can check if let's say we expect to get some authenticated
value here.
So if is ofay they hate it then we'll do something will render this part here and otherwise this will
not be rendered because we don't make it into that if block.
So if I do it like this and I reload this page I get an error.
Dead.
Is that OK that is not defined.
Because we're not always rendering this to our different views.
So what we actually need to do since the whole thing is part of every page for every render call here.
We need to pass the information whether the user is authenticated or not.
And for that access request is authenticated because that is exactly where is locked in excuse me is
locked in because that is the field we're storing that information.
So access request is locked in because that is what I will set to true when we do log in.
So our ad is authenticated and stored at value to every render recall here.
Here hear for get at product.
Also on the error page here like this and awls in shop Ejaz of course for all our routes here like this
one basically every time when we call render in all these cases I will add my is authenticated information
so now that I added it to all routes and I saved all files if I reload I still failed because I obviously
alternated need to render and edits to off Jay as to my render out there.
So now if I reload this works and we are missing these two fields if I log in we are still missing them
though.
And why is that.
Do you know why this does not work.
Even though I am storing the information that I am locked in in is locked in.
When we click that button I just ring it in my request and then I use that information request on every
route I handle and I pass it into is authenticated which is the field which I'm using in my front to
my navigation there.
I am checking for is authenticated and that is what I am passing today at Front-End in my render called
here.
Well the problem of course is yes I update is locked in here in the request and what happens to the
request once I send a response.
And we do send a response by redirecting.
Well the request is that it's done with a response.
We basically finished a request we got a request and we sent the response.
We're done.
This data does not stick around.
This data is lost after the request or after we send the response.
So whenever we wisit a different page like here where we do get redirected so we get redirected here
and we reach our Get index action here in the end and there we do render the sharp index page.
But this is a brand.
You request their redirection creates a brand new request and does a super important to understand we're
working with totally separate requests and that is important because your application your page will
have hundreds of users and obviously the requests of all these users are not related to job.
Otherwise you could maybe look into data that they shouldn't see and even the requests of a single user.
So requests made from the same IP address are treated as totally independent requests.
They are not seen in a bigger context or anything like that.
And this is a good thing.
This is deliberately designed that way and for any data we store here can be used as long as we are
working on the same request.
That is why when we retrieve the user and actually is here and it is stored in the request that is why
we still can use that request user in all our action controllers because they again at a later point
of time.
Does middleware runs on every incoming request before our routes handle it.
So the data we store here is used in the same request cycle in our route handlers in our controllers.
But if I do a change to request at the end of its lifetime like here right before I send the response
this data will not be useful to us.
It's really important to understand this.
So lets now see how we could solve this in a better way.