So we found out dead using a request for storing this is not ideal because the request is dead after
sending a response which alternatives do we have.
Well one alternative would be some kind of global variable you could use a global variable which you
store in an extra file in which you export from that file and which you'd then change and that variable
would actually survive your request cycles.
But since that variable would be shared across all requests it would all be shared across all users
and that is exactly where cookies can help us with cookies we can store data in the browser of a single
user and store data in that browser which is customized to the user which does not affect all the users
but can be sent with requests to tell us Hey I already am authenticated and that is exactly what we
will do here.
So instead of just redirecting your well we can do is we can set a cookie and we set such a cookie simply
by setting a header.
So we set a header on our response and we set a header here.
But first of all defining the name of the header and the name is set cookie Indie's.
That is a research name which will set a cookie and then you have the value of that header and the value
for set cookie in its simple form is simply a key value pair where you define any name you want in any
value you want.
So you could have something like locked in or locked in makes it easier to read.
Equally true this would set a cookie and I can show this to you if you now save this and you go to the
logon page and you click post here or click log in open your developer tools and then the chrome developer
tools you can go to the application tab and there are two cookies.
And if you expand this you should see your current address here.
If you click on that you will see some cookies.
Now some cookies will be set by a third party plug ins Chrome extensions and so on.
But you will also see locked in and the value true.
You should see that at least that is the cookie which just it.
Let me out a bit here.
There you see the domain to which it belongs.
The path when it will expire and this state is in the past because it's a so-called session cookie.
It will basically expire once you close the browser and come back.
You see the size and some other information to which will come back in a second.
So this cookie is now set.
And now this cookie is not only set but the browser by default sends it to the server with every request
we make.
So if you click on products have for example we go to the Network tab.
This is a request which was sent to the product's page.
And there if we have a look at the headers we scroll down to the request headers you'll see that a cookie
was sent.
The first one comes from an extension but here this is our cookie.
So it was sent to our server and now since we have debt every request will have that cookie attached
to itself and therefore this data is sent with every request.
And now we can use that.
Let's start simple let's say in the get log in page here we can have a look at our headers the console
log request get and then you enter the header name which is cookie because remember in the client side
def tools you saw that the cookie had a wast send with the request and now if you go to the logon page
or reload that page if you are on it I reloaded it a couple of times.
You see this output.
Now we can ignore the first cookie but these are locked in cookie.
And now we could extract that value for example by splitting on the semi-colon and then taking the second
value in that array.
The array index starts at zero so one gives us a second element.
And now if a reload is used to get locked in true here you could trim that to remove any excess white
spaces we could split this again on the equal sign.
This is obviously a very complex way.
But if I do this again and then I use the second value then I should get to true or false value.
So now either reload this I get.
True here.
So obviously it is a very complex way but should be quite readable.
And then I can extract my is locked in information from the incoming request header I'm getting the
cookie header.
I make sure that I get the second cookie that is sent which happens to be on is locked in cookie.
If you only have one cookie being sent by the way then make sure you extract the first value.
So whatever or wherever it is locked in is located for you if you only have one cookie use the first
one with zero.
If you've got multiple ones used to set the third one and so on.
And then I extract the true value.
And now I have that is locked in information which I can pass through is authenticated.
And with that on that page if I now reloaded hey here are our two options in the menu because now we
do enable that again because now we store that information across requests.
So now even if I never get away to a number page right.
Don't extract that cookie.
And it come back to log in there I do extract it and it is always sent with every request.
So it is a cross request data storage.
Still there is a big disadvantage.
And do you know which one that is.