So he can manipulate cookies.
So storing sensitive data is not ideal but I mentioned that for example for tracking users.
It's a popular instrument and why is that.
Because as you can for example see with the cookies I have here the cookies don't only have to relate
to your page.
A cookie can also be sent to another page that is a common instrument in tracking where you have that
so-called tracking pixel on pages which is simply image you are ill with no real image.
But that image can be located on let's say Google's servers and you have a cookie on that page which
is also sent along with that.
And therefore Google can track on which page you are and how you are moving through the web even if
you're not on their Web sites because some data is stored in your client and obviously you could delete
it therefore.
Which is why you can block such mechanisms too.
But it is stored there and it is sent with every request to Google so they can track you without you
being on their servers.
So storing that information on their servers would not work but storing it on your computer will work
because obviously that can be sent on every page you visit.
So that is something where it is could be interesting if you want to track your users.
That is a very common thing to do.
And you can also configure cookies.
We set a value but actually you can set more things than just the value here.
I set my cookie by adding that key value pair.
Now obviously we could add multiple cookies mult multiple key value pairs.
We can also add a semi-colon after to the pair and for example set expires to some expiration date this
state would have to follow a certain format THAAD date format.
All linkit attached to it is video here.
So you could set a certain date when this cookie will expire because remember if you don't set this
it will expire once you close your browser.
Alternatively 2 x bars you can set max age written like this.
And this is a number in seconds how long that cookie should stay around.
So we could set this to 10 for example.
And now if I click that log in button here I got locked in.
And now you see the expiry date all have changed here the expiry date.
If I decreased debt the expiry date here basically is today and now it already is expired and if I reload
that page is locked and it's therefore gone.
So this is something we can do.
And this is of course interesting if you want to control for example how long you want to track a user
or we will actually use that together with authentication later.
You could use this to all control how long and authenticated sessions stays active for a user.
You might know that from your online bank where you time out after a certain duration you can all to
add a domain to which to cookies should be sent.
And here we again are on that tracking thing again.
You can add secure just like this without an equal sign just secure.
This means this cookie will only be set if the page is served y.
H t d p s.
Now I can demonstrate this here because our local development is not using HVAD b.s. but we will eventually
use HTB us later in the course where it will show you how to set this up.
So now you can already see how ever that I get an error if I try to reload log in because I try to extract
the value which is not there.
So for now let's simply comment this out and set this always to false so that I can just show you how
this cookie is now not set.
If I reloaded and click here you don't see the cookie here because I added secure and it would only
be set if we are serving each page.
Why are HTP.
And you can also set this to HTP only.
Now if I do that they go back to log in and I click here.
It is set but now it has this checkmark here in the HTP column.
And that means that now we can't access to cookie value through client side javascript.
So in the scripts running in the browser this can be an important security mechanism because it protects
us against cross-site scripting attacks now.
Because now your client side javascript where someone could have injected that malicious code can't
read your cookie values and that will be important later with authentication where a cookie will not
stored the sensitive information but an important part of authenticating the user.
So this can be an extra security layer because now the cookie will still be attached to every request
that is sent to the server.
But you can't read the cookie value from inside the browser Javascript code.
Obviously as you can tell as a user and developer tools you can still read it.
But then again it's your own cookie and you will not store information like hey I'm locked in there
because Dad would be easy to manipulate and you can't protect against that.
These are the key values you can set here.
And this gives you a lot of flexibility.
That being said often you will not directly set your cookies because you robery use some packages like
for example for authentication that will manage setting the cookie for you and that is something which
I'll dive into in the next lectures where we dive into sessions what sessions are how they can help
us with storing sensitive information across requests and how cookies still are important when using
sessions.