So we had to look at cookies.
What is a session.
Well we have the same set up as before user using the front end our use interacting with our server
where we have our node application code we send the request and we do log in.
And again let's assume we do is send a valid credential stare.
We're not validating them in this module because I want to focus on sessions and cookies.
So now instead of storing the information that the user is authenticated in the front and which was
a bad place as we learned we'll stored in the back end with a so-called session and A session and you
construct which we haven't used before.
With that I'm not meaning that we stored it in the request because we already saw that this will not
work.
And I also don't mean that we store it in some variable in our express app because Dad would be shared
across all users and all requests.
We only want to share the information across all requests of the same user and that's really important
the same user sort of Abra users can see your data.
Assume your role can't tell the server that they are offended Kheta only you are authenticated.
Now for that we need to store it on the server.
We'll start by storing it in memory which is then pretty similar to storing in that variable.
But eventually we'll move to a different session storage that database and we need one important piece
of information a client needs to tell the server to which session he belongs because the session will
in the end just be an entry stored in memory or stored in a database.
Now we're not matching this by IP address or anything like that because that is a bit hard to maintain
and can be faked and all that fun stuff.
So we're not doing that.
Instead we'll use a cookie where we will store the ID of the session.
Now obviously you can still change that and assume a different ID if you want to but that will not work
like this because actually the value we store will not be d d id but the hashed ID hashed with a certain
algorithm where only the server can confirm that it has not been fiddled with so that you didn't play
around with it and tried to create a different one.
So this will be a secure way because you basically stored the ID in an encrypted way where only the
server is able to confirm that the stored cookie value relates to a certain ID in the database.
And therefore we got a safe value stored in the cookie which you can't.
You can change it but you will not assume a different session.
A session can be matched and that session can then contain the confidential data which you can't change
from inside the browser.
That is the idea here.
So sessions are stored on the server side cookies client side sessions service side.
Now let me show you how to implement a session.