So we added the session.
Let's now start our server again and let's use a session middleware.
And how do we use it.
Well we can use it in our off controller in log in instead of setting that cookie we can reach out to
request and then the session object does is added by the session middleware this session object.
And here we can add any key we want for example is locked in but you can names however you want and
set this to true.
Now if you saved at and you go back to your browser go to the log in page maybe reload and get rid of
that locked in cookie.
You can simply delete it here.
Now click log in.
And what you should see is that a new cookie was added to your does connect ID for a session id cookie
if you expand the value here.
You'll see some strange string and that is what I meant.
This does encrypt the values so to say and this is now the cookie by default.
It's a session cookie so it will expire when you close the browser.
It's a session cookie.
Dead will identify your user here you're running instance off this website you could say where you are
browsing around does it identify you to the server and to today's session.
And I can prove this to you if we now go to get log in page here and I console log requests session
here like Det.
Let me then go back and click on the logon page here again and go back to our server and there you see
the session object is locked.
Now let me all the output is locked in here by accessing that go back log in again.
It's undefined because I added that this code only after submitting this for the first time.
So let me save this again.
And now simply click click that log and button your again.
And now you will see if you go back to the log in page you see true here because now indeed in the session
is locked in a stored it we can go to a different page and come back to loggin and these are all individual
requests which technically are totally individual from each other totally separate and still we see
true here because we still store doesn't the session on the server side by default just in the memory
not in the database yet and the session is identified for days browser because we have that cookie and
I can prove that to you by starting another browser and this will technically be treated as a totally
different session and environment could be a totally different machine.
So I am a local host for thousands here.
And if I click on log in here you see on the find and that undefined is coming from the log in request
just sent because Despereaux Eleazer this user technically this is a totally different user even though
I'm the same but it's a different browser different user does user does not have this cookie set for
him does not have an active session on the server.
And this is how we can store data that persists across requests.
As you saw I clicked around and still that was sent to true value was sent to when I came back to log
in.
So this is saved across requests but not across users as you can see.
This is a different user.
I go to log in I have undefine down there and that is the power of using a session.
It still needs a cookie to identify the user but the sensitive information is stored on the server.
We can't modify it.
And that of course will be super important for all syndication.
And what we see here already is the core mechanism behind authenticating users in the web.
There are other techniques too.
For example when building arrest API something will come back later.
But this is a core thing on how syndication generally works especially when rendering views as we are
doing it with Ejay s and dessous what we will build up on in the authentication section where we then
also dive into things like validating credentials logging users out and fun stuff like debt.