So now we had a look at how we can use sessions and what the advantage of a sessions.
And we also of course learned about cookies what a cookie can be used for and how it plays together
nicely with a session to identify a user a client and then store the sensitive data on the server.
So in the session and that difference between sessions services and cookies client side is really important
to understand.
You also learned how to set a cookie and how to use a session.
By the way if you're wondering how that session cookie this cookie or how does a set all this is done
automatically by express session.
So by that middleware we're configuring.
That's also why you can add cookie related configurations here because this middleware automatically
sets a cookie for you and it automatically reads the cookie value for you too.
So does all the cookie parsing and setting for you now with that you actually really need to manage
cookies on your own.
Because dead session cookies.
And with that I don't mean a cookie which gets lost after you close the browser but that cookie that
identifies a server side session that is the most prominent The most common use case for cookies besides
advertisements tracking which you typically don't implement on your own but you use for party tools
like Google for that.
But that session took me so that session identifying cookie is an important thing.
And Sessions on the server are often used for all that occasion.
But as I mentioned you could use them for any kind of data you want to store.
We happen to store the information wherever the user is locked in.
But you could be storing the cards that the shopping cart user here or anything which belongs to a user
which should be shared across requests as I highlighted.