We're now using sessions everywhere and we have our dummy authentication process in place it's missing
crucial features like log out and so on and that will all come and you'll find dictation module.
But we have something in place and you might have noticed that of course.
Regarding the log out I always just deleted the session cookie.
That is what I did and the assignment to I deleted the session cookie to demonstrate what happens if
we don't try to do something that is relying on data that is stored in the session.
It will fail because the session cookie which is required to identify the correct session is there.
Now deleting just a cookie is of course not ideal because right now for example if you have a look at
compress and a intercessions collection I have free sessions here because I always just delete the cookie.
Now there is a cleaner way of doing that and that cleaner way is to use method provided by the session
middleware.
Now let me show this to you and find out.
First of all go to my views and they're to the navigation and next to my log in button here.
I'll actually add a number field another list item into which I'll add a form which should lead to log
out and use POST method.
And in that form I'll have a button like this which is of type submit where I'll say log out.
Now if we save that and we reload our page wesay log out next to log in.
Now to make sure the styling is correct we need to add that list item class here which we also have
on the list item here.
And after adding this if we reload this looks better.
And I've got my log out but you know when it clicked as I want to clear any session I might have.
And for that I of course need to register a new route.
So let's head over to our off routes and let's add a new poster out here because we will send a post
request which goes to log out and there will trigger a post log out action in my controller.
Now it is action of course does not exist yet.
So let's head over to the off controller and maybe duplicate the post log in route to your name and
post log out and in there.
What I want to do is I want to clear my session.
We can do this by reaching out to our session object and then we can call destroy there.
This is a method provided by the session package we're using.
Now this also takes a function which we passed to it which will be called once it's done destroying
the session and in their request session will then not be available anymore because we got rid of that
session.
We can recreate it for the next request.
When we do does it again then it will be sent again.
But in here all the session data will be lost because the session was destroyed.
So here I will then actually redirect back to my starting page with rest's redirect slash.
We also get a potential error here which we can try to log to the con..
Now with that we have to post log out to registered.
Now let's head back to our application and first of all let's log in.
Now let me hope the developer tools again.
I've got no session cookie here.
I can click log in and redirect that session cookie is set and we can now use that session.
Now if we go to Kompas real quick and we refresh we see we have four objects now which makes sense.
We had three before.
Now we have four.
And now let me click log out.
We are redirected the session cookie here actually still exists.
But you see the session was deleted over there and the session cookie still exists but that is no problem
because no matching session will be found.
So that is fine it's basically not doing anything.
And it will be renewed once you log in again.
Then this will all be overwritten.
And when we close the browser it will also be deleted because it's not a permanent cookie.
It's a session cookie which means it's a cookie that does not have expiry date in the future.
It does not have a max age.
It will simply get deleted when you close the browser and it's worthless in this state here.
So now as you see if I click around I have a problem with my orders here.
I'll fix that in a second.
But you see the cookies stare.
Most importantly the session was cleaned up.
Back there though.