So knouted we learned a lot about sessions.
Let me fix some things here real quick.
For example if I go to my card or to my orders I have some issues there and the problem of course is
that without a valid session and we don't have a valid session now after destroying it all these methods
under all these actions where I do reach out to my user to fetch to occur and orders these will all
fail.
And of course this makes sense because we need a secondary because we need a user for debt.
So what would work our shop and products and their details.
Andrew Card will not work though.
So a first step to improving debt besides checking for the existence of a user on the server which we
will all add in the indication module.
But first thing we can do is that we adjust our front end to only display things we can actually interact
with based on our current authentication status.
So for debt I'll go back to my views and I'll start with the navigation First of all because we can
all say that log in and log out should only be displayed should only be rendered when we are actually
not locked in.
So here I'm checking if we are often dictated to show ad product and Edmon products.
First of all this should move up and also include cart and orders because DS also only makes sense if
we have a user because otherwise Anbesol will get an error.
If you visit these pages and then we can repeat the logic down there and only showed this entire unordered
list.
If we are not indicated So if this is not true then I want to show these items.
Now we can also add this code and if we now save that and we reload this page we only see sharp end
products by default.
Once I log in though we see the rest well actually log out should be visible once we are authenticated
not to think about it.
So we should reverse this move that in there and only don't show this log in list item.
If we are not authenticated if we are often the case that.
So here we can use else if we are often educated then I of course want to show the log out screen.
Me get this correct here.
So now here I can now close this.
So now if I saved that again and I reload my page here I do see log out once Eclectus I.S. log in and
once I do log in again I see worse.
And now all of you are free to post a video.
Make sure for add to cart.
The same is true.
This should only be visible when you are locked in but not when we are locked out.
Here's your chance to post a video very successful.
It's actually the same logic because it is information we pass to every view anyways so therefore we
can go to the product list each fall where we doing collude Add to Cart.
So we should go to add to card actually and there.
This entire You should only be rendered if we can add the item to the cart.
So if we do have a session if we are authenticated and therefore let's go back to the product list doesn't
hire here should only be rendered if we are authentic.
So if it's ok authenticated is true then we'll include this year over y as we won't.
So now with this change if we saved it if I reload this page and I'm not locked in I still see it because
I'm on the wrong page for products this will work but for the index page this is a separate page.
In each case there we should also replace our include with that updated logic where we check for the
existence of our while locked in user.
So now with this added to index Aegeus to now either reload the starting page does is only there.
After I locked in as you will see now we can add to the cart and we fail again though.
Now why is that.
Let's check this in the next lecture.