So I clicked at cart in the last lecture and we're now failing to do this.
And if we go back we actually see an error or that request session user add to cart.
It's not a function.
So we Semino fail to execute our Add to Cart function So basically our functions that normally are a
way lable on the user object.
And why is that the reason for that is that trivia Cely in previous setups we always store the user
in the request and does was up her request action anyways and we fetched dead user for every request
in the middleware in app.
Right.
So we fetch the user from the database and mongooses automatically gave us a full user object not just
the data in the database but the full user model with all the methods and we stored dead user model
in the request of the session.
This works have been different with the session.
We are not fetching this for every request.
Instead we store a user in our session upon logging in here.
Now what happens to the user.
Well its gets stored to a database.
If we refresh there we can see here is our user object.
And this is now just the data.
Now for every new request the session middleware does not go ahead and fetch the user with the help
of mongooses it fetches the session data from long OTB.
That is correct but for it it uses them long would he be store and the mom would be store does not know
about our mongooses models.
So when it fetches the data from the session database when it fetches does data it only fetches the
data.
It does not fetch an object with all the methods provided by mongooses.
Now what can we do regarding that well.
One thing we can do of course and now were reporting back a bit we can reach at that middleware which
we had earlier here after we initialized our session.
So here I have my general middleware which we used before to store our user in the request and we can
take our logic from our post log in route where we fetch a user for a given ID move that back into that
middleware.
So exactly what we had before.
Instead of redirecting will call next so that the incoming requests can continue with the next middleware.
But in the here we dont want to store anything in the session because the session is already something
which will be managed for us automatically and 40 incoming requests we register the middle where the
middle where we'll then basically look for a session cookie if it finds one it will look for a fitting
session into a database and load data from there.
So by the time we reached his middleware we'll have our session data loaded.
Now this means that now we just want to use that session data to load our real user to create our mongooses
user model and how do we do that.
Well we don't need to reach out to the database again.
Instead we can again set the user Florida's request only.
And now here I want to create a user based on data stored in the session.
So data that persists across requests and I will create that user and store it in the request user which
will then only live for Dad request but it's fueled by data from the session and therefore it also survives
cross request.
You could say and I simply need to do that because I need a mongooses model to work with because the
data we store in the session storage in one load be there well we retrieve it as just plain data not
as a mongooses model with all the cool methods mongooses gives us and that is why we get this error
regarding add to card not being found and so on.
So here I will initialize request user and actually I don't want to find a user by id like this.
I will find the user by reaching out to request session user id it does make sense I guess because that
is the data the user is what is stored in my session and I want to get the idea and then find that user
in the database with the help of the user model which is provided by mongoose of course.
And then here I get back a mongooses model user which I store and request user and this is exactly what
I need now to make sure that I have a mongooses model to work with so that all these cool mongooses
methods work again.
And now we need to just admin JSM shopped as again and replace requests session user with request user
again because that is where I'm storing my mongooses model user.
So let's do that in shop genius and then all the files where I do use requests session user.
I want to mark these all with command or control D and revert back to request user because now we store
our mongoose model in that request only object again do the same and admin japes.
So in not for locked in because that's just true or false we don't need to turn this into anything but
for all the places where I do use my request session user here.
All these places which should only be one here is now request to use her again.
Again this will not mean that it's now only X for this request.
The mongooses model object is but it's fueled by data that's stored in the session and therefore data
that persists across requests and knouted we saved all of that.
Let's go back and let's try adding this whole card again.
And now this works ASP for as long as I'm locked in if I do log out we now get an error that error is
now stemming from my app use function which is triggered for every request and this will simply fail
after logging out because request session user ID is not set there.
Well we can fix this in this app use function.
Actually yes by checking for the existence of requests session user.
And if we don't have one.
So if I don't have a user stored at my session then I can just call next and I return next so that the
code there after this one will not be executed.
This will only run if we do have a session user.
So now with that we can safely reload the starting page this works.
I can log in again I can add this to the card.
I can also add this from the card from the details page.
I can delete this and I can log out additional work.