That's it for this module you learn a lot about cookies and sessions now about cookies.
They're great for storing data on the client side.
So in the browser and since they're store dare you should not store sensitive data and cookies because
they can be viewed by the user.
That might not be the worst part because each user can only view his own cookies but they can also be
manipulated.
And you don't want to let your users control whether they are authenticated or not by simply switching
some cookie value.
Now you can configure cookies in a broad variety and often you won't do that at least not directly by
setting that header.
Instead you'll use something like the session package which also uses a cookie.
But more on that in a second.
But you can configure them for example to expire.
By default they will expire when the browser is closed and such cookies that expire when the browser
is closed are called session cookies.
Now this term can be confusing.
Session cookies are not cookies necessarily used to identify a session concept which had come back in
a second.
They're just called session cookie because they only survive as long as you are using that page and
the current browser.
You can also set an expiry date or an H after which the cookie will get invalid and that is thing called
a permanent cookie.
It's not permanent in the sense of lefse infinitely long but in a sense of it does not necessarily go
away when you close the browser it will still be there when you reopen the browser.
It will be invalid deleted once it expired.
Now cookies work well together with sessions but they're not limited to using sessions.
Keep that tracking cookie in mind as an example.
Sessions are never a great concept.
You use them to store data on a server not on the client.
And therefore since they're on the server and they can't be viewed or manipulated by your users they
are great for storing sensitive data that should survive across requests.
Because that's important too.
You could store data in requests as we did earlier in this course.
But then the data is lost for every new request with sessions the date of her wife's new cancer anything
and sessions you could store your shopping cart there but often you use them for authenticating users
for storing user data in their already authentication status in general.
Now a session needs a cookie to be identified and that's not the session cookie which is simply a cookie
that dies after you're close to browser.
You can use a session or a permanent cookie for that actually.
And on Express session package we used which sets to Cookie automatically by the way there if you remember
you could configure it a cookie when registering the session middleware.
So we're not talking about that here.
Instead you just have a cookie that is used to identify a session and that is important because otherwise
you have that data on your server.
That is great but how do you know which user it belongs.
Well for Dad you need the cookie.
This is how sessions work and how to use cookies.
And since the session is also stored on the server you can choose from different storage.
You could use a MS sequel storage you could use file storage or as we did here you could use more would
be to store your session data.
So these are sessions and cookies crucial concepts which you might not always control and use directly
but often indirectly.
For example with authentication something which will will come back to the next module where we will
implement a real authentication workflow with Sign-Up logging in logging out storing real user data
creating users and all that fun stuff.