So what is authentication.
While we obviously got our user using our application interacting with our dues and we get the server
and also database with which our server works.
These are all things we worked with in this course already.
Now in our application we might have different routes different actions.
A user can do.
We might be able to view all products to create and manage products or to place orders.
Now obviously we can do more things in our application but these are just some examples.
Now the idea behind authentication is that not all these actions are available to every user of our
application.
And now here's one important thing with user I don't mean locked in user I mean simply a person with
getting our page Wisting localhost free.
And in our case here later of course the domain under which we deployed it.
So I'm not talking about locked in users but really just people using our page and such anonymous users
who are not locked in should not be able to do all these things.
They certainly should be able to view all products just as you are able to view all products on Amazon.com
even if you're not locked in.
We want to allow this in our shop too.
But there are other things like for example here creating products managing products and placing orders
which should only be available to locked in users and not to every Wiznitzer of our page because in
order to buy a product you need to be locked in and in order to create a new product you also need to
be locked in.
Because in our application we of course connect a product to a locked in user we match to two things.
And this is what we need authentication for.
We need to be able to differentiate between anonymous users who are not locked in and locked in users
and we need to provide a flow of view and the back in logic that allows people visiting our page to
sign up and then to sign in and then we can use sessions as I showed it to you in the last module to
store the information whether a user is signed in and well let him interact with the page across requests.
This is the idea behind authentication.
Now how is it implemented.