How is authentication implemented same set up we get a user get our backend server side code into a
database.
And now typically a user will ascend a log in request.
Now obviously for that a user a visitor of our page needs to have signed up before but offer you signed
up.
You can log in with your email and password and on the server we'd check whether that email and password
combination is valid.
However we have a user with that e-mail and their password in our database.
If that is the case we create a session for this user and you learned how this works in the last module
and this session then identifies this user.
This is required because otherwise without a session even if we find out that the credentials are valid
for the very next request the user would be locked out again because remember requests interact separated
from each other.
They don't know anything about each other.
We need a session to connect them.
That is why we create one with the user or the authentication information we then return a 200 response.
So basically a success response and we obviously also store the cookie belonging to the session on the
client.
We returned with that response.
So did we really established a session and there after the user is able to visit our restricted routes
because now this cookie is sent with every request on the server we can connect to this cookie to a
session and then the session we have the information whether that user is signed in or not.
And if the user is signed in we can grant access to certain resources.
This is how authentication is implemented in any web application that renders the use will learn a different
way of adding authentication later when we work with an arrest and graph Q API.
But for a traditional web app as we are building it here where we do render Ejay as or handle bars or
whatever templating engine you use where we render such use there we will use this session based on
indication approach.