So let's dive back into our project and make sure you are locked out and make sure you download detached
snapshot because there I did add a sign uplink to our navigation bar and click on that.
We also load a sign up page where we should edit the caption on the button by the way.
So if you download the hatch code what was added and you can also add this to your own project.
I did add the sign up each file where I also should change just to sign up so you can simply add deadfall
to your all folder.
I did manipulate or changed navigation each last fall there what I did add is I simply added the sign
up again in menu entry.
After log in both forward and normal menu and all that for the mobile menu down there.
So basically one list item was added to each menu.
Does this what I edit in this file.
And then I worked on my route STEHR I added two new routes posts sign up and get signed up where I use
my control or get sign up and post sign up actions.
And in that controller I worked on these actions.
I edit posts sign up which is an empty placeholder nothing in there.
So that is not that difficult get sign up all is is a pretty simple route there.
I simply render you off.
Sign up view so you can just add this to your existing project or use my attached snapshot and replace
my mom would be you are with yours.
And once you got all that you should be able to have a running application that looks like this with
a sign up page that looks like this because now we will use or we will need a way of signing up users.
So let's now start implementing the full authentication flow in this module.
And for that first of all make sure that we can create new users then that we can sign users in and
sign users out of course that we can then use the information wherever a user is signed.
It was signed out in all our viewers and that we can protect our routes on the service side too because
right now even if I'm not signed in what I can do is I can manually wizard admin add product and this
works.
So I can't get there by menu because he hides the menu options but manually visiting this works.
And there's also something we'll work on in this module.
So let's get there step by step and let's start by adding user sign up in the next lecture.