So here I got a very simple sign up form which is a pretty typical sign up for that though you have
to enter an email.
You have to enter a password confirm the password and click sign up.
Now in that sign up view I changed my button label and there I also want to point at the sign up route
in the action slash sign up send a POST request to reach that sign up that post sign up Raud here which
ultimately triggers to post sign up action.
Now in this action we want to store a new user in the database.
Now which steps does this include.
Well obviously we want to extract the information from the incoming request.
We want to read the email from the request body email field and make sure you check your view.
How these inputs are named because you retrieve the values on request body by these names.
So email password and confirm password in my case so request body email should work here.
I will have request bought a password to retrieve the password and then I will also retrieve my confirm
password here from confirm password.
So these are the free values that should reach this route.
Now typically what you would do first is we would validate the user input.
So for example we would check is this a valid email address and do password and confirm password match.
And we will do this in this course too.
But actually I will have a complete module where I dive into how to validate user input because you
can of course do a lot of cool things when it comes to that and therefore I dedicate a whole module
to that.
For now we'll ignore this and that means for now you of course don't have to enter a valid email and
you don't have to enter a valid password.
You don't have to confirm it either.
But of course you should do all that to have a realistic testing environment will add validation later.
We still need the values here at least the first two because the next step is that we treat a new user
or actually there is one step we want to do before we created you user.
Do you know which step that could be well we want to find out if a user with that e-mail already exists
because there should not be any duplicate e-mails in our database for dead.
We actually can do two things when using Mongo DBI.
You could create an index in the Mongo database on your email field and give that index unique property.
Now this is something you can do if you know how long to be works.
If you get a little bit more experience with it which you can get with my mom would you be Course there.
I do show this scenario for example but this is only one option of achieving this.
An alternative is that you simply try to find a user with that e-mail.
So for that we'll use our user model which is of course a mongoose user model.
And there we can find a user can find one user because we already know we don't want to create a user
with that e-mail.
If we find only one user who already has that e-mail and we find one user bypassing a filter with these
curly braces and we'll look for the email field in our collection.
So in the documents in our collection and see if we find a user where the email field holds a value
equal to the email we're extracting here.
So right sort of the colon is the email we're extracting.
Left side is the field we're looking for in the database.
Now here we get back where we can call then to find out if this worked.
We also might get an error which I'll simply log here then and then I will get my user object so my
user document you could say you can name as however you want.
Now we know that if user dock exists.
So if this is not undefined then we do have a user.
And if we do have a user then I certainly don't want to create a new one with the same e-mail.
So if this exists I will actually return a response and it will redirect back to slash sign up to inform
the user that this did not work right now not much informing is going on as you can tell we just redirect
without showing an error message.
This is also something which I'll show you how to better solve this.
How to show error messages to the user.
For now we'll just redirect back to the sign up page and will not create a new user.
If we make it past disk check we know that no user with that e-mail exists yet and therefore we can
create a new one.
So what we can do here Dennis we can create a new user object with new user and because there are new
user and there we store email.
The e-mail we're retrieving here and will store the password like this for now.
One important thing in the user model there right now I have a name and an e-mail and no password.
So I will change to use Ramal.
I don't really want to store a name.
You could do that but I'll do it here.
But instead I will store a password for the user which will be of type string and which will absolutely
be required like dis.
So my user model changed slightly here.
Now with that change in the user model if we go back to our post Sign-Up action I can create a user
like this.
We can also add a cart here the card by default will be an object where items is equal to an empty array
And this is now a valid new user which we can save database by calling Save As you learned.
And then I can return this so that we can change a number of then block here which will be called once
this safe action completed.
So it does function here will be executed.
One saving is done and here we can then redirect to let's say the starting page because here we then
know the user did sign up or to be precise.
Let's redirect to the log in page because after signing up you need to log in.
So this should now be an authentication flow that does check for the existence of a user and then create
a new user.
I'll quickly also go to my actually last fall and at the very bottom here where I always create a new
user if we don't have one yet I will get rid of that code because now we have a real user creation flow
so we don't need that dummy user anymore.
And I will also head over to Compaq's which I'll start to connect to my Mongo database again and interconnect
the database server if we have a look at the shop database in users.
We obviously have one user the dummy user we used before.
Now let's delete that user now.
We don't need it anymore.
And with all these changes in all these files saved let's reload the sign up page and now let's try
creating a new user with a dummy e-mail dummy password.
You don't really need to enter a confirmed password because we're not checking does anyways.
And click sign up.
Now it is looking good because I'm on the logon page so I was redirected.
I also have no server error.
If I now reload my users collection in Mongo DBI in contests I also see this is a user with the credentials.
I add it.
So we did add a new user but we have a huge problem with that user.
Can you identify it.
We'll fix it in the next lecture.