Now that we are able to sign up let's also add some functionality to ensure that we can sign in.
And for that we obviously have our log in page and when we enter something here we reach our posts log
in route here.
Now there we still have the old dummy code where we just find our default user which by the way won't
exist anymore because we deleted it.
And then we would create a session.
This is obviously not the approach I want to use anymore.
Instead what I want to do is I want to find the user in here but I want to find the user by the email
the user entered.
So let's first of all extract that Let's extract the emails from that request body and let's let's extract
the password from the request body.
These are two pieces of information I need for assigning a user in.
And then here I'll not use find by ID but find one to find one user with specific e-mail.
And there should be only one user with an email in the database and all find to user by looking for
the email field in the documents and comparing it to the e-mail value we are extracting here.
Never find a user here.
So if I make it into your and I don't have a user then I know that we can check the password next.
If I don't have a users you're so user is undefined.
I did find a user in the database and then I can simply return here.
Not execute the honor code and simply redirect back to log in for now because the log in failed because
we tried to use an e-mail which does not exist in the database as we didn't find a user for it if we
make it past.
If Geck we know that the e-mail exists but now we need to validate the password of course we'll do it
as the big trip package again because deep password is of course stored in a hashed form.
And I mentioned that we can't rewords this.
So how can we now compare the password.
Well remember that big tripped was responsible for creating the hash Beecroft uses a certain algorithm
for that.
And we can essentially passed the password the user entered into B tripped and let the script compare
it to the hashed value and Picric can then find out if the hashed value does make sense taking into
account the algorithm that is used for creating that for the password you entered as plain text.
So if that plaintext password if you what hash it could result in the hash password and if the answer
is true then you know the user entered a valid password and Fritz decrypt has to compare function.
And there we entered a password.
We want to check.
So the password we extract from the incoming request and then the hashed value against you want to compare
it.
And that is found in our user document which we get from the database and they are of course in the
password field.
Now this also returns a promise.
So here we can add then and a catch block.
Now if we have an error here.
So if we fail to compare this then I also want to redirect back to the log in page but if we make it
into the then block then I want to check whether we were successful.
Now important with compair will only face an error.
If something goes wrong not if the passwords do not match in both a matching and an non-matching case
we make it into the then block and result will be a boolean that is true if the passwords are equal.
So we could also name to do match to make this clearer and it will be false.
If they are not equal.
So here we can check if do match is true.
That means the passwords are equal the user entered a valid password and then we could return to not
execute any other code.
We could return a redirect to the starting page.
If we don't make it into their den we want to redirect back to the log in page because then the user
entered the invalid password.
Now we also want to set a session as we did it before.
And that session code should only be set if we have a matching password.
So if the user did authenticate then we can still say it is locked in.
We can still store the user in the session because we still need the user object and the user your keep
in mind is to use or we retrieved from the database and we want to save that session and only redirect
in that session after we saved it successfully.
Therefore we should also return this to a white code execution of this line because the callback here
will execute asynchronously.
So this needs to be returned to not execute this line here in here.
We don't need to return then because after this line this line can't be reached because this line isn't
a callback in a different function.
So with all of that in place we should be able to sign in if we do enter a valid password.
Let's give this a try.
So keep in mind my email is tasked to and I use testor as a password and first of all I will try a wrong
email redirect it back to log in.
So this didn't seem to succeed.
We can also quickly go to the sessions and clear all sessions here so that we can really prove that
no session was created.
So now let me enter a valid email but an incorrect password and again redirect it back and no session
was created here.
But now let me entered a valid email and the valid password.
And now I'm going to start page.
I see all options which is looking good.
We get no error here.
And if I have a look at my session's collection we've got a session here because now I am logged in
does this user object with which I'm locked in.
So is this correct.
And now we got a working log in flow taking into account our email and so on.