Knouted we are able to sign up and sign in.
We have to work on route protection.
We already have a set up where we only show the menu options we should be able to interact with.
But even when I log out and they offer Mei's session is gone even when I do that I can still manually
enter admin at product and reach that page and I could even try to create a product here.
I would fail then because there would be no user object on the back and where I tried to get locked
in user.
But this is not user experience.
You want to offer.
We don't even want to be able to load this page if we're not locked in.
And for that we need to protect our routes.
Now how do we protect routes.
Well to protect routes we want to check where the user is authenticated before we render back.
Let's say at product page.
So an admin and the admin controller in get at product which loads that page before we rendered it.
Page I want to check if in the request session is locked in a set.
And to be precise I want to check if it's not set because if this is not true the user is not locked
in.
And if the user is not locked in then I want to redirect.
Let's say to the logon page like this.
So then since I return here this code will not execute and it won't load the added product page.
So now let me try to reload this page.
Keep in mind I'm not locked in and I'm on the logon page.
So this works.
I am redirected here because sessional locked in is not set.
On the other hand if I do a log in now.
So if I do enter my valid credentials you're try to access add product.
This does work because now I make it past it check.
Now this is a code we could add to every route which we want to protect but adding it like this is a
bit cumbersome.
So let me show you a better way of protecting our routes we're a more scalable way in the next lecture.