Knouted we have are often dictation flow and drought protection in place.
Let's talk about security and they're about C S r f.
Attacks C S R F stands for cross-eyed request forgery.
Now what is this.
This is a special kind of attack pattern or approach where people can abuse your sessions and trick
users of your application to execute malicious code.
This is how it works.
You have a user in your application.
And now let's assume this is a Wiznitzer who indeed is locked in.
You have your server side code and your database with which you interact.
Now the user interacts with your front end views so the pages you render back and you get a session
for that user and of course a cookie that belongs to that session.
So everything you knows now the user can do intended things like for example send money to B if you
are building a banking app or in our application order some products with his own shipping address.
If we had such a checkout process now in a C S R F attack scenario your user is tricked onto a fake
site.
And this can be done for example by sending a link in an e-mail.
That side can look like your own page but it technically is a different one.
Now on that site there could be a link leading to your page to your real page executing some request
there.
Of course you could include a form for example which sends a post request to your page so to your own
notes server where you added some fields to send money to another person to see.
In this case instead of beat to the user it is pretty invisible because he saw a page that maybe looked
like your page or clicked on a link that instantly redirected to your page.
But with behind the scenes some data being sent there that does something the user would not want to
do normally.
Now why does it work.
Well since you got valid session for an user if you send something to your site to your service your
session is used for that user and therefore that behind the scenes data that the user never sees that
configures their money transferral or the order in a certain way that it's not OK to the user.
This part is invisible to the user but the Valot session gets used for it because your server is used
and therefore does this except it does the attack pattern where the session can be stolen.
So to say where you can abuse the fact the users are locked in and you can simply trick them into making
requests which they might not even notice and obviously want to protect against this attack pattern.
And how can we protect now.
Well the idea is that we want to ensure that people can only use your session if they are working with
your views.
So with the view is rendered by your application so that this session is not available on any fake page
that might look like your page but that aren't your page and to ensure this to add this feature we will
use a so-called see as our token.
Now let me show you how this works in the next lecture.