So as RF protection is an important thing and to support data or to add it to the app.
I'll quit my server and I'll install another package with an install dash Esch save the name of the
package.
See sirf does a package for node Express which allows us to generate a so-called C as our token.
Basically a token string value.
We can embed into our forms so into our pages for every request that does something on the backend that
changes the user's state.
So anything like ordering something anything that does something sensitive which we want to protect
against we can include such a token in our views then and on the server.
This package will check if the incoming request does have dead valid token.
Now how does this protect us.
While the fake sites might send a request to your backend and they could theoretically use your session
they are for but the requests will be missing the token and descant guess the token because it's a random
hashed value and only one value is valid of course and the package here which runs on the server determines
whether a token is valid so they can't guess it and they also can steal it because a new token is generated
for every page you render.
So with the package installed Let's rerun NPM start and let's use that Sezer package.
And how do we use it to enable CSR protection.
We go to our actually last fall and then there.
First of all at the top let's import this package name the constancy SRF and all require to see serve
package.
Please note the package is named see sirf.
The attack pattern is C S or F.
That is why I named the constant like this.
You can name it however you want of course.
Now we can create a new constant where we initialized this.
You could say down there maybe where we initialized some or all things to all initialize Mirer Cirrus
Caesar or any protection by executing C is r f as a function.
Now you can pass an object here where you can configure some things for example that you want to store
the secrets that is used for assigning your tokens so for hashing them that you want to store them in
a cookie instead of the session which is the default.
But I want to use the session default.
And we also don't need to set any of the values you can dive into the official docs of that package
to learn more but the default settings should work fine so if that we get this seeis RF protection middleware
here we now just have to use that as a middleware.
So here ofter we initialized the session.
That's important because see as are if the package will use that sessional author we initialized the
session all at c is Areff protection.
So basically the constant which holds my created middleware here.
So now with that SEUS RF protection is generally enabled but we still need to add something to our viewers
to really use it.
Right now if I saved this and I go back to my app and I reload this page this works if I go to orders
this works the log out.
This fails the invalid see SRF token here and this is already showing us how we are what we have to
do in general.
It failed here because dead log out action here actually was a post request.
And for any non get requests because you change data why a post requests typically for any such requests.
This package will look for the existence of a C S R F token in your views in the request basically and
the request body now to make sure that such a token is there.
We first of all need to ensure we have it a way lable in our views to do that.
We have to pass data into our view.
So let's say I'm on the starting page slash nothing.
So in the controller actions that is my get index action does one.
Now here we would have to pass a new piece of information into the render method you could name it as
our token that name is up to you and you get it from request.
And then there there will be a series or a token method.
This method is provided by DC SRF middleware which we added by this package.
So now this will generate such a token and will store it in CSR a token which we Denne can use in our
view and there we could use it for example in the navigation where I have my log button form in there
we would have to add input which is hidden.
So it had no real input is rendered but word of value now is a value we output with the help of Ejay
us and that value here will be oleracea or f token and the name here is just a field and storing that
token when rendering that view.
This you'll see is or have token with that if I reload this page let's inspect the log out button here
in the developer tools
and let's make sure that in the navigation each S fall we don't just add it to the mobile logger but
all in the menu here.
So with that changed let me reload this and now inspecting the log out button you will see that there
we also have that input with the value of this token and this year is D.C.'s R.F. token which was generated
by the package.
If I now click on log out I still get an error here though.
The reason for that is that my package C S or f does not know that this hidden input contains my token.
It's just a hidden input without any name.
So what we have to do is we also have to give this a name and here important the name has to be underscore
Seer's or F because the package which we added will look for this name.
So for input with that name and the same of course should be done here in the mobile logon button.
Now if that if we reload this view for click log out.
Now it works because now the package is able to extract that see Aref token.
It also finds out that the token is valid and therefore it allows us to proceed.
So now it's not just a session that matters but all of the existence of this token.
Now we can add this to all our render functions because we need it in all our routes but that would
be a bit cumbersome.
So let me show you an easier way of getting data like this or also is authenticated into every page
we render and not just some.