So he added see is or if token protection but it will only work if we are visiting or get it next page.
Now we want to have such a token and by the way also our authentication status on every page we render
what we can do to get it onto every page is we can remove it from our render function here and instead
tell express chase.
And does this now totally unrelated from D.C. Is there anything tell express to us that we have some
data that should be included in every rendered view.
We'll do Disney-ABC J.S. file and there after this middleware where we extract the user.
But before all are relics I'll add another middleware normal middleware with our normal middleware function
with the free arguments and in there we can use a special feature provided by express JS We can access
a special field on the response the locals field.
This allows us to set local variables that are passed into the views local Simply because while they
will only exist in the views which are rendered.
So there we can add our is authenticated property which I removed from the render function where I X-ists
request session is locked in.
And I can also add my or f token variable which I get from request C is f token from this function.
So now for every request that is executed these two fields would be set for the views that are rendered
and then we have to call next so that we are able to continue with this if we go back and we reload
this page seems to work seems to work.
And now let's all try signing in where we also have a post request.
And now does fails.
And how do you know why it well.
Because I do pass my token into all views but in the views I still need to use it.
So for that we have to repeat the code we added to the navigation.
We need that hidden input with that name and that value.
And we have to add it into all our forms and that is something you just have to do.
So for example here in the Add to Cart Post forum we need Deadhead input to see is our token and also
an admin added product we need somewhere in that form that hidden token input the same for our all for
all it's of course when logging in we need to hit and put it the same for signing up.
This is required in the products Jasin the admin folder there.
We also have a forum for deleting a product we need to token in there too.
And in a shop in the cart we all have a delete card item button when you didn't put there as well.
And also down there for the order now button this also sends a post request and we need our hidden input
there are C S R F tokin on index Ejay S..
We don't need an add to cart.
I just added it so there we already have it in the product list page it's the same and it was added
to add to cart and all the product detail page.
I also only have to cart on the orders page here.
We all have no post for him.
So now we should have this tokin everywhere where we needed.
And if you save all that and you now go back to your let's say starting page and use it to logon page
and you do log in.
This now works because we have that token we also can add items to the cart.
We can also order them.
Well there is an area which you will fix in a second.
So for now let's not order them but let's delete them.
This works and generally just works.
Let me fix this bug here which is not too late to see SRF token in the next Lechter real quick but this
hopefully and that is the main takeaway here shows you how to use Sezer of protection and this is a
crucial thing which you have to add to any production ready application.
It's not optional.
Otherwise you'll have a huge security issue on your page.
You need to add this to ensure that your sessions don't get stolen.