So now it seems our protection was added.
Let me quickly fix that error where I was not able to order an item and their pop user name is required
ISDE issue which is frozen.
Let's quickly check the shop controller and their post order and in there I indeed store the username
and I'm not storing to user name any more here.
When signing up users only have to email.
So here we could store the e-mail for our user with request user e-mail on the order like this.
So instead of the name I now store the e-mail of the user in here or you also Amadis isn't just a user
id whatever you want.
Now in our order model This means that here I also don't expect the name but the email which still is
a string and still is required.
So this is a tiny change that needs to be done to fix that issue.
And if I now go back to products and I add this to my card and I add it to my card.
Again let's say that I have to order this.
Now this works.
And the cart is empty.
So this was just a little note something that was required.
Let's log out.
This all works.
Does this does bug fixed.