We've got all the core features that are related to authentication.
Implement it now when I work on the user experience a little bit at least right now when we log in and
we for example try to log in with invalid credentials where we don't find the email or the password
does not match or we try to create a user for whom the email already exists.
Then we are just redirected without any error message being shown on the page.
Now I will dive deeper into how to validate user input in the valley Dacian marginal to course but here
we're not talking about validation so much but really about giving some feedback to the user in general.
Now when rendering Due's with the render method as we are doing it here including data that should be
rendered on the page was simple by the way is offene.
It can be deleted here because we always include this as a local.
That is the case for all our routes.
As a side note.
So you can remove that indicated thing from all render methods but this is not really what I wanted
to do here it's a little aside thing we can do though.
The main thing is that it's easy to pass data to our views inside of the render method as you can see
it was never a problem to get our data into did you stare.
However it is a huge problem if you want to pass some data into the rendered view when we are redirecting
as we are doing it here because upon a redirect technically a new request is started a new request to
slash log in in this case.
And on that new request we don't know that we got here because the user entered an invalid e-mail or
anything like that when we triggered this new request.
Dessous treated in the same way as a request was triggered by clicking on the log in button in our menu.
So we have no way of finding out if we want to display the error message or not.
And hence in the render method of get log in where we showed the log in page we don't know if we want
to include some error message.
Now to solve that problem and storing some data before we redirect which we then use the brand new request
that is triggered by the redirect.
How could we do that well you learned if you want to store data across requests you need a session.
So we can use a session for that.
But of course I don't want to store the error message in the session permanently.
I want to add something to the error message kind of flash it onto the session.
And once the error message was then used to once we pulled it out of the session and did something with
it I went to remove it from the session.
So did for a subsequent requests this arrow message is not part of the session anymore.
And for this we can use another package which makes this really easy.
We installed it with NPM installed Asheesh safe and then the package is called connect.
Dash flash if you hit enter.
This gets downloaded and added to your project can restart the server thereafter.
And now connect flash is really simple to use.
First of all we initialize in our app chase folder and file in there we install it or we import it just
as we import our packages.
You can store it in a concept which you name however you want I'll name it flash and I will require
Kinect flashier now flash then needs to be registered.
You could say initialized I'll do this year at the bottom.
You need to do it after you initialized the session so certainly after dismal where they are I will
call you as and I will simply call flash as a function here.
Now we can use that flash middleware anywhere in our application on the request object.
So now let's save that.
Let's head over to office and let's say here when we're logging in and we don't find a user with that
e-mail which is the problem here we want to flash an Arab message into our session.
We do this now with request and there will be a flash method.
Now added by this package this flash message now simply takes a key under which this message will be
stored.
We could name this error.
And then the message.
And in this case this would be invalid e-mail were password.
Now you could also say just invalid e-mail.
Some people advocate not being as clear as people can.
Otherwise guess which part of the credentials was wrong.
I'd argue they can test is anyways by trying to sign up with that e-mail.
But whatever you want you can output or flash such an error message.
Now if there is a session and it's indure until we use it.
Now we want to use it here when we do render the log in page here.
I want to include an error message very let's say.
And that error message variable will simply pulled it by using request flash again.
And here we now just access to key for which you want to get the message.
So in my case that key is what I specified here.
Error.
So now I can pull that message out with error.
So whatever I stored in error will now be retrieved and stored an error message and there ofter information
is removed from the session.
So now error message will be set and will hold a value only if we have an error flashed into a recession
and therefore we can now move over to our view to the log in view and display the error message.
Let's say above all of that I add a death.
And for now let's make this really simple and just output our error message.
So here error message is the variable in which I'm storing it.
Obviously I want to check if that exists before I rendered this.
So we'll wrap this with some Ejay as if statement were a check if error message.
This will not be treated as true if it's simply not defined so if we simply are not able to retrieve
anything.
And then let's try to output it like this.
Let's see if that works.
If I go back to my application and I reload that log in page that seems to work.
And now let me Andray invalid email.
And indeed I see invalid e-mail or password if I do enter a valid email but the invalid password I don't
see that because I don't flash anything onto my session yet.
So this is working.
Now let's quickly reformat that.
I'll do that in next lecture.
You can skip it and download the finished formatted code if you want to and there after let's add an
Abra useful places to.