I'm outputting that error message I just want to style it a little bit now.
And for Dad I'll give it a C is this class and it's simply named add user message and then maybe user
message dash dash air or using some BGM styling here.
That's a SEUS as styling convention or a convention of naming your classes doesn't matter too much.
You can name just where we want the end.
I edit these two classes one to have a general message look and then one for errors because maybe we
all want to be able to output success messages later.
So with that let me quickly add this to some see as false and you can skip this lecture if you want.
In the next lecture you'll find the finished code attached which you can use in the main C of S all
quickly at this let's say at the bottom of this fall.
It's up to you right before the media queery maybe I have my user message.
So this is as class I just added here.
And let's say such a user message should use a margin auto to be centered get a width of 90 percent
by default.
I'll also set up some styling in case I'm on a bigger screen.
Their user message will have all width of let's say 30 REM and then here I'll give it a border of one
pixel Sallet and let's use maybe some some bluish color here maybe not that blue.
Well basically which ever blue color you want maybe does one and a background color.
Also use a blue here also a different blue so some light bluish color here.
So General Info message should have maybe some neutral colors so some blue like this.
And let's see how that looks like.
With it at it let me try entering invalid email again.
Looks like that.
Nah not too pretty.
That should be much lighter.
I also want to have some padding in here.
Maybe one ram and let's give it some rounded corners as well.
Now with dad if we enter the invalid email that looks much better.
Ok so now this is my general info message list maybe also to send her a text if we want to.
And now let's give it is air or we're basically with dash dash air or at sea class I added to this specific
box in my log in screen and there I will change the border color to be red and the background should
be a light red.
So let's start with red and then tear Turnus in for a light red.
And now if we try this again now it looks like this OK so this could be the error message we're outputting
here.
You could also turn the text red if you want so you could also say text color should be red here maybe
and reduce to padding maybe 2.5 that could look a bit better.
So invalid email or password.
That looks good.
Now I always have that stick around.
Now reason for Dad is if I go back.
Error message seems to be set to something even if we're not having a message in there and that is something
I'll check in the next lecture.