So I added a messagebox and the last lecture you can download the finished word not the entire project
attached.
I simply added C as this classes to my div which surrounds the message.
And then I worked on these classes and the mains is as follows.
I added user message and user message error and also added some user message entry to my desktop sys
classes so you can add this manually from the attached code.
Now one thing you'll notice is that even if you load the log in page regularly you'll see an empty box
here.
So even if no message is flashed it looks like error message is not set to undefined and therefore let's
quickly go to off and let's simply console log request flash error or to see what's in there that's
causing this to not be undefined.
Basically if I reload this page I see it's an empty array.
And if I do enter something here you.
It's an array of messages.
So in the end what do we want to do is we want to extract our message here is equal to request flash
error or now if message length is now greater than zero then I know I have a message ender.
So now actually turn into a variable by using LET here and then I can set message equal to message the
first element because I want to retrieve that overwise altered message equal to null and now down there
we can use the message and pass that as I erro message we now safe that don't have the box you're due
and or something invalid.
We do see the error message though.
But if I go to the logon page regularly without an error I don't see it.
So this is now how we can use these flash messages and output them in a nice air box.
Now here's a challenge for you.
Find some other places in the log in and sign up screen.
Really what makes sense to flash messages onto the screen.
We'll do it together in the next lecture.