So were you successful.
We added our flash message here when we used an email which we did not find.
Now obviously if we have a password that does not match here where we redirect to log in I also want
to flash my invalid email or password message onto the session.
So it is a great place because we now save this on the logon screen.
I might have a valid email but an invalid password and I get this error message with valid credentials.
It of course works fine though.
Now we could also do something when signing up because when signing up I'm checking with an email address
already exists.
Well before redirecting here I can also output something there.
Email exists already.
Please pick a different one.
Something like that we now save debt and I enter the e-mail address which indeed does already exist.
Well then I redirect it without having any effect.
And that makes sense because we flashed a message but I'm not outputting it.
So we need to go to the logon page and copy that code for outputting an error message and then go to
sign up and there above the form.
Let's also output the error message here.
But of course for this to work we also need to extract that when loading the sign up page.
So that code which I'm using and get log in to render my error message I need to get in get sign up
to.
And then there I also need to pass this error message variable Ceuta view which holds that message I'm
extracting.
I realize we can't display it even though we flash it into the session.
So now if dat Let's try again let's reuse a passenger email that already exists.
And now I get this error if I do create a valid user with a valid email.
This works however.
So now we quickly check our users collection.
We see that was added.
So these are some messages.
I can flash onto the screen you could add more.
For example after logging out you could also output some confirmation for that but this should do it
for now was a nice practice and improves the user experience a little bit.