So that's it for this module I'll actually dive into some other indication related things in the next
modules for example we'll add password resetting but these are the basic things you need to know about
all indication you learned what authentication means that it means that not every visitor of your page
can view and do everything that all indication has to happen on the server side to ensure that users
don't trick you into thinking they are authenticated and that you Daffer use sessions to stored the
authentication status and that you can't protect routes by checking that session controlled log in status
right before the request reaches your control or action or the code in general that is executed in a
route.
Now of indication obviously all the is strongly tied to security and providing a good user experience
and they offer passwords should absolutely be stored in a hashed form if you store them in plain text.
If your database gets compromised the attackers have full access to your user accounts.
Additionally see SRF attacks cross-eyed request forgery attacks are a real issue because your session
can be stolen there so to say and therefore you should implement SRF protection as shown in this module
in any production ready app you're planning to ship.
Now for a better user experience you can look into flashing data or messages as we did in this module
into your session store.
Flashing means that this data will be removed from the session automatically by a package we use once
we used the data and we can use that data to persist data across redirects because redirects technically
triggered two different requests or we have the old request redirect and then a new request starts.
If you want to share data cross request as you learned we need to use a session.
So these are the general often occasionally the things you need.
And with this knowledge you already get very very far.
Now in the next module we'll have a look at how we can send mails from inside our Dode application because
we'll need that feature to enhance our application a little bit regarding the authentication so that
we can also add a password resetting mechanism.
We'll do this in the module there after the next module.
Let's first of all have a look at how we send mails.