Welcome to this module the best things always come at the end.
In this module I want to dive into an exciting piece of technology whether you will dive into graph
Cuil and alternative to building a restful API that you would use in the same scenarios.
So when you have a de-coupled front and back end you will not render use with a graph to Al API to but
it provides some significant advantages over rest.
API eyes at least in certain scenarios.
So in this module we'll explore what graphical actually is and how it compares to rest API eyes and
you will learn how to use graphs you of course will actually take our existing project and turn it into
a graph l API or use a graphical API.
A very exciting technology.
I'm super excited to get started with it.
So let's dive in.