Know what is graphed you l to really explain it.
Let's compare it to arrest API which we already learn about arrest.
API is a state less co-aligned dependent API for exchanging data.
So it's a node express application or a node with any framework application of course that we build
to exchange data.
We don't render views we don't store sessions we don't care about the client.
We only get requests parse the data and return responses with data.
Typically Jason data a Graph API is generally not that different.
It's also a stateless client independent API for exchanging data.
But and that's the important part of course with higher Querrey flexibility and to understand that let's
look at some rest API limitations let's say in our rest API we have and pointed to it looks like yet
we can send a GET request to slash post.
And as you might imagine does what fecche as opposed to let's say from the database but could also be
from a file or anything like that of course.
And this is how a post might look like.
Now we returned Adjt. to decline that everyone is happy.
But what if we actually only need to title and ID on the client.
What if we don't need the content or we don't need to create or data we can of course have many scenarios
where we use one at the same and point in our front end application.
So in our single page application or our mobile application and in one place on one page we might need
Tideland content on the page we might need content and creator how can we solve that.
Well solution 1 is of course to simply create more endpoints dad returned to different types of data.
We can create a new rest API endpoint for example sending a GET request to post dash slim to only return
title and ID.
Now obviously by the way you could also of course use the same endpoint all the time and just pars or
filter out the data you need on the front end.
But then you sending a lot of unnecessary data over the wire which is an issue especially when working
with mobile devices.
So our solution could be to simply create more endpoints that simply return the data you need for each
of these endpoints.
The problem is you'll have a lot of endpoints and you'll have to update them continuously and you also
have a very unflexible solution here if you're front and engineers and in bigger projects you typically
work in different teams if they need more data on a new page.
They come to you as a back and developer and ask you to give him an endpoint that returns that data
and their stack in their frantic development until you added this so fast iteration on the front end
is made harder.
And on the other hand you want to back and continuously have to add new endpoints to cater for the needs
of your front and engineers.
So this is not the ideal solution to be to use Kuri parameters on your existing endpoints.
You could accept query parameters like data equals slim.
Now obviously that is an option but just as with the first solution you always have to add it so that
your front and engineers can continue and you have this dependency between front end and back end.
Additionally your API might become pretty hard to understand because it might not be clear which query
parameters can I set which values can I set on these query parameters.
So this is also not ideal ideal for apps where you often have different data requirements on different
pages is to use rafts you l there.
You don't have the problems I described before because there as you will learn you have a rich query
language that you use in your front end to send it to the backend which is then parsed on the back end
and dynamically retrieves just the data you need.
So it's almost like a database query language which you use on the back end like sequel or mom to be
query language almost like something like this for the front end.
So which you put into the request you send to the backend.
Now that is the idea but how does graph work then.
Well we get our client we got our server and on the server you generally have your logic for interacting
with the database with files.
Anything like that.
Now what do you send from client to server in that graph Q L world.
You only send one kind of request and that is a POST request to graph Q L slash graph Q L.
So you only have one single and point where you send your HTP requests to even for getting data.
And why is that.
Well for a POST request you can add a request body and that request body will contain that query expression.
Raf Curiel defines its own query language and I will show you where to learn more about this module
of course and you use that Korean language you put it into a request body and you just can't send request
bodies on get requests for example.
So you put your query language expression into that request body and data will be parsed on a server
to then do some magic on it and return you just the data you want.
That is the idea behind graft.
Well now such a gradual Kery would typically look something like this.
It's just an object like structure where you have an operation type query before getting data.
You also have other types like mutation for editing or deleting or inserting data or subscriptions for
setting up real time data subscriptions using web sockets.
You also have d d and points.
You could call them or the commands you can execute and you to find them as a developer on your back
and the away label endpoints and then the fields you want to extract and that is the flexible part because
you could in one place get the user with just a name and in another place you could get name age and
email.
So that is exactly what you put into your query which you send to your back and which is then parsed
there now regarding these free operation types as I mentioned we got a curry there.
We retrieved data and we use a POST request for that.
But if we want to compare it to the rest API world then this would be your equivalent to sending a GET
request to some path there.
We also got mutations which basically are used for everything that changes data.
So what you previously handled with post put patch and delete requests and subscriptions as I mentioned
set up real time connections.
Why a web sockets will not focus on that.
And this module because this is no graphical course and indeed you can create whole courses on graph
you all here.
I want to focus on the core features.
So to sum it up in a big picture we have our client we send a request to that single graph to Al and
point on our server.
And then there and this is the part you will do with me in this module.
There you set up your definitions for Curie's mutations and possibly also subscriptions indeed definitions
you use type definitions because graphed you use is a typed Clery language which means you define the
types of data you work with the types of data you return in a query and so on.
And DS and points you define here.
So these queries and mutations and subscriptions you define these are connected to so-called risk solvers
which are functions that contain your server side logic and if you compare that to arrest API the definitions
would be your routes and there is solver's would be your controllers and that is how you can look at
graphs well and this is how we will implement it.
So to sum it up its a normal node and possibly express server.
Of course you are also not limited to using Express J.S. you're also not limited to using note by the
way the graph Q L language or broach can be used with any programming language.
Just as rest API is good but this is a node course of course.
So we'll focus on that.
You have one single endpoint.
Typically slash graph to l though you could change this of course.
You only use post requests because you put that query expression into the request body and you have
resolvers on the server side that analyze that request body and then do something with your data based
on the query expression you had in that body and will use third party packages for that parsing and
so on.
So posting for getting data that is the most confusing thing you typically have when diving into graphs
you.
Yes this is what we do.
Does this what is ok here.
Because we describe that data we want to get in the request body.
Now that was a lot of theory.
Let's see it in action.