To see an action I'm back in our rest API project we created earlier where we previously added socket
IO.
And first of all I'll get rid of that socket IO part I'll remove it I'll remove the socket and just
fall in and actually yes I will also remove my routes because we will have no more routes will not set
up routes anymore will use graft you will endpoints instead.
I'll leave the rest as it is for now.
Remove that code where I use my routes.
And then here I will not store the server because I will not set up any socket connection.
And we can also now remove the routes folder because I will not use it anymore.
So now I cleaned it up a little bit and now I want to use graphed you out and for that all install to
new packages.
The first one is called just graft you l.
This will be required for defining the schema of our graph.
Q else service.
So basically the definition of the queries amputations and so on.
We want to allow.
And I will also add express craft well to install a simple server that will do the parsing of incoming
requests and so on.
Now if you want to learn more about graphics you'll check out graph Q l dot org.
It's a great resource with a lot of documentation on raft to L and it's core language which by the way
is clearly defined.
And we need strong rules sets to know how we write queries and there if you click on code you also find
libraries for all kinds of languages.
And if you choose javascript you'll find the graphs you all package we just installed which allows us
to define such a schema as I mentioned.
You'll find the expressed graphs you will and you also find other solutions for ABA frameworks Appollo
for example is super popular and works with any node framework.
It offers more than the Barebone set up expressed graph.
Google gives us though and I want to show you a very raw approach in this module so that you understand
all the behind the scenes things Apollo would hide some of these things.
So I will instead use Express graph Cuil.
Now with that out of the way we installed that we cleaned up our project.
Now lets add some graph to all logic.
And how do we do that.
First of all I'll create a new folder named graft L where I will put my graph to all related code and
there I'll add my schema dot js file where I find the queries mutations and types I work with in my
graph tool service I'll create and I'll add a resolver as JS file where I will define the logic that
is then executed for incoming queries.
Now in schema JSE Let's start with that there.
First of all imports something from that graphed you l package installed not from Express graph but
just graphical.
And that's something I import is to build schema function which allows me to build a schema which can
then be parsed by graph Kielland by express graph Q L I will export this schema so I'll use module exports.
And then I will call the build schema function and I will return that schema object.
This will generate for me.
And now here we pass a string where we describe our schema use doubleback ticks here.
So not single quotation marks but back ticks to create a string literal template literal because there
you can simply write multi-line strings.
And now to define a graphical schema in this string we type schema and add drolly bracers.
Please note that there is no colon after a schema and in that schema we now define a query field.
And this now will be an object with all the queries and queries are the parts where you get data.
So all the Corrie's you want to allow to make it easier to read.
I'll now add a separate type for that with the type keyword which I'll name Kuri you could name this
differently you named as root query however you want now in there you will have all the different queries
you can make in the end.
For example you can add one to this named Hello.
Simply a basic dummy query here hello which let's say returns a string.
This is how you define the return type for a query.
You add a colon after declaring name and then the type and graphed your nose a couple of type's strings
into tears floats booleans IDs and you can learn all about that in the official docs of course.
So now this is my rude Korean does the return type of my query here.
This is now a very basic schema where we can send a Hello Korea to get back some text.
Now that some text now is the find in the resolver the resolver is an export object where we now need
a helo function.
Hello Methot.
So you need a method for every query or mutation.
You define your schema and the name has to match of course.
I have a method named Hallo here because here I have a query named Hello.
You don't need to resolve this query because in your schema you basically set up your rude query which
has then made up of these sub queries which now need resolvers.
So now we have as solver for a Hello Dad Hello method and there we need to return a string.
Right.
We expect the string you can buy away to make this string required by adding exclamation mark.
Now if you don't return a string you'll get an error.
So here I could return hello world like this if I now save that I have a very simple graph cool service.
Now before we test it let's make it a little bit more complex in my schema.
I'll add a new type and I'll name that test data.
The name is up to you and there I'll have a text which has a string and I'll have the views property
which is like say integer.
Both are required.
Please note there is no comma authored these fields.
You simply use new lines.
And now let's say my Hello query should return that test data instead of a boring string Well then we
can go back to the resolver.
And now we need to return an object in there with a text field that should be a string.
Hello world.
And with a views field which should be an integer.
Now we have a valid resolver.
We have a valid schema.
Now we need to expose it to the public and that can be done with the express graphical package in actually
as we now import dead.
So here all implored Grath Hugh l age to be.
You can named it however you want from Express graph you el And let's now scroll down all the way to
the error handling the louer and there let's add another middleware so that all the words do apply here.
I will apply this to slash graph Cuil and you could change that.
But that is a common convention to use.
And I deliberately don't limit this to post requests here and I will show you why in a second.
So please make sure you use use here and then you use that graphical HTP method which is provided by
express ref Q L and you has a javascript object to it to configure it now this needs two items to work.
The first is the schema.
And for that we need to import the schema which we export into schema skate Jarius file.
So here I'll import raft you l schema by requiring it from graphical schema and I need to import my
graph 2L resolver by importing it from the resolver as Voll in the graph Cuil folder.
Now we can go down and use the graph gules scheme schema here as to schema.
And we also need to set the root value which now points that our resolver.
So this is now digraph QOL resolder.
With this setup we can start our node server here and now let's try this out.
You might remember that we have to send post requests right.
So let's use postman for testing there.
I'll send the request to localhost 88 slash graph Q L and that should be a post request.
Now in the body of that request we sends Jason data that describes our query.
So we set this to raw application Jason.
And here you send data like this.
You send a javascript object with a career wiki and this does not mean that we send a query and not
mutation.
It simply is something which the Express graphical package will look for inside of these curly braces.
You now write the real query.
But actually here this is a string.
And then the value here between double quotation marks is your graphical query expression.
And there you add curly braces and in between the name of the query you want to target.
And if we have a look at our schema we see that we have a hello query so we can target.
Hello here and hello.
Returns us test data which has text and views.
Now we need to find which data we want to get back for that query and therefore offered the name of
the query.
We add a number pair of curly braces and in between we list the properties the fields we want to get
back for that query.
We simply separate them with blanks.
So here I could get my text for example but not the views if and I would send.
Indeed you should get hello world here.
And if you add a whitespace and then views you will get the views too.
And this shows you the flexibility already.
It's one and the same endpoint but we find which data we want to get on the front end.
And it's important to understand that we don't filter the data on the front and it gets filtered on
the server by express graph.
Well in our case which does the heavy lifting here and we simply define our schema and the resolver
in the resolver.
We return all the data but then graphed you all on the server will filter out just the data that was
requested by declined.
This is how graphical works in a nutshell.
Let's now see how we can add a mutation.