We edit our first graph kill Querrey which allowed us to get data.
Let's now add a query that allows us to save data and for debt.
Why don't we start with our Front-End which we used and make sure that we can actually sign up users
so that we can create users because that sounds like a mutation to me for it.
First of all let me clean up my front and I'm not using Succot I O error there anymore.
So in the fetal J.S. file at the top.
Remove that open socket import and then let's remove that logic from component did mount where I created
my socket connection and let's all the room move add post and up that post.
I'll do that differently later after changing this.
Let's go to actually yes which is where we do sign up and we want to make sure that forward a sign up
Handler.
We now reach one of our mutations.
And for that we first of all need to create it.
Now how do we create a mutation.
I'll get rid of this resolver will later add.
Can we resolve this again.
For now I will get rid of my query here.
For now I only need a mutation and we add that no schema by adding mutation here and then just as with
the query we define a type which you could name station or root mutation whatever you want.
And there you now to find different mutations.
You want to allow.
So here I'll just point at the root mutation and then the root mutation.
I'll add one Witchell name.
Create user you could name it sign up you can name it whatever you want.
Now that mutation here will actually require some input some arguments and that is a difference in text
which you now haven't seen before.
You can add parentheses after you require the name.
And this allows you to specify arguments that have to be given to Dad resolder that will run in the
end.
And here we could find that we need some user input data.
And now we need to find a type of that data.
So how does this data look like.
Well first of all we could of course except the title of type string and then another argument which
is not the title the email of type string and then a number argument which is a password of type string
that would work too.
Or we bundle it in one object which we expect and for data object we can create a new type and we don't
do does with the type keyword but there is a special keyword for day that that is used as the input.
So for data as is used as an argument and that is the input keyword and you can now named as however
you want.
I'll name it user data and their.
How does my user data look like or my let's name it.
User input data maybe.
How does that look like.
Well that will be an object which has an email field which is a string that is required.
I need that to be a string and I need that field to be there.
I also will get a name which is a string and a password.
Now this is the data type I'll use here for my argument to create user.
And now the question just is what do I get back after a user was created.
Well there I want to get back a user object.
So for that all define a new type not input but normal type which name user.
There I'll have an underscore ID field which will be an ID type.
It's a special type provided by graft UL which simply signals that this is unique and well treated as
an ID.
I'll then also have the user name which is a string.
I'll have the email which is a string.
I have the password which is a string which I don't require let's say because I don't necessarily need
to return that I'll have a status which is a string and I'll have my posts now that will be an array
and for that I also need to define how my posts should look like select me to find another type for
the post type and that will have an ID.
That will then also have a title of course.
A post will also have a content the post will then also have the image you are el
And of course you might notice some similarities to my mongoose models.
There I also defined how the data will look like and how it is connected.
We're essentially doing the same here because this will allow us to then retrieve that data efficiently.
So now I have my post in which you are all we alterable have a creator which is a user object and we'll
have to striated at field.
Now granule does not know dates.
So I'll use a string here and the same for updated at.
Remember we'll get these two fields because in the mongooses model for the post we enable time stamps.
OK so that is the post model we needed that because the user type we now will have an array of posts.
And this is how you tell graphs you all that you have an array of something you enclose it in square
brackets and that user data is now what I want to return here when I create a user that is a schema
defined.
Let's now work on the resolver for that.