We have to create user schema.
Let's now work on the resolver that allows us to create a user for Dad and the resolvers file all as
create user like that.
And now here I actually get some arguments.
You all do so in queries where you get data right away.
There you could also get arguments for example when you want to retrieve a specific post with a specific
ID.
Here are my arguments are no post-paid either.
But the user input data.
My first argument there will be an R X object.
There is a second argument available which is to request byte away.
This will become important later now on the incoming Ark's object I can retrieve all the data I find
in my schema.
So email name and password that is my argument data.
So that is what I can retrieve from the Ark's object.
Not directly on the Ark's though.
Instead our X will have a user input field because our X actually will be an object containing all the
arguments passed to that function.
Here it's only one but could be more.
So args will have a user input field and then there will have email name and password so I can retrieve
them.
I can for example retrieve my email by typing R X user input because in my schema I named this field
here user input and on the user input I can get the email.
So Dot email like this.
This is one option.
We can all use destructuring to get user input out of my args object.
And then the email will just be user input email.
So a bit shorter now we'll use this in a second.
First of all let's import the mongooses user model.
Because I'll still interact with the database of course.
So I will require model's user and then in here I want to use the async awaits syntax to use that I
need to change the way I write this method.
I add a colon after create user and use the function keyword.
And now I can add async in front of that.
So now I can use a single weight that is purely optional though.
You could also use the normal then catch approach with your promises now and there.
First of all I want to find out if that user already exists and for that I'll get an existing user by
a waiting for a user find one where the email in the database matches the email entered in the user
input.
Now one super important note if you're not using a single weight you need to return your find one query
which you're executing here where you'd then add then because if you don't return your promise in the
resolver graph kill will not wait for it to resolve when using async wait it's automatically returned
for you.
We don't see the return statement here but it is there.
So that is super important.
So now I'm getting my existing user and if I have an existing user Well then I know I don't want to
create a new one.
So in this case I will create a new era or with a message of user exists already and I will throw dead
error and I will come back to error handling and draft's you all in a later lecture.
If I do you will have no existing user with that email address.
Then I can continue with storing it and the logic for that is similar to the one in my off controller.
We need to be tripped to hash to password.
So in my Risaldar function here let me import be tripped at the top and then there we can use the hash
method to hash the user input password with twelth salting round's.
Now again I'll use async await your.
So I'll get my hashed password eventually ofter awaiting waiting for days to finish.
Now after I got that I can create a new user object and then that user object I will pass to email which
is user input email I'll pass the name which is user input name.
I'll also pass the password which is my hashed password.
Now I need to save that to the database and I do care about the created user so all stored at stored
or that created user are in a constant by a waiting for a user safe and that will just be returned at
user object.
It created now here finally I need to return some data and we see which data in our schema we need to
return a user object.
For that here I will return my created user underscore doc field which contains just user data without
all the meta data.
Mongoose would add our Weiss and it will override the underscore ID field by adding it as a separate
property and therefore it will override the one I'm pulling out of.
Underscore doc because I need to convert it from an object id field to a string field.
Otherwise it will fail.
So here I will access created user underscore ID and then call to string.
This is not a user Optik.
I'm returning when I'm creating a user.
Now one important note before we actually tried an R fronted application.
We can of course try that from inside postman but there is an even more convenient solution for testing
this before I show you a solution.
Let me first of all clean my database though.
So did we start from scratch.
And for that I'll delete both my posts and my users collection here.
It will be created on the fly again.
Once I got data to enter and I simply want to remove all entries I have thus far.
So now I have to clean database.
Let me show you that simpler approach am referring to to test does mutation.
I can go back to aperture Yes on the back end code and there where I register or set up my graphical
endpoint besides setting the schema and root value.
You can also set graphical written graph IQ L to true.
This gives you a special tool and this is the reason why I'm not listening for a post requests only
here because now with your running server.
Try visiting local host 880 slash RAF to L and this will send a get request if you enter something in
the browser here here you sent a get request and you will get this screen which allows you to play around
with your graphical API.
Now if you go back to your back end to the schema quickly add a query again to your schema your root
query
creates data types your real quick and then there just at that how low again like this.
We don't need to resolve for dead.
We just did that query.
Now if you reload your graphical interface you actually have that documentation on it right here where
you see the operations you can do but you need to have a query defined for that even if it leads into
the white.
And there you can click onto it to see which mutations you have which data you need to send and so on
and you can not just explored it here.
You can even send your data so any year you can now create a new mutation about hyping M-E you and you
will even get all the completion.
Then curly braces and now with control space.
You even get suggestions if you have more than one object will not be filled in automatically but you'll
get a dropdown instead.
You get suggestions for what you can run and here you now.
This needs a user input then a colon and then an object that contains the user input data.
And there you see we need that email wrapped in double quotation marks.
Test test.
Com we let's say need a name that could be max and we need the password and that is testor and there
after we add a pair of curly braces.
And now we can find the data we want to return offered as cories done with control space.
We get some suggestions.
I liked the idea that was generated or email and now you can run this query by pressing that play button
up there or hitting control enter.
You also see the commands here.
And this will now execute it and it seemed to have succeeded.
You see the idea of the created user and to email and if you go back to Mangieri become pass and you
refreshed it.
Here you should have the users collection back and you see the user in there with the hashed password.
So this is a great tool for playing around battered and postman because you got this nice interactive
support with the auto completion.
You've got the documentation here and you can test your graphical query in this tool in a really nice
way.
And now with that let's see how we can enhance this for example by adding validation before we then
also connect our front end application of course.