Now we added our first nutation and mutations of course also means that we store data in the database.
When something like this happens we want to ensure that the data we store is valid and previously in
arrest API and also in the normal node express application where we rendered views we use Express validator
for that and we added that as a middleware on our routes with graft to elders is not an option because
we only have one route.
This one does the only endpoint we have and we certainly don't want to validate all requests in exactly
the same way.
So to change that and to adjust it to our needs we want to move validation into our resolvers.
There we have our endpoints and there is a place where we can now validate our incoming request data
to do validation dare all install a new package with NPM install and then dash dash save.
And that is called validator and that by the way is a package which express validator use behind the
scenes we can use that directly in our code now so line resolvers fall.
I will import that validator object provided by the validator package and now uncreate user we can add
some validation logic with simple IF statements.
For example I can check if I don't have a valid email.
So not validator.
And then is e-mail and you got the same rules as with Express validator because as I mentioned it builds
up on this validator package and then check is user input email is not an email address.
And if that is the case then I want to store that error so I'll create my own arrows array here.
And that's just one way of handling this.
You could find a different pattern of course.
And I will push a new error onto desir.
And for me here and that again is only my implementation and error will be an object where I have a
message for example e-mail is invalid.
Now let's say we don't just want to validate to e-mail.
We also want to check whether our password is there and if it's too short.
So if validator is empty
user input password then we have a problem because then we got no values for the password or we all
have a problem if it's not empty.
But if the length is not long enough.
So if the length for a password is not fitting the criteria we specify in the second argument to is
length which is an object where we can set a min and max key and I'll set mine to 5.
So if we enter a password that is empty or not long enough.
So if it is not long enough we need to add an exclamation mark here.
Then we make it into this if statement here.
And then we all have a problem in there.
I also want to push an error onto my arrows aere and they are all add a message of passwords to short
notice it is just one way of implementing this.
Now after having all these checks I can check if my arrows array has a length that is greater than zero
which means I do have errors and if I do them I'll create my own new error object where I've fro invalid
input or where a report invalid input.
And now I throw that error.
Now let's give that a try.
If I now try to add an email address which is not an e-mail address and I hit play here I indeed see
my invalid input message and that is how we can add validation.
What if we now want to pass more data with our error message here.