We added validation and we see that a failing validation and hence of an error.
As we were doing it here leads to a response that actually has null in the data it gives us back but
that has an error or a key with an array of all the arrows Gabbert.
If you open the network tap right away.
And you relax.
Q Did you also see that it sets a status code of 500.
No that's nice.
But sometimes you want to add more detailed information.
You can set your own status code though.
But we could add more information to the arrows.
We'd return and to do that you can go to your Actually us file and there where you configure your draft
Cuil API.
You can add a number a configuration option which is called format error and this is actually a method
which receives the error detected biographical and allows you to return your own format.
Now if you just return error you keep the default format which is exactly the format we see here.
But you can change it of course.
You can check if in your error here you don't have the original Arrowfield.
So if you don't have that hence the exclamation mark at the beginning or original error will be set
by express graph Cuil when it detects an error free zone in your code either by you or some third party
package.
If you have a technical error let's say a missing character in your query here or anything like that
then it will not have that original error.
And if we don't have that then I'll just return the error that was generated by graph Q L but if I do
have my original error Well then I can extract useful information from it that I can add in other places
and that is what we can do into resolder Now let's say validation fails on the error that gets created
here.
I could add a data field which is my array of errors which I populate here with my validation error
messages.
I could also add a code here which is set to 422 or I come up with my own coding system.
I don't have to use HTP status codes here and now in actually yes I can retrieve all of that from the
original error so I can get my data from error.
Original error data.
And that might be undefined for grown aerostat though and said it but that's ok.
I can retrieve my message directly from the error because Dad has already pulled out of the error.
Biographical And in case that should be undefined somehow I can set this to an error or cur'd and I
can get my code from the original error again Dare I named that code too.
And it could set this to a default value of 500.
Now if all that pulled out I can return my own error object here where I have a message just like the
original one but where I'd then also add my status field which contains my code and a data field which
contains my data.
And you can name all these fields in exactly the way you want.
And now with that and all the files saved here.
If I hit enter again or play again.
Now I see I get a different era output with the data I added and this can be very useful.
And this is how you can handle errors engraft you El.