Now it's finally time to work on that re-act application we have as a front into YOUR which you also
find attached to this lecture again in case you skipped the modules so re-act application will not work
on the code here too much because it is no re-act course and now I'm interested in signing users up.
There's a standard the aperture last fall there and there and the sign up handler here we send the request
for creating a new user.
But this is of course a request from the rest API world.
You learned that from now on there are only as Slash graph Cuil for all our API requests.
And then here does has to be a post request.
The type is still application Chaisson and this needs to be set but the body will now be in the Rathcoole
query language and vidis all create a new constant which all named Q L graph Q L query.
The name is up to you though and this will be a javascript object where you need to have a query key
that is required even for mutations.
Their value here then is a string which you create with double tactics tactics so that you can write
multi-line string single quotation marks will not do it.
And here you add mutation to define that you you're running a mutation now curly braces and now the
name of the mutation.
The name of the mutation you want to execute is create user.
Essentially you could just copy this query here.
Now this is what you could copy and what you could move into your query here.
Now of course we need to replace these values with the values we fetch from the user input though and
we can do that by using dollar sign curly braces in this back.
Take enclosed string because it is a template literal and this allows us to inject values.
Now just make sure you keep the double quotation marks around and check that values.
Otherwise this will fail because this query language here needs to enclose strings in double quotation
marks.
Now the email can be retrieved just as we retrieve it down there so we can copy that code up there.
And the same of course also for the name and the password for it name.
We all check the value of Thaller assigned curly braces and we used that syntax from below.
And the same for the password.
Let's copy that and replace this with D inject that password code.
Now here I am retrieving ID and email.
It's up to you we don't need any of the data.
I'll leave it like this and now does the object I want to string you fine.
So my graphical query object.
No I don't need to check the status code here because there will not be a set.
It's either 200 or 500.
I'll cut it here and I'll remove that and end the response data then block here where I have the Parus
to request a response body there.
I can now check if response data has errors and there on the first error I could check for the Status
field.
So here I will check if response data has errors.
That's the case I'll check if response state errors and they are the first element has a status field
just as I explained.
Accessing this field and if that is equal to 422 and then I can feel my validation failed error.
Maybe we have other kinds of errors so I'll check a number of thing here in case we don't Frode at first
error.
I'll check just for the existence of errors.
And there I would fro a number in error where it just.
User creation failed like this.
Now offer DS error or checks I'm printing my response data here.
And actually we should have all we need to sign users up now.
So let's run our server with an p.m. start.
It runs on localhost free 0 0 0 0 0 0.
And let's open that here and there.
Let's navigate to the sign up page and create a new user.
Now this is a email address which is already taken.
And actually therefore I should fail doing that.
Let me click sign up and indeed I get an error.
But this is a different error and you might expect an error here where my method is not allowed and
this can be a tricky thing to fix if you're brand new to craft.
Well the reason for this error is we get this error.
Actually as a response to our options request here not to our post request.
Now you might remember that I explained that the browser sends an options request before it sends the
post patch put delete or so on request.
The problem is expressed graphed you l automatically declines anything which is not a post or get request.
So the options request is denied.
The solution is to go to that middleware where I set up my course headers and there I check if my request
method is equal to options and if it is all options request then here I'll return rest's send status
200.
So I'll simply send an empty response with a status code of 200.
I return so that this code is not executed and therefore options requests never make it to digraph cool
end point but still get a valid response.
And with data fine I'll go back to my Front-End I clear my error and sign up again.
Now the user creation fails but now it simply fails because if you look into our data we see that the
user exists already and that is what we expect.
And now if we take a valid email address which is not taken yet it actually succeeds.
And here is the response I get back from graphed you l My data that is provided automatically for the
create user query.
To date fields I requested and this is how we connect the front end to our back and by simply sending
a post request with a valid graphical query expression.