Knouted we're able to create new users.
How does authentication work in the graphical world.
Does it work in a similar way to rest your eyes.
Do we use sessions again.
Well remember this slide a graph to you all API is also stateless and client independent.
So generally we still offend DK by using such a token which we then attach to every request that should
be able to access protected resources and a log in action is in the end just their normal Kery where
we send some user data and where we want to get back a token.
Right.
So in the end what we can do here is the following on our back and code in our schema.
I will now to find a real query instead of my dummy placeholder.
Hello query which name log in here.
I'll need some data.
And I could again to find my own input like here.
I did for a user input data but also to show how to use multiple arguments.
I will expect that email which is a string and a password which is a string.
And then I will return not a user but some data that contains let's say the user id and the token because
these are the two pieces of information.
I happened to need here and that makes sense as a response.
Of course you could return the overall user object.
So here all the a new type I'll name it off data and that will be my token which is a string and my
user ID which will be a string.
This is the data I will return when someone sends a query to log in.
Now we need a resolder for this of course so let's head over to resolvers and offer trade user.
I'll add my log in solver.
There again I get my R X and I can use destructuring again to retrieve the email and the password argument
which I both get because I did find both here in my log inquiry.
Again I want to use async await.
So I will turn this into a async function with this syntax and then there in my log and resolder to
go.
Now of course is to find a user with the right email address and then confirm the password.
So first of all I'll get my user by waiting for a user find one where I look for e-mail address in that
database that should match the e-mail I'm getting as an argument.
If this is not said if the user is undefined.
No I noted I've found no user with that e-mail address and therefore I can create a new error where
I say user are not found or whatever you want to set as I arrowed As such I can set a code here just
as I did it for a create user of let's say 404.
Because we didn't find a user or four hundred one because the user could not authenticate all go with
for 0 1 and all Froedtert error if we have passed does a check then we know that we have a user with
that e-mail address.
Now we need to check the password for Dad we used to beat up the package in there to compare function
and we pass in the password send with the request and the stored hashed password.
Now this is an asynchronous operation which gives us a promise so we can await debt and get back to
you is equal response.
Now if it's not equal then I know the user entered a wrong password so I can create a new error here
where I say password is being correct and I can also set the arrow code or 400 in one of your.
And then all is a fraud data error of course our Y is both to email exists and the password is correct.
And now I can generate a token and for that I'll again import my Jason web token package by requiring
Jason Webb token here and then down there in the log in resolver I will generate a token by running
JWT sign here are you now past data you want to encode in the token that could be your user ID which
you get from user underscore ID to string to convert to a string.
Maybe you also want to encode the email by getting data from the user or you you retrieve from the database.
And the second argument to design method Dennis your super secret secret which you use for assigning
the token which you don't use for verifying it something will do later.
And I'll configure it a token with the third argument by setting to expire is key in that object you
pass to the third argument to one hour so that the token expires after one hour.
That is exactly what we did and the rest API I.S. to now I will return that token in a token key and
make sure to match that schema you defined here so token and user ID is returned.
So in the resolver will you return the token on the token key and user ID which is again my user underscore
ID to string
and now with that we have a log in Clarion place where we send like a get request to lock the user into
gets the token and so on you could say now we need to wired it up to the front and in the next step.
And then of course test it.
If you're feeling bold all to try that on your own of course.