Did you try it on your own.
Well let's wire it up together for dead in the front and we need to go to the log in hndler which is
where we do log in users in the log in hndler I need to send the request to slash graph queue.
Of course it's a POST request.
And now all define my query.
So my graph all query you can name this constant however you want.
It's a javascript object with the keyword and then a string that defines to query and for a normal query.
You now don't repeat Kuri you just start right away with the curly braces as we did it.
And the graphical interface earlier.
Now let me splitters over multiple lines to make it easier to read in that Koury your.
I want to reach out to my log inquiry.
So to that query I find in that schema log in and need to pass email and password here.
So log in actually gets curly braces here and the email between double quotation marks will be the email
I also extract down there off the email in this case.
The second argument separated with a comma in this function like call here is to password also enclosed
between double quotation marks and there you inject off password off the password.
Now we can get back some data which we enclose between curly braces and the data we get back.
While there I'm interested in both the token and the user id so I specify both between these curly braces
here.
That is decree I want to execute and that is to date I to Jason string of ify on my request.
Body here.
Now as you learned checking the response like this will not work.
Instead we can grab the code we're used for signing up
this code here and copy that over in the log in hndler we therefore removed these checks in the first
then block and the second then block we now add the cockpit checks.
And here I just will say user log in failed because creation doesn't make much sense here.
Thereafter we set the state and the way we retrieve data from the response will not work.
I can already say that now.
Why will it not work well for that let's first of all run the query in the graphical interface there.
Let me get rid of that mutation instead.
Let's run a query.
You can also admit it does by the way and in their Donnelly's Hello I need to reload it now.
Log in.
Let me specify the valid email which I did use for the user and the password.
And now I want to get the token and the user id if I now had control enter.
I do get my data here.
And I do get it on an object which has a data field that is always added by graph Q L in there I have
the name of my query which was log in and there I have no response data.
So this is my rest data object in my re-act koto.
So rest data will be this entire object.
So if you want to get the token I need to drill into it into data log in token.
So in places where I'd just X-ists rested a token I instead need to do rest data.
Data log in token that is now the case for all the places where I retrieve something from the response
data I need to add data log in
with dead in place.
If I knew I was safe that front and code in the back end should be safe to of course we can go back
to our app and try logging in here.
And indeed we then get an error for fetching the posts which makes sense because we try to use our best
API you are l which does not exist but logging in actually succeeded.
So we got users sign up and log in emplace.
We now need to add some routes 4 or some endpoints for getting posts and for adding posts of course.
And we then also want to use that token we do get to protect certain but not all graft you'll endpoints.
These will all be steps with which we continue.