Knouted we have users in place let's work on posts.
And for now I will add posts without a real image because the image upload is something all managed
differently for a post with just title the content.
Some dummy text for the image you are L and an attached user.
You can definitely try this on your own though that will be challenging of course but give it a try.
Go as far as you can and then try to solve it together with me.
I will of course now also do it with you.
So I would start in my back and in my schema here and I will add a new mutation create post there.
I expect to get some data that describes the post.
We could get it all as separate arguments.
Or again we define import type which I will do here and that will be my post input data and in my post
input data here I will require everything I need to well create a new post and I expect that to be a
title which is a string the content which is a string and also the image Eurail the user is something
I can retrieve from the token which has to be attached at some point anyways and DMA upload something
will handle differently later.
So to post input data isn't the end what I get here.
So post input will be of type.
Post input data and I will return the created post here.
Remember that we did create that post type earlier already and now with that we can actually already
move on to the resolvers and add a new resolder Witchell name.
Create post in there.
I can use destructuring to extract by post input argument which I just find in my schema here.
And I do get the request as the second argument will need to add later to get the user data.
Now for now let's simply create a dummy post with dummy data we are able to use right now.
And of course let's also validate the input for validation.
I'll use the same approach as when we created oarlock to users in I'll create an empty array and empty
Aeros array and then I'll add a couple of if statements.
Here I'll check if validator is empty but this is empty.
So if the input is empty and I'll check that for my title.
If that is the case or if it don't meet a minimum length requirement with is length for the post input
title and then I can figure out its length with the second argument to be a minimum of five characters
long.
If we have either of these two cases then I'll push a new object onto my Aeros array with a message
of title is invalid.
Obviously again you could be more detailed here.
So that is my title validation.
I'll then add a number check where I check the content for exactly the same two things.
And that is it for now.
Now with that in place all keep my code I have up there where I have a look at my error.
Length and I will copy that down here to to throw an error if we have any validation errors.
If we make it past this if block here.
I know my input is valid and we can now create a new post for it.
It will eventually all need a user but for now I'll ignore the user and instead here up there.
I'll import my post mongoose model from the models folder and now we can use that to create new posts.
Which you of course do.
It's not user post.
By using our constructor mongooses gives us.
Now I want to use async a way.
Again all tweak that to use this syntax here.
Del down there where I create my books not user my new post I pass in the title which I get from post
input.
Title of course.
Also add to content here so post input content the image you are l.
Post input image your L and for now I won't add a creator here because I'm not able to retrieve the
user yet so that is my post.
I can now store the created post in a new constant and I get that by a waiting for post save to finish
here.
I'll then also need to add posts to users posts later once I do all the retrieve to user.
For now I can just return my response here so to say why getting all the data from the request from
the created post doc and then I'll overwrite the ID because I can't returned Mongo D-B object id I need
to return a string and I will override.
Created at an update to that because these will be stored as data types.
Graph CULE does not understand that.
So I need to convert that to a string too.
So I get that from my created post there.
Created at.
And I need to call to ISO's string here.
The same for updated at.
Updated at.
Will be created post updated at you Isel string and now with that does is the data I want to return
when a new post was added.
Now for now I'm not checking if the user is authenticated and so on.
I'll just have this resolver added this create post Roessler for the respective mutation.
Let's try it out in graphical.
First of all.
So here if I reload that sauted it loads my latest definition.
I can add a mutation here and that is now create post there.
I have my post input which is an object where I have a title test where I have a contant test and where
I have image your L sum you are l and where I then went that is recreated.
Can get back to the ID at the title at say let me click on pre-define to make this a bit easier to read
and now if I hit the play button I get invalid input which makes sense because Tyler and Condit are
too short so let's make them 5 characters long and now I simply get an error from the database that
the Creator is missing which makes sense.
But the general mutation is working.
Let's now make sure we also validate that token which we need to send anyways and that we extract the
user id and the user therefore so that we can connect posts and users and their ofter will of course
also connect to our front end.