The basic create post mutation is in place.
But now we need to be able to validate our token and extract the user from it and that is not too far
off on how we did it in our rest API.
First of all we need to ensure that we sent a token in a header off our incoming request and if we have
a look at our front end code and they're at feet J.S. which is where we do create new posts we do that
and finish at it hndler there.
We do indeed attach our token to the outgoing request.
And this is still the wrong you are here but this is how we will send the request in the end.
So we'll have that token.
Indeed you are l and previously and the rest API we use is all middleware to get our token from there
validated extract to user data and add the user data to user ID to the request object.
And that is pretty close to what I want to do.
Now I will just tweak it a little bit.
I'll name it off because it's not just there to validate authentication.
It will also give me the user data but that is something purely cosmetic in there.
I will still First of all get my off Hetter.
I'll check if it is set and if it is not set then I will do something different though I will not throw
an error instead on my request.
All set is off to false so that I can handle this inside of my resolvers.
And then I will return next to continue with the next malware and not execute the code here.
That is why all that the return statement.
If we do have the all pchter we continue we extract the token as before we try to decode it just as
before.
Make sure this key here match stickie you used in your resolver for signing the token byte away.
If these two don't match you have no chance of validating it or token.
We catch an error but if I get an error I again don't throw it.
Instead I said request is off to false and return next year to do not execute any error code.
If the decoded token is undefined.
I also Frot no error instead.
Here again I set is off to false and return next and if I make it past all these checks I will get my
user ID from the decoder token and it will set off to true.
So that is a new property at the request and I call next.
Now does tweak middleware is something I add an app.
Yes before my graft you l endpoint.
So here I will simply import that off by requiring it from malware off.
This is my middleware and I will add it here like dat dismally where will now run on every request that
reaches my graph CULE end point but it will not deny the request.
If there is no token the only thing it will do is it will set off to false and then I can decide in
my resolver whether I want to continue or not and this is the next step in my resolvers there.
I don't care about is often create user and so on.
So there I will just not do anything with that information in create post here.
I will first of all check if request is off.
If that is not true because then I know hey the user is not authenticated.
I certainly don't want to grant access to creating a post so if the user is not authenticated here then
I will create a new error not authenticated.
And I'll set a code of let's say 400 hundred one and that I'll throw my error and therefore the recode
in this resolver here will not execute.
If the user is authenticated we can continue then we validate the input and then before we create the
post we can now also get the user from the database because remember that we do store the user id in
our request as well so under a solver right before creating the post now I can get my user by a waiting
user find one or not find one.
I can actually use find by ideal of course and dare I pass and request user id so exactly the thing
I'm storing here.
I passed it in and now I get a user if I don't get a user here then something is wrong and I will throw
an error.
So here invalid user maybe set the code to 401 and Frode it.
But if we make it past that we have a user object with which we can work.
And now in the newly created post I can set the creator equal to my extracted user.
So to the user I got from the database
once I created the post I can now also use that user and x' the posts of that user to push the created
post onto that list of posts.
So to set up that connection that is now it.
And now we need to work on the front end to also send the request to design point so that we can see
those in-action.