On the front end in the finish add a handler function in the feet.
JS file there.
I'll ignore the image upload for now.
I want to now reach Mike Rathcoole and point and create a new user for debt.
First of all I will get rid of this code because I will not send this request to defend you or else
any more and I'll not use different methods.
It's always the same your L and the same method localhost ADHD graphed U L and the method simply is
host.
The body is all an open forum data.
But here I'll create a new query with LET because this will change when we edit the post later and my
query here is crap.
Well query my query here is defined as before query and then dessous multi-line string with back takes
it then actually is a mutation and the mutation is create post to that.
I need to send the data I did on my graphical user interface.
So actually I can copy that Yeater move that over there and now replace these hardcoded values with
dynamic values.
So here for the title I will pass post data title for the content.
I will pass post data content in the image.
I'll keep that to some your L for now.
Until we have a real image.
I get back to the idea and title.
Now let me first of all send this in a string if I were in the graph will query and then lets do something
with the response.
Now again this way of handling it will not really work.
So let's instead copy the code where we use an app geus where I check for errors on the extract of the
response body.
They offer I'd do it here.
Then I log my response data and you see I'm interested in the ID title content creator and created that
here.
So I should actually retrieve all of that.
So in my query I get the ID title content image.
You are l creator and created at St..
By the way the creator if you have a look at my schema is again a more complex object.
It's a user object.
So for the Creator we need to be more specific and that is the cool thing about graph.
All we can really drill into the data here.
Let's say I'm only interested in the name and indeed I am.
I don't care about the ID or email.
In this scenario here I want a name so that I can rendered it onto the screen next to my posts and this
shows the power of graph to really well we get exactly the data we need well.
Now with that we sent the post request here for extracting that data will have some problems.
But first of all let's focus on what we locked to the console and see if that works.
So back to our application I am still locked in because I have a valid token and I do still attached
as token by the way here.
But we all need a number header.
We need to add the content type and set that to application chase and that is required.
So make sure you add this.
And now back in the application click new post add a deck.
You have to choose the image here even though it's not uploaded.
Otherwise you can submit and then I'll add my lovely duck.
And here I get an error which was expected.
But I also see a console log which actually doesn't look too bad.
I do have all the data I entered and we can now have a look at more.
Would he be Compaq's and there if I refresh this and look into my post collection I indeed see a post
with the data I entered with that creator.
Ending with a 1.
If I have a look at my users I see that it's that user and they are on the posts.
I am unfortunately missing my post so that is one thing I will need to tweak but the rest is already
working really well.
Let's make sure we at that post here too.
And then of course let's make sure we extract the data on the front and correctly so that we also rendered
that post for Dad.
By the way we'll all have to make sure we load all posts initially though.