Know let's first of all thicks the fact that our user does not have the post added to his posts Saray
the reason for that is that I do push to post here.
But of course I forgot one important thing.
I never saved debt change I need to call users savior and I'm not interested in the result but I certainly
want to await it none the less so that I only return after this has been done.
So this is one important change and this is only one change we need though we can quickly validate whether
it works.
However by going to posts let's delete that post which we added here and now let's go back to our front
and add and you post and number.
Duck choose an image even though it's not getting used.
Let's add some content and click except we still get that error.
But if we go back to camp pass we have a look at our users for the first user.
We now also see that post here.
So Dad is now working.
And now let's make sure we also extract the data correctly on the Front-End and that we don't all load
all posts so that we really can see them there.
Now for the data extraction we see that this is the data in the format we get it back.
An object with a data field then the name of our query and then in another nested object the fields
for that query.
And this is exactly how we have to retrieve our data.
So in our re-act code in feet.
J.S. here.
When I create my post there and I try to access the response data post and this will not work.
I have two axes rest data data.
Create post so here its rest data data.
Create post ID and debt is the case for all these places.
Whoops where I do access fields on my created post.
Now with that we should not get an error message anymore.
When I create a new post at least.
So let's try it out.
Let's choose to cap image though it does not matter.
We're not uploading it it accept and I don't get that error anymore.
So extracting the data works.
Now let's focus on adding a query that allows us to get our posts so that we can also rendered him here.
This is also a great practice for you will do together in the next lecture.
Try fetching your posts on your own.
Try creating that query on the back and on your own.
You don't need to tweak the front end code.
If you can do that.
Perfect will do it together Oberweis but add your graphical query and test it with the graphical interface.