Let's make sure we can all get all posts in for that I'll start on the back and in my schema again getting
data of course is a normal Ikari.
So next to log in I'll add a query and I'll name it posts you can name it however you want.
I don't need any arguments here.
I instead can directly define my return type and that will actually not be an array of posts.
As you might have expected.
But actually I'll create a new type for debt because remember that in the rest API We also did not just
return an array of posts but for page anation also a number that specified our total amount of posts
in the database.
So I will try the new type and I'll name it.
POST data which now has a post's key and that will be my array of posts and I'll also have a total posts
field here which will be an integer now.
POST data is what my query here should return.
And now we need a resolver for that.
So let's head over to resolvers and there all add posts.
All right.
As a async function like this I will actually not care about the first argument for now.
My artics.
But I will need the request to find out whether the user is authenticated that is actually the first
thing I'll check and I'll copy the check from create.
Post this if statement here and I'll add it here.
Now if the request is not if indicated if the user is not the indicated of row an error Arbre Why is
a later add some pagination logic.
But for now I want to find the total number of posts and then all posts so total posts can be found
while waiting.
Post find this gives me all posts and then count documents the posts themselves can be found by using
a weight on post find like this and again later.
I will also add skip and limit for now only at sort and I will sort by created add in descending order.
I will also populate my creator to fetch the full user data with the name and so on because I'll need
all that on the front end.
So here I get my posts.
Now we can already return some data.
I'll return an object and that object has to look like.
I did find it in my schema so it has to be an object with a post key and a total posts key.
So in that object I'll add posts and that will be the posts I've fetched here and total posts which
will be total posts now.
Posts will not be returned like this because there would be fields like underscore ID or treated at
which hold data formats that are not understood by graph Q L.
So instead I will add map here and you'll learn about map.
For example in the javascript refresher which allows me to transform every element in that array.
So here I will return a new object for every post which will generally be the same so I will pull out
the existing elements on the post document.
But then I will override the ID with the underscore ID to string to return a string and for a created
at.
I will use p created at Q iso a string and the same for updated at where I will use be updated at 2
Isel string.
And this is now how I will transform my posts every single post in the post Saray and they are for the
overall array.
Does this back and desist schema and the resolver set up for getting posts.
Now let's test this on graphical.
Here let me reload that page and there I will run a new query.
Which will be called posts.
And let's say they are interested in both the posts and total posts.
Posts is an array of complex objects.
So there I also need to specify what I want to get out of there.
Let's say I'm interested in the Id the title and the content.
And now I had control enter and I get not authenticated which is correct because I am not sending a
token here so that is the next step will send requests from the front and add our token and then of
course also render our posts.