So let's use that query year from the front end.
And for that I'll go to my re-act application of course there to feed J S file.
And here we have to scroll up a little bit to load posts.
There we have some page anation logic which we can ignore for now and then.
All right my graph will query here.
Which is a javascript object where I have a query which now is that multi-line string and in that multi-line
string I now will start with curly braces right away and in there just as I did it in graphical and
therefore we can of course again copy that I'll look for posts.
Does this the name of my carry and in there does happens to return this post data object which has posts
and total posts and for every post I'm interested in the ID title content image you are l also creator
and also created at Creator again as a complex object.
And there I'm interested in the name.
So does the data I need to render my posts sufficiently now to run that query.
Let's change that.
You are all down there and you know which your elde it is localhost 88 slash graphed you will.
The method will be post of course headers is the token but also the content type which should be application.
Jason and of course I need to add my body here and that body will be string you find with the adjacent
package and that will be that graph called queery.
I wrote up there.
And please note again that we see the entire flexibility of graph all doing its job here.
We're fetching exactly that post-state we need we don't fetch things like create or email which we don't
need we don't fetch the updated field which we don't need.
We only fetch what we need and we actually don't even need D-Mich. you all here now that think about
it.
We're not rendering that image on that starting page.
So really we only fetch what we need and we use graph tool to its fullest potential here.
But back to our request I'm not sending this request now.
Again handling errors like this will not succeed.
Instead we want to handle it as we did down there.
We don't need to check for validation errors though because in this query we can't send incorrect data.
So we'll simply check if we get any other errors.
And I'll then say fetching posts failed and otherwise we'll have our posts and we can't access them
on rest data posts.
Though as you know instead we have a look at our schema our post data will be found on data then posts
because that's the name of the query that will be an object of this type with the number of field of
posts in there and then we can drill into our post data.
So here the posts the final post can be found on rest stayed at that data posts daat posts.
Does this decree and desist and the posts field in the returned Adolph decree.
And then we can let re-act do its job for the total posts.
It's all the rest data.
Data posts and then it's not total items but total posts.
I renamed that on my back and if we now save that we go back to our re-act application we can already
see it.
That arrows coming from the user status but behind that we see our posts are getting rendered we see
the user name.
So that is all working.
And now let's also add the code to add a new post to this page immediately before we then also add page
nation and then also have a look at how we can get our image onto the server.
So let's quickly add the code to add a new post immediately.
We do that in the feet Jasc file of the front end code in the finish added handler and there we scroll
down to the place where we create our post object.
We're not actually doing anything with that thus far so that's time to change so there.
With this post I prepared some code which you can now use can just copy it in and replace the.
This said states step in with the hash code and thereafter go back to your application and add another
cup.
For example
also hot and hit except and you see that chapter 2 page nation is not working but will take care about
that later.
For now we can add that and we can load our posts in general.