Knouted we're able to fetch our posts through graph Cuil lets at page nation again.
How does that work with Graph Cuil.
Turns out not to difficult.
We start on our graphical schema again because there will need to change something on our posts query
because it is depost query where we want to add pagination right.
We want to be able to page in eight Freule the posts.
Therefore to posts Corey needs an argument it needs an argument that allows us to define the page we
are on and I'll name that page.
You can name it however you want and this will be of type int..
Now with that argument added in the schema in our resolver we can implement page anation there.
In my posts resolver my arguments now will have that page property so I can retrieve it with destructuring
and after checking whether I'm authenticated or not.
I now need to set up pagination or I need to find out which page I'm on and use that.
Now first of all a quick check if Page is not set because if it is not set so if it is undefined I'll
send it equal to 1.
So did it always start on page 1.
In case I don't specify any other page as a next step we can define the per page variable which is true
as it was an hour rest API scenario.
You could theoretically all fetch this as an argument all hardcoded here.
For simplicity reasons because this was primarily something we would have to manage and the front end
with a dropdown offering the user different page sizes and so on.
So all hard code is here and now we have per page.
We have the current page.
Now we can use the tear when we find the posts and you already learned that you can page neighed with
Skip and limit so skip and limit is what you can add here your and Inskip you want to skip your current
Piatt page minus one times per page.
So if you're on page two you have two minds one which is one obviously and you skip one times two.
So the first two items the two items that were on page 1.
You don't just want to skip though you also want to limit and you'll limit the result set to the amount
of pages of items you want to render per page.
By adding per page as an argument here and that as it does is page nation in place on the service side.
Now in the front end there we already have some logic for the page anation if we go to load posts there.
I do already get my page variable.
Now I just need to send that with my query and for data on the Post's query I can set page equal to.
Well the page I calculate up there since it is a number.
I also don't need to wrap that in double quotation marks.
Let me Safehold at.
Also make sure the back and code is saved and let's reload on from that application.
For that I should restart the server
and indeed here I got paged nation in place.
Now when I add a new post to make sure that it does not show up as a third element.
When you only want to have 2 I will go back to my re-act coat and there to the finish editor Candler
and here and set state where you find that unshipped statement.
Simply add up posts pop in front of that.
That is all.
This will remove one element and add a new one at the beginning.
And now let's give this a try.
Let's add another duck choose to duck match all is very lovely except this and here is the duck and
cup.
Here is the rest
and this is exactly the data we find in the database too.
We got two and numbered docs just in case you got confused.
So this is working.
Let's now work on the image upload because that obviously is something very interesting which we haven't
touched on thus far.
For our graphical API.