How does uploading data work.
Now the thing is graphed you l only works with Jason data.
You can find a couple of articles third party packages that help you with getting data fruit graph QOL.
But in the end one of the cleanest solutions is to use a classic and point like a rest and point where
you send your image to and then let dat endpoint store the image and return the POV to the image and
then send another request with that poverty image and you are Obert data to your graphics you Allen
point and dessous disillusion I'll implement here I'll implement that an app.
S because you could outsource this into a separate file.
But it'll be the only route we add here and there.
I'll register a new route on my app for incoming put requests because I plan to send an image with a
put request to slash.
Let's say post image.
You can name this pov however you want.
There we have our traditional middleware function.
I hope you still know that even though we haven't used it in the last lectures and they're all first
of all check if we don't have a file.
Now how can I check that.
Well I still have mulcher in place.
We added that and arrest API module and Malta is the package which takes our multipart foreign data
requests and extracts a file and stores it in the image folder and they still have that in place.
So all my files still will be extracted and mulcher then populates the file object with information
about the extract that file.
Now if this is not set then I'll just return a response here with the status of 200 and a message where
I say no fall provided you could set an error code here.
But actually this scenario is fine for me as you will see when we later edit a post because there we
might or might not add a new image.
Maybe we stick to the old one.
Maybe we did choose a new one.
And then this is one way of handling both cases.
If we do ever request fall we can get some data from it though.
And of course we want a clear and existing image if there is one for that I'll create a new function
here.
Or actually I have that function the feet.
J.S. controller already I can copy that from there the clear image function at the bottom of the feet
to file.
I'll move that into aperture.
Yes this depends on the F package and on the POF package the POF module lbf is already imported.
Now also import F here and now with that all imported
back in our port request here.
I'll check for the existence of a body field which is named old Poth which simply means that an old
port was passed with the incoming request in which case I want to clear my old image and I'll pass in
the old Poth because then we added a new image.
We can be certain about that.
After does it check and then we should all have an old POF which we delete so that we don't keep the
old image and a new image.
Instead we delete the old image here and then only keep the new image which was stored by Mulder and
then at the end here I will return a response.
With a status code of 201 and that data differs differentiates it from this response.
And here I will add some adjacent data lets say a message file stored.
But more importantly I'll add a file Paul for however you want to name it which is request file path
and this is the path where milters stored the image.
And this is the lbf we can then use the front end with this added on the back.
We can now work on the front end to use Does rest API endpoint and this also shows you that you can
use rest and graft you all concepts together.
It's not like a hard decision you have to make.
You can use the best for a given problem.
So now we can use that on the front end and we want to use it in this finish added handler.
So the feat J.S. followed through re-act app in the finish edit handler there.
I'm preparing some foreign data and does foreign data does not get a Tideland content anymore but it
would still get D-Mich..
Additionally though I also want to check if we are in edit mode.
So if this state added post if that is true and then I will append the old PAF field which is this state
added post which is supposed to we're currently editing image.
This is a field where setting when we're loading all those there when be load posts.
We all set the image Poth and there is a field which today for all ages should set.
When we added our posts so there when they create a new post
I also add image Pasquier gets that from Create post that should be my image.
You are Ellwood to get there and that is all something I need to request therefore for sure L is something
I do request here so I do have that available.
So I'm setting this image Poth I have that available.
This will be the POV of D.
Well the old image on the server and now with that I have left for data set up.
Now before I sent my graph Q L query.
I will therefore send a number query to HTP localhost 88.
But there are two slash post image.
So to this new endpoint I find and that the method here will be put because on my back and here I simply
defined this to handle put requests you could of course also argue to use post but since I'll replace
the old image put makes a lot of sense.
I'll then add my headers.
Now regarding offer I sation here we want to make sure that our off middleware actually runs first on
the server so that we know if the user is offene credit.
And if is off is false then we can certainly fro new error here not authenticated so that we protect
does route as well.
So now on the front end we need to add our offerings sation header and now we'll just copy the headers
from my graft you all request because the headers actually are the same and the body is now here.
My forum data does fetch request will be made first.
Then after it has been made I'll get back a response some produce some response data.
Well PA-RISC the body and there ofter I'll have my file response data.
You can named it however you want.
And in here I now can extract the image you are el by accessing file response data and their file path.
Because in my end point I am setting this file path key here and I can now use that in the graph queue
El-Khodary So now let me grab all that graph.
Q L cosier this code up to the then block caught it and move it into this then block and then remove
this semi-colon and change this then block.
Here I just need to return dispatch call so that the next then block refers to the result of this fetch
block here.
So now I do have my image you are l.
Now I just need to pass a tear for my graph Q quarry image.
You are L and now we should have a set up where we are able for now to at least create new posts.
Editing is something we'll work on later.
So let's try that out.
Let's try creating a new post.
And first of all on the server I'll clear all the images in the images folder so that we can tell whether
this works or not.
So back here I need to log in again.
Let's quickly do that.
And let's create you duck and you post but it can be a duck a duck with an image.
Hopefully Let's choose our deck shape.
This is a lovely duck again accept and I get this error regarding payload to lurch.
This is actually coming from an error on my side that Vetri Quest here where I send to post image I
should not set the content type to application Jason.
There are wise it will be parsed as data and that does not work for my binary data here.
So after removing this header.
Let's try this again with another duck here.
Add that image.
So Levalley except this and now it uploads this first and we can prove that by looking two images.
Here is our doc image.
So this works and it still creates that post which we can see here.
Next challenge is to make sure that we can click View button and view the detail page for one post.
And this again is a challenge for you implement something some schema or a query in the schema of your
graph Q L API and add to resolder that takes the ID of a post and Lote's that post.
You can then work on the front end too if you feel bold.
Otherwise focus on the back and we'll do it together in the next lecture.