So let's make sure we can also fetch a single post and for that I'll go to my schema again because on
the schema is where I will work.
And so here I will add a new query host which will get an input and Id off that single post I want to
fetch.
And will return a post in the end.
This is how my query should look like in the schema definition.
Now let's of course also add a resolver for this single post for Dad.
I'll go to my resolvers J.S. fall.
Add it down there.
Use the async function syntax like this.
And in that function here.
Just as in the function up there I'll get arguments and the request object with object destructuring.
I can get my post ID or whatever you chose as a name here.
So in my case just ID out of that request.
Arguments object I get the request object as well and first of all I can check whether a user is authenticated.
So I will copy this check and at this year and then as a next step I will add the logic to retrieve
a single post and vedette.
I'll get my post by awaiting post fine by ID for the ID I get as an argument.
Now I will also populate the creator here so that we have all the user data and not just the ID and
there after all check if we did not find a post in which case all create a new RR No post found and
also set a code of 404 and Frode error.
But if we make it after or past this check we know we have a post and then I'll return an object where
I get all the data from that post and then again I overwrite the ID because I can't return object IDs
so post underscore ID to string and the same for created ad because I can't return dates created at
two ISO's string and update it at will also be changed to Isel string.
With that in place I have everything I need to fetch a single post.
I'd say let's now go back to the front end and wired it up and there.
I'm interested in a single post in.
Well single post page here in there in component at Mt..
I'm sending my request and I'll again adjust.
You are l to go to local host ADHD slash graph Q L them Meffert here will be a post request for the
headers.
I add my content type application Jason header and I will need to prepare my graph you all query here
which is as before an object with a query key and then a query is surrounded by these tactics and in
there.
Well I want to reach out to my post query.
I will send my ID so my post ID I get up there should be surrounded with quotation marks.
And regarding the fields that I'm interested in.
Well they're after I use the creator name the title the image you are l the date the created at Date.
To be precise and the content.
So I want to fetch that one to fetch the title content image to your L creator and for the Creator only
the name.
And then also create to that that is what I'm interested in.
And this is now what I will append as a body to my request.
So Jason's string ify and at discraft Ul-Qadri here with that we are sending that request as you learn
before handling the error.
There will not really work.
We want to handle that error ofter we parsed the response data and then we can check for errors.
So I'll copy that logic from feet J.S. into a single post.
Genius here where I check if we have any EHRSSON that fro an error if we have no arrows.
We just need to drill into the response and for that you must not forget how your schema looks like
we'll have data then we have that name of the Kuri which is post and then we can access our different
post properties.
So here we access rest state DOT data and then indeed dot post dot Tidelands on.
So just dot data has to be added to all these places where I extract some data.
And with that I should be able to load a single post saved ad and make sure your back end is saved.
And click on View and looks like I have an error.
My you are.
Yes this colon needs to go.
Now let's click view I get user log in and failed.
That is the wrong error message I copied there.
Fetching post failed but somehow it failed.
Let's quickly check what's wrong.
Yes there is a syntax error in the query.
We need to have surrounding curly braces around the overall query so added your to have opening and
closing curly brace right at the start and end and there ofter.
If you click on a single post now you'll load the post data there.
So this is now working.
What's missing is a possibility to edit and delete posts.
And of course to work with the user status.
So let's work on that next.