Not have we can load a single post.
Let's make sure we can also added a post.
And as always that journey starts on the back end there in the schema we want to add a new mutation
because obviously editing a post is a mutation.
I'll name it.
Update post and I expect to get the idea of the post.
I wanted to edit and then some post input which is my post input data so the exact same data I expected
to get for creating a new post as a result I will return the updated post.
So this is my schema.
Now onto the resolvers where I will add update post as async function again where I get my arguments.
I will have the ID and the post input and the request object.
So this is my update post.
Resolder in there.
I first of all want to check the authentication status and fro an error.
If the user has not indicated.
Hence we can copy the code from our umur resolder functions where we had a similar check and then all
first of all get my post by using a wait and post fine by id and using that ID extract as an argument.
I'll also populate that with the Creator.
So did we have the full user data when we returned the update post.
Then I'll check if we don't find a post and I can copy that check from up there to return an error.
In that case and if we do have the post I don't want to check if the user who tries to edit it is the
user who created it and for that I'll check.
If Post creator underscore ID to string.
If that is equal to request user ID
and that also convert to a string.
If these two matched then I know this user is the creator.
If they don't match.
So if I add exclamation mark here then know someone tries to edit the post who is not offered to do
so and it is Kasal again creates an error.
Not all fairest could be the error message fro.
I'll add a code of 403 and I'll throw that error and then we can continue.
If we are to write user however we can now edit the post and set the title equal to post input title.
We could now also add validation by the way and we should.
So I can scroll up to my Create post function and grab that validation logic.
All that logic beginning from the empty array being set up to the cross being checked and that is something
I also want to do before I start editing my posts.
Tidelands on.
But now here I know that the input is valid.
So now I will edit my title.
I will add it my content and I will now also added my image you are l.
If it changed and that is not guaranteed because the user did not select a new image the image will
not have changed so I'll check if Post image image.
Your L is unequal to undefined.
And now this has to be checked against a text because it will be converted to text.
By the way I'm sending it on the front end so if this is on the find.
Dana will continue but if it is not on the find then I'll also overwrite the image you are l with the
new image and you are l of course.
Otherwise I will not touch the image you are el and then I'll have my updated post by a waiting for
post safe and I will then return my updated post here or some data.
I will return my updated post doc data and again replace the IDE ID with updated post ID to string and
the same for the dates created at will be replaced with updated post created at 2 Isel string and updated
at will be replaced with updated post updated at 2 Isel string.
So this is the response I want to send back to my client here.
With that we get a resolver in place we hopefully get everything in place we need.
Let's now go on to our re-act application and there in Fida J.S. we need to find Finnish added hndler
so scroll down
in this function and the finish edits handler function we will always send our image to Dad and point
though of course it could be the case that there is no image to append if no new image was chosen.
But that will be fine.
We do handle that scenario in our end point right in post image.
We check for the existence of a file and we send the response if no file was provided.
So thereafter here we continue.
And we'll have a file path though that file path might very well be undefined and that is why in my
graph l API I check for it being undefined.
We could handle this in different ways of course we could alternatively simply keep the old file path
here then if this is on the find.
But I will go with this approach and then we sent the graph Q out query.
Now of course it will not always go to create post though it might also be that we added a post.
So I'll check if this state Adut post is true ish which means we are editing and they don't set RFQ
all query to a different query.
So to an object where my query it then looks differently I won't copy this query in generals or copy
all the code between my opening and closing back takes like this.
But of course I'm targeting update post here and not create post so I'm targeting this mutation here
and there I also need to pass in different data.
I need to pass in my ID
which I get from this state added post underscore ID.
I still pass in the post input as before.
That did not change and I still want to get the same base data back so that also does not change.
Then we send the data request and in the handler off the request.
I already have some logic that should handle this correctly if we are updating.
So let's save that all and let's give it a try.
Let's reload and let's edit another doc and add a couple of exclamation marks without adding a new image.
And I get it the error here.
In general though it looks like it worked.
I have my exclamation marks here and the image the old one is all still there.
I can also still use it.
And here I see the change to now regarding that error.
Well that is related to how we extract data from the response we Axxess create post.
But of course if we send an update post request then this field in which our response data is stored
will be named update post and not create post.
Therefore here and we can.
By the way validate us here.
It's stored in update post.
Therefore all we can do is we can add a new variable response data field or whatever you want to name
it.
And by default that should be create post because creating a post also is our default query up there.
But then I'll add a check and see if this state added post is true ish.
In which case the data field where I want to extract the data will be update post.
And now we just need to use that variable here to dynamically retrieve our data and we can do that by
selecting all these create post instances year with the first dot and replace them with square brackets
where we pass in rest state of field and this will now use the value inside of rest data field to access
Well property with the name of that value on our data object.
And now if we reload we should be able to remove the exclamation marks and try out choosing a cup as
an immature.
Except no error and we see the crap here too.
So this all seems to work the status and deleting of posts are the remaining things that don't work.