Let's finish the post functionality by making sure we can delete posts.
And as always feel free to do that on your own as a practice.
Create the appropriate queery or mutation and respect them for a solver functionality on your own and
feel free to edit the front end too.
After a short pause which you can use to pause the video.
Try it on your own we'll do it together.
Were you successful.
Well again we start in the scheme of our Bacchante and I'll add that the lead post mutation here and
I expect to get the idea of the post which should be deleted.
I will then only return a boolean that indicates whoever did succeeded or not.
Does this like mutation.
More interesting is the result.
For that let's go to the resolvers file here and there.
I'll add delete post all retrieve the ID from the incoming data package so to say from the arguments
object and I'll write this in the async function syntax again so that I can use async await.
And again I'll start by checking the log in status.
Now obviously you could refactor this into a common function.
I deliberately have the more we're both set up here to make it really clear that we have to check in
every of these were sold or functions.
After knowing that the user is signed in let's fetch the post we want to remove so that we can check
whether the creator of the post is a user who tries to delete it.
So we get the post by a waiting for a post find by ID with the chosen post ID.
Now here we can check if we don't have a post and again does this some logic.
We can copy from before and the same is true for our authorization.
Check regarding the quality of the Creator and the locked end user so it copied these two statements
in here to check if the post exists and then I want to compare the creator with the locked end user.
Not important since I don't populate my creator field here.
The creator here is not an object with underscore ID but creator itself is already the ID.
Because that is how it's stored in a post.
And we need to call populate to change that and the result.
We're not doing that here so we only Xs creator to directly get the ID of the user who created the post.
Now we got all the checks in place we need an offer dis We want to delete the image that belongs to
that post.
Now for that I have that functionality in apt.
Yes your.
Now I will copy that and put it into a separate folder util where it will add a file js file and in
there I will just import Poth by requiring
path and it will import the file system by requiring that core node module.
Now in here I can export clear image so that we can use it in our files and I want to use it.
Actually yes where I already did use it in the past.
There I don't need to file system import any more but I will add import to my own clear file functionality
by requiring utl file and then here I use destructuring to get that clear image function.
So this is now using that restructured code where I moved that function into a seperate file and in
the resolver.
I can also import debt.
So here I also want to import clear image by requiring.
And here I need to go up one level then util folder and then the file file.
So now I have clear image available and now at the bottom of my resoled verse in that delete post resolver
here I will call Cleator image and pass my post image.
You are there because that is the Pawlowski image on my server.
Now after this was done I will await the result of post find by id and remove and I'll do that for my
post with that ID.
Once this is done I just need to make sure I removed that post from my user as well.
So for that I first of all need to get my user by a waiting user find by ID for the user ID stored in
my request object due to the off middle of where we added earlier and on that user I can then access
to posts and pull my ID.
So the idea of the post which I just deleted and after.
I will await the result of user A safe to save that updated user back to the database and then I will
return true because remember in my schema I find that I want to return a boolean.
I could wrap this all with try catch this part too also and return false if it fails and that is generally
something we can do on all these resoled rows.
I will not do it here to keep just code a little bit more simple but in the end that is something you
could add important that you hear return true.
That is the back end.
Let's all work on the front end as well and let's make sure we can trigger the deletion of the posts
there for Dad and the feed to js file.
You want to go to the delete post handler and there again to find your craft you will query
which has the shape you already know and love.
In that query here I'll run a mutation.
The Delete post mutation.
The idea here is inject that between double quotation marks.
The post ID I am getting as an argument.
And we have no nested object here so we couldn't even get any nested or detailed data.
We only get true or false.
That is my query.
And then here again I'll send this request localhost ADHD slash graph Q L the method as always will
be a post request.
We add our token.
We also set the content type to application.
Jason and of course we need to add or Kuri expression as a body by using Jason's string you fly and
passing our graph you'll carry in there we don't handle errors like that as you learned instead.
We do it on the parsed response because that is where we would have an arrows object if there are any
errors.
So copy that code from above and then move that in here to check if there is an error object which means
something did go wrong and then deleting the post would fail.
And that is it.
Now let's save that as well as the back and code.
And let's click on the link to your and that is looking good.
And I can carefully delete all my data on Lesters only until there is only one doc left.
And if I now refresh my posts only one doc is there and in users that user still has two decks where
two posts but that is probably related to something I deleted earlier behind the scenes which is all
the reason why I have two images here.
To validate that everything does work.
Let's delete that.
And on that user let's manually delete the 2 array elements clear all the posts.
As I mentioned clear all the images here
and now reload we have no host so let's create a duck and let's give it a dead duck.
Imagine I'm content.
Let's also create another item a cup and give that the cup image here.
Kind of you to come see it we all see the duck here.
Now let me delete the duck.
The cap is still there.
Only one image is looking good but I expect my users only one item to cup so that now makes perfect
sense.
And now let me also try logging in with a different user who didn't create that and they're deleting
and did does not work.
So we have all that in place let's now finished is all up by making sure we can view and edit our user
status.
And again is this a great challenge for you.