We're almost done.
Let's make sure we can.
Also the you are user status and delete it.
And as I already mentioned at the end of the last lecture this again is a great practice for you.
So definitely feel free to try this on your own first posti video now and then implement these two functionalities
of course.
We'll also do it together after a short pause.
So did you succeed.
Well let's try it together and I'll do both in one go.
I need to add two things.
One theory and one mutation decree is for getting to status.
And actually since we're not using the approach I mentioned earlier where we add a new endpoint for
everything we have to remember that with craft you l we can control which data we get back.
So I will add a general user query without any arguments.
All this for the currently locked in user and I will return a user object here.
Now in my mutations I will add my update status.
Nutation I could add an updated user mutation if I generally would be fine with the user changing since
I have no such functionality planned in my app.
I will only add a special mutation for justice status.
Otherwise we could of course go with a more generic approach here to there.
I expect to get the status as a string and I will return the updated user.
With that we can move on to our resoled Rhus.
Let me add the code for returning a user.
So for this user there I get no arguments so I get that object but I will not retrieve any offering
anything from there.
And again I will write this as a async function to be able to use D-Wade keyword.
I'll then check if the user is authenticated.
If he's not then well you have a problem and it will not continue.
Otherwise I will get my user by waiting for a user find by ID and I can use the user ID stored in the
request and on that user here I'm interested in the status right.
That's the state is I want to return.
So if I find no user for that ID somehow then I will basically do the same I did when I found no post
on return an error no user found.
If I do have a user though then I will simply return a response and that is my whole user data.
I just will make sure to replace the ID with user underscore ID to string so I can now theoretically
fetch all the data about a user I'm interested in but obviously I'll implement that in a way that I
only fetch the status and that is something I do here in my feature Yes file of my front that application
there in component did MT I send the request to an endpoint which does not exist anymore.
Instead we're now of course targeting graft to L.
The method here will now be post.
I will send the token but I'll also set the content type to application.
Jason and I'll set the body to Mike vary and that query is something I need to create up there.
Graph Cuil query is a constant I'll create here that is object with the corroboree key.
Which again is surrounded by doubleback ticks or single back ticks but I need to opening and closing
and here I'll send my request to my user query or else use the user query and all the data I get back.
I'm not interested in the name or the email.
I'm only interested in the status that is biographical Korea and that is what I'll send in spring you
fight.
Werman To that end point.
Again handling arrows like this will not work.
Let's instead wrap the code we have below here where I just check for the existence of the error or
object after parsing the request body.
So you're fetching status failed would be my error message.
And when I extract the data I need to drill into the data field and then the status field.
Now if I save that and I reload
the internal error here cannot return NULL.
Let's quickly check our resoldering a user's Soler.
I return my user object here.
But I did not save it.
I guess this now looks better but I'm not seeing the status here.
And I got an error about which shall take care of the second my status here is not found in data.
I have to drill into a user field as well.
We can see that if we go to the network tab and have a look at that request where we get that data we
get data and in their user which is the name of our query of course and ever got that but obviously
Cuore name is always where the data is stored in and that Dan has a status field.
So this is a change that is required.
And now that we see the status and this error message also is gone.
Like dead.
So this is it.
Now let's all make sure we can update a status and for that let's first of all make sure we do something
for this schema.
We added for the update status schema in our resolvers file.
So this is the last resolve or functional add here update status.
I'll get my status argument and the request of course and I will ask before I use my async function
syntax and any here.
First of all will check whether the user is authenticated.
But that's not the case we throw in error and then all get my user by a waiting for a user find by ID
for the request.
User ID.
So for the locked in user if I have no user then we get a problem so I will copy that code from above
and fro in error.
If that's the case otherwise I'll set the user status to the new status I'm getting as an argument.
And then I will await user save to safety update.
User
I can then return an object where I take my user doc data and where I replaced the ID.
So user ID with the string you fired weren't all that.
And this is my update status mutation now.
Last but not least I also need to edit this on the front end.
So in my re-act app and there we simply search for the status update handler here where we of course
send the request to draft Q L and Datchet a post request.
The headers are all right and I will define my graph all query.
Here is an object.
The query key my the back takes of course and the worry now is a mutation with the name update status
or whatever you defined in your graphed ULS schema file.
And there I need to pass in the status which is a string.
So we need double quotation marks around de-value which I'll now inject here and the value is still
state status dessous where the status is stored to which the user enters into the input field and off
the data I get back.
I'm only interested in the status then we want to send this here in a string you fight.
Werman And again we don't handle arrows here.
We handled them as we do up there checking for the existence of the error object in our parsed response
data.
And that is already it.
Now if I saved that and saved the back end as well.
If I add a couple of exclamation marks and I click Update seems to succeed.
If we can validate this by reloading if I now log in with a different user there of course we should
not see that updated status.
There we see the status of that user.
And with that we moved our entire rest API over to graft to L and I hope you see the power graph tool
gives you by being more flexible regarding the data you fetch from the backend and therefore your front
of development can move faster because your back and gives you the entire bandwidth of data.
You might be interested in.