Now finally before we leave that module there's one thing we can optimize now because there is one thing
which I did in a way that is ok to do that will work but that is not recommended doing and that we can
do better.
Whenever we pass a dynamic value to our graph all the queries as we are for example doing it here where
I do have a page we currently do use stee interpellation syntax here where I used to store curly brace
thing to inject or interpolant a value into my string literal.
Now this absolutely does work.
But this is indeed not the recommended way of adding variables into our graph kilocalories.
There is a better way.
Maybe you all to remember that for mutations we had to add mutation here but for queries we didn't have
to add query here.
And indeed if you would have added a query like this we would have got an error.
Well now I will add it because now I will also add something else.
I'll gift this query a name a name that does not really make a difference it does not make it behave
differently it will help in error messages for example.
But that name then also allows us to do something else.
So here we are of course getting all posts so here all named as fetch posts and you can give us any
name you want.
So this year is totally up to you.
Now with this name assigned I can add parentheses after this name to define which variables Discovery
will use and we create such a variable here with a dollar sign.
But then no curly braces.
And then the name of the variable you want to use and that name is again up to you.
I'll name it page but you could have named it current page whatever you want.
This will be of type integer.
So you assign a graphical type again here and this is really important to understand.
Does this graph you old syntax here.
This will be parsed on the server.
This is not javascript code that runs on a client.
This will only tell our graphical server that we have a query which will use an internal variable.
Now that I'm saying internal to a question of course is where do we use that Thaller same page.
Well we use it in the place where we do have dynamic variable value and that would be here where we
currently inject our value.
Now I use my dollar sign page here and this name here has to match his name and it has to start with
a dollar sign.
And now graft you Onos.
OK this part here is dynamic.
It might change and it will be an integer because we're defining this here.
So now the only question is how do we get our page variable here in javascript into our dollar sign
page.
The variable here in graph Q out and for.
We add a second property to that query object we're creating here.
Thus far I only have to query expression now after death.
I'll add a comma and I'll add a second property.
Which are my variables and this has to be named variables just as this year had to be named query.
This now is declared expression and variables.
Now is the object where we can assign values to the variables we pass into our query here.
So here I have Dala signed page here.
It then should be just page without the dollar sign.
And then my javascript variable or value so I could pass one.
To always use the first page or in my case.
I do have that page constant or variable here in javascript now so this is the value I want to sign
here.
Now I have page 2 times but the first page refers to the internal variable used in the graphical query
and the second page ofter to Colon refers to my javascript variable just to make this clear.
And now with that let's save this and let's reload our application or first of all let's quickly log
in there because I was locked out.
And now here you see I get my post.
Now if I add another deck here
and I then add one more item so that we do have page anation going on
then after reloading we can indeed see that this works.
Ask before I can switch between my two pages and I simply have two cups under.
By the way maybe you notice that we didn't get to that next and previous link after we created our item.
Our new item that is something we can fix too but for now let's focus on the variables and there in
our front end code.
Does is how we use variables.
And technically it works just as before but this is the more elegant the better way of using variables
in your graph kilocalories.
So now we can replace that in all our queries.
For example in this mutation there I also use string interpellation to get my value in there.
Better would be to give does a name.
Update user status or anything like that.
And then to find which variable we need in here.
That would be the let's say user status.
Again his name is up to you.
And then Rathcoole type of that which will be a string.
Then here without the double quotation marks because we define it to be a string.
You add user status like this and then again you add a second variable to that draftable query object.
Where you at.
That variable is key where you now assign a value to that variable you to find here.
Without the dollar sign and then the value you want is stored there.
And in this case this would be does state status just as before.
Now if I continue here in the next query where I do edit or create a post there I also give it as a
name.
Create new posts seems like a fitting name here and there will have a couple of variables which is no
problem we can of course have more than one will have the title which is a string will have the content
which is a string and will have the image you are l which is also a string.
And now just as before we use these values in here.
So title
content.
And of course also the image you are l.
And now we just need to add that second argument here.
The variables so that we can store our title and you might remember this was post data title then the
content was.
Post data content and the image you are l.
Well that is our image you are wearable in javascript or the constant which I am creating here.
Now when we edit a post update existing post could be a name we assign to that and there we all have
some variables and there we will need our posed idea let's say which is an idea.
We then also have our title which is a string.
We then have our content which is a string.
And now just as before I'll copy that value because I'll need it in a second but then I'll replace this
year with post ID.
I'll replace the rest in a second too.
Let me first of all add my variables below that.
And then here we have that post ID which is de-value I just cut out.
And then here we have to postdate a title in the post data content.
So here we use the title there.
We used the dollar sign content not wrapped in double quotation marks and we also have the image you
are up there which is all the string.
So we should also of course use the image Eurail here and now we need to assign values to these variables
down there too.
So we have the title which is posted data title.
We have the content which is post data content.
And we have the image you are l which is image u r l.
Always remember the first part here so the key name in our variables object refers to the variable to
be defined here.
Without a dollar sign.
The second part offered a colon.
So the value of our key value pairs here refers to the value we want to pass into that variable.
Time for a little safe to just check if that is all working.
So now if we create a new post and rubber duck because as you get to help laid out decks are lovely
animals it's still lovely.
Vi except that than we seem to have an issue here.
So that did not work.
And the problem we have here can be found when I inspect my raft 2L request which fails dare I get some
errors.
We see that all my variables are of type String expected of type string which is required and that of
course is my mistake here.
We should add exclamation mark here because if we have a look at our back and our schema here we have
a look at our mutations there.
Then we can see that create user has user input data and create Post has post input data and that is
what we working on and data input data.
The Post input data indeed does require all these strings.
The page previously was optional.
There we had no exclamation mark which is why I did get no such error before.
For the status by the way we would also get an error because as status as you can tell all has a required
string and that is really important and therefore a good debt does slip through the types you assign
and your Frontiere for your variables have to match the types in your back and schema.
So here for example in create new post all my strings here are required and for update existing post
while there for update post.
We also have the same type of data and the required ID so we should make sure that we add that exclamation
mark after all these values here because they are required in our schema.
They have to be required in our front end too.
So let's add this.
Also on update status.
So after this change let me go back.
Let's try this again with another doc
and doing some dummy value here and now this is looking better.
Now let me edit this by removing the exclamation mark
and dare I still get an error image your el was not provided.
Let me quickly have a look at what's wrong there.
If we go to our update existing post I do with my image.
You are all here it on the back end an update post I all do require their but indeed the problem I have
here is that D-Mich. your L is not always set when we don't choose and you tried and you might remember
that indeed on our back and we have a check in update post where we see if that is undefined as a text.
So we should at least pass that text an arm to go through that check.
So well do is if my image Eurail cannot be set here I'll set it to a string on the find which is not
the same as the default value of the type undefined.
And with that if we now reload and I tried it again.
Now that works because now we're setting this to a value we are checking for in the back end for the
use case that we don't have an image.
And then we'll keep the old image here.
With that back in the Front-End this is taking good shape the recoveries in feet J.S. are all right
in this single post.
J.S. fall there though here.
I also have a query where I can check the value when I get a single post so I'll give it as a name by
adding query and the name fecche single post.
And there I expect to have a post ID which will be of type ID and that is required because it is required
in our back and schema here in our host country we do require that ID and then here I can also assign
that here.
And as you learn add a second element to that graph you'll clearly object the variables property where
I then set post ID equal to host ID so to dispose ID which I'm extracting here and now that if I saved
this and I go back and click view this still works without issues.
Now with that let's all go to app J.S. in our front and code because there we do sign users up and in
and here we also inject values into our queries.
Now just as before we should name these queries and use that different approach.
So here all name that user log in.
And I do get an e-mail which is of type string and which is required.
And I do get my password which is of type string and required.
And then here where I have off data email off the password I can use e-mail.
So dollar sign e-mail and dollar sign password and we added new variables object to your as a property
to digraph cool query and that email will be off.
Data email and password will be off.
Data password.
Just as before but now with that more elegant syntax.
And last but not least when we sign up so when we create new users then I'll also give this nutation
a name create new user what ever you want.
And here again I expect a couple of values.
I expect the email which is a string and which is required I expect a name which is a string and which
is required and you can always check your back and schema to learn what is required and what is not.
And here are user input data is what we have to pass to the back end.
So last but not least your.
I also have my password which is a required string and then I'll just quickly copy that because now
I will replace these values with my graph killed variable equivalence.
So dollar sign email dollar sign name and of course your dollar sign password.
And then again add that variables object and pass email which is all data.
Sign up for email value past a name which has off data.
Sign up for him name value and pass the password which is off data.
Sign up for password value just as before.
And with that we should have replaced all injected values in our application with new values.
Now let me quickly sign up with a new user here.
Now let me all to quickly logon with that user and that also works.
And with that we got everything in place.
I can't delete that obviously because I'm not the user who created it.
I would have to log in with the correct user for that.
So with that everything is working the way it should.
And now we have a graphical API that uses that new variable syntax which is the recommended way of passing
dynamic values into your queries.