Now there's one thing you also might have noticed when we only have two posts so we have no page nation
because we don't have enough poets to have a second page and add a new value like a duck here.
Then the stock will show up but we don't get that next button.
There is a little box here which is easy to fix has nothing to with no chance.
But it is really easy to get rid of in or finish edit handler here.
When we go down to decode where we create that new post and we then add to our existing posts it's this
block here which is interesting to us where we in the end make sure that we only render two items at
a time and then we add our new post at the beginning of the list.
Now here what I need to do is I need to make sure that I do increase the amount of total posts in our
state in re-act here where we manage how many posts we have on that page.
I do set total posts here to a different amount of posts.
When I fetch all posts where I get that total posts information well when adding a new element I know
that total posts will simply be the old total posts plus one.
So I will add a new variable here.
Right below up the posts and that's updated.
Total Posts and that will be previous state total posts and that is a bit off re-act logic here but
this first of all takes the old status and now when I do go into to the else block which is the case
when I am not editing but what I am adding then I want to set updated total posts plus 1 with the plus
plus syntax I incremented by 1 and then here is the return statement.
I'll set the total posts equal to updated total posts and have this change in place.
Fine I'll quickly delete my doc again so that I'm back to two items and I do add my doc so that I go
up to free items again.
Now you see that next button and you can use it of course because now we're managing the total post
correctly too.
So that's just a Leelah adjustment has nothing to do with Knode or graphs you all.
But since I spotted that bug I of course also want to get rid of it.
And with that we moved our entire rest API over to graft to L and I hope you see the power graph tool
gives you by being more flexible regarding the data you fetch from the backend and therefore your front
that development can move faster because your back and gives you the entire bandwidth of data.
You might be interested in.