That was a lot of content on graph QOL.
And as I mentioned you could fill an entire course just on graph 2l.
And indeed there are courses on it do you official docs on graph Cuil dot org are a great place to dive
deeper because they're really good.
And there you can learn more about all the features graphical offers including its more advanced features
in this introductory module.
I hopefully gave you a good overview over the graphical core concepts and how you built a graphical
API with Node.
And in this case with the express chase framework you'll learn that graphical allows you or is a technique
to build a stateless client independent API just as we did with the rest API but that it offers a higher
flexibility than the rest API eyes typically do because you expose a custom very language to your client.
A gradual API is made up of queries which you would compare to your get requests and rest.
API is mutations dad would be your post port patch and delete requests in rest of your eyes and possibly
all subscriptions.
Something I didn't cover in this module.
You use these constructs to exchange data and to manage data.
And the important and characteristic thing about graft UL API eyes is dead.
They only expose one end point to the client and that is post requests to slash graphics.
Well typically it has to be a post request though that is something you can't avoid.
And all requests are directed there and then in the request body off that post request you use digraph
you all Kuri language to describe the query you want to execute.
Or the mutation you want to execute does server parses that incoming query expression and then calls
the appropriate resolvers to execute the logic you wrote and returned the appropriate data.
Or do the appropriate manipulation graph Q L and that is all important is of course not limited to react.
You asked for on today applications.
You can use it with any front end application needed a mobile app a single page app with any framework
or what ever you have.
It's not limited to react.
Now when we compare it to rest then we have to understand that recipes are not strictly worse.
They might still be the perfect solution for your next project.
They are especially great for static data requirements so you don't need that additional flexibility.
And then you have a very clearly structured and explicit way of defining your endpoints and defining
the possibilities.
Your API offers so for file uploads or scenarios where you simply don't need that flexibility because
you always get the same kind of data.
There rest your eyes might still be the perfect solution and now there is graft you might be better
because you get a higher flexibility due to dead x post for very long which your client can use.
And I also want to highlight that bouffe rest and Rathcoole API eyes can be implemented with any framework
and actually even with any server side language you are not limited to.
No genius at all.
No genius.
You are of course not limited to express and that is really important.
The core concepts you learned here and a lot of the logic you applied will actually be the same no matter
which framework you use or no matter which server side language you use.