So knouted we know for whom this modulus.
Let me summarize javascript briefly.
Javascript is a weekly typed programming language.
It's an object oriented programming language.
It's very we're style.
And what do you mean with that weekly type.
Instead we have no explicit type assignment.
Javascript knows types like numbers or text which is called string or booleans which is true or false
but it doesn't force you to define which type you're using in a variable or in a function.
And indeed you can also have a variable where you store a number which you then suddenly change to a
text variable.
So you can switch types dynamically in overlaying which just does this differently.
And was this gives you greater flexibility to be able to change it and to not have strict typing.
It also can lead to errors.
So it is just something you have to be aware of.
Object oriented simply means that data can be organized in logical objects and we'll see these objects
in this module.
And one important concept here is did you have to be aware about the difference of primitive and reference
types and attached to this lecture.
You'll find a link to an article and video I created for my free YouTube channel had a mind where I
do dive into primitive and reference types and where I do explain the difference and why they are important.
So definitely check that out if primitive and reference types don't tell you anything regarding the
versatility.
Well we can see that in this course.
Javascript runs in the browser and this is actually where it comes from but you can also use it with
no chest to run it on your PC.
Outside of a browser set up or on a server.
Therefore And that is exactly what we'll do in this course.
We'll build a web server with no chance.
So we got this Broadway versatility of being able to use javascript on different platforms and you can
also perform a broad variety of tasks with javascript Also depending on the platform you're running
on.
You can in the browser listen to user events read rendered the DOM and on the server or on a PC you
can work with files with databases.
Lot of cool stuff.
So this is a summary of javascript and what makes up the language.
Let's now dive into some core features also some core next generation telescope features which are supported
by no choice.
And let's see some things we'll see from the course.