Ford it let's just play around with javascript and I'm in a brand new empty folder which I opened with
my ID do you code and in there altered a new file and I'll name it played out just the name is totally
up to you though.
Now let me start with some core language features variables and functions.
And again you should definitely dive into a core javascript resource like the ones I linked into second
lecture off this module.
If you are brand new to Javascript.
So by now do expect you to know what variables functions are also expected to be aware of what if statements
or loops are.
These are all core things you got to have set by now because you are crucial for javascript no matter
if you are using it in the browser or on the server.
So for variables you might know disinfects with the a keyword.
You can have a name in for example store Maxson there right.
This would be a variable and now you can use that for example to simply output it like this.
And if we now run this file with no chance by running node played out just as the command we have to
write in a terminal navigate it into dead project folders so into that folder where I'm having display
Chia's file then I see Macs down there right.
So that is some Javascript code.
We can also create a number verbal age which now would be a number.
It's not in close to quotation marks so this first one is a so-called string.
Does this number.
We can also add a third one has hobbies and that would now be a boolean.
These are some core types.
Javascript knows.
True false are booleans numbers are well numbers.
They can also have decimal places.
These are strings.
And now here I can also define a function with the function keyword summerize user.
Does this how you create a function javascript and there we could return something.
Functions can return values with the return statement.
They all can get input like user name user age and user has hobby you can name these arguments as these
things here are called.
However you want.
These are not local variables only available in instead of a function not outside of it.
And then you can return.
Name is Plus user name plus let's say some text with a comma a whitespace H is whitespace used are h
class and user has hobbies and then user has hobby something like debt.
Now here I am simply returning some text which I manually concatenating by a hardcoded strings and the
dynamic values I'm getting as an argument.
Now we can also cancel the result of summerize user we call a function by adding parentheses offered
a name.
And now we just have to pass in data we expect here as arguments so we need to pass and free arguments
your the name D.H. and has hobby's sort of free variables.
I'd have find up here we could have directly access them in the function too by the way.
We don't have to take the way of accepting arguments but this is a pure function which does not depend
on anything from outside the function but gets all the data it works with as part of the arguments which
is a nice way of writing functions.
And now if I execute this well then we get this output.
Now this is just a summary of the features you should be aware of.
As I mentioned I just want you to know or I just want to be sure that you know how we work with variables
how we would work with functions how we call functions.
And did you understand how parameters or arguments in the function are used in there and only in there.
We couldn't use user name outside of therapy because of something called scoping in javascript.
We can then call a function like this and pass in the data.
We could hard code the data here or refer to variables which have to be a way in the scope of this statement
which is the case for these variables since they are global variables and these are variables and functions
and how we interact.
And these are some core of features you have to be aware of.
Let's not dive into something more exciting in the next lecture.