Now that I had a quick look at the very basics and the core turns you have to know let's dive into some
next gen javascript index you'll see for all this module and from this course waar is a key word that
creates a new variable.
And actually it's a bit of an outdated syntax from now on we'll use LET instead of war and let also
creates a variable the scoping behaves a bit differently but we can ignore that for now.
Here check out some NexGen javascript resource like my ears 6 course or of course all some free resources
to learn all about LET.
But the core reason for using Lepp is that we now also have another way of creating a variable and with
that I mean a variable which never changes which actually is the case for all free here.
But let's say we actually do assign a new value to age here but we never change name or has hobby's
we could absolutely use LET.
There is nothing strictly wrong with that.
But to be clear about our intentions in the code and we know it will never change.
Let name and has hobbies.
We can also use a new keyword available in javascript and that's a Konst keyword discreate creates a
so-called constant.
And this makes clear that we never plan on changing the value of name or has hobby's.
We do plan to change of age.
That is why we have let And that is the reason why we have two different keywords for creating variables
though.
Again these are not really variables there are constants either Konst or let depending on whether you
plan to change this or not.
So now if x Q Does it works in exactly the same way as before but by the way if I tried to set in name
to Maximillian here and I do run node play chess again I actually get an error.
Now that I try to assign to a constant variable so does actually already shows us the idea behind Konst
and you want to use Konst as often as possible to be as clear about what happens in your code as possible
and if something should never change make it a contest so that you get an error.
If you do accidentally change it zero triggered this change.
But I want to show you how length and cons to work.