Know let me get rid of that existing code.
You find a snapshot of the code you wrote thus far attached to the last lecture.
Let me write some new code.
An important thing you work with or important data structure you work with javascript are objects.
You could have something like a personal object and you create an object typically with curly braces.
And then in there you have key value pairs.
You to find a key by simply typing well whichever you want to use let's say name.
Then you have a colon and you must have the colon and offered a colon.
You have your value.
In my case a string max and then with a comma you can add an average key value pair.
Age 29.
Now this is an object and I can lock person to your if I now execute placates we see that object being
printed here.
Now objects allow us to group data together.
You can also not just have variables in there so to say but you can all have functions in there.
For example agreed function and there you can simply have an anonymous arrow function or an arrow function
general as a value after de colon and then in there you could have consul lock.
Hi I am.
And then the name and does would now be accessed with the this keyword instead of an object you have
to use this to.
Typically and there is something special about this which I showed in that video I linked before it
in an earlier lecture.
But typically this refers to the surrounding object.
And now we can use the dot notation.
So Dot two Xs properties or methods.
So variables are functions inside of that object.
So we could now use this name.
And now I can use that person and call agreed with the dot notation and executing it as a function.
So the dot notation is important on this which refers to the object or on you referring to that object
which is stored and is constant here and now of execute to say again I'm saying hey I'm undefined.
Now why is that.
Well the reason for it Ed indeed is what I talked about aero functions.
This now here refers to the global scope to the global node runtime scope and not to this object to
have it refer to that.
We either have to use the old school function like this now I never repeat that I'm saying Hey Max or
we use a slightly different approach or syntax here in an object.
And that is you don't use an arrow function but you use grid like Det.
So you admit to Colon add the parentheses offered a key name and then without a function key word or
anything like that you add your function body.
And now this is a method of this object.
And you see.
Hi I'm Max 2 now.
So this is something important and does the index you'll see me use for this course without the colon
parentheses right after the key and then the function body.