The sides objects another crucial data structure in notorious or in Javascript in general are a race
like hobbies an array is defined with square brackets and in the array.
You can have any data you could normally use to.
You can use strings in there like sports and cooking.
You can have numbers in there and you don't have to use one the same type in the array.
Here we are mixing text and numbers.
You could have arrays with just text just numbers and so on.
Q Of course you can use boolean values and you can even store objects in there or ever arrays.
That is all possible.
Now here I'll have an array of text though.
And you can use for loops to go Fruitbat with this index for example with the four off loop where we
store each element for each iteration in that hobby variable.
And now if we do that we would execute Cancellara two times because we have two elements and we're looping
through all of them and then outputting the current value we're currently looking at because this will
change for every iteration going through it from left to right will output that for every two creation.
So now if I run this we see sports and cooking printed in two lines because it is executes two times.
So these are arrays.
Before all loop is interesting and it's also interesting that in javascript we got a lot of built in
methods we can use on the erase.
So on hobby's on that array.
If I add a dot my ID suggests a lot of methods I can use on arrays and Javascript and all these methods
help me go through the elements in the array manipulate them get a subset of that array whatever I need.
Often you'll see map for example which allows you to transform an array or transform the values and
map will actually return a new array.
So it will not added the old one but give you a new one.
And we can print dead new one here actually.
And just to show that the old one was not edited.
We can print that right below.
And now map always takes a function where you define how to add at that array or how to edit the elements
of the array.
That function will be executed on every element in the array one after another and you return the updated
version of the element.
So here we would get our hobby.
You can name this however you want and here I'm using an arrow function with one argument only.
Hence no parentheses and any Here I'll return D added to the word.
For example here I could take my old hobby string and simply add hobby.
White whitespace in front of that.
So I'm simply constructing a new string which keeps the old hobby name but adds hobby and white space
in front of it.
And yes since we only got one statement in that arrow function with the return statement we can get
rid of the curly braces.
Get rid of her turn and just return like this.
This would be the equivalent.
And now has it cleared us and I run plage Yes I see the old array was not added it.
That is my second output here.
It's coming from this console lock where I console locked the original array.
But the result of my map here is a new array where I have my edited items with hubby added in front
of every item.
And this is something you'll see me do quite a bit in this course.
Used that map method.
And as I mentioned it's only one of the many methods provided here.
Always check out the docs on M.D and to learn more about all these methods.
Link can be found attached to this video and make sure that you understand how to work or that when
we use one of them in this course you can quickly look it up in case it's not clear what exactly that
does though of course I will do my best to explain it when we use it.
But these are arrays very important data structures and some very important methods you can use on arrays.