Knouted we learn about objects and their race.
There's one common misconception I sometimes see in the Q and A section.
Please check out that video I linked earlier in this article where I talk about primitive and reference
types and Javascript because that is a crucial concept.
Objects and arrays are so-called reference types and you'll learn all about that and what that is in
the linked video.
So I'm not going to re-explain it here.
They are reference types and therefore when I store an array in a constant hobby's I can still edit
disarrayed without violating the restriction that constants must not change.
Let me prove that to you via comment.
They are out and they add a new line here and I use a number image method.
The push method which allows me to add a new element to the existing array.
So this will not return a new array.
It will add to the existing array.
And here I will add programming over.
Now console lock hobbies ofter pushing and a run node play Geass you'll see that Asti output and we
get no error or about editing this constant.
The reason for that is that reference types only store an address pointing at the place in memory where
that array is stored and that pointer does address has not changed by us adding a new element.
Sort of thing stored and as constant is just as pointer just does address and this has not changed.
Therefore our constant value has not changed the thing it's pointing at has changed.
But that totally does not matter here.
And this is something you have to understand so that you don't wonder what's going on.
When we do edit in quotation marks a constant value.
We're not really editing a thing that is stored in a constant.
We're only editing the thing.
That constant thing is pointing at.