In modern javascript there are two important operators.
You all should be aware of since I'll be using them from the Course as well and that are to rest and
spread.
Operators know specifically the spread operator is one will use quite a bit.
Let's say we want to implement the pattern where when we add a new hobby we don't edit the original
array.
But we create a new array with all the old values and the new value.
This is actually a pretty common pattern called immutability where we never added existing values but
we're we always replace them with copies plus the changes.
And that is all a pattern I'll use quite a lot in the course.
The idea behind that is that we avoid errors because we always have this clear approach of copy.
Then add it and don't edit existing objects which might lead to more unreadable code.
Now to copy an array let's say Here I create a copied array.
We got a couple of possible techniques.
One of them is to used to slice operator.
Now if I output copied arrays down there and I run no place I see sports and cooking's so I did indeed
copy it Sly's simply copies an array we can pass arguments to narrow down the range of elements we want
to copy with no arguments.
We copied the entire array.
Now instead of Sluys There is also a different technique we can create a new array with square brackets
and we could at hobby's stare right.
Now what happens if we execute this what will we see in the console.
Well if I hit Enter we see well it looks like a copy on first sight but actually it's an array with
a number array in it.
So the outer array has only one element and that's the inner array.
So it's not a copy.
It's just a new array where the first element is the old array.
And with that I mean the exact same object not a copy of that.
So we just create created nested array here.
That of course was not what we did want to do here and here we can use to spread operator the spread.
Operator are three dots we can add in front of an array or of an object.
And these free dots are an operator just as the plus or minus are.
And they do one thing.
They take the array or object ofter the operator and pull out all the elements or properties.
So all the elements of the array or all the properties of an object and put it to whatever is around
debt spread operator.
In this case we got square brackets around the spread operator and they had for all the elements which
are pulled out of the existing array or add it to the new array.
And therefore if I now run this fall again whoops and I save it before running it again.
Now we see this was the output of the old approach the nested array.
Now we got no nested array anymore.
We got one array.
And this is now a copy of the old one because we take the spread operator to pull out these elements
and add them one by one to the new era.
So this is something you'll see me do a lot to copy existing arrays or object and would work in the
same way we could have our copied person by using curly braces then the spread operator the free dots
and then the old person and now if a console locked to copied person your and I execute this file again.
This is our copied person here because I'm pulling out all these elements from that object and I added
to a new object.
So this works for both objects and arrays.
And in this syntax I'll use quite a bit in this course.
Now does this to spread.
Operator I also mentioned the rest.
Operator and the rest operator is essentially the opposite.
Let's say I have a function which all named Q array.
It's an arrow function.
And there I expect arguments are one or two are free I want to return an array that contains these arguments
and issue at equal sign here.
So I want to return an array that contains these arguments.
I can return square brackets here of course and then the first element will be one then I have are two
as the second element and are free as the first element.
Now I can console lock to Array and I pass one two and free as the free arguments to that function.
If I now execute plage as we see an array with 1 2 and free these free elements.
So this is working.
But this is totally not flexible.
What if we want to pass for arguments.
Well we could call it like that.
Javascript actually allows that.
But of course it doesn't get added because we only work with free arguments here where we could do was
we could use the so-called rest operator dear dot dot dot.
And then just aurochs and this will actually take all the arguments how many we might specify that doesn't
matter and we'll bundle them up in an array for us.
So here args will be an array and I can just return data actually.
And now if we execute this with two aere getting four arguments you'll see now I have my array with
four arguments here.
So the rest operator looks just like the spread operator.
Three dots and it's the place where you use it that defines how you call it.
Are you using it to pull elements or properties out of arrays or objects then it would be the spread
operator.
Are you using it to merge multiple arguments into an array.
And you use it in the argument list of a function.
Then it's the rest operator.
It's the same operator by the syntax or from a syntax perspective the name differs depending on the
place where you use it.
I'll not use that syntax a lot in this course but it's still nice to know.
But being able to pull out elements or properties that is something you should understand because dad
is a Sendak's you'll see me use quite a bit for all the course.