Rest and spread are important syntaxes to know.
Now I want to dive into another important feature and that is deep structuring.
Now let me comment out this code down there and let's begin with object.
Destructuring I got my personal object and now let's say we have some code where I only need the name
so I have a new function print name let's say.
And that actually takes the full person object because for whatever reason we write roaded like this
or we simply have a function where we are able to get multiple arguments or a full object because some
third party package all this gives us that person we can't change that.
So we get the person here and I only want to console lock person name.
Now that is totally fine of doing it like this.
I can now execute pretty name here.
Now I need to pass a person here.
Now to a wide naming confusion confusion you can name this year however you want.
So here we could name it person data.
And inside here we use person data.
So that function does not use that person.
It just expects any person data.
We didn't call that function and pass in that person as an argument.
And now if they execute that file I see Max here.
Does this stemming from this line here.
Now of course we can absolutely do it like that and we always get person data because again let's say
it is a function which is actually called by some third party package which is a pattern you see quite
a bit from this course now.
Therefore we can't change the data we get.
But in this function here we are only interested in the name.
We can then use a Sendak's or a feature called object destructuring where we add curly braces here in
the argument list and we then specify the property of the incoming object we are interested in name
that is property we have here.
Then this will be pulled out of the incoming object.
The other properties will be dropped for this function and it will be stored in a variable named name
which we then can use in there.
So now if they execute this again I also see Max but now we're using this destructuring syntax and we
can pull out the h too if you want to or degreed function.
So Dad all works and that is just the syntax we can use that allows us to write a bit of a more understandable
code where we are very clear about what we need from the incoming object and which then gets stored
in a local variable that we can just use in this function.
And you can of course not just use destructuring instead of a function.
You can also use it outside of there.
You can create a new constant here for example and then the syntax will look like this curly braces
equals person curly braces on the left side of the equal sign are something we don't see that often.
Javascript because typically it's wrong but for destructuring it's correct.
And then here we can have the name of the H.
And this will create two new constants which hold the values stored and name and age.
So these names here have to match the property names.
Off the person.
And now we can console log name and age like this and now execute that file this output here is coming
from this console log.
And the value is where outputting here are retrieved wya object destructuring not aerosols and not just
object destructuring.
You can also structure arrays.
So if we go back to the hobby's what you have you're well and if you would want to structure that we
can also create a concert.
You could also use LET by the way to save for the object restructuring if you plan on changing it you
could use a concert for hobby one and hobby two wrapped in square brackets.
And then assigned us to hobbies and now if you console log hobby one and you can SLOC hobby to and you
execute that file again you'll see the two hobbies being printed there.
Please note there are no square brackets around them in the console lock because we're not locked in
array here.
We are logging to individual values which we got wya aere destructuring.
Unlike the optic destructuring here you can choose any names you want because in arrays your elements
have no names.
They are instead pulled out by position.
So this will always be the first element.
This will be the second element in object.
You pull them out by name by property name so that is destructuring.
And this is also something used in this course.
It simply allows us to access elements in objects or arrays quickly by their name or position and to
draw up.
And that does not mean the elites are not getting deleted they're just not used and our function or
whatever we're writing.
So to draw up the data we don't need in that specific code snippet we're working on.