Now I cleared the place as falling in because to conclude is a quick refresher module I'll dive into
Naracoorte concept and that is how to work with a synchronous code and for that we first of all have
to understand what a synchronous code is.
Let's say I set a timer with set timeout which is a function built into node.
Yes there we define a function that should execute after a certain time are expired.
Here I'll use an arrow function.
You could use a named function or whatever you like.
The second argument is the time or let's say two seconds.
You express it in milli seconds so two seconds are 2000 seconds in there I'll simply lock.
Timer is done.
If I now run this file for two seconds nothing happens and then we see timer is done.
Now this is a synchronous code because it doesn't finish immediately.
And it would even be a code if we had one millisecond there.
So if it's super fast it does not happen immediately.
In our code step it's like if we have a console log hello and console log high these two snippets are
synchronous code because they are executed right after each other.
And yet technically of course node will take some time to execute them but there is no delay Ivrit on
your hardware.
So to say and therefore does a synchronous code this is async code asynchronous because it does not
execute or finish immediately.
It takes a little time even if that super short.
And indeed if I execute this fall like this U.S. Hello.
Hi.
Before you see timer's done even though it's super fast because no J.S. and Javascript in general does
not block your code execution until that is done indeed here it will recognize this so-called callback
function.
So a function that should execute in the future it should call back later once it is done so once this
time it's expired here it will just recognize that and will then immediately move onto the next line
and it will execute all the synchronous code and then execute your async code once it is done.
Which is why we see how low and high.
First even though in our code timers is print at first and that is a crucial concept you have to understand
in javascript and especially Knode and now will come back to that throughout the course because it's
so important now when Rikan with debt and all increases to 2 seconds I get to make it even clearer.
Then you will see again our sync code runs and then after two seconds discard runs.
When working with async code we get multiple techniques of well handling it.
The callback function is one.
The oldest one and you'll see it quite a bit especially notorious.
There is nothing wrong with it but you'll face a problem if you have a couple of the pending async operations.
So here we set the timer and now let's say I create a number function
which I'll name fetch data.
And in there I will also just set a timer because I don't want to set up some data base or something
like that where we fetch data from will do all that for the course of course.
No worries.
So here again I have a number timer in there which takes like 1 and a half seconds.
And now here in fecche data I need some way of well doing something when this inner timer is done.
So here I will actually expect an argument which I'll name call back because this argument will be a
function I will eventually call in my inner function here once I'm done with the timer and there I can
pass done as a value.
Now in the place where a use fetch data let's say that's inside of this set time I'll call I call fetch
data like this.
There I now need to pass never call back.
And here I will get the text passed by a callback in my function when they execute it.
So we'll get some text you're an icon so lock data text.
Now this might look confusing in the end here I'm creating my own function which gets a callback so
that I can define a function which should execute once his inner timer is done from some other place.
So from this place here does the function which effectively is passed in as the callback and I'm executing
that function here.
Now if I save that and run that takes 2 seconds then it's time the timer is done.
And then after 1 1/2 seconds I see done.
Now if we have a couple of nested async calls as we have here we go deeper and deeper from a callback
perspective.
And that is what we all have a feature called Promises which we can use no Chia's now often we'll use
third party packages that already use promises for us.
So to Centex I'll show you now is one you really have to write on your own.
That will be done by the packages behind the scenes.
Still nice to know you create a promise inside of our fetch date a function your let's say by storing
it in a constant or variable and then by using the new keyword which you use in javascript to create
a new object based on a constructor.
If constructor functions are something that tells you nothing.
Check out some basic introduction resource to javascript because constructor functions are a core feature
in Javascript.
And here you use the promise constructor function which is built into javascript and no notorious and
does actually also takes a callback which gets two arguments Rosol than reject.
You could name them however you want but these are two functions and the first one completes the promise
successfully.
It resolves that successfully.
The second one rejects it which is like throwing an error.
You then take your async code and move it into there.
And again you really have to write this on your own.
Most packages already do that for you and give you the finished promise which does all the magic behind
the scenes.
Hidden away from you.
Here we do it manually.
So now in Dad's call we have our own function set.
Time out does not give us a promise API unfortunately so here we all have to use a callback.
But in their we now know no longer use any callback function we get I get no argument here and fetch
data anymore.
Instead here I resolve done let's say.
So I successfully return to resolve value.
Now in fecche data ofter defining the promise we just have to return it.
And please note this is synchronous code.
So actually this will be returned immediately after the promise gets created before the code and the
promise is run which will happen sometime later when we actually call that function and when this time
it completes.
So we now return that promise here and in the place where we call fetch data we now no longer pass a
call back but we can now use then which is callable on a promise and we return a promise and this simply
allows to now define the called function here which will execute once the promise is resolved.
Now what is the advantage of that.
If we had multiple such promises so let's say I called fecche data again in there.
Then I don't have to use that like dis and therefore I would end up with nested callbacks again.
But instead inside of a promise and then block is part of a promise.
I can just return a new promise and then add the next and then block ofter the previous one like this.
So now we have a chain.
Then blocks this one gets called on the first promise that ended then block and return another promise.
And even if that would not give us a promise instead of a then block returning it would convert it to
a promise that instantly rissoles and then we add a number.
Then block which is now referring to this promise year and this is more readable than having infinitely
nested callbacks.
So now if I run that and we see Hello high to time or is done we done and we sit down again because
I'm calling fetch data twice.
So this might be difficult to wrap your head around for the first time.
We will reuse it for this course and that it will become clearer.
Again this code is mostly not written by you but it is a crucial concept that makes our async code more
manageable.
There also is another way of managing this async await two special keywords you can use in modern javascript
and all have a separate section about this toolbar.
And of course I don't want to introduce it here because it can actually be more confusing than dissent
next year and I'll want to stick to this one to not introduce too many new features at the same time
here.
Async code is something you have to understand though.
And if it's not totally clear by now that is fine though you will see it for the course.
A bunch.
Because we have a lot of asynchronous events in notorious and it will explain this multiple times.
I'll also explain promises again.
I just want to ensure that you have seen this by now and that you don't have a chance of understanding
this how it works and how we deal with it.