That's it for this refresher module Obviously there's no complete javascript module.
There are way more feature which I didn't touch on.
And the reason for it at a simple I do require very basic javascript knowledge at least if you've gotten
on.
Check out the resources linked in the second lecture off this module.
These resources allow you to dive into javascript for free or with paid courses whatever you want.
And with that plus as a refresher about next gen javascript items or features as well you are more than
prepared to continue with the course and now understand the code.
We will ride for the course.
I hope this was helpful.
Let's now dive in to know Chase and write exciting applications.