So let's dive into No.
J.S. now and what better way to start with it then of course from scratch with its basics in this module.
You will learn how the web actually works.
This will only be a brief refresher.
But since we will of course use no chase in this course to build a server a web application and writes
to recite code we obviously have to make sure we all understand how the web works and which role no
Chase plays in that bigger picture.
Now this will only be a brief refresher.
Obviously we'll then dive into creating such a node.
J.S. server and running.
No.
Yes code when requests are reaching that server.
And of course we'll also send back responses.
For this we'll also use node core modules like a file system module you saw in the first course section
will use a number of very important core module in this section which is related to creating such a
web server.
Now as I already mentioned an important part of creating a web server is of course that we're able to
handle requests and responses so that you'll learn how you can use no Chiasson the many features that
offer us to accept incoming requests and do something with them.
For example parse them and how to send back responses.
These are crucial things you've got to know now related to all of that.
We'll learn how no Che's uses asynchronous code and a concept called the event loop to stay reactive
and ensure that our script never slows down and always works just fine.
So with that let's dive into no Geass.