So let me quickly refresh our knowledge on how the web works.
If you are totally weariful DOES YOUR KIND of course skip this lecture.
Now the web works like this.
We get got a user a client.
Maybe you sitting in front of your browser wasting a web page or already being on a web page and submitting
a form.
So you're interacting with web pages.
Let's say you are wasting it.
So you're entering some you are l into your browser.
And what happens behind the scenes is actually that the browser reaches out to some domain name servers
to look Data Domain up because this domain is not really the address off your server.
It's basically encoded human readable words that address you could say your server itself has just an
IP address but it's just some technical thing behind the scenes.
In the end you enter this you are l and it will lead to some server you therefore or the browser therefore
sends a request to that server.
With that given IP address I mentioned Sodhi IP address belonging to that domain.
Now that's far Densil interesting but now we reached a part where no chase comes into play where your
no chase code matters.
You write the code that runs on that computer in the Internet which has that IP address.
You write the code that spins up that server which is able to handle the incoming request and do something
with it.
Now you don't need to use node.
JS For this you could use BHP as Peter that Ruby on Rails.
Anything like that.
But in discours will obviously use no yes because well it's no chess course.
Now in this code you can do all kinds of things and I already mentioned just the first course module
user input validation.
Communicating with a database maybe which runs on a separate database server but which you typically
reach out to from your back and so your server side code.
And once you're done with that you do one important thing you'll send back a response to the client.
This response can be some HD mail text some TMail code which is then handled by the client but it could
also be some average kind of data like a file some Jason or XM.
All data.
The response is more than just the content by the way a response and a request also has headers.
Does is some meta information which is attached to request and response describing what's inside it
for example.
But we'll see this too.
So does is how the Web generally works and no chases the part we will focus on it is the code that makes
up that server in the end.
Now that request and response transmission is done through some protocol.
So basically a standardized way of communicating you could say because obviously to correctly handler
request and send back a response the browser can work with.
We have to follow some rules and these rules are defined by the protocol we use age to be or age to
be as HTP stands for hypertext transfer protocol.
And there we simply define where it is defined how a valid request looks like and how that data should
be transferred from browser to server.
And the other way around an age to CBS simply is the same with SSL encryption turned on where all the
data that is transmitted is actually encrypted so that if anyone is spoofing your connection they can
read your data.
Now towards the end of the course I will show you how to enable h to be s for the majority we'll just
use HTP since we'll only be developing that code will only work on it locally.
But once you put it into production I will also show you how to turn on that SSL encryption.
This is how the web works.
In a nutshell and how no chase is related to it and this is exactly where we will now continue working
with no chase and where we will now finally create a server with no chance.