So let's go back to the request object relocked here.
Now important just to keep that in mind.
This request object is the object no chaced generated for us with all the data off the incoming request.
When we visited localhost few thousand which we in turn can do because we listened to requests on that
port.
So this is the request object if we have a look at it.
We see it's a very complex optic.
There's lots of data in it.
It's not just data.
These are also partly functions we can call and so on.
So this is quite a complex object but we all see that for example we have some hetero's here headers
as I mentioned earlier our meta data meta information added to a request and also two responses by way.
And there we see for example the host this was sent to the request was sent to you.
We saw Zalm headers attached by the browser.
Like for example of how the response data should be cached and stuff like that which browser we used
for data request which kind of response we would accept that we accept some age Tim L A SML and so on
that we would accept and coded responses so where the response is actually many fights to well save
bandwidth and so on.
Gerald It was a cookie attached.
Even we have learned about cookies yet we will sell later.
But this was attached some Google Analytics cookie we saw which HTP question was you asked and so on.
So there's a lot we can gain from that request but a bit too much.
Now there are only a few important fields you typically need.
The first important or interesting field is you are.
Let's output debt and let's all the output you can output more than one value by separating them with
Comus request Methot and all the request headers here.
That's output.
Free values and restart the server with node actually.
So now it's again listening and let's reload that page on localhost three thousand.
We do so now we see the output has changed.
We still have all the headers stuff because we're outputting request headers but prior to that we output
the method which you see here it's get and two-CD you are ill and you are elist justice slash here because
you are l.
It's basically everything ofter our host and we just have localhost.
Well nothing.
And that basically translates to local host slash.
If I had slash test now we see a number output and there we see slash test being locked here and then
also get for the method and our headers.
So this is basically how we can access some information about our request.
Now one crucial thing that is missing here is the response.
So let's have a look at sending responses in the next lecture.