In the last lectures we learn how to spin up that server and that we get a request object with information
about the incoming requests and the response object that we can use to send back a response.
Let's now connect both requests and response.
Instead of printing some request data to the consulate which of course doesn't do much for us.
Let's instead start writing a very simple web server that does different things depending on which route
we enter.
So depending on which slash whatever part we enter here.
So let's say for Slash nothing.
We want to load a page where the user can enter some data which we don't store in a file on a server.
Once it is sent we can do this by first of all parsing D U R L I'm storing it in a new concept and I
do this by accessing request.
You are l remember there was something like slash slash test whatever we entered.
I will then add an if statement and check if your L is equal to just slash and only this will match.
By the way the triple equal sign means that this will only be true if you r l is both a string and has
that value.
So now here if that is the case I want to return a response which holds some H T.M. that gives the user
input form and a button that will send the new request in return and that will not be a GET request.
By the way.
So let's see the step by step let's copy this code here and put it into this if statement.
And here I will write to HTL document with a hat maybe a different title enter message.
And the body will now not hold the H-1 tech but instead a form.
This is a DiVall Tim L. element of course with input of type text.
Let's say and a button and does we'll be super awkward because we have no styling but it's about the
functionality for now.
That baton tag must be close by the way the button will be of type submit so that it submits to for
him and there will be some default H.T. male behavior we're using here.
Wear a button with type submit in a form element will send you request and we'll configure it and request
in a second.
Let's first give the button a caption send.
And now on that form element here we add action which is basically you are all this request which will
be generated automatically should be sent to and I will use a slash message here and this will automatically
target the host.
It's running on so local host in our case your localhost free 0 0 0 0.
To be precise.
And then we defined the method.
The HTP method that should be used and there we previously saw if we expand this that we get a get request
which is the default if we enter a u r l.
Well here we are not entering a u r l Instead we want to send a so-called post request there is a limited
set of HTP words you can use GET and POST are the two most important ones that get request is automatically
sent.
When you click a link or enter a u r l a POST request has to be set up by you by creating such a form.
There also are some other ways by using javascript but we'll ignore them for now.
So in h tim L we create such a form and we find that the Moffit should be post and this will send a
post request to slash message and the cool thing about formis it will not just send such a request.
It will also look into the form detect any inputs or related elements like selects.
We might have.
And if we give that input a name which we should message it will also automatically put that message
into the request it sends to our server.
So now here when we wisit just localhost free thousand slash nothing we will return a response where
we render dis h team l code.
Now let's also put a return statement in front of rests and does this not required to return a response
but to return from this anonymous function and to not continue this code because we return prior to
it.
And this will quit the function execution and we must do this because I told you that ofter rests and
we must not call any Over rest riots or arrests set headers.
But this what happens if we not return because standard would just continue execution with these lines.
I don't want it.
If we make it into the if statement.
We should also quit here.
We should exit out of dysfunction with this let's restart the server by quitting it with Control-C and
restarting it with node apps.
Yes and let's reload this page on localhost Fredo and slash nothing.
And we see why input and the send button here.
Again not super pretty but it's working.
Now let's make sure that if we enter something we hit send.
We see this that we now not only see this but that something else happens.
By the way we do is see this because now the you are l is slash message and slash message does not make
it into the if statement and therefore this code runs.
But we want to do something else.
So let's do that in the next Electra's.