So we made sure that we listen to requests to just slash nothing and that we return some age HTML code
with our input field on it.
Now when we click that send button we send a POST request to slash message but we're not doing anything
with that time to change that.
Let's add another statement here.
And let's check if your L is equal to message and let's add another condition and that condition is
that I want to be sure that we're not handling a GET request but a POST request here.
So let's also parse the method from request method and make sure that method is equal to post.
Now we'll only enter this if statement if we have a POST request to slash message which happens to be
exactly what we create with this form.
In this case I want to do two things I want to redirect the user back to slash nothing.
So not leave him on slash message.
And I want to create a new file and store it a message to user entered in it.
Now this involves a couple of things.
Let's start with redirecting and creating that file.
We actually already worked with a file in the first core section.
And do you remember how Dad worked.
Feel free to go along on your own if you know that we need another package and not a core module.
And that was the file system core module.
So let's import it by storing the functionality in a constant.
You can name it however you want.
I'll name it.
F s.
Because the package is named FS but you can also named it differently.
This not the package just a constant so f s allows us to work with the file system.
And here I now want to write a new file.
So here let's execute it right file and right file takes a to the file and I'll just use the file name
to create in the same folder as Apicius and I'll simply name it message dot text and in there I obviously
want to store what the user sent.
Now this is a little bit more work so for now let's just put some dummy text in there and let's redirect
to user.
Important.
We should actually use right files sync for now and I'll explain what the difference to right file which
Oulds exists is in a while.
So let's use right files sync for now.
Now right.
Head which basically allows us to write some method information in one go and then we set up status
code of free 102 which stands for redirection.
And then we pass a javascript object with some headers.
We want to set and you could also do this in two steps.
By the way you can also set the status code to to 302 and then simply have a set header.
And there we set the location.
This is also a default header except that by the browser.
And we set that location to just slash and it will automatically use to host.
We're already running on.
And then we have to call rest and and important ask before returned us so that we don't execute these
lines otherwise we will get an error.
Now let's restart our file here.
And make sure to go back to slash nothing and reload that page with the input field and send the value.
And you should simply reload that in the end because you get redirected here but you can see that redirect
here in the Network tab of the developer tools here 302 indicates we send a request to message and we
were redirected to localhost.
So this is working.
And we also got the message text with dummy inside of it.
Now let's also get rid of that though.
And let's work on actually parsing the data.
The user sent us and writing data data into that file.