We already achieved a lot in this section.
And I noted all this code looks kind of intimidating and no worries it will become much easier but I
find it super important to learn it the hard way first so that you'll never forget what's happening
behind the scenes.
Now one crucial thing which I note that people often struggle with is that the order of execution of
your code here is not necessarily the order in which you write it.
For example this year will actually execute after this code so it will even execute after we already
sent the response.
This has two important implications for one sending the response does not mean that our event listeners
here are dead.
They will still execute even if the response is already gone.
But it also means that if we do something in the event listener that should influence the response this
is the wrong way of setting it up.
We should then also move the response code into the event listener.
If we had such a dependency.
But it also means that it's super important to understand that if request on or code like HTP create
server.
So basically always when you have code where you pass a function as an argument to a function that in
such cases no chase won't immediately run that function.
Instead what it does when it first encounters this line is that it will simply add a new eventless internally.
It manages all these listeners internally.
In this case for the end event on the request which will be triggered automatically once no chase is
done parsing the request.
So this is something no chase does for you.
And it will then call that function for you.
Once it is done so in the end you can think of this like no chase having some internal registry of events
and listeners to these events and a function like this is such a listener and when sort of something
happens so when no chance is done parsing your request it will go through dead registry and see.
I'm done with the request so I should now send D and events.
Let's see which listeners I have for debt and will then find dysfunction and any other functions you
might have registered for that and will now call them but it will not posti average code execution and
that is so important to understand.
So for example here now since I moved return response and into this function the flow is like this.
It will now reached as if statement and if these conditions are met it will go inside of it.
It will then register these two handlers and not immediately execute these two functions.
Instead the functions are just registered internally in its event emitter registry and then it will
jump straight the way to the next line and therefore right now if I would restart my server and save
to code and restart my server.
Your you will see that if I enter something here I actually get redirected to this page or not even
redirect it as you can see.
There is no 300 status code instead of just Lote's this page because it executes these lines because
as of now mentioned multiple times it will not execute this right away.
And this return statement will therefore not quit this overarching function here.
Instead it just registers this callback and immediately moves onto the next lines.
And it would eventually execute this line but that is already too late.
Which is also why we get the cannot set hetero's error here because it already moved along and executed
this code when all of a sudden the parsing of the request finished and it executed this code and tried
to again send a response which obviously is too late because it already did here.
Now I know that it is hard to wrap your head around but it is a crucial concept that you can register
code functions which run some time in the future but not necessarily right now.
And therefore the next line of code does code here can run or will run before this code simply because
it is just a callback to be called sometime in the future.
And this set up is important because otherwise node would have to pause until it's done pause until
it wrote the file.
And if it does that it will simply slow our server down and it's not able to handle incoming requests
or do anything of that kind until it's done.
And that's not what we want.
We don't want to block our code execution.
We always want to be in that wait for new events loop the event loop and then only execute code once
it's to be executed and never blocked that event loop for too long of a time.
And this is why we have this set up.
And this has one implication for design and for this line application for design is that we reach it
too early.
So to a white this we should actually return here.
We simply return request on so that this gets executed.
But the line thereafter doesn't.
And the important application about this line will be discussed in the next lecture.