Over the last lectures I extensively mentioned how Noad works with asynchronous code.
And they mentioned this event loop which is important.
Let me dive deeper into that and deeper into how.
No chance exactly executes your code to stay performant and still be able to handle long taking tasks
like working with files or things like that because there is an important concept which you have to
understand to understand well what is happening behind the scenes.
So in our node application we have our code.
And one important thing to understand and to really keep in mind is that node J.S. uses only one single
javascript Fred.
Fred is basically like a process in your operating system you could say.
So it's only using data one thread and the obvious question is how is it then able to handle multiple
requests because if we're not able to assign a new fret for each request they ultimately end up all
running in one on the same fret.
And this of course poses a security question.
Can you then access data from request a from request B and most importantly here at this point when
we talk about performance there are of course always the question of does does not mean that if you
request a is still doing work request B can't be handled well both this taking care of all.
No.
Yes.
And at this point of time here I want to focus on the performance question though I'll also briefly
touch on the security question.
Now let's start with the performance.
Let's say we have some code which accesses the file system as we already did in this course to now working
with files off this a task that takes longer because files can be very big and it doesn't necessarily
complete instantly.
Therefore if we're doing days upon an incoming request a second request might have to wait because we're
not able to handle it yet or it even gets declined.
So basically our Web page is down for dead user.
Now one important construct I already mentioned is debt event loop the event loop is automatically started
by no chase when your program starts.
You don't have to do that explicitly.
No chase dust when well.
It basically starts running code.
This is responsible for a handling event callbacks though.
So all these nice functions we basically added thus far in create server for example the event loop
is responsible for basically running that code when a certain event occurs you could say it's aware
of all these callbacks and basically well execute said code that doesn't help us with our long taking
file operation though and it's important to understand that this operation is not handled by the event
loop just the call back that we might have to find on right file.
Once it's done that code will be handled in an event loop but that code will finish fast.
So basically the event loop will only handle callbacks that contain fast finishing code.
Instead our file system operation and a couple of Avro long tagging operations are sent to a worker
pool which is also spun up and managed by no js automatically.
This worker pool is responsible for all the heavy lifting.
This worker pool is kind of totally detached of your javascript code you could say and it runs on different
frets Fretz it can spin up multiple Fretz it's closely intervened with your operating system you're
running the app on.
So this is really detached from your code and this worker pool is therefore doing all the heavy lifting.
If you're doing something with a file Well a worker from that pool will take care and will do its job.
Totally detached from your code and from the request and from the event loop D-1 connection to the event.
We will have though is dead.
Once the worker is done so for example once we read a file it will trigger the call back for dead read
file operation and since the event loop is responsible for two events and the callbacks does well in
the end and up in the event loop.
So there no G-S will then basically execute the appropriate callback.
Now this is a lot of behind the scenes stuff which is nice to know you don't have to write any code
to make this work.
This is all built into no jack ass.
And if you write code as you learn it in this course you automatically take advantage of this.
I still of course want you to understand how it works behind the scenes because I believe that helps
you understand.
No change is better.
Now let's look into that event loop.
Then that event loop isn't the end.
A loop which is run or started by no chase that keeps the no chase process running.
And as I just mentioned that handles all the callbacks and it has a certain order in which it goes through
the callbacks.
So basically it's a loop that just keeps on looping.
Unsurprisingly at the beginning of each new iteration it checks if there are any time or callbacks it
should execute We haven't set up any timers yet.
But basically there is set time out and set interval.
You might notice from Front-End javascript to their DS methods also exist now and no chance you can
also set a timer and basically you set a timer and always pass a method a function that should be executed.
Once that timer completes and no chance is aware of this and at the beginning of each new iteration
it executes any due time or callbacks.
So any callbacks that have to be executed because of timer completes then as a next step it checks Avro
callbacks.
For example if we had write or read file we might have a callback because that operation finished and
it will then also execute these callbacks.
Now be aware that with I O here I mean generally any input output operations that typically is file
operations but can also be network operations and in general I'm talking about blocking long taking
operations.
Now it's important to understand that no chase will leave dead face at a certain point of time and that
can also mean that if there are too many outstanding callbacks it will continue its loop iteration and
postpone these callbacks to the next iteration to execute them after working on these open callbacks
and hopefully finishing them all.
It will enter a pulse face the pole phase is basically a phase where no chase will look for new events
and basically do its best to execute dare call backs immediately if possible.
Now if that's not possible it will defer the execution and basically register this as a pending callback.
So this is how that works.
Important it all to we'll check if there are any timer callbacks due to be executed.
And if that is the case it will chum to that time or face and execute them right away.
So it can actually chump back there and not finished iteration.
Otherwise it will continue.
And next set immediate callbacks will be executed in a so-called check face set immediate is a bit like
sex time out or is that interval just deaded will execute immediately but always offer any open callbacks
have been executed.
So typically faster then sets time out with one millisecond of open duration let's say.
But after the current cycle.
Well finished or at least finished open callbacks that were due to be handled in that current iteration
and now we're entering a highly theoretical terrain.
And I don't want to dive too deep into that though you will find a couple of resources that you dive
deeper at the end of this module in case you want to join you know chess team and really dive super
hard core introduce.
Now we're nearing the end of each iteration cycle and now no chase will execute all close event callbacks.
So if you register any close events and in our code we haven't.
But if you had any close events this would be the point of time where no chase executes dare appropriate
callbacks.
So roughly spoken we have timer callbacks we don't have any I O related callbacks and other event callbacks
and set immediate followed by close event called x.
So close events are basically handled separately or they're callbacks are handled separately we should
say well and Denn we might exit the whole node Jasp program but only if there are no remaining event
handlers which are registered and that is what I mean with this refs equal Knol thing here internally.
Note J.S. keeps track of its open event listeners and it basically has a counter references or refs
which it increments by 1 for every new call back to registered.
Every new event listener that is registered.
So every new future work it has to do.
You could say and it reduces that counter by 1 for every event listener that it doesn't need any more
every call back it finished and sends a server environment.
We create a server with create server and then listened to incoming requests with listen.
This is an event which never is finished by default and therefore we always have at least one reference
and therefore we don't exit in a normal node web server program we can call the exit function as you
already saw.
And if we do anything else like at the beginning of the course when we just use node to execute a file
that did not listen to a web server or on a web server then it all finishes eventually once its done
with its work.
So this is how it eventually works.
And this can be very few radical all these different phases typically don't matter to you certainly
not when getting started with no chance.
Now consult these advanced resources if you want to learn more.
For now just be aware of that first picture I showed you of how node shapes handles complex work that
there is a worker pool that takes care that your things are not getting blocked and that it therefore
stays performant.
Now I also touched on that security thing with that one javascript fret.
And regarding that we also got no problems by default.
Though I will come back later to how we can manage global data and how we should manage it to ensure
that we do not spoil data from request to request be by default.
We have some separation because remember that callback method in 3:8 server gets executed for every
new incoming request and therefore dysfunction only runs for that incoming request and anything we do
to a request or a response Optik there will not be exposed to our request or response objects because
each function is only scoped to itself and not accessible by the functions.
So by default we have that separation due to how javascript works.
Now that was a big chunk of theory.
Again not something you have to learn by heart but something where you should at least keep that big
picture in mind of how no chase manages its work.