So let's wrap this Monch.
And right before we finish Let's actually start wrapping it up by improving our code a little bit.
We've got all this code in this file and actually typically you write multiples or work with multiple
files.
And why don't we create a new file that actually contains our routing logic.
So the logic where we check the you r l and do different things.
So I'll trade and you follow your routes.
J.S. the name is up to you and I get this special I can buy my ID.
It is an all javascript file.
Don't be confused.
And in that file I basically want to have my IF statements here and my default response code.
So I'll cut all of that out of yours so that this is a pretty Leeton file and move it into route's chase.
Now this wouldn't work like that.
Let me say that we'll have to tweak that.
But this is now the code moved over.
I don't need the file system in.
Actually yes I mean we're so we can remove that import.
We do need HTP because we still use that there and we don't need to you are Ellen Methot Here's let's
remove that go over routes.
Yes add is important than to hop.
And now start working with that.
Now what do we need to do in this fall.
We somehow need to be able to connect access to routes.
CHACE right.
Because we need to be able to send our incoming request to that file.
So to say and for that let's create a new function I'll name it.
Request handler and we can either create a function like this.
It should receive request and response as arguments just as dysfunction does because we'll effectively
replace that function or we use the iOS 6 function.
Storing it in a constant request handler which looks like this bit of a strange syntax if you've never
seen it before but we're essentially creating an anonymous Erol function which we store in a constant.
And this therefore has to function name.
Now here we again receive request and response and in that function we now move all that code because
that code obviously uses the request and response object.
So we need to have them available as local variables and we do now because these arguments are now named
this way.
We also use u r l and Methot.
So we need to reach at these Constans by getting that data out from the request request your L and request
method and now we just need to export this handler we're importing with this requires syntax.
But how are we exporting and no chance.
There are two ways of exporting.
The first one is to go at the bottom and add module exports.
This is another key word or object which is X-posts globally to you by no Geass which has an exports
property.
And we can assign a value to this like our request handler.
So this constant which holds dysfunction it's now stored in module exports.
And since this is a global object exposed post by note no it is actually able to work with this.
And we can now import from that route's chase file by requiring it and node will look for module exports
and see if something was registered for this file here.
And we do register something in Marchal exports the request handler and you can register anything here.
You can add and new javascript object with multiple key value pairs whatever you need here.
I'll just register my function.
So now I can get go back to actually yes and import my routes the name of that constant is up to you
by requiring it.
And since this is now not a global module we don't just type routes.
Instead we want to add a local port to it with dot slash and you can omit dot J.S. because no trace
will automatically attached as at the end.
You can add it though.
But I'll just tell you it.
Tie up dot slash routes separated from the core modules to make it really clear that this is a custom
file.
And now Noad will go ahead and look for our routes.
Yes fall in the same folder as actually yes which it will find and in that file it will look for module
exports and see what's registered in there.
And now we export dead request handler method and now we can use that.
It will be stored in that routes because we assign whatever is exported from that file in that route's
constant.
So this route's constant will ultimately hold this function.
And now we can use that here as a handler.
Routes don't execute it.
So no parentheses just pass the name telling node hey please execute the function that's stored and
routes for incoming requests.
And now if we save that and we restart the server and we reload this page does this looking good.
And this is also looking good.
We should have tests stored in message a text and we do.
So now we simply split our code over two files having one file which is very lean that's just spins
up the server.
But and that's important.
That also creates a connection to another file through that import and through that export where we
export our request handler function here.
This is how that works.
Now one important note about notes modular system the file content here is actually cached by note and
we can't edit it externally.
So if we somehow define route's as an object and we tried to add a new property on the fly here this
would not manipulate the original file.
So this is basically locked not accessible from outside.
We can only export stuff that we can now read from outside though.
You could have functions which you export that start changing stuff inside of that file.
But let's not make that too complicated for now.
We'll see all of that for the course obviously for now we have that connection.
There's one Iverson's ex you could use instead of module exports.
Sometimes you export many things and you could do that by having an object which has like a handler
a key and that is my request handler function.
And then also it has some text key which is some hard code it's text.
In this case now we would export to things and that is how you can group that or separate these two
things and still have one export being managed here which is the most you can have.
And now an app japes route's would be that object and not that function.
So here we would have to access to a handler property.
So this property which holds the function referenced one of us and we could also simply output console
log routes some text here.
So this is how we can have multiple exports in one file.
Now you see some hard coded text here from this console lock and we still have the same functionality
as before.
Now there all is a different way of exporting multiple things.
Besides this code which you can of course use you can also have a module that exports Daut handler request
handler and then Oulds a module that exports dot some text some heart coded text.
Now it might look different but we still only have one export.
We still have module exports which bundles all the exports but we explicitly assigned different properties
like this.
So this is basically equivalent to this code.
If I now safeties and restart my server it's we see some hard coded text and if I submit this it all
still works.
And last but not least there is a shortcut for this syntax.
You can now emit module and just write exports.
This is simply a short cut supported by no J.S. not some general javascript magic.
It's just an explicit shortcut supported by no choice where now we all have multiple exports being merged
together into one export.
So therefore again who would execute this.
We see some hard coded text and some lost value being submitted here still works and still ends up in
message to text.
So this is how we can connect multiple files by exporting either one element one function as we had
it initially with modular on exports equals request handler.
Right.
This is what we had initially.
Let me comment this out with two slashes in front of it or module exports pointing at an object to combine
multiple things or using modules on exports dog handler he calls request handler and module Daut exports
start some text equal some text or Again
shortcut which is the same as it is just with this shortcut offered by no G-S.
So this is how imports and exports work how the module system works and we'll work with a lot of files
from the course.
So this is important to understand.
With that out of the way let's now finally wrap this Marchal up.