So let's sum this Monch a lot.
No.
First of all we had a brief refresher on how the web works and in general it looks like this client
so the browser sends a request to the server the server does some magic reaches out to a database works
with files sends back a response can be.
Tim L can be something different and sends it back to the client the browser which then can display
that.
And that is the entire flow we all saw in this module.
Now no chase the part that runs on the server.
And regarding its lifecycle there is one important concept in data that so-called event loop.
No chase code runs in a non-blocking way which means we only register a bunch of callbacks and events
and no chase will eventually trigger that code.
Once a certain task is done so that the javascript threat is always free to handle new events new incoming
requests and stuff like debt and no program can exit if there is no more work to do.
But on a server this wall should at least never happen because create server registers an event listener
for an event which is never done.
If new event triggers a venue request is received this does not mean that node unregister is the event
listener.
Instead we keep on listening for more requests and that is of course how a server should behave.
So it's this cycle that's important to understand and that we have to is LWT which always keeps on going
keeps on waiting for new events and which does something when some event happens and then basically
dispatches some actions to the operating system you could say for example.
And then again frees up the threat.
Now this all involves a lot of asynchronous code which we saw with all the callbacks the javascript
code should be nonblocking.
So we have this callback and event driven approach where we are able to register some code to be executed
in the future instead of running right away and blocking the main threat because this has to be avoided
under all circumstances and no chase is built around that concept of avoiding this issue.
We also saw how to work with requests and responses.
Dino SJS way we saw that we have to parse the requests data which arrives in chunks and we can use this
concept of streams and buffers which I explained and did we showed a white sending double responses
so that ofter rests.
And you must not send a response and this can happen easily if you forget about that asynchronous nature
and that a line of code you write might not execute immediately.
So depending on where you write it if its in an event listener it will not execute immediately.
That is what I mean.
And that is what is important to keep in mind here we also learn that no chess is all about using it's
built in functionalities.
And whilst there are some global variables or objects or functions we can use this also means that we
should use its core modules core modules are things like the HTP DFS or the path module.
There are more and you can learn all about them in the official no chase docs of course we'll also use
quite a lot of them for this course and these core modules give us a couple of different functionalities
that allow us to basically do what ever we ever could want to do on a server like create and use it
with the help of DHC to be Mauch all there.
Or did y d requires syntax.
And we can only use them in the file into which we import them.
And if we want to use them in two different files we have to import them and both files separately.
Now that leads us to the no node modules system and this basically works with the help of this required
keyword which pulls some functionality from one of our files.
If we start with Slash or dot slash or from a core or third party module we haven't used any third party
modules thus far.
But we'll also do that soon.
And it basically pulls in whatever we export there and stores it in a new variable or constant as we
did it in this module.
And export is important keyword here.
We do export with the help of module Daut exports or for multiple exports with the export shortcut.
I showed you in the last lectures.
So this is what we learn in this module.
And I know that this was a lot of fury or nitty gritty stuff about.
No it just doesn't look too easy and beautiful but it'll get way more beautiful from now on.
It is super important to never forget what no chase is and does it for you though because many courses
right away start with Express shapes which will also use starting soon.
And therefore you never really learn what's happening under the hood which is sad because this is important
and makes you a better note developer.
But with that let's move on.