In this course you obviously learn a lot about Noad and how to write code code and build web servers
or web applications with Knode because there really is its main thing.
But note NPM the package manager we get for free when installing no chase can also be used as a build
tool.
So as a tool that runs utility scripts on your computer and can help you with building any mostly javascript
driven project and that does not have to be a web application or a service wide web application if it
is one it could be a front and web application too.
Like do you react as we had in this course the front end for the arrest and the Graph API and in this
module will briefly dive into that and I'll explain why that is to case what exactly NPM is and how
we can use it and how we can use node as a built tool.