It's important to understand.
Dead when we install no yes we get two tools or things for the price of one you could say we get no
genius and we get NPM notes package manager.
And remember that this was the tool we used for installing packages into our project or when I share
my project like with all the code attachments that you could re-install all dependencies required by
that project.
Even though I did not shared a node modules folder because we have that packaged adjacent fall where
we see all the dependencies.
So no.
To programming language we used to execute code to execute javascript code based on that note has runtime
with all the features that gives us and especially important when we look at it from a built tool perspective.
We have to remember that with note J.S. we were able to interact with files and this will become important
in a second.
NPM as I said is node's package manager.
So we manage guess what packages with it and with that I mean we can install packages download them
manage their work chansons on and we can also run scripts.
We did that with NPM start for example to start our server so that we don't have to write or type the
full command for that.
Now let's have a closer look at these two pieces and see what else they can do or how that can be helpful
to use them in the context of build tooling so in the context of utilities scripts and not in the context
of spinning up a web server.