Now and we briefly walked through NPM and what we use it for.
Let's bring something back into our memory note.
J.S. indice course was primarily used to spin up a web server and write code that runs on the server
side and that is indeed the main thing you do with no TS When you write your own notorious apps.
But we have to remember that theoretically you can run any javascript code with no genius and specifically
you can also interact with your local file system.
You can read and write files after all.
And that opens up a new door a new opportunity.
We could use no chance to execute utility's scripts that for example parse certain files manipulate
the content and output the manipulated content back into the original file or into a new file.
And that is the idea behind so-called built tools and that is something notorious awls as capable of
being used for.
And it's important pointing out here that when we talk about built tooling and build workflows we mostly
talk about front end web development like for example with our re-act application here this re-act application
is not a node JSA app but still we use a package adjacent fall and we use NPM to install packages.
These packages are all holding code that runs in the browser though and in the end the code we write
here in the source folder will also end up in the browser.
But let me point out that the way we write it here would not run in browsers at least not in all browsers.
For example we are splitting our javascript code here across multiple files and we're using it as module
import syntax for merging these files together.
Now this does not natively work in all browsers only in very modern browsers and therefore it does is
indeed not the code that will end up in the browser.
Does this code we work with.
But we use a built tool build workflow which is stardate during development with NPM start and for production
with NPM run build this build workflow we'll take our code and kind of merge it together and transform
it into code that runs in older browsers too.
And that is also minute fight and optimized because that's all important we use build tools to optimize
our code.
We might write code that looks like this.
That is indeed how our code looks like into react.
I just showed you.
But as I mentioned this does not run in all browsers.
And even if it would it would be very large in the browser.
Since all the code has to be downloaded by your users before it runs.
And that's different on the server there decode sits on the server and that's it in the browser.
The code has to be downloaded and therefore you want to keep it as small as possible so that your app
and your javascript code in the browser starts as quickly as possible.
Therefore we want to end up with optimized code and the idea here is that we also have code that is
not only too big but dad is using next gen features like here to spread operator or aero functions and
we want to work this to code that runs an older browsers too.
And that is like an example optimized code which is shorter we use less characters and therefore the
code is shorter and it also does not use next generation javascript features.
And that is the idea and as I mentioned it's primarily important for Front-End development because they're
not all browsers support the next features.
And we want to keep our code as small as possible.
That does not really matter that much on the server side.
So that is the idea.
That is what we can use node in and plan for.
Because if we go back to our re-act project we want to convert dat code into our optimized work.
And if you run NPM run built in your project here you actually start such a production of workflow which
means now it's creating an optimized production bundle.
And this is all done by NPM which started the script and by node.
And here it completed and now indeed if we look into this build fuller this now holds our app code.
So the code we wrote and source.
But in an optimized way they are in the static folder we have javascript code and if we look into that
this in the end is our code.
Just many fight a lot and therefore it's pretty hard to read but it's our code and this code is not
just very condensed and only contains current gen javascript logic so logic that runs in all the browsers
to do is of course not the code we would like to write.
It's very hard to dig through that but it is to code want to output and we use NPM and node to transform
our code.
That's the idea behind built tooling.
And now let's have a closer look at how NPM and node can help us with that.