So we want to end up with optimized code.
And again this is most important for Front-End projects.
NPM is useful because we can install packages we can manage this project with our package touch base
and fall and we can of course install packages that run in the browser too.
It's our duty as a developer to ensure that we don't try to install express years into this project
because we couldn't use any functionality from Express Yes in the browser but we know as a fronted developer
which package we can use and we want to use we find that out with research and so on.
And then we can install these packages and we can import them and our files with a slightly different
syntax that just happens to be primarily used for undented development.
Import Export syntax.
With that as module style because dad is actually the style that is supported in modern browsers too.
And then this is done by NPM we install the packages and now we also want to start a script with NPM
now and PM's work is over and no chase takes over.
Do you react scripts.
Package here.
Let's look into that.
And for that we can look into our node modules folder and run NPM install in case you don't have that
because that will install all dependencies that are listed in your package don't chase and file and
now in modules.
Let's search for it at re-act scripts.
Package and you can see by the list that is very long that all package have a lot of dependencies which
in turn have dependencies which is why we end up with a lot of packages being installed here.
Now I'm in the re-act area though and there I find re-act scripts now there we all are packaged our
chase and fall because if you share a package you all to meet that you need to add some extra information
to the package.
Jason Folden and you can learn all about creating and sharing packages in the official NPM docs if you're
interested.
And there you will all find like the entry point that is executed which is in the bin folder re-act
scripts James co-teacher.
This is the end to code that will be executed.
And now here's something important.
This code well and can't be executed by Noj J.S. because the idea behind build workflows is of course
that it runs on your computer before you deploy your optimized code.
So before you upload your optimized code to some server so this code will not run in the browser or
anything like that this code will run on your local machine and therefore it will be executed by node.
J.S. This is also the case because in the end this code will kickstart scripts will kick start a recode
and will kickstarted code that will also work with your local file system.
For example in the scripts folder we find to built js file and there we will see what else it does.
And now this is actually a very complex build workflow.
LDN does use a tool called web Pech which is used heavily in front and development to orchestrate your
build workflow and to compile your different files and unlock next gen features and make sure that you
can handle the features correctly again by using all the some other tools like babble but that would
lead to far higher.
The idea is here we are using notes as we can all tell that we are but a fact that we now have a different
import export syntax and we are loading different packages here.
We're running them and some of these packages will in the end all pick up our files.
So our local source code we have written here in the source folder.
We'll parse them and we'll transform the content in their poll.
All of them together because we don't want to have multiple files in the end but only very few files
with one main file.
We'll pull all that code together and then also rewrite our code in a way that also runs in older browsers.
And this is all done by a couple of packages which are used behind the scenes here which are installed
by NPM and then the code in that packages is executed through node J.S..
And that was a lot of talking about that but I really want to get that into your heads because it's
so important that you understand that you can use not just to execute any javascript code which uses
notorious features of course on your machine and that it's there for all you used to run utility scripts
and you could also write your own utilities script that like calculates or Taxus But here the utility
scripts actually take our source code and then transform it as defined by the packages we use because
we don't want to write all that built tooling code on our own.
And that is another important area where you can use yes and if you want to dive into that area.
Actually a lot of the knowledge you learn in this course like for example when it comes to work with
files will be useful but you will also have to pick up new skills because you need to know all the ins
and outs about working with files managing large chunks of data efficiently and so on.
You don't need to create a web service or anything like that.
You don't need to validate user input and that of course was the main topic off this course.
But this is a different area of notorious that you can all dive into if you are interested and especially
NPM is something that is worth having a look at.
Having a look at the commands you got there so that you farly understand what you can use NPM for and
if you want to learn how to distribute your own packages for example the getting started guide there
also teaches you dad how to publish an update packages and so on.
So check these resources out if that's interesting to you.
I found it important to mention that this also exists and is important area where no chase and NPM are
being used.